I have learned to become more forgiving
and more tolerant of people,
because when we think that in
each of us there is something that suffers,
a child that cries, we become
more indulgent and tolerant.
I think that the heart is something
very important,
and that we we have to always
speak and see with our heart,
as Saint-Exupéry said,
"We see clearly only with the heart."
We go on vacation!
Come on, let's go on vacation!
Gently, Marie, with your suitcase.
- It's going to be great!
- Long live the vacation
Long live the vacation!
Alice!
A big son of a bitch has put his car
in the "handicapped" spot again.
But we don't care.
Go ahead, buddies.
Arnaud.
Change your shoes.
- OK.
Boris!
What did we say about costumes?
We put them over there, OK?
I'm not Boris, je suis Cléopâtre.
Yes, go change, Cleopatra!
Your backpack is coming, Marc has it.
Are we OK, is everything there?
Mayane, what's this?
We said one suitcase per person.
I only have one.
What's this?
- It's bags.
- It's bags... It's bags.
You're right, it's bags.
I just have to be more specific.
And I'm the one carrying them, huh?
There.
Hello, it's Céline again,
from the Lilacs Home.
There's still a big bag of shit...
Can't you see that I play football?
- Eh, eh!
- Get lost!
You can see that...
Come. Come over there.
Céline, if we could avoid this, please...
- You have to be on the ball!
- It's OK, it's OK.
They have to learn from mistakes.
The mistake is that he's going to
get hit by a car.
Thank you, Marc.
It was nothing. I am here,
I will always be here.
Can we avoid playing
football on the road?
Stop whining!
We are robbing her,
it's normal that she's whining!
This is crazy!
She has the right to cry.
This is crazy.
We are robbing you, you have the right.
- Merci...
- It's normal.
- Are you together?
- Yes.
Yes?
Married?
No, precisely, I wanted to choose
an engagement ring today.
Huh?
Oh, she didn't know!
The timing sucks, but it's cool.
- Marc.
- I'm here, I'm always here.
Can you ask the driver to wait
5 minutes, please?
Damn, Thibaut.
No, Mayane!
Let's get out of here!
- Come on, let's get out!
- Yes, but I...
Congratulations.
- What are you doing? Come on!
- I'm coming!
Let's go!
Come on! Go, go, go!
To the right!
Take the bag.
Hurry up! Hurry up!
Yes, uh...
Let's go!
Get the clothes out!
Quick, come on!
It's good, I got them.
The clothes, the clothes!
Hurry up, asshole!
Yes.
Come on, come on!
There... Good, that's fine.
Come on, let's go!
- There.
- How are you dressed?
- Huh?
- How are you dressed??
Like a tourist, a German tourist,
it goes unnoticed.
You're like a clown,
they'll see that it was you!
You, it's obvious that you
just committed a robbery.
Marc?
Alice? Ouch! Yeah?
Any news on the new one?
Sylvain? I got his parents, he's coming.
Ok, great. Thanks.
Thank you, sir.
On behalf of the Republic,
as Nicolas Sarkozy said,
"The test is the absence,
and not the wound of vanity."
- Come, sir...
- No, we have to thank him!
It's not because he does a job
out of spite,
due to an academic failure, that we should not thank him.
No, Alexandre, you shouldn't say that.
The gentleman surely did not do
great studies, but it's a job like any other.
You go, it's better this way,
we thank you, sir...
- Thank you, sir.
- Goodbye, sir.
Let's go!
- Did you say goodbye?
- Thanks, goodbye, sir!
And there, it's complete.
You won't be able to carry the suitcases!
- Why, Ludo?
- Because you're fat!
Hey, Ludovic!
What did we say about insults?
- It's not nice!
- Then why do you say that?
Because he's fat!
He knows, there is no point in telling him!
Boris, what did I say?
I'm not Boris, I'm Supergirl.
Stop drinking, Gnafron!
- Are you crazy or what?
- Gnafron?
Eh! Are we on vacation
or are we not on vacation?
Soso.
Gad.
Alexandre.
- Marie.
- Absent.
Boris.
Arnaud.
- Present!
Baptiste.
Princess Mayane.
...and basket!
Thibaut.
- We're going on vacation!
- Ludovic.
- Everybody's here.
- Cool.
- Except, uh... Sylvain.
- We'll wait for him.
You distribute water bottles.
- Let's go.
- Ludo.
Catch. And you...
- There!
- And there!
Oh, damn it, Marie!
Nothing serious, she's used to it.
- I'm not  firsty!
- No, she's not  firsty, I think...
Come on, come on! Over there!
The car is no longer there.
Obviously, you parked
in a "disabled" spot.
Obviously, obviously...
You know everything!
- What'll we do now?
- Hush, we walk quietly.
Guten tag.
Hacht Fartun Ouch.
Ich Liebe Dich.
- Is that normal?
- I'm trying...
Shut up, it's better.
Go ahead, go ahead, go ahead.
Shit!
When do you park in a "disabled" spot?
There was one spot, I needed it...
- Shut up
- It was obvious.
- Move!
- We move, we move.
- They are over there.
- There, there.
What the hell is this?
It's nothing.
I think your latecomer has arrived.
- What's he doing?
- Oh, yes. Sylvain?
I'll find a solution... What?
Sylvain, is that you?
I am Alice.
I'm happy to see you, we were
waiting for you. Coming?
Come.
Yes, Sylvain. You have to go.
- We were waiting for you.
- Oh, yes?
Come on, we have to go.
Go ahead, get in.
Let me introduce you to Sylvain, my friends!
Excuse me, we're going to leave.
Yes, we have to leave.
Who are you to him?
His educator?
Yes, exactly.
I have to be with him.
There's no question about it,
last time it was shit.
But we didn't plan that.
Sylvain?
Welcome.
Do you want to sit at the back of the bus?
- OK, uh...
We'll sort this out at the lodge?
- Let's do this, come on.
Unfortunately, you are in a sector of activity
very little represented in
the popular imagination.
And in the end, the only figurehead
of your profession remains Emile Louis.
- Can we go already?
- Yeah, we're going.
- What do we say to the driver?
- Son of a bitch!
No, Ludo, not that. We say...?
- Long live the holidays!
So, did you convince her?
What did you tell her?
- Eh?
- What did you tell her?
Well, I told her that you were...
...you were sensitive, and there were
moments when you shit yourself.
- How come? I don't shit myself.
- Oh, yeah?
Well, no.
Should I remind you?
Palavas? Luna Park?
I was four years old, are you serious?
Well, you were four,
you were shitting yourself.
So what do we do?
Do what they do.
Look at them, look what they're like.
- I don't do the German anymore?
- No. You shut up and do like them.
Damn, he has a kippah.
He believes in God, doesn't hold grudges.
Come on, find your inner clown.
Find your inner clown.
It's too much, it's too much.
I'm trying to find the right way.
- Damn, but look at them.
- I'm trying. Excuse me, but...
She's coming, she's coming!
Shut your mouth.
I'm delighted to be on vacation.
Ah, it's cool.
- Are you okay, Sylvain?
- Yeah.
Yeah? I'm pleased to meet you.
You're going to make friends,
it's going to be great.
- Should I put your bag up there?
- No.
No, in fact, I have to keep the bag.
- All the medications are inside.
- All right.
There.
Will you introduce your educator?
What's his name?
- I'm...
- No!
In fact, no, no, it's better...
He's having trouble, we can see...
Yes, but we'll take our time,
like that, we'll meet.
I hear the sound of your voice,
you haven't lost your tongue.
What's your educator's name?
We have time, OK?
Orpi. Orpi.
Orpi.
- Orpi?
- Orpi, yeah.
- Okay. It's funny.
Orpi. Orpi.
- Yeah, Orpi.
- We understood.
We understood.
I'm Alice. I am delighted.
- Me, I'm Sylvain.
- Yes, Sylvain.
- Sylvain, and he is Orpi.
- Yes, that's it, we understood.
- Sylvain et Orpi.
- It's good.
Orpi, present. Sylvain, present here.
- There.
- Ok, great.
- If you're a little upset...
- Yes, it's hot.
...you tell me and we'll stop.
All right?
OK.
Don't poop in your underwear.
OK?
- No.
- No, no.
See you later.
And according to Séguéla,
Sarkozy, at the first dinner,
would have whispered in Carla's ear,
"Can I kiss you on the mouth
in front of everybody?"
"Are you up for it or not?",
at which she apparently answered
"not up to it".
And since then, they have been in love
for life. It's beautiful, huh?
Alice, can I put a little zizik?
Yes, go ahead.
Intro!
Contrary to what everybody thinks,
that's why he wears heels.
It's funny, huh?
What is this?
This music sucks.
I can't stand this music, Marc!
It absolutely sucks!
- It sucks!
Go fuck yourself!
Hey, what the hell is this music, Marc?
This? This is shit?
Yes, Dalida is better.
It's Paul Diamond, guys.
Paul, Diamond!
- I like it.
- You're jealous! You don't know...
Leave it. Go sit down,
I'll take care of it.
OK.
Come on.
There.
She is great!
That's not shit!
Pan pan, the pistols.
I'm loading.
Oh, I dropped my magazine.
- What are you doing, Paulo?
- I put myself in character.
Click-click,
Pan-Pan-Pan
And it's click, click-click,
What do we do?
I don't know. I'm thinking.
Ah, I know.
We can take them hostage.
Stop thinking.
Ah, I'm going to...
I'm going to call Rico.
Ah, damn! No network, obviously.
Hey!
Hey, excuse me.
Do you know where there is network?
You have a little in the field,
but it's hot.
OK, thanks.
Boris, can I help you with your suitcase?
Why doesn't the bus go up?
As I tell you each year,
Moisard the owner is afraid
that we will damage his path.
Because? Because?...
Because Moisard is an asshole!
Asshole! Asshole!
Moisard, asshole! Moisard, asshole!
Moisard, asshole!
...asshole! Moisard, asshole!
- Bonjour, M. Moisard.
- Hello, Mr. Moisard.
- Moisard, asshole!
- Hello, Mr. Moisard!
- Bonjour, M. Moisard.
- Hi, you're nice kid.
Hello.
Moisard, asshole!
- Hello, how are you?
- Good morning.
- Excuse them.
- No, there is no harm.
- Here you are, the keys.
- That's great, thanks a lot.
And I wanted to tell you,
next year I will increase the rate.
- Is this a joke?
- No.
But our entire budget for the year
goes into this rental.
- It's not my fault.
- They have been coming here for 10 years.
Well, yes, that's why I warn you in advance.
Can't you make a good deed?
We have no subsidy.
This way you'll have the chance
to find something else.
We don't want something else.
They are attached to this place.
It's not my fault.
So, have a nice stay.
It's not your fault... Jerk.
- Excuse me?
- What?
I didn't say that. It was...
Ludovic, we said
"no more bad words"!
I didn't say "jerk", but "asshole"!
All right...
Enjoy it.
OK.
Alice, no, no, you shouldn't do that,
I should.
I'm here, I'm always here.
Yeah, thank you.
Orpi, can you come help us?
We're settling in.
No, it's not possible,
because I'm making a call.
It's not the time now for that.
And Sylvain's parents still haven't
paid for the stay.
Ah, well, it's funny that you should say that,
because, exactly, I have to call
Sylvain's father
so that he can pay you the money
and you're not in trouble.
- Where is the network, you were saying?
- Towards the two trees.
- Be quick about it!
- Of course, what do you think?
Are you okay, Sylvain?
Sylvain?
- I'm hungry!
- Are you OK, Sylvain?
- Yes.
- OK. Alright?
Yes.
Feel at home here, OK?
I'll manage the beds, Céline.
- You...
- Yes.
Let's go.
Gad, you come up with us.
Gad, Gad! Not there.
Alice. I and Sylvain,
we want to sleep in the same bed.
Huh?
It's not possible, my darling.
It's possible. We are in love.
Oh, yeah, you're already in love?
Yes, anyway, it's...
We are in talks.
It's not acted upon.
In any case it's not possible
to sleep in a friend's bed.
- Oh...
- Each to their own bed.
Oh, it's not possible...
Oh, what a shame.
It's not...
It's bad luck.
It's not my fault.
I would have loved it.
You each have your own bed.
Let's go.
What "let's go"?
Don't worry, everything is fine.
Come.
- Everything OK?
- Yeah. Did you see Baptiste?
No, I imagine that he's
exploring the surroundings.
This is my tattoo.
Ah yes, I can see it.
I'm a fan of Dalida.
- No, really?
- Yes.
I should've guessed.
She was singing "With time",
"Dying on stage" and "I'm sick".
Okay, okay.
Maybe you could... Yeah.
Thanks.
Which bed do you want?
Well, I...
This one, it is good.
OK.
I'll take the other, no big deal.
- OK.
- That's it.
And which one do you want?
Oh...
This is gonna take a while...
Yes, yes, yes, yes. Yes.
Oh, damn.
- Do you want to come and play football?
- Wait, I'm making a call.
Come on, lift.
Wait! Cut! Cut!
Cut.
Hello?
- Yes.
Yes. It's, uh... it's The Strawberry.
Come!
Do you wanna come?
- Wait a moment.
Do you understand when I talk to you
or don't you?
- Come, we're going to play.
- No, I'm OK, it's fine.
Listen, I have a problem with the...
I have a problem with the car.
- What?
- We have to rec... This pisses me off!
You have to go get it in...
to the pound, because
if they make the connection,
they'll go back up...
Come and play!
...they will come up to me, understand?
Damn, guys.
- You think this is funny?
- Come on, come on!
Stay where you are.
- I'm getting the car back.
- Come!
Well, you sort it out!
Damn it!
We're going to play a game.
You go in the goal. Be the goalkeeper.
- You wanna play?
- Come, we're going to play a game.
There you go!
Go play the game. Yeah, go!
Come on, run!
Come on, go!
That's good.
- Where is my ball?
But where did it go? Oh!
Where is my ball?
You keep this one.
I'll take that one.
Like this, we are... We each have
our own. That's good too.
And which one do you take?
I'm your buddy, and you're the best.
Cool.
Very, very close.
That's for sure. Day and night.
Day and night...
Cool...
- Aren't you with Baptiste?
- What?
Aren't you with Baptiste?
- Which one is he?
- The tall one with a ball.
Ah, no. He must have fun with the others.
What the hell is this?
That's enough, turn off the music!
No, no, get off the table.
Get off the table, girls.
Everyone in the shower.
Ludo, stop eating candy.
Boris, come down.
Orpi, can you help me
manage the girls, please?
- It's too high.
- He'll take you off the table.
- What's wrong with you?
- It's okay.
No, it's not, they'll get hurt.
No, but I mean, there are worse things.
For example, we lost Baptiste.
- What?
- We lost Baptiste.
- Meaning...?
- I can't find him.
Did you look for him?
It's okay, don't worry.
At the speed it's moving,
he can't be far.
Yeah, great... Marc!
Alice!
- Marc, can you come?
- Yeah.
I am here.
I'll always be here.
- It seems we have a problem, we lost Baptiste.
- We lost Baptiste?
- We lost Baptiste. Don't panic.
- OK.
What we'll do is, you go with Orpi
to look for him,
we don't tell anyone,
we don't create panic. OK?
- He can go alone.
- No, no.
- Come on, to the shower!
- To the shower!
Follow me.
Damn.
Hey, you forgot me!
- Baptiste!
Eh, oh, buddy!
- Hey, hey, come there. He's...
- What?
He's not there, he's in the forest.
What would he do there?
Well... I just know it.
It's the instincts of an educator.
Baptiste!
- Damn.
- Oh, damn...
Baptiste, my friend!
Baptiste!
Okay, let's go. I'm sick of this.
That's enough. This is worrying.
I'll call the police.
No, no, no! No police.
Orpi, my phone!
This is the procedure.
Stop!
No!
Damn!
No! No. No.
Listen, no.
Excuse me.
It is important for them to discover nature,
to immerse themselves in it.
It's part of the process.
Huh?
Don't worry.
In 15 minutes we'll call the police,
if we don't find him.
- In 15 minutes.
- There you go.
OK? Come on, go on that side.
- Baptiste!
- My phone.
Orpi, my phone!
It's good, I have it.
He's annoying.
Come, little one!
Come!
Baptiste!
Come on, my Baptiste! Ronaldo!
It's okay now, Baptiste.
Oh, damn!
Orpi!
It's good! I found him, he's with me!
- There he is.
- Well, here you are.
We've been through the whole forest...
He was here.
- Shall we go, my friend?
- Let's get up. Stand up.
Super.
Holy cow, what's wrong with him?
I lost my ball.
- He lost his ball.
- Yes, OK, I got it...
Don't worry, we'll find you
another one.
Let's go.
I want mine. Don't follow me.
I want to look for it by myself.
He's gone again.
If you have another intuition, I'll take it.
You have to bring it back, period.
This is stupid.
My phone, Orpi.
Oh, damn!
What are you doing there,
behind me?
What are you doing there?
You're not disabled.
Yes, I am disabled. I've always
been disabled, since I was little.
It doesn't look like it.
I am too, I believe I...
Ah, well, it shows right away.
You're right, I am not disabled.
There. I'm...
I'm from the police.
I'm investigating a guy in this region...
You're not a police officer.
No, I'm not a police officer either.
I... I did some little stupid things.
So I have to hide a little while.
There, at least, you tell me the truth.
- What's your name?
- Arnaud.
Delighted. Paulo.
Don't tell anyone anything,
otherwise I'll go to jail.
I won't say anything to anyone.
Apart from Ludovic.
Who is Ludovic?
It's me, little dick!
Do you know what they do in prison
in the showers?
Uh, no. Why is he saying that?
But I don't know!
All right.
OK.
You don't tell anyone anything.
- I won't say anything.
- We say nothing.
- Nothing to anyone.
- OK
- Trust me.
Is it difficult to wash your back?
- Excuse me?
- Wash your back?
Wash your back? Uh, I...
Wash my back.
I don't have...
Wash my back!
Oh yeah, that's what I had...
Okay.
- No. I won't do it.
- You will too.
- No.
- Alice!
No, no! OK...
OK, fine. I will...
I'll wash your back, there.
I'll wash your back. Come in, then.
- All of us?
- All right. Everybody.
OK.
- Let's go.
- Wow, wow.
Wait, that touches me.
Damn, you found him, great.
Where was he?
- In the forest.
Great, Orpi, thank you very much.
Thank you, Orpi, thank you Orpi...
I'm the one who found him.
- Huh, Baptiste, I'm the one who found you?
- No, it's Orpi.
- Are you taking him to the shower?
- Yes.
Shall we go?
I want Orpi.
Oh, no. No, no.
Go with him,
he has his little pink gloves.
I want it to be with Orpi. Sorry, Marc.
Is that okay with you?
I have no choice.
The shower is here.
Come on, take your shower.
You have to undress me,
I can't do it alone.
Damn, what a pain.
Ok, raise your arms.
Not the belly. Don't touch the belly.
I don't want that!
Damn, that's stupid!
Shht!
Damn, you broke my phone!
- I didn't break it!
- Shh, not so loud. Be quiet.
- I didn't break it.
- OK.
But we don't speak loudly.
I didn't want to break it, excuse me.
OK...
It's cool.
OK, come on.
I'll undress you. I'll try
not to touch your belly, OK?
I undress a kid...
Higher. Higher.
There.
- Not the nose, don't touch, no nose!
- Not the nose.
- Not the arms!
- Fine.
- Not the arms, not the nose...
- Not the belly.
From behind? I think it's...
Not from the back.
- We're going to eat!
- We're going to eat, yes.
You all take your places.
Gad here, Baptiste there.
Come on, Boris, sit down.
Baptiste, you're there.
Everyone in their place,
we're good?
Sylvain!
Can you come?
I have to talk to you.
- Where are we going?
- To activity?
We go to activity!
We're going to the whores!
No, no one will go to the whores!
We're not going to the whores?
No, we're not going to the whores,
I'm sorry.
- Why?
- Well, that's how things are.
But we're going to do activities,
don't worry.
A little bit of silence
and I'll tell you something
because it's the beginning of summer.
We're going to have a great summer together.
I'm really happy.
Well, we're not.
You're not?
That's it, you liar.
Above all, the important thing is
that today we welcome...
- A shit!
- No, we welcome Sylvain.
Sylvain!
There. So say hello to Sylvain.
Hello, Sylvain!
Speech! Speech!
Speech! Speech! Speech!
Eh! We let Sylvain speak.
Come on.
Th... Thanks...
It's good, Sylvain, it's good.
- Great.
- Bravo!
You're at home here, OK?
Today, you are the king.
You sit at the head of the table.
He has the right, this is his first day.
Tomorrow, we will take back our places.
Come on, let's start.
Are you hungry?
Sylvain, carrots?
What's that?
This is, uh...
- Moussaka.
Oh, OK.
With Alice, we have a great bond.
We have the same humor,
the same conversation subjects.
We are on the same wavelength.
She has this terrible little thing, see?
When she gets angry,
she has this little vein,
so cute that...
And I tell myself that it would be good
if we could move forward, she and I.
You who have an outside perspective, Orpi,
do I have a chance or not?
Huh? No.
Damn.
I see what you mean.
It is true that it puts distance between us.
It is a form of modesty.
Come on, I'm going to pee.
I'll wait for you!
From home,
we'll be 2 hours from Los Angeles.
We take a plane and we'll be able to travel
around the United States.
That's crazy.
Even Yosemite Park, I told you about it.
Yeah, it's cool.
My love, we're going to be able
to do some crazy stuff.
Besides, you'll have to send me your papers.
Yes, I'll do it.
This is the 10th time I've asked you.
I'll do it.
They are annoying with the paperwork.
By the way, did you tell them
about your departure?
Uh, no. I didn't have time.
You're annoying!
We've talked about it 10 times!
I know, yes. I'll tell them tomorrow.
Tomorrow, yeah.
- Tomorrow?
- Yes, I promise.
Tomorrow, because after that,
things will turn and turn,
and after that, the
United States will be ours!
- It's gonna be wonderful. I can't wait.
- Yes, me too.
- I love you. It's from there.
- You're silly.
- I love you.
- Me too. Kisses.
Sylvain?
What?
You don't do the disabled too well.
What, I'm not doing it right?
You're kind...
I'm just starting.
Do you want me to show you?
Show me how to do it.
The tongue is placed to the side.
At the edge of the lips.
And you try to lean... that way.
- Head tilted and tongue out?
- Yeah, that's it.
- Like this?
- Yes.
That's a lot, isn't it?
Note, that looks very handicapped.
And the voice?
What do I do with the voice?
For the voice,
we will learn to speak well.
You can still talk, though.
Yeah. Sorry.
And if I do it... like this?
That's fine.
Or... like this? Like this?
There, I do it like that.
Maybe I can press it a little more.
Yes, that's it.
What's going on here?
This is crazy!
Often you move a little bit like this.
Well, yeah.
- That's it, right?
- Great.
It's great?
Awsome.
You have... to... help me...
find... a gift for... Marie.
Which one is Marie?
Sylvain, I have to talk to you.
We have to... Anyway.
You have to go pee
before you go to bed.
Come on. I'm waiting.
Hurry up.
All right. And is that your lover, Marie?
Oui.
Does she know it?
No, she is not aware.
That's what I thought.
But gifts are personal.
- You have to find a gift.
- Yes.
You want me to help you.
Oh, yeah.
OK... You know what?
- If you don't want to help me...
- Yeah?
I tell everyone that you touch me.
That I touch you? You're crazy.
That I touch you?
But it's not okay.
I never touched you.
And it's you who came in my shower.
I'm the one who could say something.
This is not done between friends.
We said we were friends.
This is blackmail, it's not good.
- Come on.
- Come on. You were a good coach.
What is it?
We are in shit.
- Why are we?
- Because. Because...
I have to call Rico, but the problem is,
the mongolito broke my phone.
I have to find a solution, I have to...
And the bag, where is it?
The bag is... well protected,
believe me.
It will not move.
Hello.
There.
Good night.
Bonne nuit.
Damn, that's not fair.
What do we do?
What do we do? What do we do?
We...
We stay here, we don't move,
we don't move one ear.
You continue to do the mongolito,
like this...
And then... I will find a solution.
There. That's what we'll do.
- OK.
- Hey, hey!
They didn't spot you, have they?
They? Are you kidding me or what?
No, no.
They don't see anything.
They told me, "You're just like us."
Yeah, huh?
Yeah.
Everything is fine?
Awsome. Marc Vador sleeps upstairs.
And I met a bottle of ketchup
who was coming back from peeing.
A normal evening, really.
- I'll serve you, huh? There.
- Thanks.
I never asked you
why you became an educator.
Ah, well...
I was manager at La Défense,
and then, one day,
I was eating a bo bun on the esplanade
and a pigeon landed right in front of me.
And it only had one leg.
- What?
It only had one leg.
And there, I said to myself...
"Céline, this is a sign."
"Take care of the disabled."
- OK.
- Life changing.
Come on.
Speaking of which,
what are you going to say to your boyfriend?
Oh, damn, I don't know.
Not "Go away alone",
he's been supporting me for years.
It will not be the same without you.
I don't know how
I'm going to tell them.
And there is a problem...
you're going to break Marc's heart.
Yeah, Marc.
- You'll break his heart.
- Yes.
- Alice.
- Yes?
You're stupid!
"Alice, look at me."
"Alice, I'm here."
"I will always be here."
"Alice, don't leave! My heart beats for you."
Arrête, arrête...
"Alice, take me!"
You will wake up everyone!
- It was too loud.
- Well, yeah, it's too loud.
You're exaggerating.
I can't hear you at all anymore.
Your guy, do you love him?
Well, yes, I love him.
Well, going to the other side of the world with
the guy you love, there are worse projects.
Yeah, I know.
Mmh. You know, you know...
One wouldn't say.
Why are you saying this?
You have just torn off a whole field.
Yes.
Not wrong.
"Alice."
"I'm your guy."
Oh, damn!
Are you coming to play?
- Oh, damn.
- Come on!
Orpi, come!
Yes, yes, yes.
- Is it going well?
- Awsome.
- What are you doing, Ludo?
- A guy.
Oh, yes, great. And you, Thibaut?
- A basketball court.
- Ah, yes, OK.
It's super-well done. Wow!
- And you, Gad?
- Un sandwich.
Uh... You can't eat the salt dough. OK?
- But I haven't eaten it.
- No, no, but I'm telling you just in case.
- Sofian, what are you doing?
- A cap.
A cap?
There, that's the tail.
The tail of the cap?
The visor, you mean.
Yes, the visor.
Yeah, well, it doesn't look too much
like a cap.
But go ahead, you'll get there.
Sylvain.
I have something to tell you.
Yes, I'm listening.
There. I'm more in love with you.
I'm sorry.
Ah... oh my...
Oh, what a shame.
Don't worry, you will get over it.
It will take time, but...
you'll get over it. Otherwise, suicide.
OK...
Orpi?
Look, it's a bird.
Oh yeah, now that you mention it...
I'm going to pee.
Sylvain?
How are you?
I'm OK.
- Do you feel well?
- Yeah.
Do you like it, the activity?
Yeah, it's a blast.
Salt dough, basically.
Yes, it's salt dough.
- Do you need to pee?
- No.
Are you autonomous in peeing?
Yes, I'm "tautonomous".
- It's the poop, then?
- No, it's nothing.
- If you want I come with you.
- Come on, I gotta dry this. It has to dry.
Damn, he's annoying, Marc.
Yes, it's really incredible.
Always behind...
Did you find a gift for Marie?
Oh, no, I haven't...
That's because I thought it would be
not bad for you to see her, first.
To tell her you like her.
No.
- Why?
- It's not possible.
No, no...
I can't.
- Arnaud.
- I can't.
Arnaud!
Look.
This is a bird.
It's like bread.
We put Nutella and lots of sugar.
See you later.
- See you later.
- Yes.
Oh yeah, yeah. We already...
We had a good talk, huh!
No, Baptiste, stop!
Stop already, I can't do it... Stop.
I can't make the knot.
- Can you lend me your cell phone?
- I'm busy. Stop, Baptiste, really, I can't do it.
Do you want the loop of the champions?
Ok, Ronaldo, I'll show you.
He makes a knot, like this.
A loop.
You have to go through again...
Exactly. You go back through it.
And snap, the loop of the champions.
- Can you lend me your cell phone now?
- Yes, yes. Of course.
- Bravo.
- Thanks.
Flawless.
Look at what I did!
Yeah. It's pretty. What is it?
A wind turbine.
All right.
Maybe you need to add a mast,
or other blades, to make it more...
No, it's very good like this.
I'll show it to Gad.
No, no. No, don't show it to Gad.
Because...
Because it's not models that Gad likes.
- OK.
- Oh, no!
No, no! It's confusing,
but I didn't do that.
Oh, but you know,
it's great, Sylvain.
The idea is to express yourself.
You do what you want.
Yes, but it's not me.
- We express ourselves freely!
Listen to Ludo. We express ourselves freely,
we do what we want.
I made a heart.
Why do you laugh?
Are you in love with Alice?
- I'm not, what are you...
- When is marriage?
I'm not in love...
I'm not in love with Alice, I'm not.
Ha, ha, so funny!
Continue your sausage there.
Here, I give this back to you.
Did your grandfather teach you that?
No, it was all me, I trained...
Cool. Cool.
- Alice, come and see!
- Self-taught...
Yeah? Oh, my, what did you do, Ludo?
A man.
- All right. Is that the head?
- It's the head.
And what is this?
- The balls!
- OK.
At least one small bar...
- Hello?
- This is The Strawberry.
No, sir. It's not ready yet.
I don't have all the parts.
I'll keep you posted. Bye.
Damn. Fuck you.
A little coffee?
Honestly, your Dalida is very well done.
Oh, yeah? That's great.
- Oh, yeah. I made a heart.
- Me, the cock.
- You are really talented. Really.
- Thank you, that's kind.
There you go, you've
made some friends.
It's cool, I'm pleased.
Yeah, it's cool.
Thank you.
Come on, the starters.
The starters! The starters! The starters!
Celery remoulade.
- What is this?
- Uh... I no longer remember.
- Lasagna.
- There, lasagna.
Hop, thank you.
No, that's enough. I'm careful.
Good, well... Bon appetit, anyway.
Ah, it disgusts me.
It's disgusting.
- Let's go?
- Beurk, it's disgusting.
- Don't you want to taste it?
- No, it's disgusting.
You taste it.
My Soso.
- Yes, what?
- I just got your mom on the phone.
Oh yeah, so? When is she coming?
Uh... It's going to be complicated
with her new job and all.
I'm not sure she'll come.
Ah. OK.
It doesn't matter.
And you, why did your
parents put you in the center?
- Because you're shit!
- No, Ludovic.
Let him answer, please. Okay?
My mom is dead.
Sorry, we didn't know.
That's OK.
And my father, it's...
It's complicated.
He wanted me to be like him, but I...
mais il acceptera jamais que je sois...
I'm different.
But we are with you.
Thank you, Soso.
My mom, she is...
very nice to me.
And uh... Also, she alowed me...
My mother allowed me to come...
And my father didn't want to keep me.
And that's when she got a brain tumor.
And after her brain tumor,
my mother is dead.
I cried a lot and I think a lot about her.
And it's very hard for me.
A Santa Claus?
A robot?
- A rifle?
- Hot air balloon?
A 12 calibre?
A 12 calibre!
- A dick!
- Well done, Ludo!
Hello, Mr. Gendarme.
- Léon Zitrone?
- Yes.
Elton John! Elton John!
I didn't sing!
That was easy, honestly.
Yes, it's me, the vampire.
It's Rambo!
Come on, somebody else.
- Demis Roussos.
- Lagy Gaga!
Non, c'est pas Macron!
- Michael Jackson?
- Yes.
Sarkozy, oui!
Silence!
Your mouths!
You're not stupid.
Sylvain, it's your turn.
You haven't been yet.
Ah, you're hiding.
Look, no one will judge you.
We're having fun, no one's going to...
how to say this?...
Fine, shut up.
OK, I'm going.
- What did he say?
- Shut up.
OK.
It's good, he's comfortable.
A peanut?
- Uh, Wonder Woman?
- A horse?
Someone who phones, isn't it?
- A hen?
- Yes, that's it, it's a hen!
- Another one.
- Look at the other badger.
- Ludovic!
- Ananas?
Jean-Marie Le Pen.
- For sure, it's Ludovic!
- Supergirl!
Donald Trump?
He is good.
It's... a beautiful badger.
No, it's not a badger, it's a dinosaur.
- Good... we leave you two minutes.
- No.
- Yes, come.
- We'll watch the show!
But you wanted to tell me something.
Let's go get some fresh air, Orpi,
a little bit.
Because now, Orpi is tired.
Orpi needs to get some fresh air. Huh?
Well, yes.
Are you stupid or what?
Eh, oh, eh, oh, eh!
How are you talking to me?
What are you doing?
Hein?
How do you talk to your father?
Attention.
Why are you doing this?
What is the goal?
I'm fucking sick of this.
I'm sick of it...
All this, the shitty countryside...
It's okay, I'm not an educator.
You're...
You're not a mongol, either.
You're not mentally retarded.
So what do we do?
We're here for a week.
What are we doing?
If you want to pull a face, do it.
I want to enjoy it.
Ah, wait, wait.
I see you.
Little Alice?
Do you want to kiss her?
Do you want to ki...
- Look at yourself.
- Fuck her. Be a good man.
Why are you looking at my body?
It's none of your business,
put on your t-shirt.
Okay, I'll manage.
- How's your little injury, Marie?
- It's very good.
- Can I have a look?
- Go ahead.
My beloved nurse.
I'm sick of all this.
I'm not the one who's going to wipe you.
It's fine, yeah.
Not able to manage on your own...
I swear to you, if...
- Is all going well?
- Yes, great.
You're OK?
It's been three days already,
Sylvain's adaptation is going well.
Awesome, yeah.
- So I think you can leave him.
- No.
No. No, uh...
Yes.
But...
I don't know, I was thinking maybe
I can be of help if I...
For example, with...
- Baptiste?
Baptiste. We have We have a real bond,
there's something happening that's cool.
Would you be happy
if Orpi stayed with us?
Uh... Yes, I get along very well with him.
Good, well, great.
However, I can't pay you.
Don't tell me you're doing this
for the money?
The same.
Hey, oh!
You forgot me, you bunch of idiots.
You manage really great.
- J'ai écrit "Sylvain".
- It's great.
Who is Nicolas?
Nicolas was, uh...
He was a boarder, like you.
Like you, he had
a little something extra.
His little extra something was an illness.
The disease was stronger than him.
We engrave our names to have
a trace of those who are no longer here.
Orpi?
It's your turn.
No, it's OK, I'm past the age
to have my name on a tree.
- Are you coming?
- Yes.
Be careful.
It's good?
- Are you okay, Sylvain?
- Excellent.
Hey, guys!
We're going shopping with Marc.
For the next two hours it's Céline
and Orpi who take care of you.
- Be cool, OK?
- Yes, of course.
My mother and I always went
shopping together.
I loved it.
Alice!
On peut venir avec Soso?
Shopping?
- Yeah, me too!
- Wait.
Me too!
Not everyone.
We only have four seats in the car.
So the first: Soso, Sylvain,
Arnaud and Ludovic. You can come.
Sylvain, Sylvain.
You're not going to go.
No, because they'll...
They'll see you.
You risk being seen, being made fun of.
People will see your face.
Yeah, it's true. But I'll take the risk.
- Huh?
- Let's go shopping! Let's go!
Céline, can you manage the meditation workshop?
No, wait, can we do something else instead?
No, we talked about this,
it does them a lot of good.
No, it pisses everyone off.
- And besides, meditation not my thing at all.
- Thank you, Sylvain.
- Oh, yeah, what is your thing?
- Hunting.
- Hunting?
- Well, yeah!
I love hunting. Bang!
I love it.
It's funny, you're not easy to understand,
Céline.
You are surprizing.
You have a lot of facets.
- Merci.
Orpi, then you manage meditation?
Medi...? Yeah, oh, well...
Yeah, no... No problem, I love it.
Ok, awesome. Great.
And did you get the transfer
from Sylvain's father?
No.
We have to take care of that.
Because the other one doesn't call back,
yeah, yeah. No, no, you're...
- Are you handling this?
- Yeah.
OK, thanks a lot.
See you later, everyone.
Thibaut, what are you doing with that cow?
Celine, handle the cow for me, please!
Yeah, yeah... What's with this cow?
Oh, my, Thibaut.
Where did you catch it? Come on.
Bijou, come. Come on, come.
- Thibaut, we have no room.
- Come, Thibaut!
- No, we can't.
- Oh, she's running!
Should I come forward?
- We don't have to close.
- We do what we can.
- Are you sure?
- It'll be fine.
No belt, it rings.
Tell me...
This meditation, what do you do?
- It's how Alice said.
- OK, but what is it?
Well, meditation...
You talk to trees, you breathe...
Faggot stuff.
Oh, yeah?
And it's funny, because when you talk,
it doesn't sound like how you're dressed.
Anyway, I'm saying you're not the same inside
as you are outside.
It's best to close your eyes.
Like that, when we close our eyes,
well, we...
we see better inside... ourselves.
OK?
There.
So we close our eyes.
We do it well.
And then, there you go, we...
relax.
Huh?
We breathe.
Because breathing...
it's... it's compulsory, otherwise we die.
So, uh...
we breathe deeply.
There.
Damn, it's boring.
It's true that it's boring at some point!
Oh, yeah, I told you. We get pissed off.
Why don't you park in a "disabled" spot?
I don't have the macaroon.
With the four of us, you have
a beautiful box of macaroons.
You're right.
- Marc, would you do me a service?
- Yes, I am here, I will always be here.
There was a Jardiland
in the industrial area.
- Yeah.
- Can you get me...
- You want flowers?
- No. Soil.
- For the flowers?
- No, for the vegetable garden.
- For the vegetable garden?
- Yes.
- Take three bags.
- OK.
It's as good as done!
And we meet there?
Otherwise, you pick me up,
it's just at the...
The idea is not to exceed the list.
- OK.
We start with vegetables?
- It's you, the vegetable!
- We're all vegetables.
- Ok, that's fine, we got it, Ludo.
Why do people look at us?
- We annoy them!
We annoy you!
- With this?
- That'll be all.
Thanks.
It's good, it's too good.
Mmm... It smells good.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
We'll eat them afterwards.
- Pardon me?
- We eat the melons, you have to avoid...
You have to be stupid to eat
the skin of a melon! That's stupid!
- Well, yeah.
- He's right.
You don't normally eat the skin.
You're right. The gentleman is stupid.
He's stupid.
Stupid! Stupid! Stupid!
- Bite into it! Bite into it!
- It's okay, it's good.
Oh, he's upset. Goodbye, stupid.
- Goodbye, stupid.
Bye!
Shit, Soso.
Don't worry, everybody knows.
Who told him?
- It's not us.
It's Alexandre.
Who told Alexandre?
- That's us.
We don't tell the educators, OK?
- No.
- Yes.
- Come on!
- Wow!
- Go ahead, Baptiste!
- Come on, Baptiste!
- Orpi, catch!
Come on!
Come on, Alex! Come on!
There! Go back!
Yes! Go, alone, alone!
- Holy cow!
- Marie, are you okay?
Attention. Are you OK?
The greens, not the reds!
Are you gonna be okay?
Can you breathe?
Breathe. Look at me. Look at me.
Come on, you're OK.
We're going to win.
Yes, hello?
Wait... Hello?
Wait... Wait, I can't hear anything.
Oh, no, no, there is no Strawberry here,
you got the wrong number.
Yes, wait. No. Excuse me.
- Wait, I'll pass him to you.
- Yes. No...
It's me...
Strawberry, in fact, is Sylvain's dad
who is calling me. Yes.
We resume!
Rico, I'm listening.
Listen to me, the cops don't let go.
I have a hideout for you in Spain.
We are doing the paperwork,
wait a few days.
Ouh! It's good, that!
Good, come on, come on! Oh! Come on!
We go back! Let's go!
Are you sending me your pay slips?
Yes, I'm going to do it.
Yes, I already manage everything...
Okay, but I'm not on vacation here. OK?
Did you tell them, by the way?
- Yes.
- Damn, Alice!
I'll tell them tonight, that's for sure.
I promise you.
Hello, ma'am, this is "priority checkout".
Yes, I saw, thanks a lot.
You can't see that it's priority.
And there, can you see them?
Are we priority enough for you?
Let the disabled pass!
Attention, ma'am.
That's good, it's a gun. Bang, bang!
Are you okay, ma'am?
Ma'am? Are you OK?
Oui. Euh...
You didn't weigh your carrots.
- OK.
- I'll take care of it. I'll take care of it.
- Are you sure? Do you know how to do it?
- Yes.
Come, we continue to empty the cart, guys.
Try to put everything in one place.
- How are you? Did it go well?
- Yeah.
Here, there's this left. This...
Oh, damn. We forgot the soil.
Oh, damn. We forgot Marc.
I have to go look for him.
It doesn't matter. We're not going to
do the vegetable garden now.
I'm not talking about the soil,
I'm talking about Marc.
Oh, yes, well, no...
He's a big boy, he'll manage by himself.
Everything is fine. So there...
Arnaud, can you sit next to me, please?
Sit down.
Speak.
Yeah.
Do you know Dalida?
Oui. Je l'aime pas.
Me neither.
Yes!
- No.
- Please.
Looks good.
So? It's great.
It even has a little taste of...
My cock!
There you go.
Really, you don't know what you're missing.
Is this brandade?
- Blanquette.
Blanquette brandade.
- You're missing me there.
- Oh, kitten, damn!
There you go, you're a handsome guy again.
- There too.
- Oh, my!
Oh, damn!
♪ It's strange ♪
♪ I don't know what's happening to me tonight ♪
♪ I look at you as for the first time ♪
♪ More words, ♪
♪ Always words ♪
♪ The same words ♪
♪ I don't know how to tell you ♪
♪ Nothing but words ♪
♪ You are this love story ♪
♪ That I will never stop reading ♪
♪ Easy words, ♪
♪ Fragile words ♪
♪ It was too beautiful ♪
♪ You are yesterday and tomorrow ♪
♪ Far too beautiful ♪
♪ Always my only truth ♪
♪ But it's over, the time of dreams ♪
♪ Memories also fade ♪
♪ when you forget them ♪
♪ You are like the wind ♪
♪ that makes the violins sing ♪
♪ And carries far away ♪
♪ the scent of roses ♪
♪ Caramels, candies and chocolates ♪
♪ Sometimes, I don't understand you ♪
♪ Thanks, not for me ♪
You don't want us to sleep, Arnaud?
You don't want us to sleep?
♪ Who loves the wind ♪
♪ and the scent of roses ♪
♪ Me, the tender words ♪
♪ coated with sweetness ♪
♪ They land on my mouth ♪
♪ But never on my heart ♪
♪ A word again ♪
♪ Words, words, words ♪
♪ Listen to me ♪
Please
Words, words, words
I swear to you
Words, words, and more words
That you sow to the wind
We are all courgettes.
So, we plant ourselves in the ground
like a courgette.
We think courgette,
we are courgette.
It's very pretty, Orpi.
Again!
Alice.
Look at me.
Damn, Marie.
- Marie! Are you OK, Marie?
- Oh, damn it!
I didn't do it on purpose.
It went into her mouth.
It happens to her all the time.
And there, there's a noise.
I hear something running and running
towards me.
It arrives,
I feel it getting closer.
It's coming closer to me.
It's coming closer to me, Marie!
They are behind! They're behind!
They want to catch me!
What do I do?
You're annoying!
Always the same discussion.
Everything OK?
Are you enjoying yourself?
Uh, no, as usual it's disgusting.
- I have an idea for your gift.
- Great, that's cool.
No, this is not possible!
He's going to score!
Yeah!
- You're not in prison.
- You're not in prison?
- No, I...
- No, you're not in prison!
You're not in prison!
- Ah, I was afraid!
- Now you're in prison!
Sylvain, don't cheat!
Oh, no! I didn't mean to!
- That's great!
- No big deal, it happens to her all the time.
Come. Come on!
17, 18, 19. Good!
Your turn, Gad.
I'm going to bed.
Do you want to play another game?
No, it's fine. Good night.
- Oh, well, good night.
- They are tired.
A knight on a horse.
Do a knight for me.
I'm riding, I'm riding...
Oh! A princess!
Hello, princess.
Will you accept me as...
Oh, no!
She doesn't want to.
So, I marry... I marry the ogre.
The ogre Ludo.
We go on horseback.
I'm getting on the horse, and there!
I don't know.
I don't know what to tell you.
Okay, go ahead. Fuck you.
And I knocked you down.
No, wait... Well, yes, yes!
Oh my!
You're very strong.
You're strong. You're strong.
Come on, red.
Oh yeah, him, anyway.
Oh, yeah? He's a hottie too?
- Oh my! But what a goal!
- Did you see?
Marie, get off the field! Marie!
Marie!
- Are you okay, Marie?
- It's bleeding
♪ - Happy birthday to you! ♪
Happy birthday, Marie!
Give it to her.
"Here, this is for you."
Here, this is for you.
What is it?
Well, open it.
- Wow!
- A jewel!
Happy birthday, Marie!
- That's well done. I wonder who made it.
- I want the same.
- You surprise me.
- Me too.
Very good. Very good.
- Is it good, your cake?
- Oh, yes. Delicious.
Hello.
Hello, hello.
Good morning, everybody.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
Who is this guy?
- Hello.
- Who is he?
- Uh, he's, uh...
- It's your guy.
It's Mathieu, it's my darling
who's giving me a surprise.
- Hello everybody. Delighted...
- Hello, Sébastien.
- Mathieu.
- Son of a bitch!
- Delighted.
- Ludovic, I told you about him.
Ah, cool. Salut, Ludo.
It's the end of the world here.
I almost got lost three times at least.
- That's right, I was lost, lost.
- Thank you!
Go seek happiness.
Marie.
- OK.
- Why is he there?
Well, uh... I think he's making me...
A little surprise.
Are you OK, not too sad?
- Sad about what?
- About what?
In fact, uh...
Mathieu found a job in the United States.
And I'm supposed to go with him.
But I was waiting until the end of the
week to announce
that I'm gonna leave you, but I...
- Shit. Didn't you tell them?
- No, I didn't tell them.
What, you're leaving?
- Do not leave, no!
- Don't leave!
No, no!
Eh, eh!
Stay with us, please!
- It's not sure, kitten.
- Wait, wait. How is that, not sure?
- Are you sure you want to talk about it here?
- When exactly...
- You know what, we'll let you discuss.
- Yes.
And we are going to start a little workshop.
- Cooking!
- Cooking! Great idea!
For the green beans, grab it, hold it well.
You get it in, you turn.
- What are you doing here in the kitchen?
- We'll make a meal.
Oh yeah?
We're the ones making dinner tonight.
- Yes, it's us.
- Yeah.
Wait, nobody knows how to cook?
- We do too.
- Yes, yes.
Together we'll succeed.
We'll cook!
We'll make a home-cooked meal!
Home-cooked!
Get out! Beat it!
We're fed up with canned goods!
We don't want cans any more!
We can cook, we want to cook.
Well, figure it out for yourself.
- Come on, Julien.
- Can I give a hand?
Are you going to cook?
Well, yeah.
Yeah, Julien!
Where are the utensils?
- Let's get the utensils.
- My mother uses that.
I don't understand.
We've talked about it a thousand times.
Plus, you pushed me to apply.
I know, but it wasn't real at that time.
Damn, but Alice...
You're not going to do this
all your life, are you?
Wiping asses all your life
for a pittance?
Don't you understand that it's difficult,
that it's like my family?
You can't understand this.
Sorry, I thought I was your family.
Stop it.
If that's all there is, there are
plenty of disabled people there.
OK.
No, but... Alice.
You know what I mean, it's fine.
- Better go.
- No, but Alice...
- Get lost.
Please, Mathieu. Get lost.
Perfect, if we want to eat tonight,
we have to get moving.
Come on, let's get back to it?
Come on, let's go.
- Alice?
- Yeah.
- Are you OK?
- Yeah, that's fine.
Orpi and Baptiste are back?
No, not yet. They will soon.
I'm here, Alice.
I'll always be here.
Yeah, I know.
If you need, at some point,
somebody in your life... I...
There is always a moment
when we are not well,
and we need a shoulder to lean on,
and I can be that shoulder.
Are you hitting on me?
I just broke up with my boyfriend
7 seconds ago and...
- No!
- ...and you thought, "This is good timing."
No, not at all! Not at all.
Not at all.
It's true that it seems so.
Afterwards, you tell yourself that it's...
No, imagine the embarrassment!
- What are onions?
- They make you cry!
Yes!
I'm okay.
Watch your fingertips.
Here we go.
Let's make it flambé!
Attention!
Oh!
It's me, I'm making it flambé!
Vegetable farandole
on a bed of tagliatelle
a la puttanesca
with garden condiments.
Service!
Wow, great!
- Are you OK?
- Yeah. Three plates at once?
Be careful not to drop them.
You have a nice shirt.
Who lent it to you?
Uh... Alexandre.
It suits you very well.
You are very handsome.
Enjoy your food.
Thank you.
For once, it's good.
They're enjoying it.
- It's good, huh?
- I am not convinced by the texture.
It's good, chewing a little.
- I scored 3 goals on you.
- OK, but...
OK, but... I scored on you too.
- When you were in the posts...
- Not even!
Hey, hey! You should have been back
2 hours ago.
Yes, OK... We didn't see the time pass.
OK, fine, but he is under my responsibility.
If something happens...
- I go under his.
- There!
No, you're under my responsibility!
OK?
No... Wait. Honestly...
We were there, we were playing football.
- We went to eat a hotdog.
- Yes, it was good, huh?
- Was it good with mayo?
- Which was runny.
Hey, hey, I actually don't care!
I'm busting my ass with the
activity programs, it's not for nothing!
Are you talking about your
little coloring pages for kids? That's it?
- What?
- Mandala. It's called mandala.
The mandala? If you want!
The mandala is a clown thing.
You're supposed to be an educator,
damn it!
You are not supposed
to do things like that!
Don't talk to me like that.
Nobody talks to me like that, get it?
No, no, but...
Let's-let's calm down.
Let's calm down.
What Orpi means, is that he likes
outdoor activities. That's it.
That's why he's grumpy.
He's a country guy.
Yes. Well, yes... Sylvain is right.
Yeah, that's why.
Honestly, it's worth taking advantage
of all this.
Huh? Huh? Honestly, Baptiste?
Take advantage! Take advantage
of that, look! The prairie!
That's right, after all this time doing
the same things we could go on a trip.
Well, coloring activities bore me.
Me too!
Not its place, not its place.
I too prefer excursions to activities!
OK.
Would you like to go on an trip?
- Yeah!
We will see Dalida's grave.
So, yes, why not?
But otherwise I have another idea.
No hunting.
Oh, I have something else.
No, but... I assure you, it will be fine.
I'm checking because I'm not
sure about the safety standards.
Yes, but I tell you it's all good.
It's all good. Really.
Papi!
- What is it?
- Come see.
I'm sorry, but this won't be possible.
- Why?
- Not enough supervisors.
- If there's a glitch, I'm toast.
- No, sir!
Come on, remove those.
Oh, no!
No problem, we're
going to do something else.
That's not true.
What is this thing?
It's not cool, that.
This sucks.
Wait, wait.
Wait, wait...
- Listen to me, sir.
- No.
OK. We remove the vests.
We remove the vests.
- Oh, no!
- Yes, yes.
Come see.
I think you didn't understand.
Yes, yes, I
understood perfectly.
They are not fit to row.
That's all!
You didn't understand.
I am not a nice guy.
If you don't give up your gear,
tonight, I'll break all your limbs
and I burn your cabin.
Did you understand that?
Come on, come.
It's good, it's arranged.
Thank you!
Thanks, old faggot!
My friends are so nice,
and I like them a lot.
I'll call you back later.
Kisses, mommy dear!
It's a village party!
Sylvain! Sylvain!
Soso!
Bring out the lethal weapon!
- We'll win!
- Come on, guys!
I am the master of the world!
Why don't you go?
Why don't you go yourself?
It's cool, oh my.
We're still doing a beast of a job.
- Yeah, that's for sure.
What would you have
done in San Francisco?
The streets are like that, like that.
You have a Soso in a wheelchair,
you let him go...
"You dropped me, bunch of idiots!"
- Stop, stop!
- Céline, Céline!
- Soso! It's a "disabled"!
I'm going to swim, you're annoying.
Be careful, I'm coming!
We go back!
Hi!
- Hi!
- Hi, goodbye!
Have a good trip!
- Gad, put that paddle down!
- What?
- Oh, shit!
- Oh, damn. Marie!
- Are you OK, Marie?
- Full in the face.
Are you OK, Marie?
We're going to play!
- Gad, what did you do?
- Damn...
- It's not my fault.
- It's not your fault?
- No.
- But be careful.
I fell asleep, stupidly.
I was there and...
I didn't...
Ronaldo, whenever he scores a goal...
each time he has the ball,
even with Benzema.
- Benzema, he...
- Even with Karim.
Yes, he was switching,
and when he was switching, bang!
You took it right on the mouth, huh?
You're not in too much pain,
is it OK? No?
It's okay. It'll pass. Okay?
- The boat was good.
- Yeah.
Afterwards, you calmed down.
She was cold.
She was frozen.
Frozen, yeah.
Each time when he manages,
and he makes his pass...
Damn! Paulo, the cops!
Let's get out!
He attacked me!
It's him over there!
Police, move over!
Let pass!
Oh, damn.
Get out! Come on, get out!
They are disabled, don't touch them!
Come on, quickly!
We pull a box, we leave.
Come on!
What are you doing, Paulo?
- I stop.
- What?
I stop. I stop it all.
Come on, don't be an idiot. Shit!
Damn, Paulo...
- Don't move!
- On the ground!
- Give me your hands!
- Your hands, we told you!
Where's the other?
And I'll finish today
in appealing, Madam Judge,
to your sense of justice.
Of this justice whose primary
function is to protect society
from individuals such as Paul Mounier.
Thank you.
Thank you, Mr. Prosecutor.
Mr. Mounier, do you have
anything to add?
No.
Are you sure?
- Hi, everyone.
- Hello.
- Good morning.
- Hi, everyone.
Please, we are in audience.
Evacue everyone.
Someone parked in
the "disabled" spot.
A valid asshole!
- Sorry, it's me, the big bitch.
- Exactly, there's som...
Pardon, c'est moi qui me suis garée.
I completely forgot to put the label on.
Oh, no, no, these things happen. It's...
But I should have put it.
I prefer to say it.
People often think that...
They park while being able-bodied.
- Yeah.
- It's unbearable, I agree.
We are in the middle of an audience!
You can't come in like this.
Excuse us. I am the center manager
and I would like to add something to...
Yes, but now is not the time, ma'am.
You are in a court of law, there are rules.
Did you find a place, anyway?
Yeah, the street...
- A street.
- All right.
Please calm down.
Excuse me but since we're here,
we'll tell you anyway.
- Do you agree?
- Yes.
Calm down, please!
- So, two minutes.
- Thank you.
Actually, we just wanted to say that...
what Paulo or Sylvain did...
I don't know who you are, in fact.
But never mind.
We all agree that it's not good.
We all feel betrayed.
It's true, yeah.
Quite.
Me first and we all agree that
he must be judged for that,
there is no problem.
But...
but I have been working with them for 7 years,
and I have never seen them like that,
they had a best summer of their life.
- Yes.
- Completely.
- It's true.
Did you have fun?
- Yes, a lot!
- A lot!
Too awesome.
We had a drink!
It was so good, with Sylvain!
So good!
Sylvain, he's not a son of a bitch!
- Yes, yes, so...
- Sylvain, he's a sweetheart.
I must admit that it
was one of the most beautiful
encounters of my existence.
Sylvain, you cook good food.
- We laugh with him.
- He is too nice.
With Sylvain, we both took a shower naked.
We don't want Sylvain
going to prison, right?
- Yes!
- Sylvain, Sylvain!
Calm down, please.
Okay, calm down.
Merry Christmas.
That's beautiful.
But open it. You'll see.
It's beautiful. It's pretty, too.
Yeah.
It is less pretty than the other.
Me,
I find it too beautiful.
Thibaut!
You put this ball down and
join the others, please.
Thank you.
Eh, you lovers,
come on, let's go there too.
You'll catch a cold. They are cute.
- Doesn't matter.
- It doesn't matter.
You don't mind being a big bag of shit?
Pardon?
Wash your ears,
if you don't mind, Boris.
You don't mind being a big bag of shit?
With your big shitty car!
Get lost! Get lost!
- I'll be 5 minutes.
- Scratch!
Get lost with your big asshole car!
Asshole! And shut up!
- Merry Christmas.
- Merry Christmas to you.
Son of a bitch!
Exactly! Shut up!
Merry Christmas anyway.
- How are you doing?
- Fine, and you?
Well, if it's okay, listen...
- I miss you.
- I miss you too.
So?
- Yes?
- Did he like the gift?
- A lot.
- I think so.
And first, you have to talk to Alice.
Not so loud, I talked to her,
there is nothing urgent.
Yes, it's now, right away.
No, later.
- I'm here, I will always be here.
- Marc. Marc.
- The Papouilles, later.
- Oh my...
- Excuse me.
- No problem. Good morning.
Goodbye, my darling.
Kisses, kisses!
Alexandre, a globe?
What if we hang this on you, like this?
- Oh, that's good.
- Everything suits me. Anything dresses me.
And this one?
Oh, Orpi!
- Orpi!
Orpi!
- I'll give you 3 minutes.
- It's okay, it's good.
For you.
- For me, really?
- Yeah, you have to open it.
Oh, a jersey of my player!
Who is your player?
A jersey of Cristian Ronaldo.
And it's the real one of Real.
- Really of his team?
- Yeah.
Thank you!
Are you cuddling now?
It's the real one. It's cool, it's...
- Vraiment, merci.
- Thanks to you. And keep it.
Normally it should fit you.
It's your size.
Sympas, tes bracelets.
Which jewelry store do they come from?
Surely the same as yours, right?
How did they get you?
It was complicated,
they had a hard time because...
They had to get up from the desk,
leave the computer, that I surrender.
Three years max, a priori.
Are you going to make it?
And you?
Yeah.
I'm sorry for everyone blablablabla, there.
Dad.
Take care of yourself.
Merry Christmas!
No, really?
Can't be true! Look!
An anonymous donor
who bought the cottage!
The cottage is ours!