- Boss. This for you.
- No, no, no. Come on.
I can’t impose on your family.
No.
Yasmin, she made this
just for you.
Jefe, please.
Take it.
Tell her thank you.
Yeah.
So, listen.
Today’s gonna be hard.
- We got inspections all day.
Forms to build,
forms to break down
and deliveries
all gettin’ in our way.
- We work hard today,
there’ll be a bonus for ya.
Understand?
And let’s all go home
with the same amount
of fingers that we came with.
- All right.
- Hermanos.
-
Have a good day.
Let’s get it.
- Morning, Jess.
- Buenos dias, Levon.
- How you doing?
- I’m good.
- Gracias.
- Hey, Levon.
No one’s been asking you
for money today?
No.
- Why?
- Because, apparently,
I am the only person
in the family
who can do
the vendor accounting.
Oh, excuse me!
Hey, I guess we’re
evil parents, babe, huh?
’Cause we make her work
a couple hours.
Not today.
How about you get those
disbursements done, huh?
We got a line of trucks
out there that need paying.
You could pay me.
Pay you for what?
For 19 years of free rent,
and groceries,
and high school,
college, makeup,
karate classes?
- You want me to keep goin’?
- Really? No. It’s okay.
Levon,
can you sign that, please?
- Dad?
- What?
- Today is a total shitshow.
- I know.
And you scheduled
three things at once.
- She’s not wrong.
Hi, yeah. This is Garcia
and Family Construction.
Yeah, you’re speaking
with Carla,
you’ve had me on hold
for a bit now.
So, we’re gettin’ those
deliveries today, right?
Yeah, I’ll hold.
This is
what I need for tonight.
That’s insane. What is that?
Is that for your wedding
or something?
- No, it’s for tonight.
We finished the semester,
so we’re gonna celebrate.
I mean, you just finished
one semester.
- Right. It’s a big milestone.
- Is it?
- Yes.
- Is that a thing?
Look, it could be worse, okay?
- Look, I’m passing the hat.
- Mm-hmm. Yeah.
- That gets us a party van.
- Oh, my God.
Locks in a private room
for dinner.
Just saving like crazy.
Yeah.
I just need a card on file.
Mija, I can’t. I don’t...
Mija...
Okay, fine. I don’t need it.
Just give her what she wants.
No, Mom,
I can fight my own battles.
Oh, no, no,
nobody’s arguing that.
I mean, everybody needs
a party bus, right?
After they finish
one semester. Here.
Thank you.
Hey, Kate.
Excuse me.
He needs to get back to work.
Get the fuck out of here.
It’s not your business.
I’m good, boss.
All good. Five minutes.
Hey!
Hold on.
Put down your weapons.
I was respectful.
You weren’t.
Get outta here. Get up.
Don’t come back.
- Vamonos.
You okay?
How did you do that?
We need to get back to work.
This one.
Over to the right.
- You got it.
- Thanks, Kate.
Levon! Holy fuck!
Was that some military shit?
You didn’t see anything.
If Dad knew, he’d shit bricks.
Can you teach me?
Look, my grandpa,
he was a paratrooper.
Taught me
how to break fingers,
track animals.
Break fingers?
Yeah.
Grandma made you tinga.
Shredded chicken.
It’s good.
And Grandma made you some
handmade grandma tortillas.
Why is everyone
always feeding me?
If we don’t, you’ll just eat
canned tuna and peanut butter.
You didn’t see anything, okay?
Snitches get stitches.
Just get my back
if I ever need it.
Sure, Jenny.
See ya.
Love you, Daddy.
Love you, too, honey.
Get in the truck.
What’s the occasion?
No occasion.
Meredith’s entertaining
some friends.
Yeah.
I didn’t realize today
was your visitation.
You could let her stay.
Yeah, please, Doctor Roth,
we don’t have to do this.
You weren’t there
when her mother needed you
and you won’t be there
when Meredith needs you,
but I will.
Oh, I know.
You want to strike me.
It’s your only answer.
Violence.
You’re an unsafe parent.
You’re a killer.
You can’t pretend
that you’re not.
Excuse me, Doctor Roth.
Today’s my day.
Why’s your grandfather
throwing a party on my day?
I’m super hungry.
I didn’t eat.
I was waiting for you.
You were?
Yeah.
Okay. Let’s go.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Enjoy.
I don’t need you buying stuff.
Come on. Open it.
It’s Mama.
I took that picture
with a film camera
my dad gave me.
Grandpa took
all of Mama’s pictures down.
Sometimes I forget
what she looks like.
She looks like you.
Dad, can I tell you something?
Anything.
I’m mad at Mama.
For dying and leaving us.
It’s okay.
I hurt, too.
Matt will see you now.
He’s throwing parties for her
during my visitation time.
Staring at me, laughing.
He’s baiting you.
Hoping you throw a punch.
Nah.
Then he wins.
Opposing counsel
alleges you have
untreated PTSD
and brain trauma
from your military service,
making you
at-risk for violence.
I served Britain, the country
of my birth, for 22 years.
I’m the fuckin’ bad guy
for it?
It gets worse.
They’re requesting
supervised visits
and a reduction in visitation
from two hours a week
to one hour every two.
I have to fight this.
I have ten grand saved up.
From sleeping
in your truck?
Court won’t be thrilled
by your lack
of a fixed residence.
Hey, I’ll figure it out.
Why does Doctor Roth
hate you so much?
He thinks
I killed his daughter.
Did you?
It was suicide.
I was overseas
on a deployment.
She battled depression
her whole life.
You’ve heard
of attrition warfare?
Yeah. You grind
the enemy down slowly.
This guy’s got a team
of thousand-dollar-an-hour
attorneys
who will bleed you dry
until you turn to dust
and blow away.
The best we can do
is negotiated surrender.
You have a daughter?
I got you guys
a little somethin’.
Nina.
Jocelyn...
- Chantel. And Rubi.
- Thanks, Mama.
Dude, these are insane!
Where’d you get these?
I have a cousin. Or seven.
Salud , bitches!
Thank you.
- Shots.
Hey!
What? What? What?
What the fuck
are we still doing here?
He said he wants the One.
"I want the One.
I want the fucking One."
What the fuck does that mean?
He’ll know it
when he sees her, okay?
Do you know
how much fuckin’ money
we’re gonna make on this?
- We better.
- Enjoy, yeah?
Hey, last establishment.
You guys have early flights.
Is that back table open?
It’s yours
if you tell me your name.
It’s Jenny.
Hi, I’m Johnny.
Hi, Johnny.
Right here.
My man.
You are more
than a pitch deck.
- Nina?
- Nina, don’t throw up.
- I’m fine.
She’s making her puke face.
- Let’s get you to a bathroom.
- Oh, ew.
Cheap! Bad energy.
Ew!
- Oh, my God.
I hate you so much right now,
it’s not funny.
It’s kinda funny.
Oh, my God, I look mad busted.
I cannot go out there
like this.
Okay, well, pick your battles,
’cause we’re leavin’ in 30.
Fuck!
Go.
Jenny’s missing.
What do you mean, "missing"?
She went out
with her friends on Friday.
Saturday, we were worried,
so we called the cops,
and then on Sunday...
She had a piano recital
on Sunday night.
We invited half our family.
My cousin Dinora
is a Police Captain in Philly,
and she says
they don’t work these cases.
They take a report
and forget about it.
Can you help us?
I can keep the site
running smoothly.
No. Help us find Jen.
My dad was a Green Beret.
I can see you guys
comin’ a mile away.
You hunt bad guys.
You jump outta planes.
And you get those bad guys.
I’m a different person now.
All right, well,
maybe this’ll help her.
Here, it’s 50.
Take it.
We have another 20
for expenses.
Come on, just take it, man.
I’m sorry.
It’s not who I am anymore.
Gunny, it’s me!
Don’t kill me!
I got steaks!
If you’d shot
a foot to the left,
I’d be dead.
If I wanted you dead,
you’d be dead.
You know, for me,
there’s no separation
between day and night.
So, I got to make my own.
It’s hard livin’
in a gray world.
I couldn’t save your eyes.
Sorry.
That eats at me.
No.
You saved my life.
Joyce would be burying tags
in the back yard
if you hadn’t come along,
scooped me up and ran.
What’s her name?
Jenny.
Jenny. All right.
She a good kid?
She’s a great kid.
Now, you do this,
you better lock in.
You better go full on,
no half-measures.
But you do, God help ’em.
I told Jenny I had her back.
Well, uh...
I miss ya.
I worry about ya,
but you didn’t have
to come down here
and pretend that
you needed my permission
for something
you already
made your mind up about.
Get in here.
We’re eating.
Hey, Carla.
Thanks for coming.
Where is he?
Upstairs.
First door on your left.
"Moonlight Sonata".
- Yeah.
- It’s beautiful.
She turned down
a music scholarship
to go to business school.
She wanted to be like her pops.
Be a big land developer.
And she will.
Yeah.
Nah. No, thanks.
Your family needs hope.
But I can’t face ’em like this.
When my wife passed,
and I left the Royal Marines,
a lot of people
would’ve given up on me.
But you were patient with me.
- You, Carla, Jenny.
- Jenny.
You’re my family.
Look at me, brother.
I’m gonna bring her home.
I promise.
"Skip’s Bar."
Thank you very much.
Good, bro?
You good? Yeah?
How you doing?
You need a little aperitif,
you know?
All right.
Oh, yo. Wrong house, kid.
Get the fuck out.
Hello, Johnny.
Wanna have a race?
See who wins?
Hands up. Stand up.
Place your fingers
behind your head.
You a cop?
You wish I was a cop.
Your adventure, kid.
Where’s the girl?
What girl?
The missing girl.
The one your friends snatched
outta the back of the bar.
I told the cops. She ran off.
Drunk or somethin’.
Fuckin’ poobutt
can’t hold her drink.
How’s that my problem?
- People lie.
Do you lie, Johnny?
I don’t trust people.
I trust biology.
- We’re all wired the same.
Get the fuck up.
Fuck you.
Your mind
knows you’re in the bathtub
and it’s just a wet towel.
But adrenaline
makes your heart race,
- so you burn more air.
Your nervous system tells you
that you’re drowning.
Your bosses know you deal dope
over the bar top?
Steal from the till?
Fuck you!
You know these guys
are next level.
They wipe out
entire fucking bloodlines.
Fair enough.
Just know
you’re giving me names.
Your choice how.
Johnny?
Where are you, brother?
You’re expecting company?
Damn fuckin’ right, I am.
Open the door.
Fuckin’ kill you.
Russians.
Fuck.
I’m sorry, Mom.
I’m sorry for...
shielding myself...
in a blanket
of accomplishments.
I wish you could’ve seen me...
who I really am.
Just want to be strong
like you.
What am I doing here?
on speaker It’s better
you see for yourself, boss.
It’s not a big problem.
What the fuck
have you two done, huh?
Why’d they shoot each other?
This is very unprofessional.
Johnny has no control.
He’s a weak man.
Maybe he talk crazy,
and then it’s bang-bang time.
- "Bang-bang time"?
- Yeah.
Bang-bang time.
You notice anything different?
Your hair.
- Idiot.
Where is my fucking money?
You think this was a robbery?
Impossible.
No one would rob us.
No one is that stupid,
or that crazy.
This is a shotgun wound.
You see any shotguns?
- Hmm?
- That’s nine bands missing.
Ninety thousand dollars
of our fucking money!
It’s Symon’s money.
May your blood
purify the soil, comrade.
- Hey, sweetheart.
Hey, Daddy,
what are you doing?
Uh, nothin’. Just, uh...
Just some work.
- Are you in school?
- Yeah.
You supposed to be
calling me from school?
No.
Everything okay?
Yeah, I just wanted
to say, "hi." Love you, Daddy.
Love you, too.
Bye.
The fucking door opens itself?
Everything is fucked!
I don’t like this.
I’m alone in the bed
all night.
You eat.
You come to bed for a bit.
You think the money
falls from the sky?
- Hmm?
Bastard.
Hope you don’t mind.
I was hungry.
Thought we could
have a little chat.
I’m gonna take the tape off.
But if you can’t
control your volume...
You go in the water.
Do you know who I am?
Should I?
You clearly have no idea
who you fuck with.
Make yourself happy.
Tell me.
You have heard of us?
I have.
Really?
The Vor.
The Bratva. The Brothers.
The League of Thieves.
Whatever Russian gangsters
like to call themselves
these days.
You clearly are somebody.
You slaughter Vory soldiers.
You steal Vory money.
It was a misunderstanding.
I am a brother of high rank.
You and all connected
with you,
will be hunted
for three generations.
Yep. I assumed so.
We all know
how these things play out
if you don’t keep them tidy.
- Fuck you!
That’s for slapping
that woman this morning.
That woman was my wife.
That’s for slapping your wife.
Here’s your money.
I’m not a thief.
I don’t care
about your business.
I’m lookin’ for a young lady.
I... I don’t understand.
The bar you do
your dirty business out of,
a 19 year-old girl
was kidnapped.
I’m lookin’ for her.
Dimi.
Maybe you should
keep your voice down.
What do you want?
Gimme the girl,
and everybody
goes about their business.
A girl?
All of this is for a girl?
No one kills three people
to sell a woman.
No one.
I’m not selling her.
I’m gonna bring her home.
Not stopping until I do.
Who are you?
What are you?
Fuck you.
Fuck you!
Okay, we’re done.
Dimi.
Who are you, Dimi?
Father.
He takes money.
He leaves money.
He kills without fear.
The question is why?
Wolo was
a respected man of honor,
but his son was never like us.
Dimi is not a businessman.
He prefers mischief
over hard work.
He spits on his father’s heart
every fucking day.
Find this man.
And bring him to me.
My name is Jenny Garcia.
My father is Joe.
My mother is Carla.
You have the wrong girl.
This is a mistake.
They’re not real.
You’re not real.
This...
is fucking real.
Eat your fuckin’ food,
then you put on
the fucking clothes
- and shut the fuck up!
- Fuck you!
Have you ever seen
someone die before?
Huh?
Their eyes
just cloud right over.
Mmm.
You’re so fuckin’ pretty. Huh?
Aren’t you, Princess?
Aw.
Boop.
Eat your fuckin’ food!
Believe the idea the
White Sox are in serious talks
to build a new stadium
in the South Loops, The 78,
the location by
the Chicago River
just off Roosevelt.
I love the idea
of being in serious talks
for a new stadium
in the South Loop.
How’s it goin’, cat?
Getting rich contracting?
Oh, yeah.
Pouring concrete more like.
I’m outta the game.
I’m an honest taxpayer now.
You talked
to Gunny? How’s he doing?
Saw him the other day.
He’s happy.
Well, you never call me unless
you need something,
so, what do you want?
Lookin’ for someone
called Dimi.
Probably Dimitri.
An associate of
Wolodymyr Kolisnyk.
That’s a high-ranking
dude, cat.
Mafia captain.
Legit Bratva shot caller.
Not a guy you wanna fuck with.
Nah, never.
This Dimi fella,
he might be involved
in human trafficking.
Can you check NADDIS and NCIC?
See if you can get a hit?
I gotta be careful,
but there’s a bar
called Hattie’s in Joliet,
where they sell meth
for the Russians.
Maybe you should
get a beer there.
Nice one. Thanks.
Hey. Whatcha havin’?
I’ll just have a beer.
You pick.
Okay.
Oh, hey, stranger.
Where you been?
Tryin’ to make a buck.
You know,
rumor has it
you and your shitbag brother
have been talkin’
to the Russians.
Rumor has it you were so high,
you accidentally killed
Big Mike in a trap house
and blamed it
on a robbery crew.
Fuckin’ shut up. Fuckin’...
Dutch finds out
anybody’s talkin’
to the Russians but him,
he’s gonna lose
his fuckin’ mind.
Shh!
Do you know this guy?
No. I’ve never seen him.
I don’t like him.
Looks like a cop.
He’s got
a gun in his pocket.
Like a .38. You see it?
Fuck. Yes.
You’re up, kid.
Follow me.
Go talk to the man.
You lookin’ for somethin’?
My interests are strictly
pharmaceutical, brother.
Any reason
why you packin’ heat, brah?
I’m carrying money.
Hate to lose it
to a man with a knife.
He’s a cop.
Are you a cop?
Nah. Are you?
Run your pockets, Chief.
Let’s check for that badge.
You heard the man.
Put it on the table.
Fuckin’ now.
I didn’t come here
to be disrespected.
All right.
Let’s play.
Get him.
Get him, brother.
Bye, asshole.
Enough!
My grandpa told me to
never shake hands sittin’.
Look at those bricks.
You ain’t a cop,
you’re a working man.
Been in construction
my whole life.
Were you a soldier?
’Cause you fight
like a soldier.
I did my part.
I was Airborne.
They trained us
to jump outta planes
and we ended up
ridin’ a bus into combat.
Sounds about right.
Have a seat, brother.
I heard you’re
in a buyin’ mood.
I’m lookin’ for blue glass,
the good stuff.
I need weight. Regular.
Like four pounds a month.
That’s all?
Who you flippin’ it to?
It goes where it’s needed.
The customers
are my concern, not yours.
And why here? Why us?
My Chicago connect
is missin’ in action.
I’m runnin’ work crews
in shifts 24/7.
Time is money.
Seven K for half a pound.
That’s a Chicago price.
Five.
There’s a pancake house
at the highway junction
straight north of here.
Be there, 7:00 a.m.,
having breakfast.
And?
And bring five stacks.
Good talk.
Now get the fuck outta here.
Have a seat.
Mm.
This is like an awkward
Tinder date.
Just give her the money.
Mmm. Lo, and behold.
People talk,
money fucks.
You got somethin’ for me?
We don’t know
who the fuck you are, brother.
You’ll get a call tellin’ you
where your shit is.
That’s it?
Yeah. Uh-huh.
Don’t play me.
I know where to find you.
Yeah. I guess you do.
Thank you for not shooting me.
fuckin’ asshole.
- Yeah?
- All right. You ready?
I’m gonna tell you where
the skante’s at, big dog.
I’m waitin’.
Under your seat.
- Thank you.
- Keep the burner phone.
I’mma hit you tomorrow.
Then you can tell me
how y’all motherfuckers
built Rome
in a day off my shit.
Then we can talk about weight.
Guess who’s gonna be
princess for a night?
You are Dimi’s
miracle workers. Huh?
And that,
that is for Dimi’s miracle.
Why her?
She reminded me of a painting
in one of my father’s houses.
Take her in the back.
Sure.
Look how cute these ones are.
They look like little sharks.
Just like you, cutie.
She bit me!
She’s supposed to be asleep!
I’m so sorry, sir.
I want her out!
Yeah?
Did they like my shit?
Let’s just say
they were pleased.
There’s plenty more
where that came from,
but there’s someone
you gotta check in with
if we’re gonna do business.
What does that mean?
Precautionary measures, brah.
Seein’ as the Feds
are handin’ out
life sentences per pound.
Yeah, this game’s not
for everyone.
I hear you, big dog.
I’mma shoot you
an invite for a sit-down.
Bring your money
and wear a suit.
I don’t have a suit.
Shit. You will tomorrow.
’Cause these motherfuckers
are as high power as it gets.
I’m here
to see someone called Dutch.
He’s right this way.
He’s over there.
- How you doin’?
- Hey, Dutch.
You bring the money?
May I?
First, you gotta turn
your phone off.
Now what?
You already have my money.
I came here in good faith
to do business.
My name is Dimi.
Yours?
Bill.
Bill Coates.
Do you have driver’s license,
Bill Coates?
Excuse me?
It’s fine. Let him check.
You drive rental.
We check plates.
Tax write-off.
That okay?
This man
is my business partner.
He is small potatoes.
I am the big potatoes.
Tell me.
Will you be a problem?
Is this how you do business?
You invite me here
to be threatened?
Checks out.
I apologize
for that, "William."
You are clearly a...
serious person.
If you need resupply,
use the burner.
Text bunny rabbit emoji.
Bunny rabbit emoji.
You made aware
I need four pounds a month?
Oh.
Then text eggplant emoji.
We are aware.
If you like
what is in the case,
we do more business.
Now, you leave
and don’t look back.
Fine by me.
Johnny, you’re
a real piece of shit.
You sneaky motherfucker.
Hi, asshole.
Hmm.
He’s here.
- Oh, shit.
- on speakers
He’s in a black Dodge Ram
hiding in the trees.
Okay,
we’re pulling up now.
Let’s go!
Fuck! He just fuckin’ left
on a bike! Go!
Go! Go! Go!
Fuck!
Show me your hands.
Hey.
You didn’t see us here.
Nothing fucking happened.
We’ll take it
from here.
You’re on the payroll too?
How do you know Dimi?
What is your business
with Dimi?
Ah, you two assholes.
That man you drowned,
in his own pool
while his wife was at Pilates,
that man was our uncle.
He wouldn’t shut up.
I warned him.
- Do you know who we are, hmm?
- Hey. Hey.
Yeah, people
whose ma dresses ’em funny.
This is fucking couture, man.
It’s our fucking brand!
Tie up his legs.
If you want me to be scared,
you gotta try harder.
- Whoa!
Kill this demon.
That is Vanko.
And that is Danya.
These are my sons.
My house and my lineage end
on these cold, steel tables.
Convene the war counsel.
Excuse me, dear.
Fuck off.
Oh, wow.
Absolutely fuckin’ not.
Oh, fuck.
You’re lucky
you’re not already dead.
Dimi, apologies, okay?
I’m sorry.
I’m truly fuckin’ sorry.
She fucking bit
half his face off.
- It wasn’t exactly
half his face. But...
- Oh.
Thirty-six stitches.
That’s a lot.
To reattach his cheek.
I am in the business
of pleasure, not surgery.
Tell me...
Fuck.
Do you know
what business means?
Do I... No.
I mean, yeah. Fuck.
Business means
you keep your word.
You deliver promises.
You make customer happy.
Not bite fucking face off!
- Understood.
- No.
You just fucked me
out of 200 grand.
If you make one, I make two.
Customer wants her dead.
I want her dead.
You kill her.
You know where to take her.
Consider it done.
Now fuck off!
Fucking off, sir.
Holy shit, he was pissed.
Fucking beyond.
He was this close
to smokin’ us both.
We gotta whack that girl.
Fine by me.
Let’s do the little bitch.
We are facing a devil.
This devil kills two soldiers.
He drowns Wolodymyr,
an esteemed captain.
Now he kills my sons.
You do understand my concern?
Where is Dimi?
Won’t he know
who this devil is?
Dimi’s hiding.
They will help you find Dimi.
Thank you for bringing this
to my attention.
Now go.
- Some champagne?
Your father is dead.
Tied to a chair
and drowned in his pool.
So, it’s good news.
The man who killed him
murdered my sons.
Danya and Vanko?
What the fuck?
You did not know this?
How the fuck would I know?
Nobody tells me anything.
The Brotherhood treats me
like I’m radioactive.
Who is this man?
I ask with kindness.
I bankroll biker gang
with meth connection.
They introduce me to buyer
with real cash.
We met for five minutes.
That’s it.
Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
I have this.
He’s hunting you.
Found him.
Oh.
- Hello?
- Hi. Mr. Cade?
This is the Main Office.
Um, no one’s come to pick up
Meredith today.
I’ll be right there.
- Hey.
- Good day?
- Yeah.
- Let’s go.
Where’s Grandpa?
He’s never late.
He’s not answering me.
I sent him, like, 20 messages.
I’m sure he’s fine.
You didn’t kill him, did you?
Dad, I’m kidding.
Do you trust me?
Yeah.
So, if I tell you something,
you know
you can believe me, right?
Okay, the build-up
is just making it worse.
I made a big mistake.
Oh, my God.
You did kill Grandpa.
Merry, I’m serious.
Some really bad people
are after me,
and I don’t want anyone
I love to get hurt.
Are you sharing your location
with Grandpa?
Yeah.
Can you see his location?
Maybe, I don’t know.
Daddy, he’s at home.
Merry, stay here, okay?
Merry! Stay there!
Daddy, be careful!
Who were they?
Russian mafia?
Yes.
They were looking for you.
This happened because of you.
Violence follows you
like a cloud.
He could’ve left you
in there, Grandpa.
He saved your life.
I can acknowledge that.
You should go to the hospital.
You’ll be safe there.
I’ll take care of Merry.
It’s time
o let the cops
handle this.
Cops can’t stop them.
All right.
We’ll figure it out later.
And, Levon,
thank you.
You remember Gunny?
Your blind friend
who doesn’t know he’s blind?
That’s the one.
He has a country house.
We’ll be safe there
till the storm passes.
Hi.
You wanna come inside?
Come on.
- You hungry?
- Always.
- And you?
- Yeah.
What happened, man?
You fuck with
the wrong people, huh?
Hey, you could’ve stopped me.
What force on earth
is gonna stop you?
It’s gettin’ ugly.
Can you find this girl?
Can you really find this girl?
I can find her.
I’m gonna bring her home.
I hear that. You got a plan?
I’m gonna ask this Dimi fella
where she is.
All roads lead to him.
Now, you killed
your way into this,
you’re gonna have to kill
your way out of it.
I figured as much.
I can help you with that.
Oh, yeah?
Let me show you somethin’.
After you, sir.
All right, I will be
your weapons sommelier
for this evening.
If you come around this wall,
you see
the Avtomat Kalashnikov,
been killing Americans
since 1947.
Also, comes in a deluxe,
blingy version pulled direct
from Saddam’s palace.
What you got over here
is the M-Four Carbine,
it’s the Chevy Impala
of the war on terror.
Beautiful MP5 SD here
if you wanna kill somebody,
but you don’t wanna
wake ’em up.
But this is
the real beast here.
One of the original weapons of
the four horsemen
of the apocalypse.
The M14.
You might remember this weapon.
I don’t want to, but I do.
There you go.
I’ll have to drill out
the serial numbers.
Oh, no, that’s already done.
These were never here.
Never anywhere.
Kinda like us,
back in the day.
We did some
righteous shit, brother.
Yeah, we did.
- What’s in there?
- None of your business.
Can I come?
Absolutely not.
What about school?
You’ll miss
a couple of days, at most.
I barely see you.
I don’t want you
getting in trouble.
Then I’ll never see you.
That’s not gonna happen.
See this? This is you.
Half and half.
I want you to hold onto this.
I’m comin’ back for that.
Okay.
I love you.
Love you, Daddy.
Daddy, I don’t want you
getting hurt.
I’ll be back soon, okay?
Gunny, take good care of her.
Yeah, of course.
- Thank you, Joyce.
- This way.
- Bye, Levon.
- All right, sweetheart.
"Our Father,
who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name,
thy kingdom come,
thy will be done."
God ain’t here, sweetheart.
- Have a nice nap, Princess?
We gotta pull over
and load this bitch
with some
fuckin’ sleeping pills...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Fucking bitch!
- Hey, take it easy!
- Pull over!
- Come on! Stop!
Fucking get it, fucking bitch.
Fucking grab that bitch!
Pull over!
Pull over! Pull over!
God damn it!
Where’s my fucking gun!
- Fuck!
- Fuck.
Fuckin’ move, Viper!
Fuck! Fuck!
I mean, what the fuck?
She is fast.
We’re going back
to fuckin’ prison!
Huh?
Huh? You get it?
Yeah, I get it. I get it.
Fuck! Okay, okay.
Fuck! Fuck!
Shit.
Okay, genius,
now what?
Are you all right?
My name is Jenny Garcia.
I was kidnapped.
It’s all right.
We know who you are.
Let’s get you home.
Okay.
I’m so fucking sorry.
Miss me?
Fuck!
Fucking dome the bitch!
- You gotta be kidding me.
- Is that him?
What the fuck?
Fuck, it’s a video call.
Here, take the fucking phone!
Give me the...
- Fuck!
- ...God damn fucking gun.
Hey, sir.
Dimi says you still
have the girl.
Uh, yeah, yeah.
We still got her.
Show me she’s still alive.
See? Still alive.
I want a second date tonight,
at the farmhouse.
One million dollars.
Uh, yeah.
Whatever you want, sir.
I’ll get her cleaned up
and smelling
real pretty for you.
No, no, no. I want her dirty.
Not sleepy,
but dirty and alive.
- For now.
-
- Fuck, yeah.
- Oh, yes.
Which passport, okay?
You sent me
all these passports.
I can’t tell.
Red? Blue? Green?
- I don’t know
what color, just tell me.
- Where are we going?
What? Okay. Yeah. Go.
I take all of them, okay?
- What do you want?
You want money?
- No, I don’t...
Here, take your money.
You take money.
I don’t want
your fucking money!
- You take all the money.
- I don’t want
- your fucking money!
- You take all the money, okay?
- Let me help you!
- No, no, I don’t need help.
Fuck.
Get away! Stop!
Starting tomorrow, rehab.
All you do is let me slip down
slippery slope.
You’re supposed
to be my rock.
You know, like they say,
"Oh, she’s my rock."
"Hey, thank you."
I have nothing
to thank you for.
Something’s going on out there.
You know
what? You are just an enabler.
- he’s here!
Okay.
Okay. You made your point.
Now we make
a deal, and you begin
a new life as
a wealthy man, huh?
I can pay my own bills.
Congrats.
- Come closer and she dies.
- No!
I figured that.
You should disappear.
Take the money.
Make a nice life.
Where is she?
I do not know this woman.
You’re a bad liar.
Why risk everything?
Why kill everyone for her?
’Cause I told her
I had her back.
If I give you this woman,
you let me live?
Because if I just give you
the address,
then you shoot me, huh?
What if you give me
a fake address
and I shoot you?
That’s bad for both of us.
Head south on 57.
Then I give you her address.
Let’s go.
You know this guy?
Of course, I know. He’s Viper.
He’s Chief of
Human Resource Department
and recruiting
for special projects.
Why you do all this
for a whore?
Say it again.
Please, say that again.
Thought so.
Okay, Dimi,
tell me where we’re going.
Where is she?
There.
She’s in there?
She’s there.
- Promise?
I promise.
She’s there.
Why her?
Who decides?
Viper goes to club,
takes pictures of pretty girls.
I send them to clients,
they make choice.
Meeting is arranged.
This is my specialty service.
Like shopping for
a set of snow tires.
These are human beings.
You must be kidding.
You think money gives a shit
where it comes from?
If I didn’t do this,
somebody else would.
You still haven’t told me why.
Why do you hunt us?
You have a daughter?
No.
Then you won’t understand.
Hey, good lookin’ out.
Hey, yo, we good, brother?
Man, we far from good.
That motherfucker
we hooked up with Dimi
clapped out half
a dozen Russians tonight.
Rumor is, he’s on his way to
Dimi’s trap house right now.
Everybody,
mount the fuck up!
You heard the man.
Mount up!
That’s funny shit.
Sounds lovely, Princess.
I don’t condone this behavior,
but my bank account does.
Hey. It’s time.
What the fuck
are we still doing here?
Come on.
Yeah. I’ll get the pervert.
We’re all just numbers, kid.
Nothin’ personal.
Feels pretty fuckin’
personal to me.
We have to go now, sir.
Why?
It’s now or never.
Then it’s now.
What have I done to you?
Nothing.
That’s the best part.
I wonder
what you look like on...
the inside.
- The fuck was that?
- whoa.
Levon!
Are they fucking shooting?
Who’s gonna
get fucked now, huh?
He’s in there.
Shooting the place up.
Everybody,
lock and load.
Let’s go get this motherfucker.
Yeah, you two on me.
You heard the man. Come on.
Stay tight, stay right.
Demon, put it through
the glass.
You got it.
Levon!
- Shut the fuck up!
Hey. It’s gonna be okay.
Yeah?
You just... Yeah.
I’m beginning to think
that you do not know
what you are doing!
Don’t worry, sir.
Everything’s under control.
I promise you.
I’m gonna cut your heart out.
Good luck.
What the fuck
is your real name?
Levon.
Nice to meet you, Levon.
You ready, son?
I’m always ready.
My fight wasn’t with you.
I know, brother.
Finish it.
Sorry, brother.
- Levon!
- What the fuck?
How dare you come in here?
- Fuck! Shit!
- Oh, fuck!
Oh, that is not good.
- What the fuck?
- Hang on.
- Reload!
- wait, wait, wait.
No, no, no!
- I can explain everything!
- Fuck!
No!
Oh, shit.
Mommy!
- Fuck!
Fuck!
Fuckin’ bitch!
Fuck.
Fuck you!
It’s over now.
Fucking die, bitch!
I think I killed her.
Good.
Fuck.
Whoa.
Stay on my six.
What’s that mean?
Follow me.
There’s an active shooter
in there.
- Shit.
Let’s kill this guy.
What was that?
Bluetooth.
- Is that a grenade?
Mind your ears.
Oh.
You ready?
No.
Time to go.
See you on the other side.
What was that?
Respect for an old friend.
You ready to go home?
- Get me the hell outta here.
Yes, my brother.
He escaped...
with the girl.
None of this was business.
The devil has what he came for.
Let him go.
I understand our need
to move quietly in the world.
But I will not turn
the other cheek
to the man
who killed my children.
Then we will kill you.
The Brotherhood comes before
your personal vengeance.
Do you understand?
I understand.
Hey...
snitches get stitches.
¡Mija! Oh, my God.
- I’m sorry. I’m so sorry.
- No. No.
No. No.
Levon!
Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
I was thinking
about taking Merry
out to the chicken coop today.
Oh.
- Yeah, would you like that?
- Yeah.
- I don’t know.
You better watch out
for that old grumpy one.
- He’s mean. He’s mean.
- Oh, no. He’s mean.
Hey, Dad, it’s you!
You came back.
Told you I would.
You’re okay, Daddy?
Yeah. I nicked myself shaving.
Hi.
Welcome back.
Hey, Joyce.
You’re in one piece.
Just about.
Well, I guess
they didn’t kill you, huh?
Nah. They really tried
their best.
Oh.
You found that girl?
I found her.
So, what did I miss?
Well, I made friends
with a crow and an owl.
And there’s a goat
I taught to say my name.
- No.
- Yeah.
It was really cool.
I was just talking,
and then it was like, "Merry!
"Merry!"
Welcome back, brother.
You’re home.