Bio readouts are all in the green. Looks like she's alive.
Well, there goes our salvage, guys.
- How are we today? - Oh. Terrible.
Well, better than yesterday, at least.
- Where am I? - You're safe.
You're at Gateway Station. Been here a couple of days.
You were pretty groggy at first, but now you're okay.
Oh, looks like you've got a visitor.
Jonesy. Come here.
Hey, come here.
How are you, you stupid cat?
How are you? Where have you been?
Guess you two have met, huh? I'm Burke. Carter Burke.
I work for the company, but don't let that fool you. I'm really an okay guy.
I'm glad to see you're feeling a little better.
They tell me that all the weakness and disorientation should pass soon.
That's just natural side effects of such an unusually long hypersleep, or something like that.
What do you mean?
How long was I out there?
Inhalation Therapy, report to...
Has no one discussed this with you yet?
No. But, I mean...
I don't... recognize this place.
No, I know. Uh...
Okay. It's just that, uh, this might be a shock to you.
- It's long... - How long?
Please.
- 57 years. - What?
That's the thing. You were out there for 57 years.
What happened was you had drifted right through the core systems.
And it's really just blind luck...
that a deep-salvage team found you when they did.
It's one in a thousand, really.
I think you're damn lucky to be alive, kiddo. You could be floating out there forever.
You... You okay?
Uhh...
Uuh!
You okay?
Oh-h-h! Oh, God!
- Nurse! Please! - God!
Someone get in here now!
Now!
- Hold! - Please.
Hold on!
Kill me!
No!
Uh!
Bad dreams again? You want something to help you sleep?
No.
I've slept enough.
Jonesy.
Come here.
Shh.
It's all right.
It's all right now.
It's over.
Dr. Hirsch, 334. Dr. Hirsch, 334.
Hi. Sorry I'm late. I've been running behind all morning.
Is there any word about my daughter?
Uh... I really think we should worry about the hearing now.
'Cause we don't have a lot of time, okay? I read your deposition, and it's great.
If you just stick to that, I think we'll be fine. The thing to remember is,
there're gonna be a lot of heavyweights in there.
You've got feds and Interstellar Commerce Commission,
Colonial Administration, insurance company guys...
Do you have any news about my daughter?
Well, we did come up with some information. Why don't we sit down?
I was hoping to wait until after the inquest.
Um...
"Amanda Ripley-McClaren"... married name, I guess...
"Age 66."
And that was at the time of her death,
which was two years ago.
I'm real sorry.
Amy.
She was cremated and interred at Westlake Repository, Little Chute, Wisconsin.
No children. I checked.
I promised her... that I'd be home for her birthday.
Her 11th birthday.
I'd just like to go, uh...
back to this point about the override destruct order.
- Is it in the file? - I don't understand this.
We have been here for three and a half hours.
Now, how many different ways do you want me to tell the same story?
Look at it from our perspective, please.
Please?
Now, you freely admit to detonating the engines of,
and thereby destroying, an M-class star freighter,
a rather expensive piece of hardware.
Forty-two million in adjusted dollars.
That's minus payload, of course.
The lifeboat's flight recorder corroborates some elements of your account,
in that, for reasons unknown, the Nostromo set down on LV-426,
an unsurveyed planet at that time, that it resumed its course...
and was subsequently set for self-destruct by you for reasons unknown.
Not for reasons unknown. I told you.
We set down there on company orders to get this thing, which destroyed my crew...
and your expensive ship.
The analysis team, which went over the lifeboat centimeter by centimeter,
found no physical evidence of the creature you describe.
Good! That's because I blew it out of the goddamn air lock,
like I said.
Are there any species like this hostile organism on LV-426?
No. It's a rock. No indigenous life.
Did I.Q.'s just drop sharply while I was away?
Ma'am, I already said it was not indigenous.
It was a derelict spacecraft. It was an alien ship.
It was not from there. Do you get it? We homed in on its beacon.
And found something never recorded once...
in over 300 surveyed worlds.
- "A creature that gestates inside a living human host." - Yes.
These are your words. "And has concentrated acid for blood."
That's right.
Look. I can see where this is going,
but I'm telling you that those things exist.
- Thank you, Officer Ripley. That will be all. - Please. You're not listening to me.
Kane, the crew member...
Kane, who went into that ship, said he saw thousands of eggs there.
- Thousands. - Thank you. That will be all.
Goddamn it, that's not all!
Because if one of those things gets down here, then that will be all!
Then all of this... this bullshit that you think is so important...
You can just kiss all of that good-bye!
It is the finding of this court of inquiry that...
Warrant Officer E. Ripley,
NOC14472,
has acted with questionable judgment...
and is unfit to hold an I.C.C. license as a commercial flight officer.
Said license is hereby suspended indefinitely.
Now, no criminal charges will be filed against you at this time,
and you are released on your own recognizance...
for a six-month period of psychometric probation,
to include monthly review by an I.C.C. psychiatric technician.
These proceedings are closed.
That could have been better.
- Look, I think the... Ripley? - Van Leuwen.
Why don't you just check out LV-426?
Because I don't have to. There have been people there for over 20 years,
- and they never complained about any hostile organism. - What do you mean? What people?
Terraformers. Planet engineers.
They go in, set up these big atmosphere processors to make the air breathable.
Takes decades.
It's what we call a "Shake 'N Bake" colony.
How many are there? How many colonists?
I don't know... 60, maybe 70 families. Do you mind?
Families.
Jesus.
- I'll be down in maintenance, okay? - AI!
- What? - Hey, AI.
- What? - Remember you sent some wildcatters...
out to the middle of nowhere last week, out past the Ilium Range?
- Yeah, what? - One of them's on the horn, a mom-and-pop survey team.
He says he's onto something. He wants to know if his claim will be honored.
Why wouldn't his claim be honored?
Well, because you sent them to that particular middle-of-nowhere on company orders, maybe.
- I don't know. - Christ! Some honch in a cushy office on Earth...
says, "Go look at a grid reference."
We look. They don't say why, and I don't ask.
I don't ask, because it takes two weeks to get an answer out here, and the answer is always...
"Don't ask."
So what do I tell this guy?
Tell him as far as I'm concerned, if he finds something, it is his.
- Lydecker? - What?
You kids know you're not supposed to be on this level!
Go on! Get outta here!
- Do too. You go in places we can't fit. - So? That's why I'm the best.
Knock it off! I catch either of you playing in the air ducts again, I'll tan your hides.
Mom, all the kids play...
Wait a minute. Annie, come and have a look at this, will ya?
Folks, we have scored big this time.
What is it, Dad?
I'm not sure.
Let's see if we can't get a closer look at this thing, maybe through that crack there on the side.
- Shouldn't we call in? - Let's wait till we know what to call it in as.
That's about as close as we can get.
Should we take a look inside?
You two stay inside. I mean it. We'll be right back.
- Okay. - Bye.
Huh?
Timmy, they've been gone a long time.
It'll be okay, Newt. Dad knows what he's doing.
Mayday, Mayday! This is Alpha Kilo Two Four Niner calling...!
This is Alpha Kilo Two Four Niner!
Alpha Kilo Two Four Niner calling calling Alpha Control!
Hiya, Ripley. This is Lieutenant Gorman...
of the Colonial Marine Corps...
Ripley, we have to talk.
We've lost contact with the colony on LV-426.
I don't believe this.
You guys throw me at the wolves, and now you want me to go back out there?
Forget it. It's not my problem.
- Can I finish? - No. There's no way.
Ripley, you wouldn't be going in with the troops.
I can guarantee your safety.
These Colonial Marines are very tough hombres.
They're packing state-of-the-art firepower.
There's nothing they can't handle.
- Lieutenant, am I right? - That's true.
We've been trained to deal with situations like this.
Then you don't need me. I'm not a soldier.
Yeah, but we don't know exactly what's going on out there.
It may just be a downed transmitter, okay?
But if it's not, I would like you there as an adviser,
and that's all.
What's your interest in all this? Why are you going?
Corporation cofinanced that colony,
along with Colonial Administration.
We're getting into a lot of terraforming now. "Building Better Worlds"...
Yeah, yeah. I saw the commercial.
Look, I don't have time for this. I've got to get to work.
Oh, right. I heard you're working the cargo docks.
That's right.
- Running loaders and forklifts, that sort of thing? - Yeah. So?
Nothing. I think it's great that you're keeping busy.
And I know it's the only thing that you could get.
There's nothing wrong with it.
What would you say if I told you I could get you reinstated...
as a flight officer?
- The company's already agreed to pick up your contract. - If I go.
Yeah, if you go.
Come on. That's a second chance, kiddo.
I think, personally, for you, it would be the best thing in the world...
to get out there and face this thing, get back on the horse.
Spare me, Burke. I've had my psych evaluation this month.
Yeah, I know. I've read it. You wake up every night. Your sheets are soaking with sweat...
I said no, and I mean it!
Now, please leave. I am not going back.
And I am... I would not be any good to you if I did.
Okay. Shh.
Would you do me a favor? Just think about it.
Thanks for the coffee.
Oh!
Hello.
Ripley.
- You okay? - Just tell me one thing, Burke.
You're going out there to destroy them, right?
Not to study, not to bring back, but to wipe them out.
That's the plan. You have my word on it.
All right. I'm in.
I think that...
And you, you little shithead,
You're staying here.
Mmm.
They ain't payin' us enough for this, man.
Not enough to have to wake up to your face, Drake.
What?
Is that a joke?
Oh, I wish it were.
Hey, Hicks. Man, you look just like I feel.
All right, sweethearts. What are you waiting for?
Breakfast in bed? Another glorious day in the corps.
A day in the Marine Corps is like a day on the farm...
every meal's a banquet, every paycheck a fortune, every formation a parade.
- I love the corps! - Christ!
Man, this floor is freezing!
- What do you want me to do? Fetch your slippers for ya? - Gee, would you, sir? I'd like that.
Look into my eye. Fall in, people.
Come on. Let's go.
I hate this job.
- Crowe, Wierzbowski. Come on. On your feet. - We got some slack coming, right?
- You had three weeks on your back, Frost. - What do you want?
I'm talking about breathing, not this frozen shit.
Yeah, Top. How 'bout it?
All right. First assembly's in 15, people. Shag it.
Hey, Mira. Who's Snow White?
She's supposed to be some kind of consultant.
Apparently, she saw an alien once.
- Whoopee-fuckin'-do! - Hey, I'm impressed.
¡Que bonita!
Hey, Vasquez. Have you ever been mistaken for a man?
No. Have you?
Ha, ha! Oh, Vasquez. You're just too bad.
Uhh!
Hey, Top, what's the op?
It's a rescue mission. You'll love it.
There's some juicy colonists' daughters we have to rescue from their virginity.
Dumb-ass colonists.
- What's this crap supposed to be? - Vasquez.
- Corn bread, I think. - It's good for you, boy. Eat it.
Hey, sure wouldn't mind getting some more of that Arcturian poontang.
- Remember that time? - Yeah. Except the one that you had was male.
Doesn't matter when it's Arcturian.
Hey, Bishop, man. Do the thing with the knife. Oh, please.
Oh, come on. Yeah.
All right! Yeah.
- I don't want to see that, man. - Come on, man. All right. All right.
Hey, what are you doing, man? Hey what are you doing?
- Come on. Quit messing around, Drake. - Hudson, shut up!
- Bishop, hey, man. - Do it, Bishop!
- Hey! Not me, man! Quit messing around! - Yeah, you! Don't move.
Trust me.
Aah!
There you go, short shit. APONE: All right. Knock it off, knock it off.
Thank you.
Enjoy your meal.
That wasn't funny, man.
- Lieutenant Gorman? Mr. Burke? - Yeah, thanks.
Looks like the new lieutenant's too good to eat with the rest of us grunts.
Boy's definitely got a corncob up his ass.
Thought you never miss, Bishop.
You never said anything about an android being on board. Why not?
It never... never occurred to me.
It's just common practice. We always have a synthetic on board.
I prefer the term "artificial person" myself.
Right.
- Is there a problem? - I'm sorry.
I don't know why I didn't even...
Ripley's last trip out, the syn... the artificial person malfunctioned.
- Malfunctioned? - There were problems and a few deaths were involved.
I'm shocked. Was it an older model?
The Hyperdyne Systems 120-A2.
That explains it then. The A2s always were a bit twitchy.
That could never happen now with our behavioral inhibitors.
It is impossible for me to harm, or by omission of action, allow to be harmed, a human being.
You sure you don't want some?
You just stay away from me, Bishop. You got that straight?
Guess she don't like the corn bread, either.
- Squad, ten-hut! Officer on deck! - As you were.
Quickly, quickly. Settle down.
All right. Listen up!
Morning, marines. I'm sorry we didn't have time to brief you people before we left Gateway...
- Sir? - What is it, Hicks?
Hudson, sir. He's Hicks.
What's the question?
Is this gonna be a stand-up fight, sir, or another bug hunt?
All we know is that there's still no contact with the colony...
and that a xenomorph may be involved.
- Excuse me, sir. A what? - A xenomorph.
It's a bug hunt.
- What exactly are we dealing with here? - Ripley.
I'll tell you what I know.
We set down on LV-426.
One of our crew members was brought back on board with something attached to his face,
some kind of parasite.
We tried to get it off. It wouldn't come off.
Later, it seemed to come off by itself and die.
Kane seemed fine.
We were all having dinner, and, um,
it must have laid something inside his throat, some sort of embryo.
- He started... Um, he... - Look, man.
I only need to know one thing... where they are.
- Yo, Vasquez. Kick ass. - Anytime, anywhere man.
Right, right. Somebody said "alien." She thought they said "illegal alien", and signed up.
- Fuck you, man. - Anytime, anywhere.
Are you finished?
I hope you're right. I really do.
Yeah, okay, right. Thank you, Ripley.
We also have Ripley's report on disk. I suggest you study it.
Because just one of those things managed to wipe out my entire crew in less than 24 hours.
And if the colonists have found that ship, then there's no telling...
how many of them have been exposed.
Do you understand?
Anyway, we have it on disk, so you better look at it.
Any questions?
What is it, Private?
How do I get out of this chickenshit outfit?
You secure that shit, Hudson.
All right.
Now listen up.
I want this thing to go smooth...
and by the numbers.
I want D.C.S. and tactical database assimilation by 08:30.
Ordinance loading, weapons strip and drop-ship prep details...
- will have seven hours. - Oh, come on.
Now, move it, people!
All right, sweethearts. You heard the man, and you know the drill.
Assholes and elbows! Hudson, come here. Come here.
I don't care if you are short, Hudson. Get it done.
Hey, Sarge. You'll get lip cancer smoking those.
Corporal, I want this loading lock sealed. Now!
- How many more you got, Spunkmeyer? - Last one.
Good. Take it away.
Clear behind.
- Did you check number three? - Let me see that.
Hi. I feel like kind of a fifth wheel around here. Is there anything I can do?
I don't know. Is there anything you can do?
Well, I can drive that loader.
I have a Class 2 rating.
Be my guest.
Where you want it?
Bay 12, please.
All right, sweethearts. We're a team, and there's nothing to worry about.
We come here, and we gonna conquer, and we gonna kick some.
- Is that understood? That's what we gonna do, sweethearts. - Yes, sir.
- We are going to go and get some. - Hey.
All right, people! On the ready line!
- Are you lean? Are you mean? - Yeah! Yeah!
- What are you? What are you? - Lean and mean!
Hudson! Get on the ready line, marine!
Get some today! Get on the ready line!
- Yo! - Move it out! Move it out, goddamn it!
Get hot! One, two, three! Get out, get out, get out!
Move it out, move it out, move it out! Move it out, move it out, move it out!
Absolutely badasses.
Let's pack 'em in. Get in there!
All right! Move it!
- Let's go, let's go! - One, two, three,
four, five, six!
All right. I want combat seating. You know your places.
Get those weapons stowed. Let's go.
Come on. Settle down, people.
Lock 'em in, Hudson.
- Ready to get it on? - You know it!
Okay, Bishop, let's go.
Roger.
I'm ready, man.
Ready to get it on! Go!
Stand by. Cross-locking now. Prelaunch autocycle engaged.
Primary couplers released. Hit the internals.
Shit, man. FERRO: Confirm cross-lock and drop stations secured.
Affirmative. All drop stations secured.
Stand by. Ten seconds.
Stand by to initiate release sequencer... on my mark.
Five, four, three, - We're on an express elevator to hell, going down.
Two, one, mark.
Woo-hoo!
- Switch to D.C.S. ranging. - 240, nominal to profile.
We're in the pipe, five by five.
We're picking up some hull ionization.
Got it. Rough air ahead.
We're in for some chop.
How many drops is this for you, Lieutenant?
Thirty-eight.
Simulated.
How many combat drops?
Uh, two... including this one.
- Shit. - Oh, man!
Range 014. Turning on final.
And I'm telling you, I got a bad feeling about this drop.
You always say that, Frost. You always say, "I got a bad feeling about this drop."
Okay, okay. When we get back without you,
I'll call your folks.
All right. Let's see what we can see.
Everybody online. Looking good.
Drake, check your camera. There seems to be a malfunction.
That's better. Pan it around a bit.
- Good. - I'm ready, man. Check it out.
- I am the ultimate badass. - Yeah. That's right.
- State-of-the-badass art. You do not want to fuck with me. - Who here's runnin'?
Check it out.
Hey, Ripley, don't worry.
Me and my squad of ultimate badasses will protect you.
- Hey! - That's right.
Check it out.
Independently targeting particle-beam phalanx.
Fry half a city with this puppy.
We got tactical smart missiles,
phase-plasma pulse rifles, R.P.G.'s.
- We got sonic, electronic ballbreakers! - Whoo!
We got nukes, we got knives, sharp sticks...
Knock it off, Hudson. All right, gear up.
Two minutes, people. Get hot.
Somebody wake up Hicks.
Coming around for a 709er.
- Terminal guidance locked in. - Where's the damn beacon?
Oh, I see it.
- That's the atmosphere processor? - Yep, that's it.
Remarkable piece of machinery. Completely automated.
You know, we manufacture those, by the way.
Okay, Ferro. Take us in low over the main colony complex.
Storm shutters are sealed.
There's no visible activity. All right. Hold at 40.
- Roger. - Give me a slow circle of the complex.
Structure seems intact. They still have power.
Okay, Ferro. Set down on the landing grid.
Immediate dust off on my clear, then stay on station.
Down and clear.
Ten seconds, people. Look sharp.
All right. I want a nice, clean dispersal this time.
Let's go! Move it out!
Head 'em up!
First squad up on line. Hicks, get yours in accord and watch the rear.
Vasquez, take point. Let's move!
Move up.
Hudson, run a bypass.
Second squad, move up. Flanking positions.
Second squad on line.
You set?
Go on.
Second team, move inside. Hicks, take the upper level.
Sir, you copying this? Looks like hits from small-arms fire.
Uh, we got some explosives damage.
It's probably seismic survey charges.
Are you reading this? Keep it tight, people.
All right. Hicks, Hudson, use your motion trackers.
Nothing. Not a goddamn thing.
Quarter and search by twos.
Okay. Dietrich, Frost, you're up.
It's right in there.
- Now! - Now!
- Haah! Uh... - Good one, Hudson!
Uh, sir, uh, we have a negative situation here. Uh, movin' on, sir.
Wait. Wait, tell him to...
Hicks, back up. Pan right.
- There. - You seeing this all right?
Looks melted. Somebody must have bagged one of Ripley's bad guys here.
Acid for blood.
If you like that, you're gonna love this.
Quit screwing around.
Second squad, what's your status?
Uh, we just finished our sweep. Nobody's home.
Roger. Sir, this place is dead.
Whatever happened here, I think we missed it.
All right. The area's secured. Let's go in and see what their computer can tell us.
- Wait a minute. It's not secure. - The area's secured, Ripley.
First team, head for operations.
- Hudson, see if you can get their C.P.U. on line. - Affirmative.
- Hicks, meet me at the south lock. We're coming in. - Roger.
He's comin' in. I feel safer already.
Pendejo, jerk-off.
Sir, we got the C.P.U. on line. No problem.
Good. Stand by in Operations.
Okay, let's go.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Sir, they sealed off this wing at both ends,
welded the doors and blocked off the stairs with heavy equipment.
Mm-hmm. But it looks like the barricade didn't hold.
- Any bodies? - No, sir.
Last stand.
Must have been a hell of a fight.
Yeah, looks that way.
All right, Drake, this way.
We should be able to cut through the med lab to Operations.
Lieutenant.
Gorman.
Are those the same ones that...
Careful, Burke.
Looks like love at first sight to me.
Oh, he likes you, Burke.
Two are alive. The rest are dead.
"Surgically removed before embryo implantation."
"Subject Marachek, John J., died during the procedure."
They killed him taking it off.
Yo, Hicks.
I think we got something here.
- Behind us. - One of us?
Apone, where are your people? Anybody in "D" block?
Ah, that's a negative. We're all in Operations.
Talk to me, Frosty.
Let's keep moving, baby.
- It's moving. - Which way?
It's coming straight for us. Straight up.
- Fuck! - Hold up.
Ripley.
Hey. Shh. It's all right.
- It's all right. Come on. - Just grab her, Corporal.
Don't be afraid. Come on. We won't hurt you.
Shh. It's all right. It's okay.
Come on out. Come on.
- Easy. Easy. - I got her.
Ow! Damn!
- Watch her! She's under the grille! - Don't let her go.
- Frost, get your light up here. - Where'd she go?
- Shine the light. - Here. Here.
- Here. Here. - There she is.
Keep back. Keep back. Don't scare her.
- Grab her, man. We're gonna lose her. - Damn it!
Kick it out!
Wait.
It's okay. It's all right.
Don't be afraid.
See?
Wait. No, you don't.
It's okay. You're gonna be all right now.
Shh.
Easy. Easy. It's gonna be okay.
It's all right. You're gonna be okay.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
Easy. Easy.
- What's her name again? - Rebecca.
Now think, Rebecca. Concentrate.
Just start at the beginning.
Where are your parents?
Now, look, Rebecca, you have to try and help...
Gorman, give it a rest, why don't you?
Total brain lock.
Physically, she's okay.
Borderline malnutrition, but I don't think there's any permanent damage.
Come on. We're wasting our time.
Try this.
It's a little hot chocolate.
There you go.
Whoop.
That good, huh?
Uh-oh. I made a clean spot here.
Now I've done it. Guess I'll have to do the whole thing.
Hard to believe there's a little girl under all this.
And a pretty one too.
You don't talk much, do you?
Smoking or nonsmoking?
Just tell me what you're scanning for, Private.
- P.D.T.s. - What?
Personal data transmitters.
Every colonist had one surgically implanted.
If they're within 20 klicks, we'll read it out here.
So far, zippo.
I don't know how you managed to stay alive,
but you're one brave kid, Rebecca.
N-Newt.
- What'd you say? - Newt.
My name's Newt.
Nobody calls me Rebecca except my brother.
Newt? I like that.
I'm Ripley. It's nice to meet you.
And who is this, hmm?
- Casey. - Hello, Casey.
What about your brother? What's his name?
Timmy.
Is Timmy around here too? Maybe hiding like you were?
Any sisters?
Mom and dad?
Newt, look at me. Where are they?
They're dead, all right? Can I go now?
I'm sorry, Newt.
Don't you think you'd be safer here with us?
These people are here to protect you.
They're soldiers.
It won't make any difference.
Need anything else?
Hello, Bishop. Do you need anything else?
No.
That's a nice pet you got there, Bishop.
Magnificent, isn't it?
Yo! Stop your grinnin' and drop your linen! Found 'em.
- They alive? - Unknown,
but it looks like all of them.
Over at the processing station, Sublevel 3,
under the main cooling towers.
Looks like a goddamn town meeting.
Let's saddle up, Apone.
Aye, sir.
All right. Let's go, people. They ain't payin' us by the hour.
Let's go. Head 'em out!
Okay, Frost, you're driving.
It's okay. Don't worry. It'll be okay.
I want a straight "V", deployment, second team on left flank.
Advance on axial 664. Tracker on line.
Set the "V" gain to filter R.F. ambient.
Hudson, tracker on line. Left and right, little buddy.
Forty meters in, bearing 221, there should be a stairwell.
Check. Got it.
You want Sublevel 3.
Let's go, people. Hudson, you got the point.
Hicks, watch our tails.
Nice and easy. Check those corners.
Check those corners.
- Watch your spacing. - All right. You heard the man.
Don't bunch up. Stay loose.
Uh, your transmission's showing a lot of breakup.
Probably getting some interference from the structure.
Use those lights.
Next one down, and proceed on a 216.
Uh, roger. That's a 216.
I'm not making that out too well. What is it, Hudson?
You tell me, man. I only work here.
What is that?
I don't know.
Proceed inside.
Watch your fire and check your targets.
Remember we're looking for civvies in here.
Easy.
Tighten it up, Frost. We're getting a little thin.
Nice and easy.
Looks like some sort of secreted resin.
Yeah, but secreted from what?
Nobody touch nothing.
Busy little creatures, huh?
Hot as hell in here.
Yeah, man, but it's a dry heat.
Knock it off, Hudson.
Lieutenant, what do those pulse rifles fire?
Ten millimeter explosive-tip case less.
Standard light armor-piercing round.
- Why? - Well, look where your team is.
They're right under the primary heat exchangers.
So?
So if they fire their weapons in there, won't they rupture the cooling system?
- Ho, ho, ho. Yeah. She's absolutely right. - So? So what?
Look. This whole station is basically a big fusion reactor.
Right?
So you're talking about a thermonuclear explosion, and adios, muchachos.
Oh, great. Wonderful.
Shit!
Look. Uh... Apone.
Look. We can't have any firing in there.
I, uh, I want you to collect magazines from everybody.
- Is he fuckin' crazy? - What the hell are we supposed to use, man, harsh language?
- Flame units only. I want rifles slung. - Sir, I...
Just do it, Sergeant. And no grenades.
All right, sweethearts. You heard the man. Pull 'em out. Come on. Let's have 'em.
Come on, Vasquez. Clear and lock.
Damn!
You too. Give it up, Ski. Come on. Let's go.
Crowe, I want it now. Give it up.
Right on, Vas.
Let's go, marine. Give it up.
Frost, you got the duty. Open that bag.
- Thanks a lot, Sarge. - Hicks, cover our ass.
Head 'em out, people.
I like to keep this handy... for close encounters.
I heard that.
Any movement?
Nothing. Zip.
Holy shit.
Newt, go sit up front.
Go on! Now!
Steady, people. Let's finish our sweep.
We're still marines, and we got a job to do.
Keep it moving. Easy.
- Help! - What?
- Top, get over here. We got a live one! - You're gonna be all right.
Please... K-kill me.
Just stay calm. We're gonna get you outta here.
It's gonna be all right. Give me a hand. We gotta get her outta here.
- What is it, Dietrich? - Convulsion!
Dietrich, get back!
Get back!
- No! - Frost, flamethrower. Kill it!
- Get back! - Flamethrower! Move!
Movement!
- What's the position? - I can't lock in!
Talk to me, Hudson!
Uh, Multiple signals.
They're closing.
Go to infrared, people. Look sharp!
What's happening, Apone? Can't see anything in here.
Pull your team out, Gorman.
I got signals. I got readings in front and behind.
Where, man? I don't see shit.
He's right. There's nothing back here.
Look, I'm telling you. There's something moving, and it ain't us!
- Oh, shit. - Tracker's off scale, man.
They're all around us, man! Jesus!
Maybe they don't show up on infrared at all.
Frost!
Come on!
Jesus Christ, Apone! What is going on?
Wierzbowski and Crowe are down!
- Dietrich, Frost, off the board! - Dietrich, Crowe! Sound off! Frost!
Frost!
Wierzbowski?
Let's rock!
Who's firing? Goddamn it!
Yeah!
- I ordered to hold fire. - They're coming out of the walls!
They're coming out of the goddamn walls! Let's book!
- On the right, man. - Uh, Apone,
I want you to... lay down a suppressing fire with the incinerators...
Vasquez, Drake, hold your fire, goddamn it!
Apone, are you copying me? I want you to lay down suppressing fire...
with the incinerators and fall back by squads to the A.P.C.
- Over. - Say again, all after "incinerator."
I said I want you to lay down a suppressing fire with the incinerators and fall back...
by squads to the A.P.C. Over.
Hey!
- Sarge! Sarge! - Apone.
- Talk to me. Apone? - Copy! Copy!
- Talk to me, Apone. - He's gone!
- Get them out of there! - Shut up!
- Do it now! - Shut up!
- Hicks, whoever's left, get the hell out of there... Goddamn it! - Just shut up!
- It's coming out of the goddamn walls! - Where's Apone? Where's Apone?
The sarge is gone! Let's get the fuck out of here!
Let's move it! Let's go, marine!
Hudson? Vasquez?
- Hudson, look out! - Get it!
Watch it!
- Hicks. - Come on. Behind you! Fall back!
- I told them to fall back. I told them to fall back. - Fall back, goddamn it, now!
- They're cut off! - Hudson, move your ass!
- Do something! - Let's go, marine!
Fuck!
- Come on. Keep moving, baby. - Hold on, Newt.
Ripley, what the hell are you doing?
Turn around!
That's an order!
- Get off me, damn it! - Goddamn it, that's an order!
You had your chance, Gorman.
Come on!
Come on. Let's move it!
Come on! Let's go! Let's go!
It's blocked, man. We gotta go around!
- Open the door! Hicks! - Drake, we are leaving!
Get them, man!
Run for it!
Shit!
- Go! Go! - Come on, man! Come on!
Drake, come on!
No!
- Fire in the hole! - He's gone!
Put it out! Put it out! Go! Go!
- Come on. Put it out! - Drake's coming, man!
- Drake! No, he's not! - He's gone!
Forget him! He's gone!
They're in the goddamn door!
Eat this!
Ripley!
Go, go, go!
It's all right! We're clear!
Ripley, you've blown the transaxle!
You're just grinding metal!
Come on, ease down.
Ease down.
Ease down. Ease down.
You okay?
- I'm all right. - Hudson.
Get away from me, man!
- Lieutenant. - What happened to Gorman?
I don't know. Maybe a concussion.
- But he's alive. - No, he's dead!
Wake up, pendejo, and then I'm gonna kill you!
Back off. Right now.
- Somebody get me a first aid kit. - Fuck!
Hey. Hey, look.
The sarge and Dietrich aren't dead, man.
Their signs are real low, but they ain't dead.
- Then we go back in there and get them. - Fuck that!
- We don't leave our people behind... - I ain't going back in there.
You can't help them!
You can't. Right now they're being cocooned just like the others.
- Oh, dear Lord Jesus, this ain't happenin', man. - Damn it.
This can't be happenin', man. This isn't happenin'!
All right. We got seven canisters of CN-20.
I say we roll them in there and nerve gas the whole fucking nest.
That's worth a try, but we don't even know if it's gonna affect them.
Let's just bug out and call it even. Okay? What are we talking about this for?
I say we take off and nuke the entire site from orbit.
It's the only way to be sure.
- Fuckin' "A"! - Hold on. Hold on one second.
This installation has a substantial dollar value attached to it.
They can bill me.
Okay, look. This is an emotional moment for all of us, okay?
I know that. But let's not make snap judgments, please.
This is clearly... clearly an important species we're dealing with,
and I don't think that you or I or anybody has the right...
- to arbitrarily exterminate them. - Wrong.
Yeah. Watch us.
Maybe you haven't been keeping up on current events,
but we just got our asses kicked, pal!
Look. I'm not blind to what's going on,
but I cannot authorize that kind of action.
I'm sorry.
Well, I believe Corporal Hicks...
has authority here.
Corporal Hicks is...
This operation is under military jurisdiction,
and Hicks is next in chain of command.
Am I right, Corporal?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's right.
- Yeah. Look, Ripley. - Yes.
This is a multimillion-dollar installation, okay?
He can't make that kind of decision.
He's just a grunt. Uh, no offense.
- None taken. Ferro, do you copy? - Standing by.
Prep for dust off. We're gonna need immediate evac.
Roger. On our way.
I say we take off, nuke the site from orbit. It's the only way to be sure.
Let's do it.
Let's go. Pick it up, Hudson. Pick it up, baby.
All right. Set him down here.
Move it, Spunkmeyer. We're rolling.
Hold on a second. There's something...
Just get up here.
I'm in. Ramp closing.
Spunkmeyer.
Goddamn it.
Well, where the fuck...
Run!
Well, that's great. That's just fuckin' great, man.
Now what the fuck are we supposed to do?
We're in some real pretty shit now, man!
Are you finished?
You all right?
I guess we're not gonna be leaving now, right?
I'm sorry, Newt.
- You don't have to be sorry. It wasn't your fault. - That's it, man.
Game over, man! Game over!
What the fuck are we gonna do now? What are we gonna do?
Maybe we could build a fire. Sing a couple of songs, huh? Why don't we try that?
We'd better get back 'cause it'll be dark soon,
and they mostly come at night, mostly.
That's everything, right? All right. This is absolutely everything...
that we could salvage out of the A.P.C. wreckage.
We got four pulse rifles with about 50 rounds each.
That ain't so good.
We got, uh, 15 of these M-40 grenades.
Don't touch that.
- Dangerous, honey. - Is that the only flamethrower?
Yeah. It's only half full, but it's functional.
Got another one, it's damaged... I don't know about that one.
But the good news... we got four of these robot sentries,
with display and scanners intact.
They really kick ass. I think they'll come in handy.
How long after we're declared overdue can we expect a rescue?
Seventeen days.
Seventeen days?
Hey, man, I don't wanna rain on your parade, but we're not gonna last 17 hours.
Those things are gonna come in here just like they did before. And they're gonna come in here...
- Hudson! Hudson! - They're gonna come in here and they're gonna get us!
This little girl survived longer than that...
with no weapons and no training.
Right?
Why don't you put her in charge?
You'd better just start dealing with it, Hudson. Listen to me.
Hudson, just deal with it because we need you.
And I'm sick of your bullshit.
Now, I want you to get on a terminal and call up some kind of floor plan file.
Do you understand? Construction blueprints. I don't care.
Anything that shows the layout of this place. Are you listening?
- Yeah. - I need to see air ducts.
I need to see electrical access tunnels, subbasements,
every possible way into this complex.
- We don't have much time. - Okay.
- Okay, I'm on it. - Hudson!
Just relax.
I'll be in med lab. I'll check on Gorman, continue my analysis.
Fine. You do that.
So this service tunnel must be how they're moving back and forth.
That's right. It moves from the processing station...
right into the sublevel here.
Come down on that. Okay, come over.
Hold. Go back. Okay, punch that in right there.
No. It's back here. Okay.
Well, there's a pressure door at this end.
Couldn't we put one of the remote sentry units in the tunnel, and then seal that door?
Yeah, that'll work, but we gotta figure on them getting into the complex.
That's right, so... we repair the barricades at these two intersections.
- Right. - And weld plate steel over these ducts...
here and here and here.
That way they can only come at us from these two corridors.
All right. Then we put the other sentry units here, and here, right?
- Right. - Outstanding.
Now all we need is a deck of cards.
All right, people. Let's move like we got a purpose.
- Affirmative. - Affirmative.
Do your thing, baby. Come on, Come on, Vasquez. Let's get the hell outta here.
Hudson here. "A" and "B" sentries are in place and keyed.
Roger. Stand by. Arming now. Test it, Hudson.
- Do it! - Fire in the hole!
Okay, great. Let's get the hell outta here!
We're sealing the tunnel. Come on, baby.
For what it's worth.
Here. I want you to put this on.
- What's it for? - It's a locator.
Then I can find you anywhere in the complex on this.
- It's just a precaution. - Thanks.
Doesn't mean we're engaged or anything.
All right, what's next?
Last stop.
Get in.
Scoot down. That's good.
Now, you lie here and have a nap. You're very tired.
I don't want to. I have scary dreams.
Well, I bet Casey doesn't have scary dreams.
Let's take a look.
Nope. Nothing bad in there.
See? Maybe you could just try to be like her, hmm?
Ripley, she doesn't have bad dreams...
because she's just a piece of plastic.
Right. I'm sorry, Newt.
There.
My mommy always said there were no monsters...
no real ones... but there are.
Yes, there are, aren't there?
Why do they tell little kids that?
Most of the time it's true.
Did one of those things grow inside her?
I don't know, Newt.
That's the truth.
Isn't that how babies come? I mean, people babies?
- They grow inside you. - Oh, that's very different.
Did you ever have a baby?
Yes, I did. I had a little girl.
- Where is she? - She's gone.
You mean dead.
Here.
Take this.
For luck.
There's that.
Don't go, please.
Newt, I'm gonna be right in the next room.
And you see that camera right up there?
I can see you right through that camera,
all the time to see if you're safe.
I'm not gonna leave you, Newt.
I mean that. That's a promise.
You promise?
I cross my heart.
- And hope to die? - And hope to die.
Now go to sleep, and don't dream.
Sneak.
The molecular acid oxidizes after the creature's death, completely neutralizing it.
Bishop, you know, that's very interesting, but it doesn't really get us anywhere, does it?
I'm trying to figure out what we're dealing with here.
Let's go through it again.
They grab the colonists, they move them over there...
and they immobilize them to be hosts for more of these.
Which would mean that there would have to be a lot of these parasites, right?
One for each colonist. That's over 100, at least.
Yes. That follows.
But each one of these things comes from an egg, right?
So who's laying these eggs?
I'm not sure.
It must be something we haven't seen yet.
Hey, maybe it's like an ant hive.
Bees, man. Bees have hives.
You know what I mean. There's, like, one female that runs the whole show.
- Yes, the queen. - Yeah, the mama.
She's badass, man. I mean, big.
- These things ain't ants, estúpido. - I know that.
Bishop, I want these specimens destroyed as soon as you're finished with them.
- Is that clear? - Mr. Burke gave instructions...
that they were to be kept alive in stasis for return to the company labs.
He was very specific about it.
Look, those two specimens are worth millions to the bio-weapons division, right?
Now, if you're smart, we can both come out of this heroes,
and we will be set up for life.
You're crazy, Burke. Do you know that?
Do you really think you can get a dangerous organism like that past I.C.C. quarantine?
How can they impound it if they don't know about it?
But they will know about it, Burke, from me.
Just like they'll know that you were responsible for the deaths of 157 colonists.
- Wait a second. - You sent them to that ship.
- You're wrong. - I just checked the colony log.
Directive dated 6-12-79, signed Burke, Carter J.
You sent them out there, and you didn't even warn them.
- Why didn't you warn them, Burke? - Okay, look.
What if that ship didn't even exist? Do you ever think about that?
I didn't know. So now if I went and made a major security situation out of it,
everybody steps in, administration steps in, and there's no exclusive rights for anybody.
Nobody wins. So I made a decision, and it was wrong.
It was a bad call, Ripley. It was a bad call.
- Bad call? - Right.
These people are dead, Burke!
Don't you have any idea what you've done here?
I'm gonna make sure that they nail you right to the wall for this!
You're not gonna sleaze your way out of this one.
Right to the wall.
Ripley. I...
You know, I expected more from you.
I thought... you'd be smarter than this.
Well, I'm happy to disappoint you.
- What is it? What's going on? - They're coming.
- Where? - In the tunnel.
Here we go. "A" and "B" gun tracking far end. Multiple targets.
Those ammo counters go.
"B" gun's down 50%.
Man, it's a shooting gallery down there.
Sixty rounds left on "B."
Forty. Twenty. Ten.
"B" gun's dry. Twenty on "A."
Ten. Five.
That's it.
Jesus, they were wall-to-wall in there.
They're at the pressure door.
Man, listen to that.
Bishop here. I'm afraid I have some bad news.
Well, that's a switch.
It's very pretty, Bishop, but what are we looking for?
That's it. Emergency venting.
Oh, that's beautiful, man. Oh, man, that... that just beats it all.
- How long till it blows? - Four hours.
With a blast radius of 30 kilometers,
equal to about 40 megatons.
We got problems. HUDSON: I don't believe this. I don't fucking believe this.
Vasquez, close the shutters.
Why can't we shut it down from here?
I'm sorry. The crash caused too much damage.
An overload... is inevitable at this point.
Oh, man, and I was getting short.
Four more weeks and out. Now I'm gonna buy it on this rock.
- It ain't half fair, man. - Hudson, give us a break!
Four more weeks. Oh, man.
We've got to get the other drop ship from the Sulaco.
I mean, there must be some way of bringing it down on remote.
How? The transmitter was on the A.P.C. It's wasted.
I don't care how, but we'd better think of something. We'd better think of a way.
- Think of what? We're fucked! We're doomed! - Shut up!
Shut up! What about the colony transmitters?
The uplink tower down at the other end. Why can't we use that?
No, I checked. The hardware in between here and there was damaged.
We can't align the dish.
Well, somebody's gonna have to go out there,
take a portable terminal, go out there and patch in manually.
Oh, yeah, sure. With those things running around? You can count me out.
- Yeah I guess we can just count you out of everything. - I'll go. I'll go.
That's right, man. Why don't you go, man?
- I'll go. - What?
I'll go. I mean, I'm the only one qualified to remote pilot the ship anyway.
Yeah, right, man. Bishop should go. Good idea.
Believe me, I'd prefer not to.
I may be synthetic, but I'm not stupid.
How long?
This conduit runs almost to the uplink assembly... 180 meters.
- Say 40 minutes to crawl down there... - Right.
An hour to, patch in and align the antenna.
Thirty minutes to prep the ship,
- and about 50 minutes flight time. - It's gonna be close.
- Good luck. - See you soon.
Watch your fingers.
Vaya con Dios, man.
This is unbelievable. Twenty meters and closing.
- Fifteen. - How many?
Can't tell. Lots.
"D" gun's down 50%.
"C" gun's right behind it.
Stopping them. It ain't stopping them.
- 150 rounds on "D." - Come on. Come on, baby.
Hundred rounds.
Come on! Come on!
"D" gun's down to 20.
10.
Damn it!
Wait! They're retreating.
The guns stopped them.
You're right.
Next time they walk right up and knock.
Yeah, but they don't know that.
They're probably looking for other ways to get in.
That'll take 'em a while.
- Maybe we got 'em demoralized. - Shut up!
I want you two walking perimeter.
Move!
Hey, listen.
We're all in strung-out shape,
but stay frosty and alert.
We can't afford to let one of those bastards in here.
All right. Vámonos.
How long's it been since you got any sleep?
Twenty-four hours?
Hicks, I'm not gonna end up like those others.
You'll take care of it, won't you?
If it comes to that, I'll do us both.
Listen, let's just make sure it doesn't come to that.
- All right? - All right.
Hey, I want to introduce you to a personal friend of mine.
This is an M-41 A pulse rifle, 10 millimeter,
with an over-and-under 30 millimeter pump-action grenade launcher.
Feel the weight.
Okay, what do I do?
- Okay, pull it in tight here. - Right.
- Uh-huh. Lean into it. - Mm-hmm.
All right. Now, it will kick some.
All right. When the counter reads zero here, you...
- I press this up? - That's right.
Get another one in quick. Slap it in hard.
- Right. - And you're ready to rock and roll.
- What's this? - That's the grenade launcher...
I don't think you want to mess with that.
You started this. Show me everything.
I can handle myself.
Yeah, I noticed.
How do you feel?
All right, I guess. One hell of a hangover.
- Look, Ripley, I just want... - Forget it.
Excuse me.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh. It's okay. It's okay.
Newt, Newt, wake up.
- Wha... - Be quiet.
We're in trouble.
No!
Move, Newt!
Hey!
Help! Help!
- Somebody! - Hicks!
Say again, Bishop.
You've got it into auto-refuel mode, and it's sequencing right?
- That's right. - Okay, good. Stay on it.
Get back to me when you've activated the launch cycle.
- Roger. - He's at the uplink tower.
- Good. - Terrific.
- Hicks! Hicks! Hicks! - Help!
- Help! Help! - Hicks, help us!
- Break the glass! Break it. Break it. - Yes.
I'll try.
Ripley, I'm scared.
Me too.
Stay here.
- It's the med lab. - Hudson!
Vasquez, meet me in med lab. We got a fire.
We're on our way.
They're coming, Newt.
Shoot it out!
- Hudson! - Jesus.
Christ, kid, look out!
Fucking die.
- Over there! Ready? - Yeah! Yeah!
Now!
- Hudson? - Yeah. All clear.
Nailed the other one. It's history, man.
Jesus.
- Burke... - It was Burke.
I say we grease this rat-fuck son of a bitch right now.
Just doesn't make any goddamn sense.
He figured that he could get an alien back through quarantine...
if one of us was impregnated...
whatever you call it...
and then frozen for the trip home.
Nobody would know about the embryos we were carrying...
me and Newt.
Wait a minute, now. We'd all know.
Yes. The only way he could do it...
is if he sabotaged certain freezers on the way home.
Namely yours.
Then he could jettison the bodies and make up any story he liked.
Fuck! He's dead. You're dog meat, pal.
This is so nuts.
I mean, listen... Listen to what you're saying.
It's paranoid delusion.
It's really sad. It's pathetic.
You know, Burke, I don't know which species is worse.
You don't see them fucking each other over for a goddamn percentage.
All right. We waste him. No offense.
No! He's gotta go back...
- They cut the power. - What do you mean, they cut the power?
How could they cut the power, man? They're animals.
I want you two with trackers, checking the corridors! Move!
- Gorman, watch Burke! - I got him.
Newt, stay close.
- I'll go this side. - You do that, man.
- Anything? - There's something.
It's inside the complex.
You're just reading me.
No, no, it ain't you.
They're inside... inside the perimeter. They're in here.
Hudson, stay cool! Vasquez?
Hudson may be right.
- Get back, both of you! - The signal's weird.
Must be some interference or something.
There's movement all over the place!
Get back to Operations. It's game time.
Newt.
Seal the door. Hurry!
Come on! Come on! Come on! Get back!
Work fast.
Cover your eyes, Newt. Don't look at the light.
Movement. Signal's clean.
Range, Twenty meters.
They found a way in, something we missed.
We didn't miss anything.
Eighteen, Seventeen meters.
Something under the floor, not in the plans. I don't know.
- Fifteen meters. - Ripley!
- Definitely inside the barricades. - Let's go.
- Thirteen meters. - That's right outside the door.
- Hicks, Vasquez, get back! - Man, this is a big fucking signal.
- How you doing, Vasquez? Talk to me. - Almost there.
That's it.
Twelve meters. Eleven.
- Ten. - Then they're right on us.
- Nine meters. - Remember... short, controlled bursts.
Eight meters.
Seven.
- Six. - It can't be. That's inside the room.
- It's reading right, man. Look! - Well, you're not reading it right.
Five meters, man. Four. What the hell?
- Oh, my God. Oh, sh... - Give me the light.
There they go! Over there! Get them!
Come on! Come on! Get 'em!
Do something, Gorman!
- Get them! Look out! - There's more of them! There's more of them!
Medical! Get to Medical! Do it! Now!
Hudson, look out! Look out!
Now!
Burke!
Open this door!
Burke! Open it!
Come on let's go! Fall back!
Go!
- Die, motherfucker! - Burke!
Hudson! Hudson!
Motherfucker! Come on! Come on! Come and get it, baby! Come on!
I don't got all day! Come on! Come on! Come on, you bastard!
Come on! You too! Oh, you want some of this?
Fuck you!
Fuck you! Hicks! Hicks!
Hudson!
Come on. Let's go!
It's locked!
- Got it! Let's go! Let's go! - Go! Go!
- Move, Gorman! - Seal it!
Burke! Goddamn you! Open this door!
Get back!
- Hurry up. - Gorman, get out of the way!
- Ripley, this way! - What...
Wait. Get behind me.
Whatever you're gonna do, do it fast!
- Hicks! - Go! Come on. Let's go.
Move!
- Which way is it to the landing field from here? - This way.
Go right.
This way. This way.
- Which way? - Straight ahead and left.
Bishop, do you read me? Come in. Over.
The ship is on its way.
E.T.A., 16 minutes.
Stand by there. We're on our way.
- Which way now? - That way.
- No, wait. This way. - You sure?
Vasquez, move!
- Right up here. It's just up here. - Hicks!
We're almost there.
Newt, wait! Newt!
Vasquez!
Go!
Oh, no!
Newt.
Up there. There's a shortcut across the roof.
Hicks.
You always were an asshole, Gorman.
- Newt! God! - Ripley!
Newt!
Hicks! Hicks, get her! Hurry!
- Hold on, Newt! - I'm slipping!
- Don't let go. - Ripley!
- Hold on. Gotcha! - Help!
I gotcha.
Newt!
No!
Come on. We can find her with this.
- Stay where you are, Newt. - Ripley!
We're coming.
Ripley!
This way.
- She's close. - Newt!
Ripley!
Where are you? Can you hear me?
- Newt! - Here!
- I'm here! - Where?
Newt, are you okay?
We'll have to cut it.
Climb down, honey. We've gotta cut through.
Newt?
Now, don't move. Stay very still.
Okay.
We're almost there. Hang in there, okay?
- Hicks. Hurry. - I know.
- I know! - I mean it!
Newt? Newt, just stay still.
Almost there.
No!
Newt!
No! No!
- Let's go. - No!
No! No! They don't kill you!
They... They don't kill you! They...
She's alive! She's alive!
All right. I believe you. She's alive.
We've got to go. Now!
Go!
- Hicks. - Get it off!
Get it off!
Here.
Go.
Come on. You can make it.
Bishop, how much time?
Plenty. Twenty-six minutes.
- We're not leaving. - We're not?
- Ripley... - I don't wanna hear about it, Bishop. She's alive. There's still time.
In 19 minutes, this area is gonna be a cloud of vapor the size of Nebraska.
- Hicks, don't let him leave. - We ain't going anywhere.
- See you, Hicks. - Dwayne.
It's Dwayne.
Ellen.
Don't be gone long, Ellen.
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel must evacuate immediately.
You now have 15 minutes...
to reach minimum safe distance.
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel must evacuate immediately.
You now have 14 minutes...
to reach minimum safe distance.
Oh.
- Ripley! Ripley! - Newt.
Grab on to me! Hold on!
Let's go!
Behind us!
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel must evacuate immediately.
You now have four minutes...
to reach minimum safe distance.
Come on, goddamn it!
Hold on to me!
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel must evacuate immediately.
You now have two minutes...
to reach minimum safe distance.
No.
Bishop, goddamn you!
Close your eyes, baby.
Look!
Come on! Come on!
Punch it, Bishop!
It's okay. We're okay.
Hey.
We made it.
I knew you'd come.
He's gonna be all right. He's just out.
I had to give him another shot for the pain.
We need a stretcher to carry him up to Medical.
Okay.
I'm sorry if I scared you. That platform was just becoming too unstable.
I had to circle and hope that things didn't get too rough to take you off.
Bishop, you did okay.
- I did? - Oh, yeah.
Go! Move!
No! Here! Here!
Run!
Here!
Get away from her, you bitch!
Come on! Come on!
Ripley!
Bishop!
- Mommy. - Oh, God!
Not bad for a h-human.
Are we gonna sleep all the way home?
- All the way home. - Can I dream?
Yes, honey. I think we both can.
- Sleep tight. - Affirmative.