The Ring of the Fisherman, which bears the official papal seal
Must be destroyed immediately following the pope's death.
The papal apartment is then sealed for 9 days of mourning,
A period known as sede vacante:
The time of the empty throne.
Over the last several days,
Catholic leaders from every corner of the world,
Have flocked to Rome, shocked by the sudden death,
Of this progressive and beloved pope.
Today, in St. Peter's Square,
The faithful pray that there is among them
another leader who can unite their Church
which has been so riven by change and dissent in recent years.
As the body of the pontiff passes by,
We see prayers are being offered by the preferiti,
Favorites among those being considered
To succeed him as the Vicar of Christ.
At the end of the mourning period, the College of Cardinals
Will lock itself behind the doors of the Sistine Chapel
for conclave The process by which they will choose
a new leader for the world's one billion Catholics
who now find their church at a crossroads
its ancient traditions threatened by a modern world.
Attention, control group going online for LHC beam event.
We are powering up.
Attention, Category One personnel:
interlock areas are now restricted.
You pulled us off the power grid, Philippe.
Because you're scaring the hell out of everyone.
The collider was never intended to generate antimatter.
All three canisters are stored under every possible safeguard.
I'm only asking you to wait.
We can't wait. The bulk of the antimatter is generated at start-up.
Put us back online.
Do you want to call the director, or shall I?
ATLAS underground is now in restricted mode.
Vittoria, Vittoria.
Protons are being loaded.
Don't blow us all to heaven.
Please.
Powering on LHC magnets.
Ion source stage in four, three, two...
Start the collision sequence.
Vittoria, what did Philippe want?
They're terrified. He wants us to wait. What do you think?
I think if we don't harvest now, we never will.
Beam-on-beam stability is good. Take your places, people.
ATLAS at CMS, check.
Sending timing trigger now. Collisions imminent.
We have got 10 to the 13th protons per bunch.
Let's hope the heavy ion guys didn't mess up.
Beams at relativistic velocities.
Luminosity monitors operational.
Beamline has no restrictions.
Enable beam capture.
Accelerating the beam.
Stage one, line up.
Magnets to full field.
Load functions to magnets.
Last P is still too high.
Yeah, we got luminosity of 10 to 34.
Inject particle beams.
Filling the LHC.
Collisions are active. We should be back online.
Capture should begin at any moment.
Particles in transition.
Collisions are fixed and running.
LHC injecting protons, beam one.
Lock the feedback systems.
Particles at 99 percent the speed of light.
Colliding stable beams.
Enact injection kicker.
We have a signal on the luminosity monitors.
We have events.
Protons are moving.
We have antimatter.
It's on a scale never seen before.
That's a crate of beer on the way.
Silvano, we've done it.
We're in God's hands now, Vittoria.
I'll be right down.
Silvano.
Oh, God.
Help.
A swim might help your jet lag.
I beg your pardon?
You got bags under your eyes. It's 5 in the morning.
And you're from the Vatican.
Crossed keys under the triregnum.
It's a papal symbol.
Claudio Vincenzi, Corpo della Gendarmeria Vaticano.
Vatican police?
I was expecting another letter.
My request for access to your archives.
Shouldn't you be in Rome?
A kind of busy time for you guys, isn't it?
In fact, I was in New York, detailed to the U.N.
I receive a phone call in the middle of the night:
"Find Professor Robert Langdon.
A matter of great urgency."
They said to show you this.
The Illuminati? They disappeared hundreds of years ago.
Did they? Look at that again.
It's an ambigram.
It's the same image forward and backward.
Now, that's common for a symbol, like a yin and yang or a swastika
But that's a word.
That Illuminati ambigramatic symbol
Has been considered a myth for 400 years.
Supposedly, in the 16th century
Some artist created it as a tribute to Galileo's love of symmetry.
It was only gonna be revealed
When the Illuminati had amassed enough power
To resurface and carry out their final goal.
I wrote a book about it.
Which is why you're here.
The Art of the Illuminati by Robert Langdon.
Part One.
Haven't been able to finish Part Two. I'm not allowed access
to your archives.
It's remarkable. Singular.
Someone is trying to make you believe
the Illuminati themselves have returned to Rome.
Right after the death of a pope.
Four cardinals were kidnapped from inside the Vatican
sometime between 3 and 5 a. m. this morning.
Shortly afterward
that document was sent to the Office of the Swiss Guard
along with the threat the cardinals will be publicly executed
one per hour, beginning at 8 p. m. tonight in Rome.
- Conclave. - Was to begin today.
We've postponed its start for a few hours, a story of illness.
There are no suspicions yet.
What do you want from me?
These criminals who sent this ambigram
meant it as a taunt, a provocation.
But Captain Olivetti think if you can use it to learn their identity
perhaps we can stop this abomination.
Why me?
Your expertise. Your erudition.
Your recent involvement with certain Church, shall we say
mysteries.
I wasn't under the impression that episode
had endeared me to the Vatican.
Oh, it didn't.
But it did make you... What's the word?
formidabile.
Formidable.
A Vatican jet is standing by 20 minutes from here.
Will you come with me?
Professore Langdon, you've spent your life
searching for symbols like the one you now hold in your hand.
How much longer are we going to pretend
you have not already decided to come?
If the Illuminati have returned and are in Rome
we will hunt them down and kill them.
The Illuminati did not become violent
until the 17th century. Their name means "the enlightened ones"
They were physicists and mathematicians, astronomers.
They were concerned with the Church's inaccurate teaching
and were dedicated to scientific truth.
But the Vatican didn't like that.
So the church began to... How did you say it?
Oh,"hunt them down and kill them."
Drove them underground.
Into a secret society.
Excuse me.
Comandante Richter assures me the guard
is doing everything humanly possible to find the preferiti.
A long way to say very little.
What if you were to begin in their absence?
They are the four leading candidates.
If they're not present, they're not eligible.
There will be no consensus without them.
Who are we to vote for?
It is as much as sin to offer flattery as to accept it.
May I suggest you at least consider the possibility.
No, no, no. There is no possibility.
I have been chosen Great Elector. I am not eligible.
Camerlengo asks how long we can postpone the opening prayer...
...without making another announcement to the public.
Tell the camerlengo
the cardinal-elect will take every minute required...
...to perform the sacred trust.
No further announcements are necessary.
He'll be concerned about the public dimension.
People will think-
What we tell them to think.
- Professor Langdon. - Yes.
Welcome to Vatican City.
Ernesto Olivetti
inspector general of the Vatican police force.
- My pleasure. - This way, please.
We'll meet in the headquarters of the Swiss Guard.
I thought you were Swiss Guard.
No, la Gendarmeria.
We are responsible for everything inside the Vatican walls...
...with the exception of the security of His Holiness and the Apostolic palace
That is Swiss Guard.
The Roman carabinieri are here as well in an advisory capacity.
So jurisdictionally, this is...
A goddamn nightmare.
Oh, yes, Pope Pius IX's great castration.
- I beg your pardon? - 1857, Pope Pius IX...
...felt the male form would inspire lust.
So he took a hammer and chisel...
...and unmanned hundreds of these statues.
The plaster fig leaves were added later.
Are you anti-Catholic, Professor Langdon?
No. I'm anti-vandalism.
I urge you to guard your tone here.
The Swiss Guard is a calling, not a profession...
and it encourages a certain civiltry.
Commander Richter, the head of the Guard...
...is a deeply spiritual man...
...and he was close to the late pope. Understood?
Look, I don't study symbols
because I consider them unimportant.
Ceremony, traditions, it's how we mark our lives.
I just- I just hope I can help.
So do I.
You were my idea.
Wait here. Please.
Commander?
Commander Richter?
Professor Langdon is here.
Well, we have bigger problems than that now.
Dr. Vetra?
I'm Commander Richter, comandante principale of the Swiss Guard.
Thank you for coming.
Hello.
- Professor Langdon. - Yes.
What a relief, the symbologist is here.
This way, please, Miss Vetra.
The situation has changed.
We received another treat from the kidnapper.
The canister was stolen from our lab around noon yesterday.
The intruder killed my research partner,
Silvano Bentivoglio...
...and mutilated him in order to bypass security.
We use retinal scanners.
They cut out his eye.
Is that our stolen canister, Miss Vetra?
Where is that camera, Number 86?
It's wireless. It too was stolen.
It could be anywhere inside the Vatican.
That canister contains an extremely combustible substance
called antimatter
We need to locate it immediately or evacuate Vatican City.
I'm quite familiar with incendiaries, Miss Vetra.
I've never heard of antimatter being used as such.
Well, it's never been generated in significant quantities before.
It's a way of studying the origins of the universe...
...to try to isolate what some people call "the God particle"
But there are implications for energy research-
"The God particle"?
What we call it isn't important.
It's what gives all matter mass.
The thing without which we could not exist.
You're talking about the moment of creation.
Yes. In a way, I am.
The antimatter is suspended there...
...in an airtight nanocomposite shell with electromagnets in each end.
If it were to fall out of suspension and come in contact with matter...
...say, the bottom of the canister, the two opposing forces...
...would annihilate one another violently.
And what might cause it to fall out of suspension?
The battery going dead.
- Which it will, just before midnight. - What kind of annihilation?
- How violent? - A cataclysmic event.
A blinding explosion equivalent to about five kilotons.
Vatican city will be consumed by light.
Those are the exact words the kidnapper used.
We will destroy your four pillars.
We will brand you preferiti...
...and sacrifice them on the altars of science...
...then bring your church down upon you.
Vatican City will be consumed by light.
A shining star at the end of the Path of Illumination.
It's the ancient Illuminati threat.
Destruction of Vatican city through light.
Four pillars, there's your kidnapped cardinals.
You didn't tell me they were the preferiti
the favorites to be named the next pope.
Play it again.
We will destroy your four pillars.
We will brand you preferiti...
Wait, stop it. Stop it.
"Brand" them.
That's another Illuminati legend.
This one says that there are a set of five brands...
...each one an ambigram.
The first four are the fundamental elements of science:
Earth, air, fire and water.
The fifth, it's a mystery.
Maybe it's this.
He said they'd be killed publicly.
Yes.
Revenge for la purga.
"La purga"?
Oh, jeez, you guys don't even read your own history, do you?
1668, the Church kidnapped four Illuminati scientists...
...and branded each one of them on the chest...
...with the symbol of the cross...
...to purge them of their sins, and they executed them.
Threw their bodies into the street as a warning...
...to others to stop questioning Church rulings on scientific matter.
They radicalized them.
The purga created a darker, more violent Illuminati...
...one bent on retribution.
Look how they intend to finally get it:
Using antimatter, technology, to destroy the Church.
Science obliterates religion.
Is there any more?
and sacrifice them on the altars of science...
...then bring your church down upon you.
Vatican City will be consumed by light.
a shining star at the end of the Path of Illumination.
"Path of Illumination."
I need access to the Vatican archives.
Professor, I don't think this is the appropriate-
Your petition has been denied seven times,
No, no. This has nothing to do with my work. The Path of Illumination...
...is a trail that leads to the Church of the Illumination...
...the place where the Illuminati would meet in secret.
If I can find the segno, the sign that marks the beginning of that path
the four churches along it...
...may be where he intends to murder your cardinals.
One every hour at 8,9,10 and 11.
Then the device explodes at midnight.
If we can figure out the first church and get there before he does...
...maybe we can stop it. But I can't find the start of the path...
...until I get into the archives.
Even if I wanted to help you...
...access to the archives is only by written decree...
...by the curator and the Board of Vatican Librarians.
Or by papal mandate.
Yes, but as you no doubt have heard, the Holy Father is dead.
What about il camerlengo?
The camerlengo is just a priest here, the former pope's chamberlain.
Doesn't the power of the Holy See rest in him during tempe sede vacante?
Fellas, you called me.
His Holiness once told me a pope...
...was a man torn between the real world and the divine.
It seems the real world is upon us tonight.
I'm familiar with Illuminati lore and the legend of the brandings.
La purga is a dark stain on this Church's history.
I'm not surprised this ghost has returned to haunt us.
Comandante, have you begun the search for this explosive device?
Of course, but it could be anywhere.
My primary concern at the moment
is the safety of the cardinals.
The Sistine Chapel is a fortress.
as long as the cardinals are in conclave,
your security concerns...
...are at a minimum.
Devote as many of your resources-
If you're about to suggest a naked-eye search...
...of the entire Vatican City,
I will tell you we do not have the people.
Though I'm not His Holiness,
when you are addressing me...
...you are addressing this office. Do you understand?
Yes, Father.
Good.
You said the image on the screen
was illuminated by artificial light.
Might I suggest methodically cutting power...
...to various sections of the city.
When the image goes dark, you'll have a specific idea...
...of the camera's location.
Dr. Vetra, besides yourself and your research partner...
...who else knew about this antimatter project?
No one but the research ream.
This project was strictly confidential.
But Silvano kept detailed journals.
If he told anyone else...
...about what we were doing, he would have made a note.
Do you have these journals?
I can have them flown here from Geneva in an hour.
Please.
Professor Langdon.
Mr. Langdon, you are correct that
I may grant you access to the archives.
Thank you, Padre.
I said that you were correct that I may, not that I will.
Christianity's most sacred codices are in that archive.
Given your recent entanglement with the Church...
...there is a question I'd like to ask you first...
...in the office of His Holiness.
Do you believe in God, sir?
Father, I simply believe that religion-
I did not ask if you believe what man says about God.
I asked if you believe in God
I'm an academic.
My minds tells me I will never...
...understand God.
And your heart?
Tells me I'm not meant to.
Faith is a gift...
...that I have yet to receive.
Be delicate with our treasures.
The archives are this way.
Professor Langdon.
If this path really leads to
the Church of Illumination...
...that way may be where they've hidden the antimatter.
"A shining star at the end of the path."
Follow the path.
We may find the canister.
Can you deactivate the device?
I can change the batteries...
...as long as we have more than five minutes.
That would give us another 24 hours
to get it safely back to CERN.
Robert Langdon
Vittoria Vetra.
Are you really a symbologist, or was he mocking you?
Well, both. You're a physicist?
Bio-entanglement physics.
Interconnectivity of life system.
Okay.
Your project, it was geared towards energy research?
Eventually, yes.
One speck of antimatter
could power an entire city for a month.
Or tonight, I guess, destroy one.
What are we looking for in the archives?
Abound volume written by Galileo.
Galileo was Illuminati?
Yeah. And an obedient Catholic who didn't think...
...that Church and science were enemies.
...but a different language telling the same story.
He wanted like minds
to find the Church of Illumination...
...but he couldn't exactly advertise its location
so he created a coded path.
Richter has started to turn off the power
of various grids.
It'll be back on in a minute.
Then some unknown Illuminati master
sculpted four statues.
Each one a tribute to one of the fundamental elements...
...earth, air, fire, water...
...and placed the statues out in public
in churches throughout Rome.
Each statue held a clue pointing to the next.
At the end of the path was the Church of Illumination.
If you could find that, you were one of them.
What makes you thinking
he's going to murder in the churches?
The Illuminati called those four churches...
...by the special name L'altare della scienza.
"Sacrifice them on the altars of science," he said.
Exactly.
Oh, wow. Look at this.
Excuse me, signore.
Cardinal Strauss, you've been informed of the situation?
Yeah.
My belief is we should proceed with
the sealing of conclave.
At this late hour? That would be highly unorthodox.
And yet within Church law.
It's my power. I am Great Elector.
The cruelest honor in Christendom.
I have no personal ambitions, Patrick.
Only those I hold for my Church, St. Peter's Church...
...which is under attack at its most vulnerable moment.
And this is not a coincidence.
The Church will not fall in a day.
We must evacuate Vatican City.
Oh, That is exactly what they want.
Publicity and panic.
No, we must not give them oxygen for the media fire.
But the people in St. Peter's Square-
Care deeply about their Church, as we do.
Their faith will sustain them.
Their faith will not protect them from an explosion.
Well...
We are all bound for heaven eventually, are we not?
Spoken like one who has enjoyed
the blessings of a long and full life.
Patrick...
...do not confuse the power
of the office you temporarily hold...
...with your true place here in the Vatican.
You were a favorite of His Holiness...
...but His Holiness is with his father now.
Mea culpa.
Seal the doors.
Extra Omnes.
Hello. This way, please.
Oh, beautiful.
The chambers are hermetic vaults.
Oxygen is kept at lowest possible levels.
It's a partial vacuum inside.
So extended stays are not recommended.
So don't panic if you fell lightheaded at first.
I'll be just outside the door.
Watching you, Mr. Langdon.
By the way, it's normal to feel a little light-headed.
Yeah.
Feels like I'm scuba diving with the wrong mixture.
Take a second. We have time.
Actually, I take that back.
- Is that Mickey Mouse? - Yeah. It's a long story.
Conclave will go on without us.
It must, now of all times.
May God forgive you for what you've done.
Father, if God has issues...
...they won't be with what I've done.
They will be with what I'm about to do.
It was confiscated from the Netherlands...
...by the Vatican just after Galileo died.
I've been petitioning to see it for about 10 years...
...ever since I realized what was in it.
What makes you so sure the segno's there?
The number 503.
I kept seeing it over and over again
in Illuminati letters scribbled in the margins,
sometimes just signed "503."
It's a numeric clue. But to what?
Five?
Well, that's a meaningful number to the Illuminati.
There's the pentagram,
Pythagoras, dozens of other examples in science.
But what about three?
Didn't make sense until I thought,
"What if it's Roman numerals?"
- DIII. - D-three. Galileo's third text.
"Dialogo. Discorso. Diagramma."
Yeah.
Just a few fays with this...
and I could have actually finished my book...
...and sold dozens of copies at the Harvard bookstore.
"IL Diagramma Veritatis."
Diagram of Truth.
I know about Dialogo and Discorsi.
Galileo laid out his theories about
the Earth revolving around the sun.
Yeah, and said
the Earth was not the center of some universe...
...with heaven above, hell below,
as the Church had said.
So they forced him to recant in the second book.
But what was this one?
This is how he got the word out.
This is the truth,
not what the Vatican forced him to write.
Smuggled out of Rome,
printed in Holland on sedge papyrus, see?
That way any scientist caught with a copy
could just throw it in water...
...and Galileo's heresy would dissolve, disappear.
And between that and Vatican burnings...
...it's possible that
this is the only copy that remains.
And if I'm correct...
...the segno is hidden on page number-
Five.
Yeah.
Do you need help with the Latin?
Sure.
Movement of the planets, elliptical orbits, heliocentricity...
Sorry. I don't think there's anything that could be interpreted as a...
Wait, wait, wait.
Do that again.
What is that?
Wait. It's a watermark. And there's a line of text.
Go back.
It's in English.
English? Why English?
English wasn't used in the Vatican.
It was too polluted.
It's free thinking. It was the language of radicals,
like Shakespeare and Chaucer.
Here's another one.
"The path of light is laid a sacred test."
- Will you write this down as I dictate? - Sorry, Professor. No time.
Yeah, yeah. What the hell? Yeah.
Twenty minutes till eight.
- Where are we headed? - Hold on. Hold on.
I'll tell you in a minute. Let me see that page again.
Where did you get that paper?
We borrowed it.
"From Santi's earthly tomb, the demon's hole..."
Are you insane?
"Cross Rome the mystic elements unfold."
"The path of light is laid in a sacred test."
"Let angels guide thee on thy lofty quest."
You removed a document from the Vatican archives?
She did.
"From Santi's earthly tomb..."
- The first marker is at Santi's tomb. - Yeah.
- But who's Santi? - Raphael.
- Raphael? The sculptor? - Yeah. Santi was his last name.
So, the path starts at Raphael's tomb?
Raphael's buried at the Pantheon.
- Isn't the Pantheon a church? - The oldest Catholic church in Rome.
I just pulled a dozen of my best men for this.
- You better be right. - This is one of the busiest spot in all of Rome.
- He'd never get away with it. - The poem implies-
The poem? Unbelievable.
I'm basing this operation
...on an American's interpretation of a 400 year old poem.
The information we have clearly refers to Raphael's tomb
Raphael's tomb is inside that building.
Because the Vatican destroyed
all of the pagan statues in the late 1800s,
If this is the first marker,
Whatever clues were here to lead us are gone by now.
The path is dead.
So, this is it. Your only chance.
Separate approaches.
No closer than two blocks and no uniforms. Three minutes.
I'll need a set of eyes inside.
Excuse me?
Weightlifters in matching suits and earpieces?
They're hardly disguised.
- It's what I have. - Fine. I'll go in.
You don't have communication. You can't carry a walkie talkie.
- Tourists have cell phones. - No, no.
You can't send her in there alone.
All right. I won't.
Don't look so anxious. We're supposed to be married.
Well, maybe we're not getting along today.
Hold my hand.
- But don't crush it. - Sorry. A nervous newlywed.
Ooh. Look, honey. The oculus.
That could be the "demon's hole" in the poem.
Why are the tombs at an angle?
They're facing east to worship the rising sun.
But this is a Christian church.
New religions often adopt the existing customs and holidays
...to make conversion less of a shock.
Like the 25th of December?
It's the pagan celebration of the Unconquered Sun.
...and also makes a handy date for the birth of Christ.
- Let's check the recesses. - Okay.
I'll go to the right. I'll meet you in 180 degrees.
Follow me, please.
Now, the Pantheon, which means 'Temple of all Gods',
...was originally built as a temple to all the gods of ancient Rome...
...in 27 BC.
Although the building is usually credited...
...to Apollodorus of Damascus...
Robert!
It's Raphael's tomb.
- But it's the wrong one. - What are you talking about?
He was moved here in 1759,
...a century after Diagramma was published.
Where was he originally buried?
Urbino, I think. "Santi's earthly tomb."
What could it possibly be? "Santi's earthly tomb."
Damn it! Santi's tomb.
It must mean the chapel that he built.
He's not buried in it. He designed it.
"The demon's hole." It's not that oculus.
It's an undercroft. It's a crypt.
- Are there any questions? - Yes.
Yes.
Did Raphael Santi ever design a chapel with an ossuary annex...
...and an angel figure commissioned by the Catholic church?
I'm sorry. I can only think of one.
One is good.
- Wrong? What do you mean? - It's the Chigi chapel...
...in the Church of Santa Maria del Popolo.
It was once called Capella della Terra,
The Chapel of the Earth.
Earth. The first element. That's it.
- You're certain about the Pantheon? - We have four minutes.
Back to the Vatican. You can't.
if you care at all about your church, you'll listen.
My church?
My church comforts the sick and dying.
My church feeds the hungry.
What does your church do, Mr. Langdon?
That's right. You don't have one.
Take him if you want. I'm done with him.
All right, this makes sense. Look, right in front of the church.
An obelisk. A lofty pyramid.
Egyptian symbol adopted by the Illuminati.
If he's going to kill him, he'll do it here.
Eight o'clock.
Robert.
No. No. Here. It's an Annulus.
Which one is the Chigi Chapel?
It's in one of these apses.
Pyramids in a Catholic church.
This is it. This is the Chigi Chapel.
The Demon's Hole.
But it's askew.
Come here.
Hand me your flashlight.
What's that?
I call as my witness Christ the Lord...
...who will be my judge, that my vote is given...
...to the one before God. I think should be elected.
I elect as the most high pontiff
Dominic Scolamiero.
Eduardo Rossi.
They are voting for themselves to prevent a majority.
They're waiting for the Preferiti to be rescued.
Perhaps we should as well, yes?
Not until the smoke is white...
...will the College of Cardinals have chosen a new Holy Father.
For now, the Vatican seat of ultimate power remains vacant.
Get the body out of there and search the rest of the building.
- Chartrand! - Sir.
Outside a perimeter. Secure but invisible.
No lights, no guns. Nobody knows.
- Understand? - Yes, sir.
I'm calling all off-duty.
No information.
Is it Raphael?
The chapel is Raphael.
But the sculptures are Bernini.
The unknown Illuminati master...
...Bernini?
He worked for the church.
Almost exclusively.
But the Illuminati were infiltrators.
There wasn't a powerful organization they didn't penetrate,
...including the Vatican,
by hiding in plain sight.
Habakkuk and the Angel.
He's the prophet that predicted the annihilation of the earth.
"Let angels guide thee on thy lofty quest."
This is the first marker.
The path is alive.
Southwest.
It was pointing southwest.
Earth, air, fire, water. We're looking for a Bernini sculpture
...having something to do with air.
The second church is somewhere southwest of here.
You're sure this time?
I need a map showing all the churches of Rome.
I could use it now.
All right. The purple layers with these black crosses represent the churches.
But nothing intersects the line until it hits...
Until it hits St. Peter's.
Michelangelo designed St. Peter's
...not Bernini.
Michelangelo designed the Basilica.
Bernini designed St. Peter's Square.
The second marker must be
a statue in St. Peter's Square
It's 10 minutes till 9. Can you go any faster?
Not unless you want the full attention
of the world press.
There was no consensus after the first ballot...
...but Cardinal Baggia, the Italian,
is the odds-on favorite...
There is no new Pope, but it is possible...
...that Cardinal Guidera, the Spaniard,
is the most probable...
It is possible that Cardinal Ebner,
from Germany, is the favorite...
Stem cell research is murder!
You're condemning sick people to die.
Man is not God.
There, another obelisk.
Check the crowd. It's almost 9.
He's gotta be here already.
There must be 100 statues up there.
None of them are angels. Those are all saints.
How in God's name would anyone
create a sculpture about air?
Bas-relief. Of course. It's still a sculpture.
Check the ground. Look at the carvings.
Look for another having something to do with air.
"West Ponente." West wind.
Vittoria!
Here it is.
West wind. An angel blowing out five streaks of air.
This is it.
Get the police!
Call an ambulance!
He's still alive.
His chest. They punctured his lungs.
Clear the square.
"From within your walls to squeeze life from the Bishop."
He's actually claiming responsibility
for the death of His Holiness.
That's ridiculous. He died of a stroke.
It implies the Illuminati murdered him
with his own medication.
What?
Down here.
"With man's solution we stilled his heart.
With his own needle did we pierce his unholy veil."
Did the Holy Father take
any kind of medication by injection?
Tinzaparin.
He had thrombophlebitis.
He took an injection every day. But no one knew that.
Someone knew.
Well, he had health concerns and seizures as well.
But he took steps to make sure
he was watched, for safety.
He didn't want it made public,
so we have no reason to discuss it.
Tinzaparin is lethal in the wrong dosage.
An overdose could cause massive internal bleeding...
...and brain hemorrhages.
It might look like a stroke at first,
but in a few days his body would show signs.
This could easily be examined.
In case you're not aware of it...
...papal autopsy is prohibited by Vatican law.
We're not going to defile His Holiness's body...
...just because his enemies claims-
Why would they send this letter now?
Well, to cause panic.
"The sun will blind at midnight...
...and neither police nor professors can stop it. "
He knows I'm here.
Obviously they were hoping
this letter would become public.
We might be wise to preempt their attempt...
...by making an announcement of our own
to refute this absurd claim.
That's out of the question.
Cardinal Strauss has insisted
this entire matter be kept internal.
He shouldn't be aware of it. He's in conclave.
His final instructions before sealing the doors
were very clear.
Cardinal Strauss does not dictate Vatican protocols.
As you say, yet, technically...
...now that conclave has begun...
...it's his privilege and duty
to control public announcements.
I've drafted a release
about the incident in the piazze...
...but any other statements
are specifically prohibited.
For that, Cardinal has asked me to remind you
we have a chimney.
Commander Richter, the search for the device?
Well, we've turned the power on and off
to about 20 percent of Vatican City.
Nothing on the video yet.
We're running out of options.
How long would you need to evacuate?
If I pull all my men from the search for the bomb,
30 minutes.
Mr. Langdon.
You have been right so far about the path...
...It's now 9:15.
How quickly can you find the next church?
The lined on the carving pointed east,
away from Vatican City.
But there were five of them, so there's room for error.
About 20 churched intersect those lines.
None of them have names that invoke fire.
So a Bernini sculpture must be
inside one of them that does.
We'll need to get into the archives to find it.
- Would you escort Mr. Langdon? - Yes, Father.
Silcano's journals.
The killer's name could be in here. May I stay?
Please. Fine, of course.
Professor.
Would it surprise you to find those clothes suit you?
It would surprise the hell out of me.
The Vatican is expressing sympathy
for the mugging victim...
...a Dusseldorf tourist now confirmed dead...
The Vatican police have a suspect in custody...
The Vatican will allow the crowd
back into St. Peter's Square...
...where security will be doubled...
The Vatican did admit that
where there are crowds, so often follows crime.
We're trying now to
get the name of the tourist who was-
- Oh, wait. - Hand to the right. Keeping panning.
We're getting word now of smoke.
Smoke from the Sistine Chapel chimney.
Apparently there's been another vote.
The smoke is black.
Once again,
the cardinals have failed to reach consensus...
...and the Catholic Church remains without a leader.
What are you looking for now?
Church assets.
I beg your pardon?
Artwork, It's valuable.
Corporations tend to keep track of their holdings.
The Catholic Church is not a corporation,
it's a beacon.
A source of inspiration for one billion
lost and frightened souls.
Sure, I get that. It's also a bank.
Commander Olivetti said
I was not to leave your side this time.
It wasn't me, it was her.
Power is now cut to Zone 73.
No light reaction on the monitor.
Restore power and move on to 74.
What sort of signs?
I'm sorry?
If the Holy Father was given
an overdose of Tinzaparin...
...what signs would his body bear?
Bleeding of the oral mucosa.
His tongue.
Postmortem, the blood congeals and turns
the inside of the mouth black.
Even after 14 days?
It wouldn't show up
until at least a week after his death.
He was very important to me.
Yeah, I understand.
Will you come with me, please?
Signore, would you organize a security team...
...to escort Miss Vetra and myself down to the crypt?
- Yes, sir. - We'll be leaving straightaway.
Do you smoke?
A little bit.
Then you better sit down before you keel over.
And what's all that right here?
What does this say in Italian right here...
...next to the Ecstasy of Saint Teresa? Right here.
"Moved at suggestion of the artist."
"Moved"? To another church.
At the suggestion of Bernini?
I don't know.
Here, Translate all of this for me...
...and I'll buy you a pack of smokes.
I'm looking for a reference to fire.
Fires.
- "Seraphim," meaning "the firey one." - Right.
"His great, golden spear, a point of fire."
Then "woman left completely afire."
Ecstasy of Saint Teresa. Saint Teresa on fire.
So this sculpture was moved to this church?
Why did they shut down the system?
They know we're down here.
If there's no power, there's no oxygen.
- Can we get out? - The door is electronic.
Oh, God.
Well, that's disappointing.
Where are we going?
To see my father.
I don't understand.
I was so orphaned when I was 9 years of age.
A bombing in Ulster.
The UVF protesting the visit of a Catholic archbishop.
The archbishop felt responsible,
and he adopted me the following day.
I was raised by him and by the Church.
He was the wisest man I ever met.
Even when I was young and stubborn,
I wanted to be ordained.
But I was brought up in Italy,
so I also wanted to do my military service.
I wanted to fight.
He told me, "Learn to fly."
So I joined the Aeronautica Militare...
...flew helicopters,
bringing the wounded back to hospital.
He was a great man.
Your father died?
Fourteen days ago.
Command, do you read me?
Power is off. Oxygen is very low.
Come in. Can you read me?
Can you get anything?
No. The wall are lead-lined. There's no signal.
This way.
If the Holy Father was murdered, the implications are profound.
Vatican security is impenetrable.
No one from the outside could have got anywhere near him.
It was someone on the inside.
And we can trust no one.
No light reaction on Zone 97.
Based on the rate the battery is using power...
...the device will detonate just before midnight.
Holy Father...
...when I was young,
You told me the voice in my heart was God's voice.
You said I should follow it, no matter how painful.
Forgive me, please.
Give me strength.
What I do, I do in the name of everything you believe.
Remove the cover.
Did you not hear me?
Signore, by law, we are at your command, but...
One day I will ask your forgiveness
For putting you in this position.
But today I ask your obedience.
Vatican laws are there to protect this church.
And it's in that spirit
That I command you to break one of them now.
God help us.
Santa Maria della Vittoria. Do you know it?
- Yes, I do. - It's the next church.
I think someone just tried to kill me.
I promise you we had no idea...
- He knows I'm here. - Yes.
You heard me ask permission.
You gave me an escort.
We had no idea...
That portions of our white zones were cross-wired with that building.
Commander Richter was extending the search.
If he had known,
He never would have killed the power.
Or there is the other possibility.
Is it conceivable the Illuminati...
...have infiltrated the Swiss Guard?
perhaps.
I wanna speak to the camerlengo.
The camerlengo is unavailable.
He's found evidence that the Holy Father was indeed murdered.
- He is seeking guidance. - From whom?
From God.
- Make an effort, please. - Yeah, yeah.
The journals. Where are they?
Who took the journals from this desk?
Someone is here? What is this?
Signore, this is unacceptable.
For a camerlengo to enter the chapel
Once conclave has begun...
Forgive me. There's been a development.
His Holiness Celestine V was murdered.
Is it so hard to believe it could happen again?
Signori, please a moment.
Please, signori.
Our Church is at war.
We are under attack from an old enemy.
The Illuminati.
They have struck us from within.
Murdering our Holy Father.
And threatening us all
With destruction at the hands of their new god, science.
They call it retribution.
They think it justified.
Because of Church's attacks on men of science in the past.
And it's true.
Since the days of Galileo...
...this Church has tried to slow the relentless march of progress...
...sometimes with misguided means.
But science and religion are not enemies.
There are simply some things...
...that science is just too young to understand.
So the Church pleads,
"Stop. Slow down. Think. Wait."
And for this they call us backward.
But who is more ignorant...
...the man who cannot define lightning...
...or the man does not respect its natural awesome power?
The battle is well underway, signori.
We must defend ourselves.
But what if this time we fight their stealth with openness?
Combat their wicked scheme with simple truth...
...and end this brutish battle once and for all.
We must open the doors,
Tear down the blacken curtains and speak to our flock.
If the outside world could see this Church as I do...
...looking beyond the ritual of these walls...
...they would see a modern miracle.
A brotherhood of imperfect, simple souls...
...who want nothing more than to be voices of compassion...
...in a world spinning out of control.
Signori, I ask...
...I pray... that you break this conclave.
Open the doors... evacuate St. Peter's Square...
...and tell the world the truth.
Oh, my God.
Get him down!
No!
There, there that chain. On that pulley.
This bench!
I'm a cop.
My son...
...God answers all prayers...
...but sometimes his answer is no.
The college will not break conclave.
May I suggest...
...you direct your energies...
...to helping the Swiss Guard find this explosive device...
...if it exists.
And leave Church leadership...
...to its leaders.
Eminence.
There is a growing fear
That without four preferiti...
...a two-thirds majority for any candidate will not be possible.
- Unless. - Speak plainly.
It is recommendation of many...
...that you ask to be removed from your post as Great Elector...
...thereby making yourself eligible... to wear the Ring of Fisherman.
Well... if it is God's will...
...may his will be done.
Signore, are you okay?
Those journals are private property.
I demand you return them.
They're material evidence in a Vatican investigation.
I am an Italian citizen.
My right do not end just because I crossed to the other.
This is not Italy.
It's not even Rome, it's the Vatican.
A country of its own with its own laws.
And when those journals passed the border,
They became my property.
I will give them back to you...
...when I've decided
They contain nothing of value to the investigation.
Do you have something to hide, Commandante Richter?
Do you, Dr. Vetra?
Were it up to me, it would not be this way.
It's a sin to kill with pain.
It's a sin to kill without reason.
Father, they make me a sinner.
Saint Teresa on fire.
Professor Langdon?
- What direction is that? - West, I think.
"Cross Rome the mystic element unfold."
Piazza Barberini is here.
Saint Teresa is here.
Where is the Santa Maria del Popolo?
- Santa Maria del Popolo? - Yes.
Thank you.
St. Peter's is here.
We are here.
A church with water.
Wait, wait, wait.
"Cross Rome."
The poem must mean it literally, cross Rome.
Professor, Commander Richter has ordered me...
...to escort you to the Vatican.
Piazza Navona.
Earth. Air. Fire. Water.
Cross Rome.
Bernini's Four Rivers.
Professor Langdon,
The Vatican insists that I have to take you back.
The Vatican is about to see its fourth cardinal murdered tonight.
Now, look. You can do as they say
And force me back to the Vatican...
...Where we can all mourn his death together.
Or you can show real cops act,
And take me to the Piazza Navona.
Where we still might be able to stop it.
Oh, by all means, let's talk it over.
In 14 minutes, he's gonna be dead.
This way, professor.
Yes, Padre?
At 11:15, if the Church is still in peril...
...give the order to evacuate the cardinals.
But with dignity.
Let them walk out into St. Peter's Square with their heads held high.
I don't want the last image of this Church to be of men...
...sneaking out the back door.
"let angels guide thee..."
There it is.
- There it is. - Professor, I know this fountain.
- There is no angel on it. - The dove. The Angel of Peace.
And it's looking in what direction?
east, I think.
Professor, just wait here.
Stay put.
Good evening, can I help you?
I'm waiting for a doctor.
Come here.
Stay calm, don't shoot.
Hey!
Help!
Somebody help!
Help! Somebody
Cardinal Baggia?
Cardinal Baggia.
Where was he hiding you?
The Church of Illumination. Where is it?
Castel-Castel Sant'Angelo.
Castle of the Angel.
Sir, there's news about Cardinal Baggia.
The cardinal told Langdon he was being held in Castel Sant'Angelo
If Langdon's right, that's where the bomb is.
Send everyone we can spare.
And you?
I'm staying here.
Vittoria.
- You're all right? - I'm all right.
What about you? I just heard about Olivetti on the radio.
I'm all right. I'm okay.
Robert, we can't trust Richter. He took Silvano's journals.
There must be something in there he doesn't want us to see.
The head of the Swiss Guard.
Castel Sant'Angelo. It's close enough
so the wireless signal from that camera...
...could still reach the Vatican.
The Church of Illumination is somewhere here
and your canister is inside it
Come with me.
For 400 years, the Illuminati met right under the Church's nose.
The Vatican used this as a hideout and as a prison for their enemies.
If the explosion happens here, would the blast radius take out the Vatican?
And part of Rome along with it.
Go on.
They're pointing to it. The angels.
The container must be down there. Come on!
Where are they going?
Back to search the outer castle.
No, no. It has to be here!
Robert, it's a dead end.
No, it's not.
See if you can find a flashlight.
All of these stones are rectangular granite.
Except right here. What is this?
It's a pentagram
An eye...
that leads to...
Nowhere.
Robert?
These walls overlap and there's a passageway back here.
Here. Let me have the flashlight.
It's a passageway that leads to the Vatican.
An ancient escape route.
My God.
Here.
Look.
Get on the radio. Get the word out. Conclave remains sealed.
But the Camerlengo gave the order for evacuation at-
I'm countermanding it.
This is it. This is their church.
The canister should be lit by artificial light.
It's not here, Robert.
"A shining star at the end of the path. "It has to be.
It's not here.
- What did the poem say? - Nothing.
Nothing. It's all over.
There was just four lines, each one describing...
There's a fifth brand.
It's not an ambigram. It's just two crossed keys.
- The symbol for the Vatican. - No.
No, the papacy.
They intend to kill him.
Before they destroy the Vatican, they're gonna kill...
...and brand the pope himself.
There is no pope.
Tempe Sede Vacante
The Camerlengo.
- We have to warn him. - Take a step back, please.
Take your cell phone from your pocket.
Throw it in the fire.
Murderer.
You know, when they call me...
...and they all call me...
it is so important to them that
I know that I know that what they ask is the Lord's will.
Or Allah's, Or Yahweh's.
And I suppose they're right.
Because if he was not vengeful,
I would not exist, now, would I?
I've had several chances to eliminate you tonight.
You're still alive because you have no weapon.
...And they didn't ask me to kill you,
But if you pursue me...
...it is another matter.
Be careful.
These are men of God.
The Camerlengo.
- Camerlengo will grant you audience. - Good.
I'd like to see him alone.
That's impossible sir.
No one sees the camerlengo alone.
Have you forgotten who you're working for?
No, sir.
Have you come to make me a martyr?
Here. Here. Here.
- I need to see the Camerlengo. - He is not available.
- I demand to see the Camerlengo. - He is not available.
We'll see about that.
All locked up. Senza chiave. It's a one way portal.
The only entrance is on the other side.
No. Hey!
I don't care who he talks to. He doesn't go into that room.
This is Robert Langdon and Dr. Vetra. Open the door!
Open up!
Open the door!
Hey!
The Camerlengo is in danger.
He's the one. He's got a gun.
- Illuminatus! - You bastard.
- Illuminatus! - Sanctimonious bastard!
Order the evacuation.
We only have 19 minutes
Here. He's...
get the helicopter for the older cardinals.
Yes, sir.
Robert?
The brand, the symbol,
could it have another meaning?
Crossed keys, but those were upside down.
St. Peter.
The first pope...
...was crucified upside down.
- On Vatican Hill. - A few hundred feet below us.
Necropolis. City of the dead.
"Upon this rock, I will build my church."
"Or bring it down upon itself."
The bomb. It's in St. Peter's tomb.
The grid is still cycling.
The power to this section must be down.
It must be here. It must be.
Don't touch it.
We have seven minutes.
Robert, hold this.
It's cold down here, isn't it?
What's wrong?
Cold decreases battery life
We may have less than five minutes.
So?
If I pull the power with less than five minutes...
...the residual charge won't hold suspension.
We should leave it here and get clear if we can.
- At least down here the damage- - No!
- No. Wait! - Father!
We are live here at St. Peter's Square...
where, despite a bomb threat, and an order of evacuation...
...the crowd is actually growing in size As we await an official...
...announcement from the Vatican spokesman...
...as to the exact nature of the threat...
...and whether or not they are treating it as a credible danger.
This way.
A bomb?
Roberto, this is an emergency. I'll take her up alone.
He's got clearance.
Oh, my God.
Get down!
Cardinal Strauss?
It was the Camerlengo. He has saved us all.
He has saved the Church and he's still alive.
Praise God. Praise God.
He is alive.
He sacrificed himself for all of us.
You know the worst thing we thought would happen?
Was that our work would fall into the hands of the energy companies.
We thought we could change the world.
So naive.
No, not naive.
Innocent, maybe.
But it's not a crime.
I'm not so sure.
Go back to work.
Change the world.
A gift, uh, you understand?
Let's say for Catholics everywhere.
The Carmerlengo's age shouldn't reach the decision.
Signori
you are no doubt aware that the Holy Law of that man is ineligible for election to the papacy.
He's not a cardinal. He's a priest.
He's of insufficient age.
Or maybe there's a way we could consider the possibility.
I am sorry. The protocols of conclave are not subject to modification.
I will not call a ballot on this matter.
But, signore, you would not hold a ballot.
Surely, you remember?
You gave up your post as Great Elector.
They are singing at St. Peter's Square.
Now, what happened here tonight transcends our laws.
Has it?
Is it God's will that we give ourselves over to frenzy?
Discard the rules of the Church?
Perhaps we need not discard them.
Signori, I am thinking now of Romano Pontifici Eligendo numero 60...
- Acclamation by Adoration. - Exactly, signore. Exactly.
Yes. If the Holy Spirit speaks through us...
and we call a man's name out loud...
That is election by adoration.
He's God's choice.
Yes. And the candidate need only be an ordained member of the clergy...
present in the Sistine Chapel at the moment of his election.
I think we haven't certain...
Signor Camerlengo?
Yes?
The cardinals ask you to join them in conclave as soon as possible.
Me?
Yes, Padre.
What are you doing?
Silvano's journals. I want them back.
Richter said...
His Holiness suffered from seizures...
and steps were taken...
for safety.
He made sure he was watched he said.
What if he were trying to give me this key?
That's the Papal office.
If the Pope was worried about seizures,
he must've had Richter install cameras without telling anyone.
To keep an eye on him for his safety.
Maybe it records.
I read the journals, Patrick.
The scientist kept journals. So?
You figure prominently in them.
Really?
The Devoli wasn't just a physicist. He was also a Catholic priest.
As such, he was deeply conflicted about the implications of his work
and in need of spiritual guidance.
Like Galileo.
About a month ago... he requested an audience with the Pope.
But you know that.
You soon granted the audience and you were also present during it.
The 'God Particle'.
To actually claim an act of creation. The blasphemy. The arrogance.
The Holy Father didn't see it like that.
He urged him to go public.
His Holiness thought that the discovery
could actually scientifically prove the existence of a divine power.
And begin to bridge the gap between science and religion.
His work was not religious. It was sacrilegious.
But you... You saw the pope's position as a softening of church law.
As an old man's weakness. Your father's weakness.
Your father's weakness.
He raised me to protect this Church... even from within.
Then you conjured up an old enemy from the past. The Illuminati.
You found the ancient brands in the papal vaults and put them to use...
to spread fear!
The Cardinals are men of belief.
Right now, their belief in evil is uniting them.
The entire Catholic world will be united by this attack.
There is no attack.
You're trying to convince the Cardinals they're in a war...
so they will choose a warrior to lead them.
We are at war.
We're weak when we should be strong.
If science is allowed to claim the power of creation...
what is left for God?
It didn't work, Patrick.
- It isn't finished. - Oh, yes, it's finished.
It's finished.
I've shown the journals to Father Simeon.
The moment the doors to the Conclave open...
he will tell the Cardinals what you've done.
I was planning on doing this alone.
Put it down.
But, perhaps, it's better that you're here.
Put it away.
Help. He's the one. He's got a gun.
- Illuminatus. - You bastard.
- Illuminatus! - You bastard!
Padre.
And get the helicopter for the older cardinals, right?
I've been summoned by the College of Cardinals.
Gently.
But within our walls.
He's on your side.
Father, into their hands I commend my spirit.
Church sources now confirm that
Carmelengo, Father Patrick McKenna
has died of internal injuries sustained in his heroic fall...
The Catholic church thanks Camerlengo
for his selfless act and demands his immediate canonization.
The Vatican has also confirmed the deaths of three Cardinals
and the fire in the Santa Maria della Vittoria.
As we await the appearance of the new Holy Father
Cardinal Baggia of Italy...
one of the four original Preferiti...
who, despite terrorist attempts at disruption...
seems to have been selected in one of the swiftest and smoothest conclaves
in modern church history.
Professor Langdon? Please.
A token of thanks from His Holiness...
and from his new Camerlengo.
We are grateful you saved his life.
And it's our understanding that you require this text...
to complete your scholary work.
We ask only that in your last grand testament...
you ensure
it finds its way home.
Of course.
And when you write of us...
and you will write of us...
may I ask one thing?
Do so gently.
I'll try.
Religion is flawed...
but only because man is flawed.
All men, including this one.
He chose the name Luke.
There's been many Marks and Johns.
Never a Luke.
It said he was a doctor.
It's quite a message. Science and faith, all in one.
The world is in need of both.
You'll counsel him wisely.
I'm an old man. I'll counsel him briefly.
Mr. Langdon.
Thanks be to God for sending someone to protect this church.
I don't believe He sent me, Father.
Oh, my son.
Of course He did.