Hello!
Chuck Farnsworth? I'm Axel Bates.
You're also on with my partners, Anders, Bradley and Zeke.
Oh, my God. Thank you so much for calling me back!
I understand your daughter, Brooke, was taken 24 hours ago
on a business trip with your oil company in Mexico.
Yes!
I'll pay you guys whatever you want.
You just bring my baby girl home alive.
I... I can't see anything.
Brooke, I'm Cal. We're here to take you home.
Lean forward. I'm gonna cut you loose.
It's okay. It's okay.
Stand up.
Grab my vest. Don't let go.
Clear!
Zeke, get ready to go.
- Where's Axel and Bradley? - They're right behind us.
I'm hit.
I got you, brother.
Get in the van!
Bradley, drive!
Where's Zeke?
Axel, no!
Drive!
What's happening?
Where's Axel?
We gotta go back to get him. We can't!
I'm sorry, brother.
Could have saved you the trip. I'm still retired.
Well, so am I.
You just come all the way up here to say hi?
A guy's not allowed to come check in on his favorite cousin from time to time?
You up for a beer? I got a couple.
Oh, yeah. Love one.
Pretty out here.
Quiet.
Just the way I like it. Thank you.
Ever talk to Anders?
No. Last I heard, he was beach hopping in Thailand.
That was last spring though.
Right. That's what I'd heard too.
The number I had for him, there's no answer.
I was trying to invite him to my wedding.
Getting married?
I am, if you can believe that.
Uh, cheers to that.
Thank you.
Who's the unlucky lady? Anyone I know?
You do.
Remember Brooke?
The Brooke from...
That's the one.
Fuck.
Uh, but, uh, congrats.
I guess losing Axel and Zeke wasn't for nothing.
Yeah.
It was rough, but they knew what they were getting into.
They knew the risks of the job.
Yeah.
We all did.
I want you to be my best man.
What do you say?
Yeah. I'll be there for you.
Thanks.
Oh, my God. There's my baby.
Dad! There's my girl.
Look at you.
Dad. It's so good to see you.
So good.
You have time to call this off, right?
The heart wants what the heart wants.
Didn't your heart want it four times?
Okay. Where's Cal?
He's parking the car and bringing the bags in.
I see you still have your entourage.
Yeah.
After what happened to you, you think I'm gonna leave home without them?
You shouldn't either.
I have Cal.
And that's a long way from here.
Unfortunately, people still know I've got money.
Yeah, 'cause you don't hide it.
Nothing but the best for my baby girl, right? I mean...
I thought I was your baby girl.
Oh, you almost look as good as me.
This weekend's about your sister.
Hi, Daddy. Hey, baby doll.
Welcome, everyone. I hope you all had a pleasant journey in.
Yes, we did. Thank you. Oh, wonderful.
The rest of the hotel guests are checking out,
which means you and your wedding party will have the entire resort to yourselves
for the remainder of the weekend.
Seriously, Dad? Nothing but the best.
Is there any cell service here?
Uh, actually, you'll find that a few days out here is like taking a walk back in time.
That's why presidents and dignitaries from around the world
not only enjoy our seclusion and accommodations,
but also come back for repeat visits.
So there's no cell service?
No. But we do have Wi-Fi and plenty of beautiful mountain views.
Make no mistake, this is a weekend that you and your guests will never forget.
If you'll follow me, I'll give you a tour.
Go on over here. That's okay.
Now, as you can see, we're surrounded by pristine wilderness.
We have a 36-hole golf course,
15 miles of beautiful hiking trails.
We also have a spa on the grounds. Every treatment imaginable.
What celebrities visited here?
Oh, I'm not able to disclose exactly who...
Guess I found the right place.
Bradley, hey. Hey.
I'm so glad you're here.
Ah, wouldn't miss it.
Uh...
You could have almost gotten married at my place in the mountains.
I don't have a lake like that though.
Oh, this is gorgeous.
Hey, my dad's here. You wanna come say hi?
Yeah. I suppose I should.
Over here is our five-star restaurant,
which will be hosting your rehearsal dinner later this evening.
Yes!
This is where your ceremony is gonna be.
Sorry. Chuck, good to see you again.
Bradley, good to see you.
Especially on better circumstances, you know?
Right. Give me just a minute.
Let me finish right here, and I'll be back.
Thanks.
Oh, this is my sister.
Uh, Hailey, right? And the maid of honor.
Bradley. The best man.
Nice to meet you.
You too.
You've exceeded all my expectations.
Wonderful. Well, I'll make sure our staff has everything set up beautifully
for the big celebration in the morning.
Now, if you'll all follow me, we'll head to the casino.
It's great.
All right. We got slots, table games, you know, fun for the whole family.
And I know it looks busy right now, but like I said,
this entire casino will be completely empty
and only available to you and your guests later today and throughout the weekend.
Somebody was telling me this place had a safe room.
Oh, um, yeah, we do. I'd like to see it.
Oh, no. It's really nothing you would ever need.
Where is it?
Um, yes, sir. Yeah. It's right this way.
You know, I'm out there in the lobby,
and I'm listening to this good-lookin' woman
talk about this big, tall, handsome blond guy
she saw sittin' all alone at the bar.
And as I listen to her describe the guy, I think to myself,
"I bet I know him."
And I do.
You didn't take the tour?
No. I'm... taking the tour of bourbon country.
I see that. It's great to see you, brother.
Good to see you too. Hey.
I wasn't sure you'd make it.
Hell, I wasn't even sure I had the right number.
Yeah, look, I... I still check my messages once in a while. It's...
In some countries, it's harder than others, you know?
Retirement looks good on you.
It does. Sun, sand.
Right.
Women. Well, you know.
There you have it. Uh, Thailand.
Ma'am, I'll do the same, please.
Thank you.
Thanks for coming.
I mean it.
Cheers.
Been kind of a long, hard road, hasn't it, buddy?
Yeah.
Yeah, remember...
Remember that time in Afghanistan
we got cut into that bottle of confiscated grappa?
I thought my fuckin' teeth were gonna fall out from that stuff.
Well, you became a man that day. Bullshit!
I... I think I'd earned my stripes well before that night.
Stuck in the sand, drunk.
It was an impossible situation.
Next morning, we...
did what we had to do.
Yeah.
That, I wouldn't mind forgettin'.
That's why I drink to pass out.
Helps me to forget, I guess.
I guess Brooke's my vice now.
We kind of help each other get through the hard times together.
Mmm.
Well, in that case, if Brooke is your vice,
then this is my Brooke.
Cheers. Congrats.
Missed you. Missed you too.
All right, follow me this way.
This is where we, uh, make all the magic happen.
Don't mind the mess.
So our, uh, staff cafeteria is back that way,
and the admin offices are at the end of the hall.
Yeah. Well, you know, that's cool, but I just wanna see the safe room.
Ah, yes, well, it's actually, um... kind of doubles as two rooms.
It's our high-tech security room and it acts as a safe room,
which we have been fortunate enough to never have had to use.
All right. Now, there are two ways in.
One is typing in the code that only our security team and myself know.
The other is through the security guard, who's always stationed inside.
They monitor the entire resort at all times.
Then open the door.
Yeah.
Right this way.
Now, our monitors are back here in the cage.
Please don't touch anything.
All right. Come on in, guys.
So these cameras just capture everything. It's all state-of-the-art.
If somebody drops a quarter on the ground,
we can zoom in and tell you what year it was printed.
No.
What? Absolutely not.
Yeah, that guy was a real prick. We all wanted to kill him.
Too bad he was a colonel. Right.
No, lieutenant colonel.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, he was from Connecticut.
There's my handsome man.
Hey. Well, wait, wait, wait.
That's what you're marrying? This guy?
Thanks for coming, Anders.
Yeah. I, uh, know it means a lot to this guy.
That's great.
Yeah, it's great. All right. Well, you guys, um, have fun.
I didn't interrupt anything, did I? No, no.
Just, uh, takes a little while to get to know him.
That's all.
Let's go cruise around. Yes.
Oh.
How you feeling, baby?
Me? I'm pretty good.
I was honestly, I think, more nervous couple of months ago.
Now I'm just excited.
I think that's 'cause of how much I love you.
This is why I make all the big decisions.
Damn right.
Okay, let's make a promise.
For our first anniversary, we go someplace tropical, right?
Where you can actually play golf outside.
I just wonder if I might have made a mistake.
Excuse me?
You think I should have made Anders my best man?
Come on, honey.
We talked about this. Get it out of your head.
This weekend is about us.
You're right. You're right. Hmm?
But, hey,
if anything ever happens to me,
he'll be there to protect you.
I like you.
All right. Let's see it. Okay.
You've had a couple of lessons.
Okay, wait. Okay.
Ready? Step one.
And... batter up.
This?
Yeah, that's good for baseball, but for golf, not so great.
Why...
Feel like a club pro here. Yep.
Okay, Miss Farnsworth, soon-to-be Gray.
You just get in there.
Getting the grip.
Put that left hand down like that.
Cover it up with your right hand.
Bring it back slowly, and then...
Uh, I'm sorry. I thought this was a golf lesson.
Ma'am, I don't know what came over me. I-I apologize.
Uh, here's what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna give you the lesson for free as long as you don't tell my boss.
Okay, let's see a good swing now.
Concentrate. Okay.
My man. Good to see you.
Wonderful.
Yes?
All right. Now, look...
I'm gonna give you some advice, not that you're asking for it.
Have fun. Have a great weekend, but be careful, you know.
She'll break your heart.
Got it.
Mind if I play a bit?
Relax.
All right.
I always just thought that was a pickup line,
when he said he could play the piano.
Who knew? Not bad.
Oh, no!
You're pretty talented.
Oh, yeah? You think so?
I don't know.
Oh.
One more thing.
Need you to hold on to this for me.
Guard it with your life.
All right? With your life.
I got it.
That is a very big responsibility.
Fancy meeting you here.
So, what's your deal?
You and Cal.
Oh, uh, cousins.
Our moms are sisters.
Huh.
You two don't have a lot of family.
Are any of your relatives joining?
No.
Probably better that way. We're...
Well, our family is more likely to be the help than the ones getting help.
Guess you could say we're low-key.
I like low-key.
Do you, though?
Okay, burn.
Sorry. Cal told me that...
I should, uh, keep my eye on you.
In what way?
I don't know.
So I guess you won't be joining me then.
Too bad.
Mmm.
Shit.
Guess this will do.
Want some?
Fuck it.
Oh, I haven't...
done that since high school.
Why'd you stop?
I just wanna let you know that I was married.
Oh.
Okay.
Was?
She died a couple years ago.
It's the only reason I took the job your dad offered,
'cause I didn't expect to make it back.
I'm sorry to hear that.
But I'm glad you did.
My sister wouldn't be here if you didn't.
We can go back.
What was that?
Shit!
Has it started? Oh, God, they're setting up.
Fuck me! Shit!
Oh, fuck!
Hey, Juan. How's it looking today?
Mighty quiet here.
I could use a lot more days like this. That's for sure.
So, is that, uh... Is that for me?
Oh, uh, yeah. Yeah, the, uh, father of the bride brought in his own Colombian coffee,
so, I thought you'd like a cup.
Thanks.
Ah.
Wow. That's good.
Yeah, bud, real... real Colombian beans, you know.
Nothing but the best for this wedding party.
Well, it don't look like I'm the only one here that could use a drink.
Mind if I join you?
Be my guest.
You know, it's a hell of a place you picked here.
Yeah, it is.
You know, my daughter got married. I didn't even get an invite.
Wow.
Honestly...
if it weren't for you guys, I bet this wedding wouldn't have happened either.
And I appreciate that.
I mean, I really do.
Cal is a great guy.
You know, he might be.
But that sure don't make this day easier.
But that might.
My turn to pour.
Okay.
That's it, my friend. Cheers.
Yes.
Yeah, everything's on schedule.
See you soon.
Keep it together, Dad.
I got it.
Oh, boy.
Just let it come.
Um, I'm gonna...
Thanks. I'll see you. Okay.
Okay. I got you. All right.
Hey.
He'll be okay.
Right here. Chair.
Which one?
Hey, Dad. Dad.
Sit, sit, sit, sit. Calm down.
Go to your seat. What?
Go to your seat.
She's gonna get married, okay? Shh.
You made it.
Viktor, Marshall's putting C-4 on the exits.
Give him cover. No one gets out.
Nobody uses that door.
Clear them out of here.
I see why you got those Michelin stars. Compliments to the chef.
Look, I-I've done everything that you asked, all right? Can I...
Fuck!
Jesus!
Stop.
Stop screaming. Stop it. Sorry.
I know. I know.
Just gotta... internalize it.
Besides, I did you a favor.
You don't want anyone thinking you're in on this, right?
Perhaps I should have waited until you got us into the safe room.
Some people annoy me.
Shrimp cocktail?
Wrap it up. Let's go.
May I have the rings?
The ring.
The ring. Yeah, uh...
Well, where are they?
Uh, they're safe. I got 'em.
Are you kidding me? No.
Just one sec. Shit, shit, shit.
What?
They'll be right back.
How'd a squirrelish fucker like you get in charge of a place like this?
Believe it or not, I'm... I'm actually really good at my job.
I think there's a kitchen staff that might beg to differ.
You... You said nothing about killing the staff.
So I need to give you my plans?
No, no. Here. Here we are. Here we are.
The rest of the employees will give you no problem.
They've all been trained to do...
What the hell are you doing? He... He was knocked out cold!
Now he'll stay that way. It's one less thing to worry about.
Guys, clear him out.
You... You do realize that as soon as you get the power,
the backup generator's just gonna kick on in under a minute.
Yes, Aaron, I do know that.
But it also shuts down the Wi-Fi.
Which can only be restarted by an employee. You.
No Wi-Fi.
No cell service.
No phone lines.
They're shit out of luck.
This isn't my first rodeo.
Oh, my God!
Jesus.
Get into position. Wait for Viktor.
Oh, God!
Shut the fuck up!
We've all been shot before.
Fucking headache.
Oh, God.
What the fuck?
Is that it?
Yeah, man, we're good. Let's make our way to the security room.
Okay, boss. All exits ready to rock and roll. Fantastic.
Viktor. The boys are waiting for you. Why don't you go join 'em?
See if we can crash that wedding, huh?
Hey, Vik.
Do me a favor and save that first kiss for me, huh?
Got it.
All right. What have we got here?
That's the first floor. Yeah.
Second floor. There's the casino.
We're holding there, waiting to go in. Viktor will join.
Well, all right then.
Let's give 'em a surprise. Let's rock and roll, baby!
Where the fuck did I leave this thing?
The pool.
Of course. You coming?
Hey, hey!
Hey, we gotta go. Everybody's waiting. Let's just chill for a second.
No reason to show up all sweaty.
Nobody's going anywhere.
Okay. You're right.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Look at you. You're a mess.
Sorry. I'm usually calmer in these situations.
Don't worry.
CFO of my dad's company. I'm used to chaos.
Chuck sure did make this easy for us, didn't he, renting out this whole place?
Yeah, he did.
You wanna watch some of this? When the fun begins.
No.
Dad.
Hey, you might not feel good, but you're still looking good in the suit.
Everyone, stay calm.
You run, and we'll shoot you.
Get down! Get down.
- Take her. - Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
Come on! Come on! Go, go!
Think your sister's gonna be pissed?
No, she's gonna be fine.
Let's just take the stairs. Come on.
Uh-oh, uh-oh, oh, boss. Check out this one. Okay.
Oh, hey, kids. Anyone tell you Fourth of July is coming early?
Three, two, one.
What was that?
Sounded like a bomb.
What?
Head back to your room. Find cover.
What? Hell, no!
I'm safer with you! Wait!
Get your head down! Get your head down! Stay down!
Everybody, stop!
I'll take the guests to the holding area.
Go see if they need help finding the others.
You got it, boss. Let's go! This way.
Come on. Let's go. Come on. Come on.
I don't wanna leave you. That way. You gotta go.
This way. This way.
Come on.
This way. Come on.
There she is. Oh, yeah.
Let me zoom in on that.
Hello.
Like catching fish without bait. You stay here.
I'll get us our lovely bride. All right.
This is exactly what happened to my sister when she was taken.
Are we gonna be okay?
All right.
Boss says start checking the hotel rooms.
Stay here.
Come on! Come on! Come on!
You're lucky Axel wants you alive.
I'm here to help.
Anyone there?
Hotel security.
I'm here to help.
I'm so scared.
What are we gonna do? There's no "we," all right?
You're gonna stay here, and you're gonna find a place to hide.
What?
Look, they have thousands of security cameras.
They could be watching us right now.
Then we're gonna find you an exit. You're gonna head for the tree line and get help.
I am not going out there alone.
You used to get paid to protect people.
Protect me.
Bradley, please.
Please.
Fuck.
Stay close. Okay.
What happened?
I had him.
Who? Cal.
He do this?
Yes.
Bradley and Anders with him?
No.
Just him and these guys.
He's shit-faced.
Guess if my daughter was marrying that man, I would be too.
Chuck.
You're gonna need some new bodyguards.
These noises are fucking killing my headache.
Let's get him out of here. Go somewhere else.
Got him.
I'll search the exterior,
in case anyone made it out of any windows.
Good. Remember, Cal, Bradley and Anders, alive if you can.
'Cause I'd like to have a little conversation with 'em.
Shut up.
Wake up!
Holy fuck!
Oh, there she is.
Welcome back, buttercup.
What the fuck do you even want?
Daddy? Hailey?
Daddy, where are you?
Don't say another fuckin' word!
Let him go!
No, no. I don't think so.
Hello, Bradley.
No!
- No! - We gotta go.
I'm not leaving him. We gotta go. We got no choice. Come on.
When he dies, this is on you, Bradley!
That man is in need of a killin'.
Hey.
You knew him!
This is all your fault! No. Hey, hey.
Stop. Stop. Hey! Stop. Quiet, quiet.
Hailey, please, quiet, okay?
They're gonna... Who was that?
It was Axel.
I thought you said he was dead.
I thought he was.
If he kills my dad, it's on you.
I just gotta... Hey. Get the fuck off me! Get off me!
Can you keep it down. They're gonna find us. Fuck.
Hey.
My-My-My dad has a phone.
He has a satellite phone.
What do you mean, he's... His room.
Come on.
Hi, Chuck.
You know who I am?
We've never had the pleasure of meeting in person,
but we have spoken on the phone a few times.
I talk to a lot of fuckin' people.
Does the name Axel Bates ring a bell?
You're a dead man.
Well,
death certainly would have been merciful.
But instead, I was picked up by those friendly folk
who kidnapped your daughter.
Tortured me for a couple of months.
Unfortunately for them,
they just got a little too comfortable with me.
So they're gone.
And here I am with a fresh, new perspective on life.
Let me tell you something, you son of a bitch.
All I wanted was to get my daughter back.
What about Zeke?
He was someone's kid.
And he has a daughter.
Zoey is five years old right now.
And guess what, Chuck? Her daddy ain't ever comin' home.
So let me ask you:
Is Brooke's life more valuable than Zeke?
No!
Goddamn right.
No, you didn't...
No. No!
It's okay. Come on.
Put some pressure on it.
That was the first place I was shot.
That's the second.
And it left me with a hell of a headache.
You wanna see what it feels like? No, no, no, no. No.
I'll do whatever.
Good.
Because you offered us five million dollars to bring your daughter home.
I want my share.
Is that what you want?
You want a million bucks?
I'll make it happen. No.
No, no.
What are both your daughters' lives worth to you?
Two times? Three?
I don't have that kind of money.
Fine.
No! Oh, no!
Oh, shit.
You want five million dollars?
I'll give you five million dollars.
That's not enough for what I went through.
7.5.
But I promise you, that's all I can get out.
Okay.
I can live with that.
I don't begrudge you for what you did, Chuck.
Any father with your means would have done the exact same thing.
But Cal, Bradley, Anders,
they made their choice.
And now it's time for their reckoning.
Listen. Now, I don't care.
Just don't hurt my daughters.
You do what you say you're gonna do,
you have my word.
You fuck with me, I'm gonna kill everyone in here.
And then I'm gonna make you watch while I kill your daughters.
Got it?
Got it.
I got it.
Hey, gang.
Pay close attention now.
We have, uh, five wedding members currently roaming the hallways.
Ooh, get this. In the kitchen,
yeah, we have the lovely bride-to-be, Brooke.
I think that she is with a blast from the past, Anders.
Asshole.
And that's not all, gang.
And we have the bride's sister, Hailey, maid of honor.
Yep. On the third-floor suite.
And she's with the best man, Bradley.
But watch out, Bradley's got a gun, and it does go bang, bang.
All right.
And then, gang, our number one target, Cal,
the unlucky groom.
Looks like he's heading to the top-floor suites, I believe.
Happy hunting.
We have to go. Wait, wait, wait.
Someone will come. But don't worry, I have a plan.
You need to surrender.
What? Yes.
Put your hands up, stay right here and surrender.
Trust me. I'll handle the rest.
Okay. I'm not leaving you.
Get on your knees!
Where's Anders? No.
Let's go get me my money.
Come on.
Okay. Okay.
Over there. Yeah.
What's this moron doing? Jesus.
Hey, dipshit. Everyone's supposed to go to the restaurant.
Ah, but since you have the lovely bride that-was-to-be,
what do you say we have a little fun, huh?
Fuck you.
I never did like you, Anders.
Fuck you!
It was him or us. Good choice.
Okay, give it to me.
Good. Everything's okay.
One, two...
What are you doing?
One, two, three, four, five.
They're searching the rooms. Five seconds in each room.
I'll be right back. Find that phone.
They're holding the guests hostage in the restaurant.
Where are you going?
Do my job.
Here. Take this.
Now you know how to use it.
Lock the door after I'm gone.
Fuck.
Bradley!
Help!
Don't shoot me. Please, please. Hey!
Help. Please. Please. Please.
Hello, hello. Police?
911. What's your emergency?
Oh! Please! The hotel has been taken over by terrorists.
Please hurry!
Ma'am, the closest police force is 30 minutes away.
You need to hurry! We'll be dead by then!
No!
Oh, God.
Oh, God. Hailey.
Hailey, it's over!
There is no way out of this. They're all dead.
I have nothing to do with this!
Take it up with my boss.
Come back for more?
No weapons, huh?
Don't need one.
Fuck.
No!
Stop!
Bradley!
Cal! Help him!
Help me!
Grab him.
Okay.
Got him? Yeah. Hang in there, baby.
Stay here. You'll be safe. Just stay here.
All right. You're safe. Stay here.
All right, good.
Marshall, open up!
Marshall!
- I need the computer. - Open up.
I need the computer. Open up!
Okay.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God! Oh, my God! Baby, I'm sorry.
Okay, okay. Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Daddy.
Oh, my God!
I'm okay.
You don't tell them. You hear me?
What the fuck?
I'm so sorry.
Open the door.
Open the door!
Open the fucking door! Fuck!
No, no, no, no, no!
Don't open this door!
I'll give you a count of three. One, two...
Don't you open this door.
Daddy! Oh, my ear!
Open the fucking door! Oh, shit!
You okay? I'm okay. Okay. I'm okay.
Oh, God. I'm okay. Shh, shh, okay, Dad.
Got into your account. Need the password.
I can barely hear!
- Hey. Shithead. Password now. - All lowercase!
All lowercase words.
"brooke55...
hailey819."
- Oh, baby. Oh, my God. - It's okay. Come on.
- Goddamn, Chuck. - Okay, okay.
- You might be able to do 7.5? - Okay.
Fuckin' liar.
It's okay.
That's it. Pleasure doing business with you.
Come on, sweetheart. Time to go find your hubby. No! No! No!
No, you're not.
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Help! It's okay.
Okay. Okay.
Help me!
This way.
Help!
Hailey!
Open the door! Hailey!
Open the door!
Daddy, open the door!
Oh, my God. Daddy.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, God.
I'm okay. Keep the pressure on that.
Okay. Okay. Where's Brooke?
Axel took...
Axel took her. My God!
Axel took her.
Oh, my God! I know. Daddy's okay. Daddy, it's okay. It's okay.
Right. Stay here. Stay here. There was nothing...
Keep pressure on the wound. There was nothing I could do!
Daddy! Daddy!
Okay, come on. Come on. Okay. I'm okay. I'm okay.
Cal!
I said, shut your fucking mouth.
Jesus.
One shot. I'll follow your lead.
It's Axel. I know.
Axel Bates, you fuckin' rat.
You're a dead man.
No, I've already been dead. Your turn.
Well, lookee here.
We got the band back together.
Hey, Axel. Take it easy. All right? You don't have to do this. Okay?
You're a fuckin' asshole.
And you, Bradley, of all the people, you left me to die.
Hey, hey!
It was my decision to leave you behind. Okay?
I thought you were dead. All right?
Just let 'em go. Okay?
You can kill me. Just let 'em go.
Okay. Drop the fucking gun!
No! No fuckin' way.
Anders, drop the gun.
Drop it, or she's dead. Now!
Hey, drop it, Anders.
Hey. Remember the colonel.
Yeah. Whatever the fuck that is, remember it.
All right. You got me.
There you go.
Why don't you go join 'em?
You, princess, I made a promise to keep you alive.
Guess I'll keep it. Run along, little one.
Ha.
Baby.
It's us.
Bradley! Are you okay?
Hey. I'll be fine.
Hey.
With my life.
Where's that damn manager?
I'll get you a minister. Just don't invite me to the wedding.
Okay.
I love you all.