Stay down!
Don't move!
Yeah!
Mayday! Mayday! This is the Sawyer-Two.
We're under attack by pirates.
Requesting an immediate aid.
They say everybody's good at something.
Me? I talk to fish.
That's how I met my friend, Storm.
He's always there when I need a lift.
Some people think that makes me a joke.
But I don't care. You know why?
'Cause I'm also good at something else.
And that's breaking heads.
Pow! Papa took on all the pirates.
I was like, "Well, the pirates think that.."
Hi-ya!
Papa kicked their butts.
Those chum lickers didn't stand a chance.
Ooh!
Papa kicked their asses and took their names.
Yeah! Come on!
Watch out.
Sorry, Pops. My bad.
Oh, yeah, this is my son, Arthur Jr.
See, four years ago, everything changed.
I met a woman, fell in love, and the next thing I know,
we're getting married and having a kid.
This little guy's the best thing that ever happened to me.
But this kid, he doesn't sleep.
What you got in there, huh?
Okay..
And he never misses.
What the...
And then, I'm up at the crack of dawn
because on top of getting married and having a kid...
...I finally got a job.
That's right. I'm the king of freaking Atlantis.
How did I score that, you asked?
Well, I stopped my brother, Orm,
from attacking the surface world.
And in doing so, I claimed the throne from him.
At first I was all like...
Yeah!
The territorial waters are long held...
But then, as it turned out,
being king wasn't all it was cracked up to be.
It's just meetings all day and politics.
I'm so bored, I don't even know which end of the Brine King
I'm supposed to be looking at half the time.
Whoo!
Yeah! That was awesome!
And if that's not bad enough,
turns out there's this whole Council of Houses thing
that nobody told me about.
Which basically gets to shoot down everything I want to do.
The only thing that makes all the hard work
and sleepless nights worthwhile is hanging with my little man.
Hey! You missed me!
But of course, there are fun parts of the job.
Whoa!
I get to keep the sea safe the best way I know how.
Especially when I get to take down an illegal cage fight or two.
But for everything I get right,
something else gets screwed up.
Ah, fu..
♪ Born to be wild ♪
- Oh, yeah. - Here you go.
Slainte.
So...
he's gonna need a little brother or sister to play with.
He's got a dog.
Hey, I'm serious.
I saw how lonely it was for you growing up.
An only child.
I always regretted I couldn't give you that.
Yeah, well, don't be too hard on yourself.
Turns out I have a brother and he's a total dick bag.
Come on.
Your relationship with Orm isn't how it usually is.
Sure, siblings bicker and fight...
but at the end of the day, they're family.
You should be able to count on them for help.
Yeah, well, I'll still take the dog over him any day.
Hey, look at that.
Holy crap.
Hi, baby boy. Are you talking to the fishies?
Oh, man. Pops, this is blowing my mind.
My whole life I've wanted to share this gift with someone.
Yeah, but you and me, son, we're different.
We're special.
We're connected to the land and the sea.
I can't wait to introduce you to all the majestic creatures on our planet.
And show you how awesome this world can be.
Yeah, you and me.
I cross-referenced the coordinates from Dr. Shin.
Nothing.
Still no sign of Atlantean remnants under the ice.
Looks like he's led us on another wild goose chase.
Every day I don't fix my power suit
is another day Aquaman gets to live.
Check again.
We're close this time. I can feel it.
Expedition log day 463, Dr. Stephen Shin recording.
My quest for Atlantis has brought me to the ends of the earth.
David Kane is losing his patience.
If I don't turn up the Atlantean technology he's looking for soon,
they're probably going to... um...
You know what, let's not even go there.
I'm sure everything will be fine.
Dr. Shin, take a look at this.
Please tell me you found something.
Seismic array is going crazy.
Where's the epicenter?
We're standing on it.
Run!
What just happened? An earthquake?
No. I think it was a piece of ice sheet breaking off.
Come on. Get up.
- I think I broke my ankle! - Come on. Let's go!
Come on, get up. Go, we gotta go! We gotta go!
Come on, we gotta move! Come on!
Please, please. No, no! Help, please! Don't let go!
What the hell happened to you?
There's something back there.
Astounding.
My readings show something's down here.
And it's definitely big enough to be an Atlantean ship.
If it is, we might be able to scavenge the tech you need to fix your suit.
How is this place even possible?
This was all probably solid ice
until we started heating the planet.
Well, thank God for global warming, am I right?
Uh, yeah, that's not exactly a good thing.
The tracks lead down there.
Suit up.
Wait. The tracks lead down there, which means...
the monster's down there.
Okay. I guess we're going down there.
I don't believe this.
It's a structure of some kind.
And there's more buried in the ice.
Here I thought we were just going to find a ship.
- Everyone, fan out and search. - Yes, Sir.
We've stumbled upon something big here, doc.
This has to be a few thousand years old.
Astounding.
Whoa.
Uh...
Ow...
What is this place?
At last, you are here.
Free me from my prison
and I will grant you the strength
to kill the man who murdered your father.
You can't leave him like this!
You ask the sea for mercy.
Get out of here! You need to live
so you can kill that son of a bitch!
You will take from him what he stole from you.
His home will burn
and his kingdom will fall before my legions.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
David. No, David.
David! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
David. David, it's okay.
You're all right.
What the hell is that thing?
...Just unbelievable footage
coming in from all around the world.
Good evening, folks.
In the past five months, we've seen an extraordinary rise in temperatures
reported around the world.
And that has resulted in some of the wildest weather we've ever seen.
Yes, this is thundersnow in Dallas, Texas.
Visibility is near zero...
...and there's more snow expected tonight
than Dallas usually sees in an entire year.
It's only one part of a worldwide weather phenomenon
unlike anything we've ever seen before.
Arthur.
The Council's called for an emergency gathering.
There's been another plague outbreak.
...scientists are at a loss to explain.
But the real question is,
how long will it continue?
And how much hotter is it going to get?
Where did it hit this time?
The Ninth Tride of Atlantis,
and there are now reports of outbreaks
in the Fishermen Kingdom as well.
There haven't been outbreaks like this in centuries.
Why now?
Increased ocean acidity, decreased oxygen levels, toxic algal blooms.
Take your pick.
The surface has been poisoning our atmosphere for over a century.
You can't expect them to care about what happens to us
if they don't even know we exist.
If you want to be a part of the conversation,
we have to take our seat at the table.
It's time for Atlantis to reveal itself to the surface.
Your majesty is well aware of the Council's position on this.
Listen, we can talk to their scientists
and combine our technologies to reverse the damage that they've already done.
And I know this is against our traditions,
but the world is shrinking,
and the old ways aren't gonna protect us anymore.
Times have changed.
Atlantis wants this.
There's a whole generation out there
that don't want to hide anymore.
Have you already forgotten that this plague
killed your own beloved mentor,
and you want to negotiate with them?
We gave your brother war powers and made him Ocean Master for a reason.
If we ever decide to make ourselves known to the surface-dwellers,
it will be to eradicate them, not to co-exist.
Hey, not bad.
Used to take me twice as long to get you to go to sleep.
I don't know how you did it, Pops.
Mera and I have the whole kingdom helping us,
but that little baby boy is still kicking our asses.
And you...
taking care of me, raising me on your own...
You're the real superhero.
- To single parents. - Mmm.
Well, my job was a little less stressful than yours.
Yeah, well, I just plain suck at my job.
Vulko told me to bring the land and the sea together.
The problem is half of Atlantis still wants to destroy the surface.
They won't listen. I can't bring shit together.
Vulko believed in you. Aye.
I know.
I miss him.
Hey.
You can't save them all, son.
You really want to know how I raised you here by myself?
I just kept going.
You celebrate the wins, you mourn the losses.
And you wake up the next day and you do it again.
Sometimes not giving up
is the most heroic thing you can do.
Humans were not made to live at these depths.
Yeah, don't worry about that.
You just remember who built this ship.
I'm more worried about how long ago they built it.
We're coming up on it. Engage stealth mode.
Hey, doc.
You stand ready with that big gun of yours.
Expedition log, day 613.
Kane is off on our most dangerous mission yet.
A three man octobot infiltration team.
It's incredible that these ancient machines we found
still function after all these years.
All I did was retrofit them to our needs.
But they require a very specialized fuel to keep them running.
Kane calls it orichalcum.
I don't know how he knows about this,
but it all started the day he found that trident.
Suddenly, he knows secrets that he couldn't possibly know,
including the only way to obtain this orichalcum
is to steal it from highly-protected storage vaults.
And we're about to hit the most dangerous one of them all.
Okay, you have 15 minutes to get in and out.
No margin for error.
Yeah, this should take you through.
We don't want any confrontation.
David, we can't fight their entire army.
Stay vigilant.
We have no idea what kind of security measures they have down there.
Commencing extraction.
Be careful. It's highly volatile.
Loading barge now.
Stingray, change of plans.
I need an extraction now!
All hands to battle stations.
Astounding.
Attention, unidentified vessel.
You are out of the transit zone.
Doctor, power up the sonic battery.
Illegal border crossing will be met with deadly force.
Now!
Commencing charge.
Border Control, intruder approaching.
Arm hydro cannon and lock target.
Hydro cannon at front border gate locking in on target.
Chargers set to maximum power.
Intruder in sight.
Take them out!
What are you waiting for? Fire!
Sir, Atlantean hostiles are approaching.
Split up. Make your way to the extraction point.
Roger.
They've raided the storage vault.
We can't let them get away.
Don't worry, they won't. I'm on this one.
Hold your fire!
They're cutting through the Night Market.
Watch out for the civilians.
Warning. Warning.
Illegal entrance into hypertube.
Exceeding maximum speed of 600 knots.
Reduce speed immediately.
Oh, shit.
David, we're here at the extraction point.
The orichalcum is onboard and secure. Come on, let's go!
Not yet!
I'm gonna kill me a dead mermaid.
Get away from my wife!
Your wife?
First you steal your brother's throne,
then you steal his woman?
Aquaman, shame on you.
Uh, David, we gotta go.
The entire Atlantean army is headed this way.
If we don't leave now, we're dead.
Twenty degrees port!
Fire the sonic cannon!
Come on, Shin!
Lady Karshon has called
an emergency session of the High Council
to discuss a motion that would strip the throne of its executive power.
The throne is the heart of Atlantis.
Too often now it stands empty,
while our king spends half his time on land.
And now his surface world enemies have followed him home.
This tragedy is merely a taste
of the havoc that will be wrought,
if Atlantis ever becomes known to the surface.
Because if he cannot protect his own family,
how is he supposed to protect us?
He's different now. He's stronger than before.
And he can fight me without the power suit.
And where the hell did he get all the new toys from?
The technology seems ancient,
but we've never seen anything like it.
That weapon he used fires some kind of ultrasonic energy
that disrupts the nervous system.
Do we know what was stolen?
He escaped with a large stockpile of orichalcum.
Am I supposed to know what that is?
Orichalcum is a power source that was used in ancient times.
It emits tremendous amounts of greenhouse gases
that are highly destructive to our planet.
In fact, we almost destroyed the oceans ourselves
before we realized what we were doing.
It can't be disposed of safely, so the remaining stockpile
has been buried in 12 storage vaults deep underground.
We should warn the other places that are storing the stuff.
He's already been there. It's all gone.
We think he's been launching secret raids
for at least five months.
This is just the time he got caught.
Well, this spike in global temperatures
that's causing disasters on the surface
and making the sea dwellers sick happened five months ago.
He's using the stolen orichalcum to heat the planet.
Why would he do that?
I don't know, but I'm gonna find out.
If he is using the orichalcum to heat the planet, we don't have much time.
He is pushing this past the tipping point.
He must be stopped or a global climate meltdown is imminent.
We need to find him,
but he's completely vanished off the radar.
I think I know someone who might be able to help us.
But you're not gonna like it.
Your brother?
Believe me, he's the last person I wanna go begging for help,
but he's dealt with Manta in the past,
and he's the only one who might know how to find him in time.
The Fishermen will never allow you to speak to Orm.
He killed their king.
I wasn't exactly gonna ask for permission.
Arthur, Atlantis cannot extract Orm from an allied nation.
It would be an act of war.
Atlantis isn't gonna do it.
I'm gonna break him out myself.
Arthur, Karshon is looking for a reason to seize war powers.
You will be nothing more than a figurehead if she does that.
My place is out there where I belong,
where I'm actually good at what I do.
I'm tired of nothing ever getting done.
I've got to do this.
If anyone finds out, if you're caught...
it will tear the kingdoms apart.
Then help me not get caught.
Xebelian intelligence has recently learned
that your brother is being held on the surface
in a secret one-of-a-kind underground facility.
They're assuming no sea dweller
would ever dare cross the desert.
And here's a special outfit for you.
What is that, boy's extra medium?
It's supposed to be tight.
The chromatophores change color
and camouflage you for up to a minute,
making you undetectable to most sensors.
They'll never see you coming.
What are we doing for comms?
Open comms are too risky.
I'll be sending a cephalopod with you to act as a messenger.
That's an octopus.
Tactical Operations and Pursuit Operative.
Topo, for short.
Genetically engineered intelligence
for infiltration and espionage.
He also plays a variety of musical instruments.
Just try and lay low when we get in there, okay?
You might be invisible, but your hectocotylus
is starting to smell like warm chum butter.
Aw, Topo, you dumb squid!
God, come on!
Is ink piss?
The prison is guarded by fearsome Deserter remnants.
Death-worshipping ascetics
who survived when the Sahara went dry
by turning to blood for sustenance.
If they catch you, they'll bleed you dry.
When you find Orm, he'll be weak.
They're limiting his water supply...
just enough to keep him alive.
And if you do see Orm,
you tell him that I love him.
You tell him that I think of him every day.
I will.
Look, I know he's family,
but you can't forget who you're dealing with here.
Once you've broken Orm out,
you're not gonna be able to turn your back on him.
You need him, but you can never trust him.
Whoo... You look rough.
What the hell are you doing here?
I'm here to break you out.
Have you lost your mind?
You're the one who put me here.
Eh, why you bringing up old shit?
We'll talk about it later.
You cannot break me out.
There's a treaty with the Fishermen Kingdom.
Look, I gotta stop David Kane from destroying the world.
And you're the only one that can help me.
So you do the math.
Oh, shit.
Come on, Cast Away. Grab Wilson. Let's roll.
Come on. Let's go.
This changes nothing.
Wouldn't have it any other way, little brother.
Do not call me "brother."
Hermanito? Come on.
Come on, Topo, you stupid squid!
Wake up and open the door.
Topo?
The cephalopod?
Trust me, it wasn't my idea.
Topo!
All right, come on.
Wait.
Did you... bring water?
Yeah.
Uh, no, sorry.
I drank it all on the way here.
- What? - Bro, it's hot up there.
Whoa! Easy.
Whoa!
You know how to ride one of these?
Are you kidding?
I don't even know what the hell it is.
- Hyaah! - What?
Yeah!
Whoa.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, no!
All right, the water's right there.
Let's go, skinny jeans.
Yeah. All right.
Good job, little brother. High-five.
No.
All right. Good job.
You know, I got a bunch of king shit to do back in Atlantis
so we should go.
Ahh! Come on, Topo!
This is worse than I could have possibly imagined.
The safety and security of Atlantis is a sacred trust.
No king has allowed the great city wall to be breached
in a hundred generations.
A hundred generations? Really?
How many years is that? I'm bad with geology.
What is that, like, a million years?
Oh? You're calling me one in a million?
How can you make jokes at a time like this?
It's undignified for a king to jest.
Oh, excuse me, Your Highness, if I use comedy
to mask my feelings and deal with stress.
Otherwise, I'd end up looking like you.
A very tight butthole.
Super tight.
You know, if the pressures of leadership are too stressful,
perhaps you should leave
and let someone who knows what they're doing be king.
You know what?
I cannot wait to throw your ass back in prison when this is all over.
You won't have to.
Once I stop David Kane, I'll surrender myself to the Fishermen.
That is my honor to Atlantis.
You're so dramatic.
Whatever. Just help me find this asshole.
Well, my contact will at least know where to look.
What happened to him?
David Kane that I knew was ruthless,
but he wasn't insane.
This guy just put a gun to the world's head and pulled the trigger.
Without even making any demands.
Congratulations, Dr. Shin.
That cannon of yours worked exactly how you said it would.
Well, you found it.
All I did was figure out how it worked.
I didn't think we'd ever actually have to use it on anyone.
Yeah, well, what can I say?
Things don't always go as planned.
But that's what I'm afraid of.
David, this stuff could reshape the entire planet.
Hey, doc.
We are this close to unlocking the greatest power in human history.
Are you really telling me you want to walk away now?
If I said yes, would you let me?
Sure.
You want to see how long you last in that jungle?
Be my guest.
Yeah, I'll stick around.
Yeah.
Welcome to the last frontier.
They scavenged ships from around the world to build this place.
The Sunken Citadel.
It is the one place in the world
where the scum of the land and sea mingle.
It is where people come to disappear.
Wow.
It's an impressive shithole.
How have I never heard of this place before?
It is not meant to be common knowledge.
It's a pirate haven.
Pirates?
Listen, I don't know if you know this about me,
but I'm not too popular with pirates.
Oh, I'm well aware.
Relax. It was the only way to get us both in.
You could've at least given me a heads up.
Would you have gone along with it?
- Hell, no. - Then put a hook in it.
There. That's Kingfish.
He is the one who put me in contact with David Kane.
He brokers deals with pirates, mercenaries, slavers, you name it.
Cool.
I'm gonna go pick a fight.
Just let me handle this.
He's our best shot at finding Manta,
and he's not going to tell us anything if you go in there
flexing your muscles at him.
You're so lucky we didn't grow up together, little brother.
Do not call me "brother."
Well...
This is a bit of a surprise, isn't it?
I didn't realize you'd been released from prison.
It is a recent development.
Outlaws, aren't we all?
We need to find David Kane.
Bad news, I'm afraid.
David Kane is no longer on the market.
Not for sale at any price.
He's solely running as an independent operator.
Where is he holed up now?
In exchange, I offer a favor...
from the King of Atlantis.
You seriously expect me to play footsie with someone
with that kind of blood on their hands?
I don't have hands!
Or feet!
Um...
Listen, if the information checks out good,
I promise you that I won't immediately come back here
and tear this place apart.
That's too bad.
Traditionally, the kings of Atlantis
have turned a blind eye to the Sunken Citadel.
Now, we have to blind it for you.
Fine. Flex your muscles.
Smash his stupid head in!
Boom!
Gotcha, fatback!
Okay! Okay! We can work this out. We can.
Talk.
I don't know where he is, but there have been rumors.
A dormant volcano in the South Pacific,
called "Devil's Deep."
Talk faster.
It's been barren for years.
But travelers say there's a jungle there now.
Navigation gets scrambled as soon as you start to get close.
And if you get too close, you don't come back!
If I was a betting man, and believe me, I am,
I'd say that's where Kane is hiding out.
We got all we needed. Let's go!
♪ Rise up, come Rise up through the fire ♪
Soon you'll be more powerful than he is.
But you're not ready yet,
and you involved him far too soon.
I sense them closing in on us.
Do I seem concerned?
Hmm?
If anything, it's even easier now.
We couldn't have planned it any better than..
Oh. Oh.
Hey.
Uh, I... I just wanted to tell you that the orichalcum furnace
is now running at peak output.
I win.
Topo, go back to Atlantis and give them our coordinates.
You know what'd be amazing right now?
Reinforcements?
Great, big, greasy cheeseburger and a pint of Guinness.
You gotta admit, the food is so much better up here.
I find that hard to believe.
Hold up.
You telling me you never went topside to have a cheeseburger?
- What? - Or a slice of 'za? Pepperoni?
Or a thick, juicy, medium raw steak
with fries and a shake, and you dip it..
Even the words that surface-dwellers give their food
sound disgusting.
You've let your prejudices stop you from enjoying half the world.
You should think about that. It's your loss, dude.
Aw, yeah!
Bet you never had one of these.
- What is it? - It's a cockroach.
- You eat it? - Oh, yeah. Shrimp of the land.
- Mmm. Mmm. - Eh?
That's good. Here, drink this.
Okay, you first.
Are you seeing this?
That's not normal?
Definitely not normal. Ugh.
Let's get out of here.
You see how dangerous the orichalcum can be?
I bet it mutated the flora and fauna in a short amount of time,
turning them... monstrous.
Whoa.
Oh, shit...
Run!
Come on.
Faster!
What the hell are you doing?
I don't know. I'm not used to running.
Just do what I do.
Use your arms, use your legs. Lift them up.
Like this?
- Holy shit. - Yeah!
- Wait up. - Yeah!
Whoa!
We have to jump. We'll survive the fall.
Are you crazy? It's gonna hurt.
What do you wanna do, stay here and fight the hopping demons?
What is that? What does that say?
The writing is ancient Atlantean.
"A true king builds bridges."
What are you doing?
Got any more krill-brained ideas?
See? A true king builds bridges.
That's a metaphor!
Hey! I forgot to tell you.
Mom says she loves you.
She thinks about you all the time.
Why the hell are you telling me this now?
I don't know. I'm just tired of waiting for the right moment.
Come on.
Looks like my metaphor just saved your ass.
Uh, David? I just ran more tests,
and this data is really disturbing.
We have to stop burning the... orichalcum.
David?
Oh.
Okay, doc, you want to know my plan so bad.
Here it is.
I'm gonna kill Aquaman and destroy everything he holds dear.
I'm gonna murder his family and burn his kingdom to ash.
I will avenge my father.
Even if I have to make a deal with the devil to do it.
David, you can't trust the trident.
I never draw this blade unless it's gonna taste blood.
Pray I never show it to you again.
We must be getting close to the radiation source.
We should wait for Atlantis to receive your message.
We can conduct reconnaissance in the meantime.
Yeah. Look, Loki, I'm not asking for your advice on this.
You've already lived up to your end of the deal.
So you can go on back to Azkaban for all I care.
So, what's your plan?
I don't have one, yet. But he came after my wife,
which means I'm gonna pull his tongue out of his butt.
Arthur, you are the king. You cannot let this get personal.
This coming from the guy who turned the entire nation of Atlantis
into his own private ego trip?
My ego?
You're the one who swam through the front gate
and challenged my claim for the throne.
Only because you're trying to destroy the surface world.
If you weren't such an asshole, you'd still be king.
Unbelievable.
Wait, wait! Wait!
You took my throne and you don't even want it?
Are you kidding me? I hate this job.
Only reason I'm doing it is to keep Atlantis from destroying the surface.
And I might even be screwing that up.
You really had no ambition for it?
Absolutely not.
From the day my father found out you existed,
he prepared me for the moment that you would come
and challenge me for the throne.
Wow, that's really sad.
Especially when you think how easily I kicked your ass
with basically no prep time whatsoever.
Roasted.
That is not how it happened.
- That's exactly how it happened. - Mera saved you.
No, she didn't. I kicked your ass.
Nope. She made the little water tornado. I fell in it.
Okay, shut up. I think we're here.
Sleep, aloha.
Come on, let's do this.
Once this is over with,
we should go get some burgers and beers.
- Don't push it. - Tacos and tequila.
I don't even know those words.
- Huh? - Shh!
Hey!
Whoa, brother.
Sasa!
It's an orichalcum furnace.
All that stolen orichalcum.
They're just burning it up.
He's heating the atmosphere on purpose.
This is catastrophic.
This whole place must be heat-shielded to protect it
from the surface's thermal satellites.
Question is, how do we stop 'em?
To take out this reactor,
we would have to crater the entire island.
Get away from there! Now!
This blaster may be ancient, but it was built for killing Atlanteans.
Okay, I am so sorry. I did not mean that.
I just didn't want you to break me in half before I could surrender.
Please take me with you.
Knock him out and then help me hide these bodies.
No, no. Wait, please.
I didn't want any of this.
All I wanted was to see Atlantis with my own eyes.
I thought I could share its wonders with the world.
I'm a scientist, and I just wanted to be taken seriously.
David Kane said he could help me,
but now he won't let me leave.
You expect us to believe you have nothing to do with this?
I know.
I've done things I'm not proud of.
But he would've killed me if I hadn't.
Knock him out.
No.
- Then I'll knock him out. - No!
- What? - No.
Fine!
You can come with us.
Oh... thank you.
But you better start talking. Or I'm gonna give you one sasa!
Okay, okay.
It's the black trident.
It's a direct link to some ancient evil.
It gives Kane great powers and in return..
I hate when that happens.
Stop them!
Whoa!
Ow!
No, no, no, no, no! Not the orichalcum!
You wanna blow us up?
- This stuff blows up? - Yes!
My bad!
Then stop using it!
Just shut up and let me save your ass.
Again.
He's going to fight us without the power suit?
I told you he's stronger now.
He's still just a surface-dweller.
- Bro! - Bah!
I never expected to see you two fighting side by side.
We're making a special exception just for you.
No one hits my brother but me.
I was gonna kill you last, but thanks for dropping by.
You're making this easy.
Yeah!
Come at me, the killer of kings.
Take that island down!
Fire at will!
We've got to get out of here.
Malfunction. Malfunction.
Warning. Warning.
Shin, let's go!
What are you waiting for?
Fire the Goddamn cannon!
I'm sorry to drag you all into this.
But the Fishermen can't think that Atlantis was involved.
Atlantis does not command the armies of Xebel. I do.
And the Brine Kingdom
has not forgotten its debt to you.
You may count on us always.
Something happened to me.
When I touched that black trident.
Why is he even here?
He should be on his way back to prison.
We should hear what he has to say.
I made that mistake once.
That's why I know he can't be trusted.
And he cut off my claw.
This thing took a whole year to grow back.
Look, he wants to stop Manta same as we do.
And just for the record,
the only reason we made it this far is because of him.
I saw the Lost Kingdom.
Mom, I don't know enough about this.
Is that even possible?
All anyone knows for sure is there once was a seventh kingdom
and then one day, just before the fall,
every record of it was stricken from the chronicles.
How do you know what you saw was the Lost Kingdom?
No one even knows what it was called anymore.
It's called Necrus.
And I didn't just see it.
I knew it.
It's almost like I was... remembering it.
Flashes of someone else's memories.
During King Atlan's time,
there were seven united kingdoms of Atlantis.
And the Black City was a curse upon them all.
By exploiting orichalcum,
Necrus rapidly became a superpower unlike any other.
But it came at a terrible price.
Poisoning the land, the sea,
even the mind of the tyrant who ruled Necrus.
Atlan's own brother, Kordax.
Atlan pleaded with him
to stop using it before the world
was irrevocably damaged.
However, Kordax resented Atlan,
thinking his own brother was trying to steal his power.
So, he resorted to dark magic and crafted an instrument of evil.
That black trident.
He transformed his people and himself into monsters...
...to fight Atlantis.
So, the two brothers went to war.
But Atlan defeated Kordax
and imprisoned him and all of Necrus
with a spell cast with his own blood...
...to ensure that Kordax's dark power would never be found.
And that is why Necrus is stricken from the chronicles.
This evil was supposed to remain frozen for eternity.
But David Kane has found it.
And it's slowly possessing him.
But even with the ice cap melting,
Kordax still can't be freed.
Atlan used blood magic to seal Kordax in his prison.
Only Atlan himself could release him.
Manta doesn't need Atlan himself.
Manta needs Atlan's blood.
Blood magic isn't really magic, it's DNA.
The key to Kordax's prison is the royal bloodline itself.
That means he needs blood from either you, me or Arthur.
We're the end of the bloodline.
No, we're not.
...Wildfires would have made headlines across the world,
but now, they're almost a weekly occurrence.
We're witnessing unprecedented weather events across the globe,
and meteorologists are at a loss
to explain this rapid change in climate.
From sweltering heatwaves and droughts,
which are shattering temperature records,
to torrential rains and floodings...
- What is going on? - ...hurricane bearing down
on the East Coast, leaving one million homes without power..
Make that a million and one.
I gotta get the flashlight, bubba.
I'm gonna leave you alive, so he can watch you die.
Dad!
- Tom! - Dad!
Tom!
No! Dad!
Where's Junior?
No!
I'm sorry, son.
Where's Junior?
Manta... took Junior.
- No! - No!
No!
The medics have stabilized his condition.
He will be okay.
We just picked up a signal.
It's faint,
but it's broadcasting on an old Atlantean sonar frequency.
Headed to Antarctica.
- Bring our little one back. - I will.
I've dreamed of this.
The two of you standing together as brothers.
Promise me you will protect each other.
Promise me, Orm.
Go.
Great waves, Nereus.
Your warship is powerful, but it's slower than a sea cow.
I say we ditch all this dead weight and travel light. Hmm?
And what are you gonna do when he turns on that sonic cannon?
Our only chance is to hit him
with total overwhelming force from every direction.
Not with Junior in the crossfire.
What choice do we have?
We have no defense against that cannon.
Well, wait a minute.
So this cannon sends out soundwaves
that messes with our nervous system, right?
That's right. Ultrasonic echoes.
Well, what if we disrupt those echoes
with another soundwave on the same frequency,
but just much, much louder?
You wanna disrupt their disruption?
Well, that's gonna be the easy part.
Take your weapons.
And ready your steeds.
Hmm.
Really doesn't like you, does he?
We made a lot of progress, doc.
They destroyed the furnace before we could finish the job,
but we were damn close.
One well-placed missile should do the trick.
My God, what did we do?
Nothing the world wasn't already doing.
All we did was fast forward things a few years.
The ice hasn't fully melted yet,
but our scanning reveals a weak spot.
Here.
This will lead you straight to Kordax.
Power up the sonic cannon.
Bag the child and suit up.
Yah!
Captain, we have multiple incoming hostiles.
You're too late.
No.
Commence charge.
You've got to be kidding me.
Astounding.
This place is immense. It could be anywhere.
The throne of Necrus is in the heart of the city.
I sense something in the water.
Everyone, light it up.
Didn't you say that Kordax turned his people into an army of monsters?
Yes. I did.
Keep your eyes open.
Well, that'll be easy. Mine don't close.
Everyone stand ready. Something's coming.
Fire at will!
I think this goes all the way through.
My men and I can deal with these worms.
Go now and save the prince.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Come on, you spineless worms!
Bring it on!
Help me!
Give me the child.
You picked the wrong day to grow a spine, doc.
Get behind the portcullis!
We need to close the gate!
Get away from my son!
Your blood will do just fine.
You want blood? Come get it!
Aquaman!
Oh!
You wear my brother's armor, and wield his trident,
but you're only half the man he was.
How pathetic.
Mera!
Go!
Mera...
Run!
Free me from my prison,
and all my power will be yours to wield as you desire.
Kill him, and you will be Ocean Master again!
Well, now this is certainly an improvement.
Powerful, Atlantean body.
And this one hates you more than the other one did.
It's not true. Come on, little brother.
I know you're in there.
Don't you see? You can't win.
Either you kill your brother or you die.
By an Atlan's blood, this magic is broken.
My eternal night is ending.
I'm done fighting your puppets, Kordax.
I'm coming for you.
- Give it to me! - No!
I can end this.
Don't let him take it! Hasn't he taken enough already?
Yield the throne.
It's time for me to reclaim my destiny.
It would be foolish to think he could ever change.
I knew you would do this.
You are the one true king.
Atlantis deserves its one true king.
I am the one true king!
You know, there was a time
when I wanted to meet you more than anything.
Let you know that you weren't alone,
that we were in it together.
Promise me you'll protect each other.
Come on, little brother, let's end this bastard.
I meant what I said when I first met you.
No matter what, you are not alone.
We're in this together.
You are my brother.
Orm.
Let go.
Orm, let it go.
I live again!
I have waited countless centuries in the dark
for this moment.
Shit.
Arthur!
Never.
Arthur, we've gotta go. The magic is broken.
Let's get outta here!
Hurry!
That's right!
Come on, baby! Yeah!
Yeah!
My love.
Hi, baby boy.
Shin.
Thank you.
Astounding.
All here looking intact. That's good. That's good.
Well, I'm not.
My claw got cut off.
Again!
You're one tough crustacean, Your Highness.
Bah!
As far as I'm concerned, your debt is paid.
Not everybody's gonna see it that way though.
It's too bad you went and had yourself killed back there.
Yes.
All this ice.
It'd be impossible to find the body.
Just lay low for a while.
But don't go too far.
I may need to call you up for some advice.
You know, with the whole running the kingdom thing.
Thank you...
brother.
You're not as bad at this as you think.
The people of Atlantis are lucky to have you.
You are everything I was not.
You do the right thing when doing the wrong thing is much easier.
And you're willing to ask for help
even from your worst enemy.
I know it may not feel like
you know what you're doing sometimes, but...
keep trusting your instincts.
If you lead, Atlantis will follow.
After all, a true king builds bridges, right?
I thought that was just a metaphor.
Well, your metaphor might have just saved the world's ass.
We've got breaking news.
We are witnessing history.
A moment the ramifications of which simply...
cannot be overstated.
A first contact...
...with the undersea nation of Atlantis.
An entire civilization hidden for thousands of years
about to be revealed.
I think it's safe to say
the world will never be the same.
The King of Atlantis
has reached out to the United Nations
and will be officially seeking membership.
And is expected to propose a joint effort
to reverse the climate issues.
We are told that this was the result
of weeks of secret negotiations with the United Nations.
We now go live to Ellis Island,
where the first official ambassador from Atlantis
is about to address the United Nations.
I come here today as a representative of two worlds.
The land and the sea.
And I stand here as proof that change is coming to both.
And I'm calling for global unity for a global crisis.
To finally bring harmony between us
and the natural balance of our world.
Atlantis stands ready to help contribute
its science and technology.
And with your knowledge of the air,
and our knowledge of the seas,
together we can write the next chapter in our story,
rather than its ending.
Sometimes it's gonna seem like our differences are too extreme,
but all we have to do is look beneath the surface,
to see that we're all here on this planet
with the same goals and aspirations.
- Even when our customs... - Here you go.
...might seem strange and unfamiliar.
Beer and a cheeseburger.
Extra greasy like you asked for.
And by overcoming our prejudices,
we'll become stronger and learn more about ourselves.
We can seize this moment to create a better more hopeful future,
for our children, and our families.
My name is Arthur Curry.
I'm the rightful sovereign of the undersea nation of Atlantis.
I'm a father, a brother,
a warrior and a friend.
I'm the King of Atlantis.
I am Aquaman.
♪ Get your motor runnin' ♪
♪ Head out on the highway ♪
♪ Looking for adventure ♪
♪ In whatever comes our way ♪
♪ Yeah, darlin' Go and make it happen ♪
♪ Take the world In a love embrace ♪
♪ Fire all of your guns At once ♪
♪ And explode into space ♪
♪ Space, space ♪
♪ I like smoke and lightnin' ♪
♪ Heavy metal thunder ♪
♪ Racing with the wind ♪
♪ And the feeling That I'm under ♪
♪ Yeah, darlin' Go and make it happen ♪
♪ Take the world In a love embrace ♪
♪ Fire all of your guns At once ♪
♪ And explode into space ♪
♪ Like a true nature's child ♪
♪ We were born Born to be wild ♪
♪ We can climb so high ♪
♪ I never wanna die ♪
♪ Born to be wild ♪
♪ Get your motor runnin' ♪
♪ Head out on the highway ♪
♪ Looking for adventure ♪
♪ In whatever comes our way ♪
♪ Yeah, darlin' Go and make it happen ♪
♪ Take the world In a love embrace ♪
♪ Fire all of your guns At once ♪
♪ And explode into space ♪
♪ Like a true nature's child ♪
♪ We were born Born to be wild ♪
♪ We can climb so high ♪
♪ I never wanna die ♪
♪ Born to be wild ♪
Mmm.
♪ When your fire burns out ♪
♪ Shine a light Through the clouds ♪
♪ When you need a friend ♪
♪ If you sink or swim I'll follow you off Of the deep end ♪
♪ I'll follow you off Of the deep end ♪
♪ Sink or swim I'll follow you off of the ♪
♪ Pressure cooker Everybody's watching Your every move ♪
♪ Every move ♪
♪ You're claustrophobic Fear the future Fear for your every move ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Stuck in your personal hell ♪
♪ I'll meet you down there Myself ♪
♪ When your fire burns out ♪
♪ Shine a light Through the clouds ♪
♪ When you need a friend ♪
♪ If you sink or swim I'll follow you off Of the deep end ♪
♪ I'll follow you off Of the deep end ♪
♪ Sink or swim I'll follow you off of the.. ♪
♪ Fight the fever Tryna burn out the darkness ♪
♪ Whatever it takes Whatever it takes ♪
♪ Head underwater You can ride out the wave ♪
♪ Until it breaks Whatever it takes ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Stuck in your personal hell ♪
♪ I'll meet you down there Myself ♪
♪ When your fire burns out ♪
♪ Shine a light Through the clouds ♪
♪ When you need a friend ♪
♪ If you sink or swim I'll follow you off Of the deep end ♪
♪ I'll follow you off Of the deep end ♪
♪ Sink or swim I'll follow you off Of the deep end ♪