I used to think this was
the beginning of your story.
Memory is a strange thing.
It doesn't work like I thought it did.
We are so bound by time.
By its order.
It's OK. Come back to me.
Come back to me.
Stick em up!
Are you the sheriff
in this here town?
These are my tickle guns
and I'm gonna getcha!
No.
You want me to chase you?
You better run.
I remember moments in the middle.
I love you.
I hate you!
And this was the end.
Come back to me.
Baby, come back to me.
But, now I'm not so sure I believe
in beginnings and endings.
There are days that define
your story beyond your life.
Like the day they arrived.
Good Morning.
Where is everyone?
Ok. Well let's get started.
Today, we're talking about Portuguese
and why it sounds so different
from the other Romance languages.
The story of Portuguese begins
in the Kingdom of Galicia...
Oh... sorry?
In the Middle Ages,
where language was seen
as an expression of art.
Any news you wanna share?
Dr. Banks can you turn the TV
to a news channel?
Police have already set up
a blockade, here, around the area
And as you can see, we got just
about as close as we can...
but unfortunately,
Montana right now,
is on complete lock down.
The object apparently
touched down 40 minutes ago
just north of I-94.
We're waiting to hear if this is
perhaps an experimental vessel or...
Hold on, it...
I'm learning that more objects
like this have landed
in as many as 8 other
locations around the world
Yes? Henry?
This is from a site in Hokkaido.
This is worldwide.
It is happening right now.
OK, um...
so, class is dismissed.
For now, we're simply asking
for cooperation
while authorities assess the object.
So, you're saying its not ours?
- Do you even know if its from Earth?
- We're still collecting information.
We're coordinating
with other countries.
We're not the only ones to have
one of these in our backyard.
If this is some kind of
peaceful first contact,
why send twelve?
Why not just one?
I don't know, Mom.
I'm watching the same
news report you are.
Well, Mom...
please don't bother
with that channel.
How many times I have to tell you
those people are idiots?
Yeah, well, do I sound nervous?
Ok, exactly. So...
Ahm, me? You know me.
I'm about the same
Mom, I'm fine.
Ok, I'll call you later. Bye.
and at around 8 hours
after landing,
there's still no signs of what
might be called first contact.
Now, the objects measure
at least 1,500 ft. tall...
two more reported to have
penetrated Russian airspace:
one in Siberia and the other
off the coast of the Black Sea,
suspended above the ocean.
So far there are 12 unidentified
objects spread across the globe.
There is no obvious logic
to their locations
and no evidence that the
ships are even occupi...
who entertain the idea that
if it is a kind of vessel,
it may be unmanned.
Regardless, we have a protocol
for scenarios like this.
[Russian news]
After Tuesdays' extraordinary events,
the President this morning, has declared
a state of emergency
with as many as 5,000
National Guard
being deployed to the
state of Montana, alone.
Borders are closed and
flights have been grounded,
stranding millions of travelers.
Panic buying of gas, water and food
continues to escalate
and Federal authorities have
temporarily lifted all caps
on overtime for law enforcement.
The ATF has put a temporary
ban on new gun licenses,
forcing many independent suppliers
of hunting equipment and firearms
to close their doors to the public.
48 hours later and
no further development
Two days...
and already the public expects
us to know the answers.
I'm Colonel G.T. Weber.
We never formally met,
but two years ago,
you did some Farsi translation
for Army Intelligence? - Oh.
You made quick work of those
insurgent videos.
You made quick work of
those insurgents.
You are on the top...
of everyone's list
when it comes to translations.
And you have another
two years in the SSBI,
so you still have
top secret clearance.
That's why I'm in your office
and not in Berkeley.
OK?
I have something I need you
to translate for me.
Why are you here?
Can you understand us?
Where did you come from?
Now you heard it...
what do you make of it?
Is that...?
Yes.
- How many?
- How many what?
H-how many, speaking?
Two.
Assuming, they were not
speaking at the same time.
Are you sure that
they have mouths?
How would you approach
translating this?
You hear any words? Phrases?
I don't... I don't know.
So what can you tell me?
I can tell you that it's impossible
to translate from an audio file.
I would need to be there
to interact with them.
You didn't need that
for the Farsi translation.
I didn't need it because I already
knew the language, but this is...
I know what you're doing.
- Tell me what I'm doing.
- I'm not taking you to Montana.
It's all I can do to keep it
from turning into a tourist site
for everybody who has
a T.S. clearance.
I'm just telling you what
it would take to do this job.
This is not a negotiation.
If I leave here, your chance is gone.
Good day.
Colonel.
You mentioned Berkeley,
are you going to ask Danvers next?
Maybe.
Before you commit to him,
ask him the Sanskrit word for war,
and its translation.
An agreement on sharing scientific
discoveries looks closer tonight
as Russia and China
join talks at the United Nations.
Meanwhile, financial markets
across the world are in crisis
as the Dow Jones Industrial
Average fell over 2,000 points,
in its worst weekly decline in...
- Good Morning.
- Colonel?
'Gavisti'.
He says it means an argument.
- What do you say, it means?
- A desire for more cows.
Pack your bags.
- All right, give me 20 minutes?
- We take off in 10.
Dr. Banks.
Sorry, I couldn't hear
what you were saying.
"Language is the foundation
of civilization.
"It is the glue that holds
the people together.
"It is the first weapon
drawn in a conflict."
Louise, this is Ian Donnelly.
Louise Banks, Ian Donnelly.
- That's quite a greeting!
- Yeah? Well, you wrote it.
Yup.
It's the kind of thing
you write as a preface.
Dazzle them with the basics.
Well, it's great.
- Even if it's wrong.
- It's wrong?
Well, the cornerstone of civilization
isn't language, it's science.
Ian is a theoretical physicist
from Los Alamos.
You'll be reporting to me, but you'll be
working with him, when you're in the shell.
That's what they're calling the UFO.
Priority one: what do they want,
where are they from?
And beyond that,
how did they get here?
Are they capable of faster
than light travel?
Are they planning on...
a list of questions that
I want you to go over.
Starting with a series of
handshake binary sequences...
How about we just talk to them,
before we start throwing
math problems at them?
This is why you're both here.
I'll bring the coffee.
Coffee with some aliens.
- Alright, I want you to take these two
to Dr. Kettler. - Yes sir.
Follow the captain to Medical...
the procedure should
take just a few minutes
and then we'll get started.
They're gonna take
care of your bags.
I'll get your cell phones...
cell phones.
Follow me.
Put these on, you gotta
wear them at all times.
Sir, they're here.
Louise Banks? Ian Donnelly?
When was the last time,
either of you have eaten?
- Last night.
- Same.
When was the last time
you did something stressful?
Does now count?
Just saying.
Who was being
carted off in a med-evac?
Not everyone is able to process
experiences like this.
I'm gonna get some blood
from you
and give you an
immunization dose
that covers a battery
of bacterial threats.
Could you sign these please?
And roll up your sleeves.
- Either of you claustrophobic?
- No. - No.
Currently taking
any medications?
Allergies?
- Pregnant?
- No.
The booster is a kick
to your system,
so you may experience
some side effects:
nausea, dizziness, headaches.
Or ringing in your ears,
like you have tinnitus.
At exactly 112 minutes and 19 seconds
gravity starts to shift
and slides us out of the room.
Have you found a scientific
explanation for it?
- Like, is it for them?
- Oh, no, we think it's for us.
The air doesn't seem to
circulate inside the chamber, so...
after two hours, you run out of oxygen.
It doesn't take 18 hours
to pump fresh air into a room.
Atmosphere.
Excuse me?
If their atmosphere
is different from earth,
It would certainly take hours
to rebalance the O2 content
and pressure, for us, every time
they opened their door.
So you're saying they could
suffocate us if they wanted to?
This is Agent David Halpern, CIA.
- Let me get you two to your stations.
- Yes sir.
Remember, we need answers
as soon as possible.
What they want, where they're from,
why they're here.
This is the priority.
Everyone.
This is Dr. Ian Donnelly,
he'll be running this team, here.
Have they responded to anything?
Shapes, patterns,
numbers, Fibonacci?
We can't tell what they're saying,
when they respond to 'hello', so...
don't get ahead of yourself.
- What have you figured out?
- Just getting started.
Good Morning.
This is Dr. Louise Banks.
- She'll be heading your team.
- Dr. Banks, it's a pleasure
Dr. Banks is taking over the mission
from Dr. Waller.
It's the 15 minute warning.
D'you scuba-dive before?
What kind of radiation exposure
are we walking into?
Nominal, these are just for safety.
So, is there any physical
contact with the...
Am I the only one having
trouble saying, aliens?
There's a wall, like a glass wall.
You can't get to them.
So, what do they look like?
You'll see soon enough,
hurry up.
The suits are clumsy at first,
but, you get used to'em.
Haul up in the second vehicle.
We'll be there in a few minutes.
Make sure you hold onto something.
Every 18 hours, the door
opens up, at the bottom.
That's when we go in.
Yeah, that just happened.
Alright, lets move. Time is wasting.
Ready?
- You ready?
- Let's do it.
Condor, I'm proceeding first
with Captain Marks, over.
Gravity, nominal
in the antechamber, over.
It's all good, sir,
you can proceed.
Stand by.
OK, bring it up.
You OK?
Yeah.
Dr. Banks.
You can do this. C'mon.
I dunno, I...
I think... aah!
Grab her.
Dr. Donnelly, you good?
Yeah.
Holy fuck!
We're gonna go down there,
and you're gonna start your job.
- OK.
Everybody, move out.
Alpha Team in position?
Team's in position.
We're on the move.
Setting up equipment
with telemetry, over
What happens now?
They arrive.
Dr. Banks.
Dr. Banks?
You can start.
Wait, just a minute.
Am I fired?
You're better than the last guy.
That doesn't make me feel
any better.
You both have till 02:00 hours
to figure something out.
OK, what happens, then?
You go back in.
Violence continues to spread
across the US, today
in the wake of the 12 landings.
The President has declared
a mandatory dusk to dawn curfew,
after the crackdown
by the National Guard
failed to prevent a third night
of looting across the country.
In North Dakota, 144 members of
the St. Lawrence Pentecostal cult
are feared dead after they
set their compound ablaze.
Their website claims,
the arrival of the aliens
set in motion a prophecy
that 12 sets of...
Uh, we're up in 15.
You got any new intel?
Yeah, we've been playing back
some of their sounds...
Where does that get you?
Well, they play audio back at us,
from an unseen source.
Audio of what?
It's bits of conversations
from the room,
random clips of dialogue.
Really, we...
We have nothing.
T minus 9 minutes to shell access.
- What's that for?
- A visual aid.
Look, I'm never gonna be able to speak
their words, if they ARE talking.
But they might have some sort of
written language or basis for...
visual communication.
OK. Let's get started.
Human.
I'm human.
- Oh my God.
- Are you getting this?
Yes sir, it's all going
back to base camp.
Louise, its incredible!
Human.
OK...
OK, slow down Louise.
I don't wanna take away from
your success in there,
but Dr. Banks, is this really
the right approach?
Trying to teach them
how to speak and read?
That's gotta take longer.
You're wrong. Its faster.
Everything you do in there,
I have to explain to a
room full of men,
whose first and last question
is, 'how can this be used against us?'
So you're gonna have to
give me more than that.
Kangaroo.
What is that?
In 1770,
Captain James Cook's ship ran
aground off the coast of Australia
and he led a party into the country,
and they met the aboriginal people.
One of the sailors
pointed at the animals
that hop around and
put their babies in their pouch,
and he asked what they were.
And the Aborigines said "kangaroo".
And your point is?
It wasn't till later that they
learned that kangaroo means,
"I don't understand". So...
I need this so that we don't
misinterpret things in there,
otherwise this is gonna take
ten times as long.
I can sell that, for now.
But I need you to submit
your vocabulary words
before the next session.
- Fair.
And remember what happened
to the Aborigines.
A more advanced race,
nearly wiped them out.
- Its a good story.
- Thanks.
Its not true,
but it proves my point.
I think we were able to
reproduce some prime number
sequences back at them.
So, that's something.
Well, congratulations,
you're a parrot.
It's a lot more than that,
you cheeky bastard. Don't you see?
They can't seem to follow our algebra,
but, complex behaviors; that clicks.
Well, that doesn't make
any sense at all, does it?
Problem is, not everyone
shares our policy
of being open with the aliens.
Have you met Gen. Shang?
The call sign for him is
'big domino'.
Whatever Shang does, at least
four other nations'll follow.
- Louise, we have to
gain ground today. - OK.
- You have a vocabulary
list for me? - I do.
You're gonna teach them
your name and Ian's?
Yeah, so that we can learn their names,
if they have names,
and then introduce pronouns later.
These are all grade school words.
Eat, walk.
Help me understand.
No-no-no, not the top!
Ok, this is where
you wanna get to, right?
- That is the question.
- OK.
So, first we need to make sure
that they understand
what a question is, OK?
The nature of a request for
information, along with the response.
Then, we need to clarify
the difference between
a specific 'you'...
and a collective 'you'. Because...
we don't wanna know why
Joe Alien is here,
we want to know why
they all landed.
And purpose requires
an understanding of intent.
We need to find out: do they make
conscious choices?
Or is their motivation
so instinctive
that they don't understand
a 'why question' at all?
And biggest of all we need to have
enough vocabulary with them,
that we understand their answer.
I get it.
Stick to your list.
Just...
don't add anything to it.
Gravity: 0.97.
Oxygen level: 21.4%, over.
Al Moony, setting up equipment
and telemetry, over.
Let's get started.
Louise.
Louise, I am Louise.
What is that?
Is that a new symbol?
I can't tell.
I dunno, I think it's
the symbol for 'human' again.
It just has a little curl on the end.
Maybe they indicate a question.
I dunno.
I dunno, Louise,
I think they're getting confused.
Dr. Banks, perhaps we should
move on to the next word.
Dr. Banks!
- Hey, baby.
- What's going on?
What are you doing?
- I'm fine.
- Are you insane?
They need to see me.
She's taken off her hazmat suit.
Dr. Banks!
- Are you OK?
- You're risking contamination.
- They need to see me.
- Dr. Banks.
- Dr. Banks!
- She's walking toward the screen.
Should we abort?
Request noted.
Stand by for flag order.
Go back to your stations.
Now, that's a proper introduction.
OK.
Louise.
I am Louise.
Ian, you wanna introduce yourself?
Ah, yes...
Louise.
Screw it.
Everybody dies, right?
Sir, Donnelly is taking off
his hazmat suit.
Permission to abort?
Continue the session.
Ian.
Louise.
You?
Who are you?
I think those are their names.
They have names.
So what are we gonna call them?
I dunno.
I was thinking, Abbott and Costello.
Yeah.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, I like it.
I like it.
Wow!
Team one, exit your vehicles
and proceed directly ahead
to the decontamination tent.
Leave your respirator on until
you reach the equipment room.
- All right?
- No.
Team two, exit your vehicles and
continue to the decontamination tent.
Leave your respirators on,
and do not hesitate until
you've reached the equipment room.
- How do you feel?
- Overworked.
I guess, I don't need
to tell you,
you're putting yourself at risk.
There's no signs of radiation
poisoning, yet.
We'll see how your
blood tests look.
- For now, I'm gonna give you
another boost. - OK.
No radiation.
Nothing else we can
detect either.
But I'd give them a strong
cocktail, regardless.
It's the first time we've made
significant progress.
Alright. We'll take the risk.
- OK, honey...
- What is going on?
- Honey...
- Is there anything you can tell me?
- I'm fine.
- You don't need to worry, OK?
- How can I not worry?
Just calm down.
Becky asked me, if the monsters
are going to kill Daddy.
Honey, its not gonna happen.
- Just stay safe.
- You don't need to worry.
Please, I'm so scared.
Here are some of the many things
we don't know about heptopods.
Greek:
Hepta... seven. Pod... foot.
Seven feet... heptopod.
Who are they?
Trying to answer this
in any meaningful way
is hampered by the fact that,
outside of being able to
see them and hear them,
the heptopods leave
absolutely no footprint.
The chemical composition of their
spaceship is unknown.
The shell emits no waste,
no gas, no radiation.
Assuming that the shells
communicate with each other,
they do so without detection.
The air between the shells is untroubled
by sonic emission or light wave.
Are they scientists or tourists?
If they're scientists,
they don't seem to ask
a lot of questions.
Why did they park where they did?
The world's most decorated experts
can't crack that one.
The most plausible theory is that
they chose places on earth
with the lowest incidence of
lightning strikes.
But there are exceptions.
The next most plausible
theory is that
Sheena Easton had a hit song in
each of these sites in 1980.
So, we just don't know.
How do they communicate?
Here, Louise is putting us all to shame.
The first breakthrough was to discover
that there's no correlation
between what a heptopod says,
and what a heptopod writes.
Unlike all written human languages,
their writing is semasiographic.
It conveys meaning,
it doesn't represent sound.
Perhaps they view our form of writing
as a wasted opportunity,
Passing up a second
communications channel.
We have our friends in Pakistan to thank
for their study of how
heptopods write.
Because unlike speech,
a logogram is free of time.
Like their ship or their bodies.
Their written language has no
forward or backward direction.
Linguists call this nonlinear orthography.
Which raises the question:
is this how they think?
Imagine you wanted to write
a sentence using 2 hands,
starting from either side.
You'd have to know each word
you wanted to use,
as well as how much space
they would occupy.
A heptopod can write
a complex sentence
in two seconds, effortlessly.
It's taken us a month
to make the simplest reply.
Next: expanding vocabulary.
Louise thinks it could easily take
another month to be ready for that.
Hey.
- Hey.
- Weber's looking for you.
Yeah, well why do you think
I'm hiding out here?
Come on up.
Nice out here, huh?
Yeah, it's a nice view.
Away from the noise.
You know,
I was just thinking about you.
You approach language like a
mathematician. You know that, right?
I won't take that as a compliment.
Yeah, well it is.
And... I watch you steer us around
these communication traps
that I didn't even know existed.
So, why...
I guess that's why I'm single.
Trust me, you can understand
communication and still end up single.
Oh.
I feel like everything
that happens in there...
comes down to the two of us.
Yeah, it's a good thing,
though, right? You and I?
Have you seen the jokers
that we're working with?
Thank God, I got you.
Tonight, the first photograph
of the aliens goes viral.
"Biological contamination is a major
risk factor at the Montana site".
So, say environmental
pressure groups.
800,000 march on Washington
to protest the government's
handling of the crisis.
All this, and more, special coverage.
First contact with whoever it is
that is inside that thing,
and who do we have running the show?
The government. That's right, folks.
The same government who ruined our
healthcare and bankrupted our military.
Look at these people.
Most of them don't even have guns.
We could be facing
a full scale invasion,
and our President is just
willing to sit back
and let them waltz in
and take our country.
We are falling asleep
at the wheel, people!
You know what I'm talking about,
I know you do.
What if, the smartest thing
we could do, right now,
would be to give them
a show of force?
I'm talking about
a shot across the bow.
I wanna hear what you think.
Caller ♪ 1, you're on the air,
what do you think about all this?
What's this word?
Planet.
Green... planet.
That's lie, um,
the Earth is a planet.
Want to see my project
for Miss. Garrett's class?
Yeah, little nose.
We had to make up our own TV show.
If we had one.
- And who are those two people?
- That's you and Dad.
The show is called:
Mommy and Daddy Talk to Animals.
Ah.
Oh, its lovely.
Ok.
Um...
- You know, it's OK to be sad that
your dad and I... - You know. I'm not.
'Cause we both love you very much.
I know.
It's just a cartoon: not real.
Louise?
You alright?
Yeah.
Yeah, I-I'm fine.
I'm not sure it's something,
I can... I can explain.
When was your last checkup
with Dr. Kettler?
I'm OK.
Gonna get some air.
- I'm OK.
- Alright.
How you feelin'?
I need some sleep, but...
I'm fine.
Yeah?
Y'know, I was doing some reading
about this idea that...
if you immerse yourself into
a foreign language,
that you can actually
rewire your brain.
Yeah, the Sapir–Whorf hypothesis.
It is a theory that...
It is the theory, that,
the language you speak
determines how you think and...
Yeah, it affects how you
see everything. It was...
I'm curious. Are you dreaming
in their language?
I may have had a few
dreams, but I don't...
I don't think that that makes me
unfit to do this job.
- Did you sleep?
- A little.
Do you know Mandarin?
The voice you're about to hear
belongs to China's military chief.
General Shang.
Put it on.
We got a satellite feed, here
who he's talking to, if you want to look.
Wait, go back.
Stop.
He's saying that each of the 12
is offering advanced technology.
Back again... and play.
Our science team is attempting
to decode the sets...
"sets"?
I don't know what that means.
Something about advantage,
suits, honor and flowers.
I don't...
I dunno, that's all.
I don't know what
it means either.
An hour ago, China mobilized forces...
and now Russia is following suit.
Shang is about to start something.
Following same suits...
suits, honor, flowers...
Colonel, those are all
tile sets in Mahjong.
God, are they...?
Are they using a game to converse
with their heptopods?
Maybe, why?
Well, let's say that I taught them
chess instead of English.
Every conversation would be a game,
every idea expressed through opposition.
Victory, defeat: you see the problem?
If all I ever gave you was a hammer...
Everything's a nail.
We need to ask the big question.
Ready or not.
Heptopod's purpose.
Tell me your purpose on Earth.
What is your purpose?
Do we only have Costello?
Ok. There you are.
What does it say?
Offer weapon.
- Well, you saw what they wrote!
- Using a word they don't fully understand.
Enough!
Louise.
We don't know if they understand
the difference between a weapon and a tool.
Our language like our culture is messy
and sometimes one can be both.
And it's quite possible
that they're asking us
to offer them something,
put the other way around.
Like the first part of a trade.
So how do we clarify their intentions
beyond those two words?
I go back in. Right away we go
back in and we clear this up.
- It's more complicated than that.
- How is it more complicated than that?
Colonel, the Secretary of Defense
is on the line for you.
We need to sit on this information
till we know what it means.
So we aren't sharing it with our enemies.
We have to consider the idea
that our visitors are prodding us
to fight among ourselves,
until only one faction prevails.
- There is no evidence of that.
- Sure there is.
Just grab a history book.
The British with India,
the Germans with Rwanda.
They even got a name for it, in Hungary.
(Salami tactics)
Yeah...
We're a world with no single leader.
It's impossible to deal with
just one of us.
And with the word weapon, now...
Halpern...
Yes General.
No confirmation, yet. Stand by.
Anything...
What did they say?
China and Russia are off the grid.
They aren't speaking to anyone.
Whatever they learned in their
last session has them spooked.
Yes sir...
We have orders to do the same.
- Wait these are our allies!
- Put us on radio silence!
Do it.
We received a message
from the hept...
Dammit! We need to be
talking to each other!
You wanna talk to them?
Find out what this means.
Base-camp talk is now offline.
All interpreters...
Don't call Information,
they're offline.
stand down, report to unit coordinators.
We've never re-entered
a session, before.
Louise, trust me OK?
We got time.
Just gotta step on it, alright?
"Use weapon",
This is the alien message,
said to have provoked
the Chinese government to
withdraw their scientists
from the international
mission today.
In a statement, General Shang said:
"China no longer trusts the aliens
who want to divide us.
"Humanity must be protected."
China has asked for immediate
talks at the UN.
Alpha 1-9er, this is Condor, over.
Alpha 1-9er, this is Condor.
Come in, over.
Captain Marks, Condor,
not receiving transmission.
Perhaps they can hear mine.
Captain Marks, all escorters are
ordered to cease all activity.
No-no-no...
Dr. Banks you can't go in there.
- We just need to ask one question.
- Dr. Banks!
The session is finished.
You can't go back in, it's dangerous.
Look, we just need 5 minutes.
Don't sweat it. - Marks, let'em go.
Hey, Abbott.
So, what are we calling this?
Session 37?
Ah, no: 36, Part 2.
Ok.
What do you know?
We've been attempting
to hail Captain Marks.
The escort units are not
responding, sir. - Why not?
Send security.
Offer a weapon... question mark.
Are you offering us something?
Technology, apparatus, method.
Yeah, see, this is
a different word.
This... this segment,
it's a lot busier.
Give... technology...
now.
What's he doing?
Captain, on your 10.
Security detail inbound, sir.
T minus 4 minutes remaining.
We need to see this through.
OK, this is it, lock and load.
- We just need to hold them off
until it's done. - Copy, that.
Free shot, this is forward fire only*.
Load up and get to cover.
Stay fresh and we can
avoid casualties.
Abbott wants me to write
on the barrier.
Can you, even, do that?
I don't know.
I can't do it with both hands.
Louise.
What is that?
Hey!
Hey, hey, take it easy.
You suffered a concussion.
Just lay back.
How do you feel?
- How is Ian?
- Same as you. He's OK.
Who...
Who did this?
Some soldiers.
Been watching too much TV.
- What is that?
- Take it easy, take it easy.
This place is no longer secure.
We're standing by to evacuate.
Where is Ian?
Weber came and got him
maybe 10 minutes ago.
He wouldn't leave until
he knew you were OK.
The whole tent is on the clock to figure
out whatever it is you were given up there.
This is all of it.
The feed wasn't interrupted
by the explosion?
That's right.
- You see something?
- I don't know, yet.
I'm gonna need my team to get
together with Louise's team.
- I need everyone working on this.
- We cannot leave.
- Glad to see you're awake.
- We need to go back in there.
We need to explain to them that
this wasn't our fault.
- We can't go back inside.
- We have to!
What happened in there was
an attack.
We can hope for the best,
but I have to prepare for retaliation.
- We may have to evacuate.
- That's the wrong move.
As long as they stay,
we have to stay.
Well, they're not leaving.
Why does it feel worse?
China is on the offensive.
They're positioning their military to blow
the alien vessel right out of the sky.
And if this happens, we can't sit
around waiting for retaliation. So...
get prepared.
The Air Force and Infantry
are standing by.
Yes, sir.
Tonight, China becomes
the first world power
to declare war against the aliens.
Following the failure of diplomatic
efforts of the United Nations,
China has confirmed that its
language experts have tonight
delivered an ultimatum
at the Shanghai site.
In a televised statement,
General Shang,
Chairman of the People's
Liberation Army,
said the aliens have 24 hours to
leave Chinese territory,
or face destruction.
And he urged all other
world leaders
to unite with China and
take a similar stance.
With a huge build up of forces
at their landing sites,
Pakistan, Russia and Sudan
are thought to be following
China's lead.
[NAVY MOBILIZED IN EAST CHINA SEA]
It can't be random.
Its going to take us years.
What's this term here?
Mum.
- Mum.
- Hm?
- Sweetie?
- What's this term...
for that thing,
like a technical term...
Where we make a deal and we
both get something out of it?
- A compromise?
- No...
- Like it's a competition,
- M-hm...
But both sides end up happy.
Like a win-win?
More sciencey than that.
If you want science,
call your father.
Thank you.
Sorry.
It's OK.
What time is it?
It's time to open that bottle,
you've been hiding.
You cracked something,
didn't you?
Yeah. C'mere.
Take a look at this section.
It seems to be talking
about time.
Their symbol for time
is everywhere.
So what is this?
A formula for faster than light travel?
Who can tell?
There are too many gaps.
Nothing's complete.
Then it dawned on me.
Right here.
Stop focusing on the ones.
Look at the zeroes.
How much of this is data?
How much of it is negative space?
So, I measured it.
.0833 recurring.
Perhaps you'd like that
as a fraction.
1 of 12.
What they're saying right here
is that
this is one of twelve.
We are part of a larger whole.
Or we're 1 of 12
contestants for the prize.
- Why do I have to talk to him?
- We're all working together here.
We need to talk to
the other sites.
We need to help them with what
they got from the other heptopods.
In case you don't remember,
we're blacked out.
China just threatened to destroy
their shell. We're on our own.
But it says that all the
pieces fit together.
And I'm telling you
that no one else cares.
Two hours ago we pulled this audio off
a secure channel in Russia.
Someone from the science team
there was broadcasting live.
In their final session,
the aliens said,
"There is no time. Many become one."
I feel we have all been
given weapons.
If anyone is receiving this...
Please...
Well, I mean...
There are a lot of ways you can
interpret what he said.
I don't need an interpreter to
know what this means.
Russia just executed one of their
own experts to keep their secret.
"Many become one"
could just be their way of saying,
"some assembly required".
Why hand it out to us in pieces?
Why not just give it all over?
What better way to force us
to work together for once?
Even if I did believe you,
how in the world are you gonna get anybody
else to play along, and give up their data?
We offer ours in return.
Yeah.
- What, trade?
- Its a non zero-sum game.
Non zero-sum game.
That's it, yeah. Thanks.
9 of the landing sites have gone
total comms blackout.
The only way to reach them
is to physically drive there
and yell at the border guards which we're
doing, but it won't be fast enough.
There's gotta be a way to
get the message through...
To our allies, maybe. But at this stage,
it's little too late.
What we need, is to get
all the other nations online,
before one starts global war.
And there's no way
for us to reach them
Wait, hold on a second. There is.
It's right above us.
That's problematic for us
right now.
The Pentagon's convinced
our shell will retaliate.
My guess is, they'll order us
to evacuate within the hour.
Look they're not our enemy. They've
made no act of aggression towards us.
Maybe this is their way
of being aggressive.
It's not the question.
Well, what is the question?
How do we get you back in that room
when it's half a mile straight up?
I think our work here is done.
It's in the hands of
our superiors now.
What the hell is she doing?
Costello.
Where's Abbott?
[Abbot is death process]
I'm sorry.
We're sorry.
I need you to...
I need you to send a message
to the other sites.
[Louise has weapon]
[Use weapon]
I don't understand.
What... is your purpose here?
[We help humanity]
[In 3000 years...]
[We need humanity help]
How can you know the future?
I don't...
I don't understand. Who is this child?
The show is called,
Mommy and Daddy Talk to Animals.
[Louise sees future]
[Weapon opens time]
Wait.
No! Wait!
- Dr. Banks!
- Louise!
Are you alright?
- You alright?
- Yeah.
- What happened?
- Tried to figure it out, but it's too big
Doesn't matter now.
We have orders to evacuate.
- Why?
- Russia and Sudan are following China.
I don't understand why...?
Help me, Mama.
Louise... Whoa!
Mom!
Mama!
Sorry, honey.
What day is it, today,
you know baby?
Sunday.
Are you gonna leave me like daddy did?
Oh, Hannah, honey,
your daddy didn't leave you.
You're gonna see him, this weekend.
He doesn't look at me
the same way, anymore.
Its my fault.
I told him something that
he wasn't ready to hear.
What?
Well...
Believe it or not...
I know something that's
going to happen.
I can't explain how I know,
I just do.
And when I told your dad,
he got really mad.
And he said I made the wrong choice.
What?
What's going to happen?
It has to do with a...
a really rare disease.
And it's unstoppable.
Kinda like you are.
Your swimming...
and your poetry and all the other amazing
things that you share with the world.
I'm unstoppable?
Yeah.
I got you.
Oh!
Louise.
I just realized why
my husband left me.
- My husband left me.
- Ah, you were married?
Let's get outta here.
- Mama.
- Yeah?
Why my name is Hannah?
Well, your name is very special,
because it is a palindrome.
It reads the same forward
and backward.
- Get those lights.
- That goes here, in the back.
Civilian contractors must have
their authorization back and...
Evacuation underway.
All personnel evacuate.
Hey!
We're done, here.
Let's take this with us.
I can read it.
- I know what it is.
- What?
It's not a weapon, it's a gift.
The weapon is their language.
They gave it all to us.
- Do you understand what that means?
- So we can learn heptopod? If we survive.
If you learn it...
When you, really, learn it,
you begin to perceive time
the way that they do.
So you can see what's to come.
But, time: it isn't the same for them.
It's non-linear.
Look, we did our best
but it wasn't enough.
The captain will load you on,
and we're lifting off in 5 minutes.
Ian, Louise, it was an honor
to work with you.
Good luck.
Hey, Colonel...
I'm gonna find out
where we're going.
Wake up, Mommy.
Dr. Banks.
A pleasure.
General Shang,
the pleasure is mine, really.
Your president said,
he was honored to host me
at the celebration.
- Yeah.
- But, I confess...
The only reason why I'm here is to...
meet you in person.
Me? Well, I'm flattered.
Thank you.
18 months ago, you did
something remarkable.
Something not even my superior has done.
- What's that?
- You changed my mind.
You're the reason for this unification.
All because you reached out to me
on my private number.
Your private number?
General I don't know your private number.
Now you know.
I do not claim to know how
your mind works, but...
I believe it was important
for you to say that.
I called you didn't I?
Yes, you did.
Louise.
Alright, let's shut down the system.
Sir...
there's a sat-line, here
dialing China.
Here?! What do you mean, here?
C'mon, c'mon.
Whose phone is it?
It's your phone, sir.
Search base camp, now.
Find out who's using that phone.
- Hold onto those co-ordinates.
- Yes, sir.
What do I say?
I will never forget what you said.
Hello, who is this?
You told me my wife's dying words.
General...
I am in the US base camp
General, your wife entrusted me with a dream
Your wife's last wish is
for you to gain the courage to
She said you should have...
We found the source
of the phone call.
It's in the Clean Room.
Waiting for instructions.
...have the courage to save the world
What are you doing?
- What are you doing?
- Changing someone's mind.
- Buy me 20 seconds.
- We don't have time.
No, trust me. Buy me 20 seconds.
Do you trust me? - OK!
- General...
- What?
Dr. Banks...
drop the phone, now,
or we shoot!
General, don't be a hero
- Drop it!
- Yeah, sorry!
that will only leave widows and orphans.
You are committing
an act of treason!
Yes.
- Drop it!
- It's done. I'm done.
Thank you.
Communications blackout,
from all 12 landing sites,
continues this evening.
The two questions on ev...
Hold on, we are just hearing...
I've been told we're going to cut this
report to tell you, breaking news.
Breaking, now: China has called
an emergency press conference...
General Shang, Commander in Chief
of the People's Liberation Army,
has announced in an emergency press
conference that China is standing down.
China is stating that all
intelligence, they have received,
will be shared immediately
with all the other landing sites.
Scientists from around the world
are sifting through information received...
the Russian armed forces are
now revealing the information
they've acquired from both their
landing sites and...
...one of the 12 pieces of this puzzle,
that is being slowly put together.
So, Hannah...
this is where your story begins,
the day they departed.
Are you alright?
Despite knowing the journey...
and where it leads...
I embrace it.
And I welcome every moment of it.
Oo-wooh!
Oh!
H-A-N-N-A-H.
Now backward, H...
A-N-N-A-H.
Hannah.
You ready, baby?
- Perfect.
- M-hmm....
All right, see-ya.
Daddy!
You OK?
I'm just gonna roll over ya.
Roarrr!
Are you ready?
Oh, guess what? Star stuff.
- Ian.
- Yeah.
If you see your whole life,
from start to finish...
Would you change things?
Maybe I'd...
say what I feel more often,
I dunno.
Hm.
Y'know, I've had my head
tilted up to the stars
for as long as I can remember.
Y'know what surprised me the most?
It wasn't meeting them.
It was meeting you.
I forgot how good it felt
to be held by you.
You wanna make a baby?
Yes... yeah.