The next stop is Broad Street.
Broad Street will be next.
Upstairs. This way.
He didn't come up this way? Anything?
- Excuse me.
Go ahead and park around the corner.
Visitors.
- Do you mind if I fetch my teeth?
- Colonel, would you turn around, please?
- Sit down on the bed.
- Let's go.
They're in the... The teeth
are in the... on the sink.
Look at me. We are agents from
the Federal Bureau of Investigation.
Look at me! I'm talking to you.
We've received information concerning
your involvement in espionage.
You can either cooperate with us
right now, or you'll be under arrest.
- Do you understand, Colonel?
- No, not really.
Why do you keep calling me "Colonel"?
- You need to get dressed.
- We have to search your apartment.
Would you mind if I... cleaned my palette?
The paints, it'll get ruined otherwise.
It's just behind you there.
I have a cloth myself. Thank you.
- All right, start searching the place.
- Thank you.
All right, search the mattress,
the bed, the floorboards...
Would you put that in the ashtray
- on the windowsill there?
- Take a good look at that desk.
Let's see the desk.
Wouldn't want to get this ruined.
Don't say "my guy."
He's not "my guy."
Yes, he's "your guy."
Who are we talking about?
We're talking about a guy
who was insured by my client.
So, don't make him "my guy."
Okay, fine.
My point is,
the guy insured by your client,
he doesn't deny that any
of these things happened.
"These... These things"?
Yes, these five things.
Wait, hold it, hold it, hold it.
Not five things.
- One thing.
- Clearly, it's five things.
Well, I'm sorry, it's not clear to me.
Five things? Explain it to me.
- It's self-evident.
- Okay, then tell me what happened.
Tell me the story in a way
that makes sense for five things.
- Fine, absolutely. Your guy is...
- Not my guy. Insured by my client.
The guy insured by your client
is driving down State Highway 19
when he loses control of his car
and hits my five guys,
the five guys who hired me to represent them
because you're not honoring your claim.
You mean my client is not honoring
the claim, the insurance company?
Mr. Donovan, we're all clear
on who's who, here.
Except my client honors every claim.
They do, Mr. Bates.
Every single legitimate claim,
up to the limit of their liability,
which is $100,000 per accident,
in the case of this man's policy.
And this is one claim. According to
your description, "He hit my five guys."
The guy insured by my client
had one accident.
One, one, one. Losing control
of the car and hitting five motorcyclists.
From their point of view,
five things happened.
Well, look, Bob. May I? Bob?
"Jim."
If I go bowling and I throw a strike, one
thing happened. Ten things didn't happen.
Jim, my guys aren't bowling pins, as much
as your guy may have treated them as such.
If... let me finish. Let me finish.
If your house is insured for $100,000
and a tornado carries it away,
it carried away one house.
It didn't pick up every stick of furniture
and destroy it in a separate incident.
If that is what you're saying...
well, then there is never
any limit to our liability
and that is the end
of the insurance business.
And then, Bob, nobody is safe.
Watters, Cowan and Donovan.
How may I direct your call?
- Morning, Mr. Donovan.
- Good morning, Alison.
I moved your 9:00 a.m.
with Prudential, sir.
- Why did you do that?
- I asked her to.
Is everything all right, Tom?
Why don't you leave your stuff
with Alison. Come on inside.
Something pretty important has come up.
Somebody's here to see us.
Natalie's getting your coffee.
Nescafe, cream, two lumps, right?
That's right. Thanks.
- Lynn!
- Jim!
- Nice to see you again. How's the family?
- Great, good. Thanks. How's Annie?
Homicidal.
We had the in-laws for the holiday.
Well, if she acts on it,
she'll have good representation.
Now, what's up?
Okay, here's the thing. The Soviet spy
they caught, we want you to defend him.
Here's the indictment.
- I'm not sure I wanna pick that up.
- The accused doesn't know any lawyers.
The federal court tossed it into our lap.
The Bar Committee took a vote.
You're the unanimous choice.
It was important to us...
It's important to our country, Jim,
that this man is seen
as getting a fair shake.
American justice will be on trial.
Well, of course, when you put it
that way, it's an honor to be asked.
But... Lynn, I'm an insurance lawyer.
I haven't done criminal work in years.
It's like riding a bike, isn't it?
You distinguished yourself at Nuremberg.
- I was on the prosecution team.
- Not the point.
You're no stranger to criminal law.
Jim, look at the situation.
The man is publicly reviled.
- And I will be, too.
- Yes, in more ignorant quarters.
But that's exactly why this
has to be done, and capably done.
It can't look like our justice system
tosses people on the ash heap.
Suppose I did,
what's the evidence look like?
Pretty overwhelming.
Great. Great.
Everyone will hate me
but at least I'll lose.
Well, what do you think, Tom?
The firm will suffer. I have work here.
I think it's a patriotic duty.
It's an important mission.
I told Lynn, the firm can't say no,
and you'd have a tough time
saying no, too.
I think you have to defend
the son of a bitch.
- So, you're doing it?
- Doing what?
Defending Abel, the Soviet spy.
I may. I have to speak to...
Wait, how do you know?
Did they post it on the bulletin board?
- No, I was talking to Richard Earl...
- If I do this, I'm going to need your help.
Can you work tonight?
Well, I have a dinner date, sir.
It's Tuesday, right? Yeah, no, I'm free,
completely free. Thank you, sir.
But it's also an honor.
And the Bar Association asked me
because they want to show that even
a spy gets a capable advocate.
Well, maybe it's the kind of honor
we could do without.
Hey, honey, what are you doing home?
- I got stood up.
- Well, that's despicable.
- Who is this knot-head?
- I'd rather not say.
Well, sit down. We just started.
People are scared.
They're building bomb shelters to protect
themselves from people like this man.
I go to the store, people are buying
canned food and potassium tablets.
It's all about this man
and what he represents.
- He's a threat to all of us. A traitor.
- Who's a traitor?
- The Rosenbergs were traitors.
- Who were they?
They gave atomic secrets to the Russians.
They were Americans.
They betrayed their country.
You can't accuse Abel of being a traitor.
He's not an American.
Oh, listen to yourself.
You're defending him already.
You're rehearsing it on me. You said
you were just thinking about taking it.
I am just thinking about it,
just very hard.
Everyone deserves a defense.
Every person matters.
Jim, what do we deserve?
Do you know how people will look at us?
The family of a man
trying to free a traitor?
- He's not a traitor, Mary.
- Yes. Roger, get that! He's not a traitor...
- Why do I have to do all the work?
- You wait till we say grace.
He's the most unpopular man in this country,
and you're trying to take second place!
- Yeah, and I'm third.
- Carol, you just dated the wrong guy.
Mary, don't make this an argument
when we're not having an argument.
You're against him, I'm for him? I'm not for
him. I'm not for the Russians spying on us.
I'm for his right to have a defense
in a court of law,
- which is why they call it a court of law.
- I didn't mean to interrupt dinner.
- A court of law... Hey, Doug.
- Oh, no, not at all. Hello, Doug.
- Jim was just flailing.
- ...a kangaroo court. I'm not flailing.
Go ahead, Doug, you can join us for dinner.
We're having meatloaf tonight.
So, you came over to help Jim think
about whether he's taking the case?
Oh, we're taking it!
It's exciting, isn't it?
Lord, we thank thee for thy blessings
we are about to receive.
Thy bounty through Christ, our Lord. Amen.
Good morning, sir. My name is Jim Donovan.
These are my credentials. I am a partner
in Watters, Cowan and Donovan.
I was admitted to
the New York Bar in 1941.
You have been charged
with three counts and 19 overt acts.
Conspiracy to transmit United States defense
and atomic secrets to the Soviet Union,
conspiracy to gather secrets, and failing
to register as a foreign agent.
Do many foreign agents register?
If you don't mind my asking, sir...
since your arrest, where have you been?
I couldn't say for certain.
You don't know?
They drove me to an airport and put me
on a plane, took me off the plane.
Somewhere hot.
- It's hot here.
- Hotter, very humid.
They put me in a room.
Were you beaten?
No. I was talked to.
- Offers were made.
- What do you mean?
Offers of employment,
to work for your government.
I was told if I cooperated,
no further charges
would be made against me.
And I would be given money.
And you declined?
As you see.
Well, of course I can't endorse that.
I feel duty-bound to urge you to cooperate
with the U.S. government.
Well, I said no. Perhaps you could relay
to your friends at the CIA that I meant it.
No, no, no. I...
I don't work for the agency.
I don't work for the government.
I am here to offer my services
as your legal counsel.
If you accept them as such...
I work for you.
If I accept you?
Are you good at what you do?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm pretty good.
Have you represented many accused spies?
No, not yet.
This will be a first for the both of us.
Yes.
- All right.
- "All right"? You accept?
- Yes, all right.
- Good, okay.
Let's start here. If you are firm
in your resolve not to cooperate
- with the U.S. government...
- I am.
Yeah. Then do not talk to anybody else about
your case, inside of government or out.
Except to me,
to the extent that you trust me.
I have a mandate to serve you.
Nobody else does.
Quite frankly, everybody else has an interest
in sending you to the electric chair.
All right.
You don't seem alarmed.
Would it help?
I... I would like materials to draw with.
That's not possible.
A pencil, a piece of paper. Cigarettes.
Please?
Mr. Donovan, you have men like me
doing the same for your country.
If they were caught,
I'm sure that you would wish them
to be treated well.
- What's your name?
- Francis Gary Powers.
Rank, service?
First Lieutenant, United States Air Force.
Do you have any association
with the Soviet Union, Lieutenant Powers?
- Kidding?
- Just answer the questions, Lieutenant.
Yes, no, or as simply as you can.
Do you have any association
with the Soviet Union?
Hell, no.
Do you know why you're here?
Is that a no?
Yes. I mean...
No, it's just "no." Yes, I have
absolutely no idea why I'm here.
- Eyes front, Lieutenant.
- Yes, sir.
How'd you do in there, Gary?
Pretty good. Think I got my name right.
You probably outscored Shinn, then.
- Who's winning?
- That would be me.
Oh. Well, deal me in.
So, these are all mine, then.
I told you boys not to play with him.
Okay, drivers, here's the deal.
You've been selected for a mission
which you are not to discuss with anyone
outside of this room. No one.
I don't care who you trust.
Wife, mother, sweetheart.
The good Lord when you pray at night.
You don't tell any of them anything
of what I'm about to tell you.
Each of you drivers
has met certain qualifications.
High level security clearance.
Exceptional pilot ratings in excess
of the required hours flight time
in a single-seat aircraft.
We are engaged in a war.
This war does not, for the moment, involve
men-at-arms. It involves information.
You will be collecting information.
You will be gathering intelligence
about the enemy.
The intelligence you gather
could give us the upper hand
in a full thermonuclear exchange
with the Soviet Union.
Or it could prevent one.
For public purposes,
as far as your wife or mother
or sweetheart or the good Lord above,
your mission does not exist.
If it does not exist, you do not exist.
You cannot be shot down.
You cannot be captured.
You work for the CIA now.
So, Jim, I heard your guy is speaking
with a phony accent.
Does he keep that up all the time?
Actually, I'm pretty sure
that's just the way he talks.
He's got the Russian name
but a British passport.
Well, I doubt that that's genuine.
So, Jim, where are we? I see here...
Yes... Judge, you see,
I just don't think that three weeks
is going to do it, here.
We... got a massive amount
of evidence, as you know.
- You wanna postpone?
- Six weeks.
I mean, there's just myself
and my associate, basically.
- Jim, is this serious?
- Sir?
Is this serious?
Yes. Yes, indeed, it is.
You can see in the filing...
Jim, this man is a Soviet spy.
- Allegedly.
- Come on, Counselor!
Your Honor.
Of course, I salute you. We all salute you
for taking on a thankless task.
This man has to have due process.
But let's not kid each other.
He'll receive a capable defense.
And, God willing, he'll be convicted.
Come on, Counselor.
Let's not play games with this.
Not in my courtroom.
We have a date...
and we're going to trial.
Taxi!
Taxi! I see your light on!
Son of a bitch.
Can't wait to get back to Manhattan.
His light was on, right?
Son of a bitch.
Against their level of comfort.
The statute hasn't changed.
Oh, excuse me, sir.
Pardon me. Sorry.
Mr. Donovan.
What?
CIA.
Yeah.
I just wanted to chat.
- How's the case going?
- Case is going great. Couldn't be better.
Has your guy talked?
Excuse me.
You met him. Has he talked?
Has he said anything yet?
- We're not having this conversation.
- No, of course not.
No, I mean, we really are not having it.
You're asking me to violate
attorney-client privilege.
Oh, come on, Counselor.
I wish people like you would quit saying
"Oh, come on, Counselor."
I didn't like it the first time it happened
today. A judge said it to me twice.
And the more I hear it,
the more I don't like it.
Okay, well, listen, I understand
attorney-client privilege.
I understand all the legal gamesmanship.
And I understand
that's how you make a living.
But I'm talking to you
about something else.
The security of your country.
And I'm sorry if the way
I put it offends you.
But we need to know
what Abel is telling you.
You understand me, Donovan?
We need to know.
Don't go "Boy Scout" on me.
We don't have a rule book, here.
You're Agent Hoffman, yeah?
Yeah.
- German extraction.
- Yeah, so?
My name's Donovan. Irish.
Both sides, mother and father.
I'm Irish, you're German.
But what makes us both Americans?
Just one thing.
One, one, one.
The rule book.
We call it the Constitution
and we agree to the rules,
and that's what makes us Americans.
It's all that makes us Americans
so don't tell me there's no rule book,
and don't nod at me, you son of a bitch.
Do we need to worry about you?
Not if I'm left alone to do my job.
From this moment forward you will not
refer to the U-2 as a spy plane
or reconnaissance aircraft.
You will refer to it as "The Article."
The Article has an 80-foot wingspan.
Powered by a single Pratt
and Whitney J57 P-37 engine.
10,000 pounds of thrust
and a maximum speed of 430 miles an hour.
She may not be quick, but at your
cruising altitude of 70,000 feet,
- nothing will come close to you.
- 70,000?
The idea is the enemy
doesn't even know you're there.
It looks kind of flimsy.
Every extra pound of weight
costs a foot in altitude, and...
we need to accommodate the cameras.
That's a 4,500-millimeter lens,
times three.
A pin-sharp panoramic camera
four times as powerful as any aerial
reconnaissance cameras we've ever used.
You're gonna be taking pictures,
lots of pictures.
At 70,000 feet, The Article can photograph
2,000 square miles of territory in one pass.
Now, drivers, give Agent Sumner
your undivided attention.
The items you'll need
on your mission are over here.
B camera, Revere 8 model 40 magazine,
Keystone Capri K-25, silver.
Hollow-handle shaving brush. Complete set
of cipher tables on edible silver foil.
Specialist photographic equipment.
Yeah, we... we get the idea. Thank you.
Excuse me, Agent... Bosco. "Blasco."
Sir.
There seems to be a subsection
to this list here.
Well, most of this stuff
came from his studio,
but the rest is from the hotel
room he was holed up in.
Where we found him.
The hotel room you searched?
Well, yeah.
- Can I see the warrant?
- The what?
Yeah, explain this to me.
There was a warrant.
There was a warrant. A civil detention
writ for the arrest of an alien,
but there was no search warrant
for suspicion of criminal activity.
So the search and the evidence
that is the fruit of that search,
that's all tainted
and should not be admitted.
What protections is he due, Your Honor?
The man is not... The man is what?
He's Rudolf Ivanovich Abel.
He is a Soviet citizen.
He's not an American.
1886, Yick Wo v. Hopkins.
The court held that even aliens,
in that case Chinese immigrants,
could not be held to answer for a crime
without due process of law,
including any alien that
entered the country illegally.
The Department of Justice has its
first allegiance to the United States.
I don't see how an alien,
if he's here illegally,
how he suffered deprivation of rights.
Rights as what? An American?
Rights as what, Counselor?
We're in a battle for civilization.
This Russian spy came here
to threaten our way of life.
Now, I have a courtroom of people waiting.
Get out there, sit beside the Russian.
Let's get this over and done with.
And your motion is denied.
He should take some insurance
out on himself.
- How did we do?
- In there?
Not too good. Apparently,
you're not an American citizen.
That's true.
And according to your boss,
you're not a Soviet citizen either.
Well, the boss isn't always right...
but he's always the boss.
Do you never worry?
Would it help?
All rise.
"I pledge allegiance to the Flag
"of the United States of America,
"and to the Republic for which it stands,
"one Nation under God, indivisible,
"with liberty and justice for all."
First, you have to know what happens
when an atomic bomb explodes.
There is a bright flash,
brighter than the sun.
It can smash in buildings,
break windows all over town.
But if you duck and cover like Bert,
you will be much safer.
There are two kinds of attack,
with warning and without any warning.
- What's going on in here?
- Okay, Dad, this is really important.
When the war begins,
the first thing they do
is cut off all the water
and all the electricity.
So the first thing we should do is keep
this filled, use the shower in your room,
use the sink downstairs,
the garden hose outside...
Those are good ideas.
But, Roger, I don't see this as being
something you ever have to worry about.
Yeah, but when you hear the sirens,
there may not be enough time
to fill the tub and the sinks.
Not gonna be any sirens.
What is this?
When the bomb comes, the Reds
will aim for the Empire State Building.
But the bomb goes off at 10,000 feet up.
In Life magazine, it's called an airburst,
and if the bomb is 50 megatons,
the blast wave goes out and out and out
and melts everything from here to here.
Including where we live. Here.
Yeah, right there.
But, you know, Roger, no one
is dropping atomic bombs on us.
But the Russians want to. You know
that Russian guy you're defending?
He's here to get things ready
for the guys who drop the bombs.
No, no, he's not... Not here for that.
He's not even Russian. He was born,
we think, in Northern England.
But he's a spy for Russia.
I don't even understand what you're doing.
You're not a Communist,
so why are you defending one?
Well, because it's my job.
It never used to be.
In the case of the United States
of America versus Rudolf Abel,
as to the first count in the indictment,
how do you find the defendant?
Guilty or not guilty?
Guilty.
- As to the second count?
- Guilty.
- As to the third count?
Your Honor, I make a motion
to set aside these guilty verdicts
- against the weight of evidence.
- Denied.
The jury is discharged. Thank you all.
I would like to add that,
if I were one of you,
I would've reached the same verdict.
Sentencing will be...
November 15.
The death sentence is not
a foregone conclusion. Don't worry.
I'm not afraid to die, Mr. Donovan.
Although...
it wouldn't be my first choice.
You left this behind.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, thank you very much.
You've never asked me
if the charges were true.
If I am indeed a spy.
This is how we do it.
The case against you matters.
Making them prove it matters.
The fiction is... Whether you
did it or not doesn't matter.
The state has to prove it,
that you're a spy.
So you're not curious?
No, not really.
I always assumed you were an artist.
My wife, she's the artist.
She's a musician.
In the Children's Orchestra of Moscow.
- What instrument?
- The harp.
Then, she's an angel.
Standing there like that, you remind me
of a man who used to come to our house
when I was young.
My father used to say, "Watch this man."
So I did, every time he came.
And never once...
did he do anything remarkable.
And I remind you of him?
This one time, I was
about the age of your son.
Our house was overrun
by partisan border guards.
Dozens of them.
My father was beaten,
my mother was beaten,
and this man, my father's friend,
he was beaten.
And I watched this man.
Every time they hit him...
he stood back up again.
So they hit him harder.
Still, he got back to his feet.
I think because of this they stopped
the beating. They let him live.
I remember them saying it.
It sort of means, like...
"standing man."
Standing man.
- Hello, Jim!
- Millie, you're a vision.
Mortie's busy getting kitted out.
But come on in.
- Scotch, Jim?
- Oh, yes, please. Thank you.
Just a drop of water.
- Your Honor.
- Hello, Jim. Just going out.
Got a few minutes though.
March of Dimes thing. Millie is active.
Well, thank you for seeing me.
I just wanted to give you
my two cents on the sentencing.
And I thought maybe
I should pester you at home
as not all of my points
are narrowly legal.
Yeah, well, it's that kind of case.
I hope I wasn't too scratchy during
the trial but it's exactly what you say.
Nothing about this is narrowly legal.
There are bigger issues.
Bigger issues!
Thank you, thank you.
Sir...
I think it could be considered in
the best interests of the United States
that Abel remain alive.
Why? I'm not saying I've made up my mind
but if he was gonna cooperate, work with
the government, he would've done it already.
- True, but the issue here...
- You can't... Excuse me.
You can't say it's in the best
interest of the United States
that he spend the rest
of his days in a prison cell.
- How is this the national interest?
- Not the incarceration itself, sir.
It is possible that,
in the foreseeable future,
an American of equivalent rank
might be captured by Soviet Russia.
We might want to have someone to trade.
That sounds like spinning what-ifs.
You could do that till the cows come home.
It's my business, what-ifs.
I'm in insurance. And there's
nothing implausible about this one.
It's entirely in the realm
of what could happen.
It's the kind of probability
that people buy insurance for.
If we send this guy to his death,
we leave ourselves wide open.
No policy in our back pocket
for the day the storm comes.
Nice speech.
Sir, there is also
the humanitarian argument.
Should he die for doing the job
they sent him to do?
All right, Counselor.
I gotta run.
Good seeing you, Jim.
I'll walk you out.
All rise.
The United States District Court
for the Eastern District of New York
is now in session. The honorable
Mortimer Byers presiding.
Be seated.
The defendant will please rise.
In the measured judgment of this court
the following sentence,
based upon the jury's verdict of guilty
as to each count of the indictment,
is believed to meet the test
which has been stated.
Pursuant to the verdict
of guilty as to all counts,
the defendant is committed to the custody of
the Attorney General of the United States...
for imprisonment in a federal institution
to be selected by him
for a period of 30 years.
Marshals, you may take
the defendant into custody.
- No electrocution?
- No. No, no.
Why aren't we hanging him? In the name
of God, why aren't we hanging him?
- Sit down, sir!
- He's a spy! He's killing us with his lies!
In the name of God,
why aren't we hanging him?
That's right!
He's a spy!
Mr. Donovan! Mr. Donovan!
Just one question. Just one question, sir.
My hat! My hat! My hat!
Nobody here has a comment. Mr. and Mrs.
Donovan are not answering questions.
How do you feel now that
this national nightmare is over?
- Mr. Donovan, are you happy with the verdict?
- We're in firm ground for a case on appeal.
- Appeal?
- Appeal, yes.
Jim, you did a great job.
You fulfilled your mandate and then some.
But the man is a spy. The verdict's correct
and there's no reason to appeal it.
There's ample procedural reason.
We know the search is tainted.
And Fourth Amendment issues will always
weigh more heavily in an appellate forum.
- We've got a good shot.
- What the goddamn hell are you talking about?
We were supposed to show he had
a capable defense, which we did.
Why are you citing the goddamn
Constitution at me?
Tom, if you look me in the eye
and tell me we don't have grounds
for an appeal, I'll drop it right now.
I'm not saying that.
You know what I'm saying.
Tom's saying there's a cost
to these things.
That's right.
A cost to both your family and your firm.
I've missed music.
They checked the radio to make sure
there was no transmitter in it.
I'm sure they did.
Shostakovich.
That's a very great artist, Shostakovich.
I think...
our strongest grounds for reversal...
are constitutional.
Our best chance is if the Supreme Court
agrees to review our case.
Jim...
You should be careful.
Careful.
77 Sunset Strip
Edward Byrnes.
And Richard Long.
- Good morning, Suzanne.
- Good morning, Dick.
There is a special delivery letter
here for you.
Oh, her.
Mom!
What in God's name happened?
Honey, are you all right? Are you hurt?
I've got her. Upstairs!
- I sat with my back against the wall, Dad!
- Are you all right? Are you okay?
Dad, I sat with my back against the wall!
Away from the windows!
Good, good, good, good, good.
Good boy, good boy, good boy.
Okay. It's okay. It's all right,
they're gone, they're gone.
They're cowards. They're gone.
We have detectives canvassing
the neighborhood.
Maybe we'll find a description of the car
- but I don't think it's very likely.
- We're gonna need protection.
I have instructions to leave
two cars here. It'll be pretty obvious...
For how long? I have to be
in Washington later on this week.
What are you doing?
What are you doing to your family?
- Pardon me, Officer?
- You're still defending this guy?
- What are you fighting for him for?
- Okay, knock that off, Officer.
I'll knock off nothing.
I was in the third wave at Omaha Beach.
- I did my time in the service.
- ...and you're defending them?
Why don't you just do your job
as an officer of the law?
- Okay, I'm sorry. Let's go outside. Come on.
- You know what? Just forget him.
- What am I not getting here?
- Outside, Officer!
I'm sorry.
Do you feel that you deserve this, sir?
Should it become necessary to abandon
the aircraft over Soviet territory,
then there's a two-and-a-half pound explosive
charge contained within the fuselage.
Now, first, you activate the circuits.
But to start the 70-second timer,
you need to flip the switch
marked "Destruct."
It is imperative that these flights
remain a secret
and this equipment does not fall
into enemy hands.
What about us?
I don't know if you're kidding,
Lieutenant Powers. I'm not.
What you know about the plane
is as secret as the plane itself.
If capture is a foregone conclusion...
you go down with your plane.
Now, if you think you can ditch
and get away,
if you're close enough to a border, fine.
You know the ejection protocol.
But if you ditch...
you bring the dollar with you.
All right, there's a pin inside.
You scratch your skin anywhere,
it's instantaneous.
If you think you are about to be captured,
you use it.
Drivers, you understand me?
Spend the dollar.
Mr. Chief Justice,
and may it please the court.
The "Cold War" is not just a phrase,
Your Honor.
It's not just a figure of speech.
Truly, a battle is being fought between
two competing views of the world.
I contend that Rudolf Ivanovich Abel,
"Colonel Abel," as he was called
even by the men who arrested him,
is our foe in that battle.
- Auxiliary power?
- Connected and on.
- Oxygen seat-pack supply?
- Supply at 1,800 psi.
- Inverter?
- On, light out.
He was treated as a combatant in that war
until it no longer suited
our government to so treat him.
Accordingly... he was not given
the protections we give our own citizens.
He was subjected to treatment that,
however appropriate for a suspected enemy,
was not appropriate
to a suspected criminal.
- Fuel transfer?
- Transfer switch off.
- Destructor?
- Destructor safety.
- Climb data card.
- Installed in aircraft.
I know this man.
If the charge is true, he serves a foreign
power but he serves it faithfully.
If he is a soldier in the opposing army,
he is a good soldier.
He has not fled the field
of battle to save himself.
He has refused to serve his captor.
He has refused to betray his cause.
He has refused
to take the coward's way out.
The coward must abandon his dignity
before he abandons the field of battle.
That, Rudolf Abel will never do.
Shouldn't we, by giving him
the full benefit of the rights
that define our system of government,
show this man who we are?
Who we are.
Is that not the greatest weapon
we have in this Cold War?
Will we stand by our cause less
resolutely than he stands by his?
The President announced that a NASA
weather plane disappeared
four days ago north of Turkey.
And the Space Administration fears
that its pilot died in the crash.
Radar showed the plane wandering
off course deep into Soviet territory
before contact was lost,
complicating any effort to recover it
or the remains of the pilot.
Now to news out of Washington.
In a close vote today, the Supreme Court
affirmed the conviction
of Russian spy Rudolf Ivanovich Abel,
five votes to four.
The case presented civil liberties issues,
according to the Russian's lawyer,
James B. Donovan.
When asked how he felt about today's loss,
Mr. Donovan simply said, "Tired."
I'll have more news for you
after this message.
It's over.
Marty.
I'll be damned if I can find
the file on that Prudential case.
I... Mr. Watters had me move it
over to Jack Elwes's office
- along with the first draft of the appeal.
- He did?
Yeah, he redrafted and filed that
last week while you were in Washington.
How long have we been together?
You act as if I've never closed a deal.
Set up a meeting. Someplace fancy.
I'm betting Mr. Young would like some
of the finer things New York has to offer.
And I want you to give me the summary...
Do you know anyone from Leipzig?
"Leipzig." Am I getting hate mail
from Germany now?
From East Germany.
Is it your wife?
No.
No, no, no, no.
She pretends to be
but it's not even a good pretense.
"I'm taking this liberty to write to you
after having learned from the newspapers
"about your most humane attitude
towards my beloved husband,
"Rudolf Abel."
And do I write back?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
What's the next move
when you don't know what the game is?
Francis Gary Powers...
On the strength of Article Two
of the U.S.S.R. law
on criminal responsibility
for state crimes
to 10 years of confinement
with the first three years
to be served in prison.
The term of the punishment,
including preliminary detention,
shall be counted from May first,
nineteen hundred and sixty.
Mr. Donovan, thank you so much for coming.
It's a pleasure to meet you, Mr. Dulles.
It's an honor, sir.
Nescafe, cream,
two lumps.
Thank you.
Okay, this letter you received.
Seems pretty clear that the Soviets
are making an overture here.
They're doing it through East Germany
'cause they still don't want to acknowledge
Abel as a Soviet citizen,
much less a Soviet spy. So...
- Lot of fiction going on.
- Yes, sir, but to what end?
They got our guy, our spy pilot.
We've got their guy.
Prisoner exchange, I think
that's what they're after.
Which could hardly be
a surprise to you, Counselor.
It's an eventuality
that I think you foresaw.
Yes, I sure did, and I'm so rarely right.
Well, congratulations. Red letter day.
Now...
we have our man over there. Powers.
Good man, but with a head
full of classified information.
Abel has a head full
of classified information, too,
- but he hasn't given us a lick.
- And, sir, take it from me, he won't.
Yes, we know that, but the Russians don't.
They want their man back before he cracks.
And we want Powers back
for the same reasons.
I think you are saying, sir, that there
might be a happy ending for everyone.
Yes, if we... indulge their fiction.
We want you to negotiate the swap
because you're a private citizen,
so it's not governments talking.
They don't acknowledge Abel
as a Soviet citizen,
and we don't acknowledge East Germany
as a sovereign country.
We haven't recognized East Berlin since
it was annexed by the Soviets in '45.
So I act as a negotiator, representing...
You're not representing anybody.
Not a government official.
You have no official standing.
- So, some fiction on our side as well.
- Correct.
Which means, of course, you can't
rely on any acknowledgment
or help if things go south.
CIA can't be responsible.
We can't be embarrassed.
Where do they want this negotiation
to take place?
- There.
- "There"?
East Berlin.
Well, isn't East Berlin getting rather...
Oh, yes, the place is getting complicated.
Yeah, complicated.
The Soviet side has been setting up
checkpoints for the past few months
to try to stop people hemorrhaging to the
Western sectors, and it hasn't worked.
We have intelligence to suggest
that they may go one step further
and wall off the entire Eastern sector.
Okay, that's it in a nutshell.
The decision is entirely yours.
You need time to kick it around.
No.
- No, I don't.
- Well, fine. Fine.
Best that this all remains confidential.
Let's not discuss any of this with...
Mary or with anyone else.
Share the correspondence only with us.
Let us know what they want to do and when.
I've got no client, no wife, no country.
Don't know what I'm doing
or when or who for.
You're doing it for your country,
but your country doesn't know that yet.
What about my client, the other person
in this equation? My guy?
Your guy? You mean the Russian?
He's not your guy anymore, Counselor.
Your guy is Francis Gary Powers now.
What do I tell Rudolf Abel?
Tell him not to drop dead.
Professor?
Papa went to university.
You shouldn't be here, Frederic.
- They're having classes today?
- He went to see. That's where he goes.
- What are you doing here?
- I came to get you and your father.
You have to come with me.
You might not get out tomorrow.
- Just... just leave?
- Yes. Yes, yes, yes, leave. Right now.
Go back. Go back.
I'll be okay, I'm American. Go back.
Go back to your father's.
We'll find another way. Go.
- Hey!
- So, hi.
- Papers, please.
- Ich bin Student Frederic Pryor.
Yes, student.
My name's Frederic Pryor.
I'm an economics student.
See? It's my dissertation. My thesis.
You see? Look, look.
"The foreign trade system of
the European Communist nations."
It was a lot of work.
No, that's my only copy.
No!
Tell me something.
It came up at the last minute.
They have offices in London.
These clients. Not my idea.
Scotland, this fishing expedition.
- What kind of fishing trip, Jim?
- Salmon fishing.
Just tell me that you're
not gonna be in any danger,
that this is just a routine
business trip, and I won't worry.
I need my passport.
Just give me something to hold on to.
I don't even care if it's the truth.
I'm doing this for us.
Mr. Michener, here, is your Berlin escort.
He's an attache with the U.S. embassy.
So, it's gotten goddamn complicated.
As you know, the last letter from Mrs.
Abel, whoever she is, talks about a lawyer
in East Berlin, Mr. Vogel, whoever he is,
representing her interests, she says.
Yeah, Vogel says he's gone
to the Russian embassy in East Berlin
and they may be ready
to trade Abel for Powers.
But no one knows who's who,
but essentially they're all Russian, right?
- Well, Soviet.
- Well, we think so.
What do you mean?
Could we turn up the heat in here?
No, it's...
There's a wrinkle.
They might try to throw you a curveball.
Try and get you to accept
another prisoner other than Powers.
Another American?
The... East German Stasi picked up
an American student. Frederic Pryor.
The kid they found
on the wrong side of the Wall.
He's a grad student out of Yale.
Came over here to study economics.
So, they're making noises
about trying this kid for espionage.
Grave offense, capital crime. Well.
Vogel got in touch with us,
said he represents Pryor.
Wait a minute. Vogel represents
Mrs. Abel and this... this kid?
Yeah, he's busy.
Well, so, what is he? Vogel, is he...
East German or is he Russian?
Well, try to figure it out
when you meet him.
At Russian embassy,
East Berlin, noon tomorrow.
Hoffman will show you how to get there.
Wait, show me how to get there?
I'm gonna have an escort. Right?
Well, that was the plan but, like I said,
there's a wrinkle. I won't be taking you.
Decision's been made. No U.S. government
personnel are to cross the border
- until further notice.
- How come?
It's too dangerous.
Yeah, the East Germans grabbed this kid.
There's a degree of impunity
that we had not anticipated.
The point is that the East German agenda
and the Russian agenda
may not be the same thing.
Try and figure it out and act accordingly.
And try to make a deal. Powers for Abel.
Well, what about this college kid, Pryor?
Don't fall for that.
We can get him out another time.
Powers is the whole ball game.
Where's your room?
I'll be staying at the Hilton.
It's not far.
This is a number here in West Berlin.
Memorize it and give it back to me.
No, no. I mean, now.
The Soviets keep cutting the international
lines but local calls are okay.
Someone will pick up day and night.
Now, this docket attached
to your passport will serve
as your ticket into and out
of the Eastern Soviet sector.
The meeting with Vogel
is set for noon tomorrow.
There are only a few routes
left to the East.
You take the S-Bahn, the station
we showed you on the way in.
You're gonna get off
at the Friedrichstrasse station here
and walk to the Soviet embassy
on Unter den Linden here.
Look at the map now.
You shouldn't take it with you.
You're looking at a map, you're an American,
you're a spy. You could well be detained.
Just avoid interacting with people generally.
You don't belong, so don't stick out.
Food is scarce over there
and things have started to fall apart.
There are gangs, and rule of law
is less firmly established over there.
And definitely stay away from the Wall.
On their side, there's a line
cleared of buildings along the Wall.
They call it the "Death Line."
Cross it and you'll be shot.
Is there any outcome here
where I'm not either detained or shot?
Don't worry too much
about what Michener said.
No, I'm worried about what you're saying.
This kid, Pryor, that the East
Germans have, how old is he?
- Twenty-five. Why?
- Same age as Dougie.
- Who?
- An associate of mine.
Frederic Pryor.
Okay, okay, okay.
Danke.
So, we apologize...
if this offends.
Coat?
Okay.
- Do you understand English?
- Yes, sir.
I'm James Donovan.
I'm here to meet a Mr. Vogel.
- Mr. Vogel.
- He doesn't work here.
I'm just supposed to meet him.
That's all I know.
Mr. Donovan!
So we finally meet you.
- I'm Helen Abel. How is our husband?
- Oh. He's fine.
- How is my Rudolf?
- As good as can be expected.
And we will get him back, yes?
- This is our daughter.
- How do you do?
Lydia.
Are you Mr. Vogel?
No, no, no! I'm not Vogel.
I'm cousin Drews.
- This is Rudolf's beloved cousin Drews.
- Yes, cousin Drews.
- I am cousin Drews.
- Cousin Drews, yes.
I'm Helen Abel.
When will you see him?
When will your government release him?
Well, I'm a little... lost here.
I'm supposed to meet a Mr. Vogel.
Oh, Mr. Vogel is our lawyer.
So we were supposed to negotiate,
the exchange.
- To bring Rudolf here?
- Yes, yes, to bring him here.
But it doesn't happen unilaterally,
do you understand?
It has to be an exchange.
Not here?
- Mr. Donovan?
- Mr. Vogel.
No, no, no. Goodness.
My name is Schischkin. Ivan Schischkin.
I'm the second secretary
of the Soviet embassy.
It wouldn't be appropriate
for Mr. Vogel to join us.
He is a German national.
So you aren't here to...
To facilitate this meeting.
Perhaps Mrs. Abel would like
to compose herself privately?
And let Mr. Donovan and myself to talk?
Thank you.
- So, I'm confused.
- Yes.
I don't care who I talk to
if it's about an exchange of personnel.
- Are you the person to talk to?
- Yes, yes, yes, of course.
We should talk.
Please, have a seat, Mr. Donovan.
How did you arrive to the Eastern sector?
- The train. The S-Bahn.
- And you were alone?
Yeah.
And you are credentialed?
Now, you must know about me, sir.
I'm a private citizen.
I'm a lawyer in Brooklyn
in the United States,
and I've taken time out of my busy
schedule to help my client, Rudolf Abel.
I'm authorized to arrange an exchange
of Abel for Francis Gary Powers.
This is a full pardon of Abel
that will be signed
when the exchange actually takes place.
This is the only reason I'm here.
I hope and expect to make
this arrangement quickly.
Abel for Francis Gary Powers...
and Frederic Pryor.
- We don't have Pryor.
- No? You don't?
I've heard of Pryor, but he's held
by the German Democratic Republic,
not by the Union of Soviet
Socialist Republics.
Well, I'll tell you the first problem.
The names of your countries are too long.
Yes, yes.
If we release Powers,
it is only to promote a goodwill
between our countries.
So, it cannot be an exchange.
Perhaps... Perhaps you could release Abel
as a token of goodwill
to our friends in Germany, and then,
some months later, we would release
Powers. There is an idea.
No. That just won't work for us at all.
See, we need this to be an exchange.
You can call it what you want,
but an exchange it must be.
We can have Abel here within 48 hours.
We need Powers at the same time
we give you Abel.
This is...
Can we call this the "impatient plan"?
Well, you can call it whatever you want.
I can relay your impatient plan
to Moscow, see what they say...
But they will wonder why so impatient.
Because I have a cold. And I don't
live in Berlin and I want to go home.
They will think, "Well, the Americans...
"must have gotten all the information
that Abel had to give.
"And now they're impatient to trade him,
"hoping to get in return this man, Powers,
"that, perhaps, has not yet given up
all the information that he has to give."
This is not an equitable trade, sir.
But what you're saying is, if Powers
has given up everything he knows,
then Moscow would trade?
Why wouldn't they?
As for Abel, if he dies
in an American prison,
the next Russian operative
who gets caught might think twice
about keeping his mouth shut.
And you never know.
Abel might want to see the sky again.
And decide to trade Russian secrets
for small American favors.
How can we know this?
We little men, we just do our jobs.
Like Lieutenant Powers. He's just a pilot.
He was making photographs
from 70,000 feet
when he was shot from the sky.
People in my country consider this...
an act of war.
We have to get off
this merry-go-round, sir.
The next mistake our countries make
could be the last one.
We need to have the conversation
our governments can't.
I will ask Moscow.
Who knows what they will say.
There are a lot of people, Mr. Donovan,
who doesn't want this...
exchange to ever take place.
Can you come back tomorrow
to discuss their answer?
- Powers for Abel.
- And Frederic Pryor.
As I said, Pryor is in the hands
of the organs of State Security
- of the German Democratic Republic.
- I'm confident you can make arrangements.
I am merely a secretary
in the embassy of foreign power.
Okay.
You have to see Mr. Vogel.
I'll give you his address.
- There actually is a Mr. Vogel?
- Why would you imagine otherwise?
It's a short cab ride.
And please, Mr. Donovan,
wear an overcoat in this weather.
I had mine stolen from me.
What do you expect?
It was from Saks Fifth Avenue.
Wasn't it?
- Mr. Donovan.
- Mr. Vogel.
Please come in.
Danke.
Sorry about the embassy.
But the Soviets decided not to host me.
Very irritating.
I am still trying to grasp each party's...
Status?
Yes. And interest in the proceedings.
It's a new world.
All very disorienting, isn't it?
Let me tell you what I have to offer.
I'm a good friend... "Friend."
No, he's older.
"Protege"? Of the attorney general
of the German Democratic Republic.
Sit down, please.
This unfortunate, Frederic Pryor...
he was in the wrong place
at the wrong time.
But every accident, properly viewed,
- is an opportunity, isn't it, Mr. Donovan?
- Well...
Your country refuses to recognize
the German Democratic Republic.
They prefer to make up stories that
the GDR doesn't exist, for instance.
Sorry.
As a means of forcing your government's
recognition of this real place, sir,
in which you find yourself, the GDR,
the attorney general is happy
to negotiate with you
as a representative of your government
for Mr. Pryor's return.
Mr. Vogel, I'm not here as
a representative of my government.
All right.
I think that's childish, Mr. Donovan.
Well, I have no official status.
Fine. You do not represent the USA,
I do not represent the GDR.
My client is Lydia Abel, Rudolf's wife.
And I have also...
Lydia is the daughter. Helen is the wife.
Well...
I am prepared to offer Frederic Pryor's
exchange for Rudolf Abel's.
Then let's be clear.
We will produce Rudolf Abel.
You will produce, at the same time,
the student, Pryor.
- At the same time?
- Absolutely.
The exchange on offer is a Russian
at the end of his life...
for an American student
at the start of his.
Schischkin? He's not an embassy secretary.
Ivan Schischkin is the KGB's
chief in western Europe.
Well, whatever he is, he's relaying
our proposal to Moscow and...
they'll decide.
Could I borrow a coat? I lost mine.
- How did you lose your coat?
- You know, spy stuff.
- I'll get you another coat.
- Good, because...
So who is... who is this Vogel?
Him, we don't know. He might be
what you said he said he is.
Friend of the attorney general. Just some
guy the GDR tapped to handle this.
Sounds like the East Germans
are fighting for a place at our table.
The GDR gets Abel back for the Russians...
winning their respect and capturing
the headlines for their cause.
Which, of course,
puts East Germany on the map.
But we don't care about their map.
Stick with the Russians.
It's Powers for Abel.
So, does all this mean
this might actually happen?
Yeah, that's what you seem
to be telling me.
We'll put Abel on a plane,
he'll be here Friday.
So, if Schischkin gets the okay,
all that's left is the mechanics
of the trade.
- How we swap our guy for their guy.
- Our "guys."
Two guys. Powers and Pryor.
No, now don't go bleeding heart on me.
Powers is the whole ball game.
Forget this Ivy League boy,
who obviously thought it was a good idea
to study Soviet economics in Berlin
in the middle of the Cold War.
Powers is who we need.
You don't even like Powers.
Everybody hates Powers.
He didn't kill himself and he let
the commies parade him on television.
He's the most hated man in America.
After Rudolf Abel, maybe.
And me.
Now wake up!
I gotta sleep.
I just gotta sleep.
I told you, you can sleep
once we talk what we need to talk.
You must focus on me.
Your government doesn't care about you.
You know that. Any of you.
You know that twelve U-2 pilots
incurred brain damage?
They're vegetables because
of altitude, insufficient oxygen.
But they keep you flying, Gary.
You and your friends.
They gave you this. A scratcher, yes?
Potassium cyanide.
Does that look like they care about you?
What is the construction
of the destructor unit?
By what means is this unit operated?
With what explosives is the unit charged,
and what destruction is it capable of?
I don't know. The pilots were never
shown any of the equipment.
How wide far can the radar
- map an area during an overflight?
- I don't know, I don't know!
Were you making
the overflight on April 9th
over the industrial area and MiG
bomber base at Baranovichi?
I was not. This was my first overflight.
I need to know about
engine-out to glide ratio.
How the plane gets so high.
We know it reaches altitude
of 70,000 feet.
Gary, we know this. And I need
to know where the planes have flown.
Where they have flown, Gary.
And we must have this talk now.
Now.
And then you can sleep a little.
Sir, wake up.
Wake up, sir.
- Sir, can you come with me, please?
- Yeah.
- We gotta move.
- Yeah, of course.
- Can you come with me, please? Okay.
- Yeah.
- Got your glasses?
- What time is it?
It's late, but we need to talk...
and then we need to get on a plane, okay?
- Yep. Upsy-daisy!
- Upsy-daisy.
That's right. There we go.
Keep it moving. Thank you.
Other way, other way. There we go.
- You say a plane?
- This way, please. Keep moving.
So, I received a favorable decision
from Moscow on your proposal
that we help our friends in
the German Democratic Republic...
by exchanging Mr. Powers for Mr. Abel.
That's swell.
May I suggest the Glienicke Bridge
as a place of a swap?
- Why not Checkpoint Charlie?
- We're not looking for publicity.
The Glienicke Bridge is very quiet,
especially early in the morning.
Glienicke Bridge.
I'll run that by our side.
We can have Abel here on Friday.
So, Saturday morning?
- Always impatience, yeah?
- I want to get home and get into bed.
So, Saturday morning?
- 5:30?
- All right.
We're done here. This is a number...
in case anything should come up.
- All right.
- Someone will answer at any hour.
I don't expect to use it.
Shall we toast the arrangement?
Why not?
Armenian brandy.
Good bracer for your cold.
Thank you.
Would you mind...
This is not part of our business but...
I'd like to ask you a couple of questions.
You do not have to answer.
I shall answer what I know.
I like this guy, your guy.
What happens to your guy
when he gets home?
Well, we have to make a determination
whether our guy is now your guy.
Now, as I said to you before, he's acted
honorably. He's still your guy, believe me.
Of course you will say that
if it were true...
and if it were not true.
I guess it has come down to that?
Well, forgive me for pushing, but...
is he in any danger
if the determination is made?
Well, goodness.
As things are now, everyone is in danger.
- Cheers.
- Na zdorovie.
There will be no exchange
on Glienicke Bridge.
Excuse me, sir.
There will be no exchange.
Not for Frederic Pryor.
Mr. Vogel, I thought yesterday
we had agreed.
We agreed on an exchange, Abel for Pryor.
Now I learn you are a rug merchant
selling the same rug to two customers.
- Abel for Pryor you sell to us.
- Yeah.
And Abel for Powers
you sell to the Soviets.
I'm not quite sure what the problem is
if the arrangement satisfies
two parties or three or four.
- What difference does it make?
- The arrangement does not satisfy this party.
Now, Mr. Vogel, please...
Obviously you do not know
who you are dealing with.
Here's the interest of the German
Democratic Republic.
To deal with, and to be seen to be dealing
with another sovereign power,
the United States. An equal power.
Instead you treat us as stooges
for the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics.
Can we just call them the Russians?
It'll save time.
I have an appointment, sir.
I think it's you who are wasting time.
Now, tell me if I am describing this wrong.
You have a kid, a university student.
Someone you know is not a spy,
who's no threat to you.
And in exchange for this person
who is worthless to you,
you play an equal part in an exchange
between the Russians and the Americans.
And this is one transaction
between us and the two of you.
We're not trying to do two things here, sir.
We're just doing one thing. One, one, one.
It's hard for me to see how the Republic of
East German Democrats is being slighted.
You agreed with the Soviets
without consulting me.
- Is this a negotiation or a conspiracy?
- For it to be a conspiracy,
there would have to be harm to you.
There's just benefits here.
- We're of agreeing interests.
- No, you decide they agree.
- Where is your appointment, sir?
- In the West. Ku'damm.
Good.
Look around you. How does the Eastern
sector compare with the West?
Our Russian friends have decided that
we should not rebuild our capital city.
But we live in this ruin
made by our Russian friends.
Go ahead, make your deal with
these Russians. We won't be part of it.
There is no deal without Pryor.
We're not leaving him here.
- Is this your position or your government's?
- Sir, I'm here. I'm talking to you.
But you are not a representative of your
government. You don't know who you are.
Neither do we. You should be careful.
This is not Brooklyn, Mr. Donovan.
Look, sir. You must know
that in every respect that matters,
I represent my government.
You know who I am.
Do I?
Do you have the proper papers?
Of course not. It doesn't matter.
An American lawyer like you
can talk your way out of anything.
Can't you?
- You go with him.
- Why?
- It's passport problem.
- What problem? What's the problem?
You go with him.
And remember, we control
the fate of Frederic Pryor.
My God!
Yeah, I'll start with some coffee, please.
Then I'll have the Hilton combo
and the American breakfast.
- And coffee.
- Both breakfasts?
- Yeah, yeah.
- One first or...
Both first, both.
Whenever they're ready. And coffee.
You shouldn't be here.
Well, sometimes in Germany,
you just want a big American breakfast.
What happened? Where were you last night?
Vogel arranged for me to spend
some time in the East.
Oh, Jesus.
Frankly, it's not that much worse than
where you have me here in the West.
So the Russians
are fine with the exchange,
but now Vogel is saying that
the East Germans won't do it.
We're not gonna get Pryor.
Great, good. So the Soviets are set.
We get Powers.
We get Powers. Well done.
No, the East Germans won't do it.
We won't get Pryor, and that kid matters.
Every person matters.
Sure, that's why you tried.
That's why you tried.
Abel's on his way,
so we're all set for tomorrow morning.
Makes things simple. Makes things simple.
We are not getting the kid.
Yeah, I understand. We're set.
We can ignore the message
we got this morning.
What message?
From the East Germans.
They called the number I gave you.
They said they wanted
to speak to you today.
- Vogel called?
- No. Office...
Harald Ott, East German attorney general.
Wanting what? What does he want?
Well, to talk to you. But it's okay,
I can't ask you to go back there.
And listen, you seem to be persona
non grata to some elements,
- so we won't push our luck.
- So he wants to see me.
What time?
Oh, no, no. Now, listen. You...
You don't need to go. In fact,
you shouldn't go. In fact, you can't go.
We're set with the Soviets.
We don't want to screw it up.
- I'm not gonna screw it up.
- You're not going!
- Don't be a pain in the ass.
- I ordered.
Enjoy your big American breakfast.
I thought it should be negotiated at
the highest level as a courtesy to you.
I thank you, sir.
I don't know how things
became so confused.
Well, I guess sometimes they just do.
For sake of clarity, I say we are
fully prepared to exchange
the so-called student, Pryor,
for Rudolf Abel.
I understand from Mr. Vogel
that Pryor is very important to you.
Yes, but...
We'll do a memorandum to that effect.
Oh, a memorandum.
Certainly, we commit
to a bi-lateral exchange.
Yes, yes, sure. I'm not sure
what that means but...
My country also insists
on Francis Gary Powers.
No!
This is how things became so confused.
Powers. What use is he, sir?
You want him back for punitive reasons?
What's done is done.
He has divulged what he will divulge,
as no doubt Abel has also.
We are offering instead
someone who you insist is innocent.
And this is right.
This is who you should retrieve.
The future. Look to the future.
Ott.
I'm sorry. If you could
give me a moment, sir.
I'm very sorry. The attorney general regrets
that he had to leave on urgent business.
- He left?
- Yes. Many apologies.
- I've been waiting for over an hour.
- Very sorry, sir.
Young man.
Come here.
It's all right. Come here.
Take a seat.
Oh, come on, come on. Sit down.
Do you like your job here?
- It's a very good job, sir.
- It must be. Must be interesting.
- Oh, yes, sir.
- And important, too.
And your English is... is good.
Yes, I hesitate to say it's excellent.
But it's excellent, sir.
Good, good. Good.
See, I just lost my negotiating partner
and I need somebody to talk to,
and you seem like a reasonable young man.
Can I talk to you?
It's all right.
It's all right. I just...
I just need you to give
a message to your boss.
But it has to be very, very, very clear.
You understand?
Yes, sir. But perhaps
you should wait until he...
No, no. The thing is, I have
this cold and I wanna get home...
and get in bed.
- Can you give him the message?
- Certainly.
Well, this is the message.
"There is no deal for Abel
unless we get Powers and Pryor."
- Do you understand?
- Yes, sir.
It's arranged for tomorrow morning.
It will not happen unless we get two men.
- Those two men. Two, two, two.
- Yes, sir.
If there is no deal...
your boss must tell the Soviets.
He has to tell the Soviets
that they are not getting Rudolf Abel.
Yes, sir.
Oh, and tell him this.
That so far, Abel has been a good soldier,
but he thinks he's going home.
If we had to tell him
that he's not going home,
that the Soviets don't even want him,
that he's never going home...
Well, I imagine his behavior might change.
And who will be held responsible for that?
That's a long message.
- Did you get it all?
- Yes, sir. Got it.
Good.
You're a good man.
And also tell him there's no deal unless
we hear before the end of business today.
He has the number.
If the exchange isn't gonna happen,
no reason for everybody to get up
first thing in the morning.
No, sir, that would be pointless.
You're kidding me!
- You're kidding me!
- Not really. I need some change.
This is exactly what you
weren't supposed to do.
My instructions were
to feel out the situation.
Your instructions were to get
Powers, not Pryor.
That was not the original deal.
You fouled it all up!
How do you know?
I feel pretty good about it.
- You fucked it all up!
- Oh, don't worry.
- I think it's gonna be fine.
- How do you know? You don't know that.
United States. New York, New York. Danke.
Look, this whole thing...
has been to feel me out.
Would I swap one for one and which one?
But I said "No, two for one."
So they know where we stand.
Yeah, what if they think
about it and say...
"Forget it! You keep our guy,
we keep your guys"?
Well, then I have fucked it all up.
Hey, honey! It's me.
Yeah. The fishing's been great.
I'm in London, just for one more meeting,
then I'm on my way home.
Yeah, yeah, I remember that marmalade.
It's that shop right by Regent's Park.
All right, I will if I have the time.
Hey, can I say hi to Roger?
Could I say hi to the girls?
Is anyone not busy?
Have they even noticed I'm not around?
We're on.
Two for one.
Hot dog.
Let's have a drink.
- One wrinkle.
- What is that?
They won't release Pryor
with Powers, not at the bridge.
They'll release him at the same time.
When the Russians give us
Powers on the bridge,
they'll release Pryor
over Checkpoint Charlie.
What does that mean?
I think it means,
"We wanna have the last word."
But they will do it.
You tell me. You felt them out.
Where are they? Where's our guy?
Where's our guy?
- They're late.
- Nobody's late. We're early.
- May I?
- Yeah.
- Hoffman.
- Yeah?
- I think they have...
- What?
- ...snipers.
- Well, I'm sure they do.
How are you sure they do?
Because we have snipers.
Step out, sir.
Jim.
Dear Jim.
- How are you?
- Happy to see you.
Have you arranged all this for me?
Well, let's see what this is before I...
I take credit for it.
Any word about Pryor
from Checkpoint Charlie?
Nothing cooking yet.
Excuse me, sir.
This is Lieutenant Joe Murphy, United States
Air Force, here to identify Powers.
- Lieutenant Murphy.
- Sir.
There may be a slight glitch.
I was a young man when I left.
Who will they find to identify me?
Well, I hope it's not
your East German family.
I doubt they could identify each other.
Looks like our party.
Well, let's go.
You can stay here, Donovan.
Not likely.
Open the gate.
What do you think will happen
when you get home?
I think...
I'll have a vodka.
Yeah.
But, Rudolf,
is there not the possibility...
That my people are going to shoot me?
Yes.
- You're not worried?
- Would it help?
To answer your question, my friend,
I acted honorably. I think they know that.
But sometimes people think wrong.
People are people.
Let's see how they greet me.
What can I look for?
If I'm embraced
or just shown the back seat.
Da.
Take off the hat.
Hey, Powers.
Hey, Murph.
Yeah, that's Powers.
All right, Mr. Donovan. We go now!
Hang on.
Believe me, I will tell you.
There's no one here.
They're releasing another man
at Checkpoint Charlie.
We're just confirming that he's there.
Now!
As per plan, if you please.
Let's go. Pryor will show up
or he won't. Let's go.
They're waiting to see
if we'll do it without him.
We just have to stand here,
show them we won't.
I don't give a shit what they want.
We have our objective.
Go ahead, Abel.
Go ahead, sir. You can go.
If it is not to plan, we go home.
We exchange now or we go home!
- You're waiting for another man?
- Yup.
You want him, too.
I want him.
Doesn't matter what he wants, sir.
I'm in charge and you are free to go.
Please go. Walk across.
I can wait.
It's something. I'm not sure yet.
Hang on!
Let's go.
We got him!
I...
I sent you a gift, Jim.
It's a... it's a painting.
I hope it has some meaning to you.
I'm sorry.
I didn't think to get you a gift.
This is your gift.
You okay?
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Mr. Donovan. Colonel Abel
asked me to give this to you.
Pardon me, sir.
Were you in charge of this thing, sir?
- Yeah.
- Well, I gotta thank you.
I gotta thank somebody.
I gave them nothing. I gave them nothing.
It doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter what people think.
You know what you did.
Welcome home.
What a trip.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
- Did you get the marmalade?
- Yes, yes. Yep.
Yep.
I did.
As ordered.
Jim.
- This is from Arno's.
- So?
- On the corner!
- Well, honey, I was busy. I'm sorry.
- Oh, for Pete's sake.
- We were so busy. How's Roger? Is he home?
He's home. Carol's home,
Peggy's home. Everyone's home.
Mom! Come quick! Look!
Mom, come here!
- Come see this! Look! Watch!
- Come on!
Francis Gary Powers
has been released from prison
in the Soviet Union
and turned over to American authorities
early this morning in Berlin.
The President has commuted
the sentence of Rudolf Abel.
Mr. Abel has been deported
and has been released in Berlin.
Efforts to obtain Mr. Powers' release
had been underway for some time.
In recent efforts,
the United States government
has had the cooperation and assistance
of Mr. James B. Donovan,
a New York attorney.
Frederic L. Pryor, an American student
held by East German authorities
since August of 1961...
I thought Daddy was fishing.
For salmon.
Abel now has disappeared
into the communist world.
Powers is here, answering questions.
And Donovan has gone back
to his law practice.
And now, here is George Fenneman...