We are now
closer than we've ever been.
We are now closer than
we have ever been to victory.
Some...
Some are already
calling it the greatest...
calling it the greatest victory
in the history
of mankind.
Some are calling it already...
We are closer than
we have ever been to victory.
Some are already calling it
the greatest victory
in the history
of military campaigns.
Today, I can announce
that the so-called
Western Forces
of Texas and California
have suffered
a great loss.
A very great defeat
at the hands
of the fighting men and women
of the United States military.
The people
of Texas and California
should know that they will be
welcomed back
to these United States
as soon as their illegal
secessionist government is deposed.
I can also confirm
that the Florida alliance
has failed in its attempt
to force the brave people
of the Carolinas
into joining the insurrection.
Citizens of America,
we are now closer than ever
to a historic victory.
As we eliminate
the final pockets of resistance,
God bless you all
and God Bless America.
Give us some water!
We've been waiting
for two hours.
We want water!
My baby!
Lee.
No!
You all right?
Help!
Here, here.
You okay?
I'm fine.
- What?
You're Lee Smith?
This is crazy.
- Take this.
- Oh, no, I can't do that.
Take it and put it on.
Thank you so much.
Run!
You woke up
in Des Moines, Iowa.
And he's wearing
my wedding ring.
Hey!
Jesus. The wifi
is fucking slow.
The word I'm getting,
it's July 4th.
The word you're getting.
Like everyone in this room
hasn't already heard his bullshit.
July 4th, Sam.
The optics
are irresistible.
The Western Forces
are stopped 120 miles from D.C.
The Florida Alliance
aren't far south of that.
The WF wasn't stopped.
They stalled.
They lost
their supply lines.
What is the race to Berlin?
There's no coordination
between the secessionists.
You watch.
As soon as D.C. falls,
they'll turn on each other.
Really?
It's every night
this week.
- Ugh.
- They'll switch to the generator.
Upload was almost done.
So where you kids
headed tomorrow?
Staying in New York a while
or venturing out?
Fuck you.
- Come on, Joe.
- So you can beat us there?
I couldn't beat you
in a brisk walk.
We're going to
D.C., Sammy.
Tomorrow morning,
first thing.
Yeah, front line, I figured.
No, no,
not the frontline.
D.C.
What?
I'm gonna photograph
the president.
Joe's gonna
interview.
Photograph
and interview the president?
In D.C.?
That's the idea.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Are you serious?
They shoot journalists
on the side in the capital.
They literally see us
as enemy combatants.
Not a single interview
in 14 months.
And how are you
gonna do this?
We get there
before anyone else does.
You think there's a rush
to get executed
on the soft lawn?
Sam, July 4th,
July 10th.
Westcoast Forces,
fuckin'
Heartland Maoists,
it's all the same.
D.C. is falling and the President
is dead inside the...
Interviewing him
is the only story left.
It's not a story
if it never gets filed.
Lee, can I please
talk you out of this bullshit?
What do you think
the route's gonna be like?
There's nothing direct.
The interstates have vaporized.
And you can't get anywhere near Philly.
So you gotta go west,
maybe as far as Pittsburgh.
Then circle in
from West Virginia.
You already had that route
all figured out, huh, Sammy?
Yeah, okay, I was kind of
looking to get down there myself.
- Knew it.
- Not D.C.
I don't want a piece
of your suicide pact.
I want Charlottsville, frontline.
- Sam.
- Hear me out.
Just 'cause
I'm a rival news outlet...
You're not
a fucking rival.
You think I care if you
fight with whatever's left
of The New York Times?
You're worried
I'm too old.
Can't move quick enough.
Aren't you?
Sure.
Yes.
But...
You're gonna make me
explain why I have to be there?
If it's the frontline you want, half the press
in this room are gonna be heading there
within 24 hours.
You want me to walk around
this flipping room begging for a ride?
I'm gonna finish the upload upstairs
and pass out.
Hopefully it'll be time
by the time I wake up.
My vote,
if Sammy wants a ride,
I'm good with it.
You two figure it out.
Thank you, Lee.
Yeah, thank you, Lee.
Make me the bad guy.
Ma'am, just a warning.
If you take the elevator,
we do sometimes have power cuts
which might mean
a delay in your journey.
A delay?
We offer the option
to use the stairs.
I'm on the tenth floor.
Your choice, ma'am.
Miss Smith?
Hey, it's me.
Do you
remember me from earlier?
Yeah. How did you know
I was...
I didn't mean
to, like, stalk, but, um,
I know a lot of the press
use this hotel.
And, um, I wanted
to say thanks.
And I want
to give you this back.
Oh, no.
It's okay, keep it.
- But...
- Keep it.
And buy
a helmet.
And some Kevlar, okay,
if you're planning
on attending more stuff like that.
I am, yeah, going to.
I'm a photographer and I wanna be
a war photographer actually.
By the way, you have
the same name as my hero.
Lee Miller.
She was one of the first
photo journalists
into Dacau.
Do you know her stuff?
Yeah, I know
who Lee Miller is.
Of course.
But I want to say that
you're also one of my heroes.
And you've got
the same name too.
Wow.
Thank you.
I'm in good company.
- What's your name?
- Jessie.
Jessie Collin.
So, Jessie, I've gotta walk up
ten flights of stairs.
But, if I ever see you again,
you better be wearing Kevlar
and not fluorescent.
You bet.
A word.
What the fuck
is that girl doing here?
Right. So, she came over
to the table last night
after you went to bed
and we got talking and...
She's very cool.
And wanted to tag along.
So she's coming with us?
Lee, you let Sammy
tag along.
You think he's gonna do well running for cover
with bullets flying over his head?
She's a kid,
did you notice that?
She's, like, 23,
and she wants to do what we do.
She wants to do what you do.
We had to start one day.
Were you much older
than she is now?
Whatever happens,
she goes no further than Charlottesville.
All right. Let's go.
You don't want to miss this.
Mr. President, do you regret
any actions implemented
during your third term
in office?
I'm not gonna
softball him, Sammy.
In retrospect, Mr. President,
do you still think it was wise
to disband the FBI?
Passive aggressive.
Sir, how is your policy evolving in the use
of air strikes against American citizens?
Now we're talking.
Just be sure
you get the words out
before the piano wire
gets too tight.
There's a gas station
up ahead.
Looks open.
We got
over half a tank.
What do you think?
Any chance to refuel,
we should take.
Okay.
Help you, folks?
Just looking for gas.
Y'all look fuel permit.
No, we're...
We're actually just passing through.
Can't help, sir.
Sir, if we pay.
I was never gonna
give it free.
Over the odds.
What's over the odds?
Three-hundred.
For half a tank
and two cans.
Three hundred buys you
a sandwich.
We got ham or cheese.
Three hundred Canadian.
Okay.
Hey.
Stretching your legs?
Uh, no, I just saw something
from the road.
This isn't going
to take long.
Sure.
Are we good?
Yeah, we're good.
I told her,
I don't mind if she looks.
- Who are they?
- Looters.
I just met him.
I used to know that guy.
Went to high school together.
He didn't talk too much.
Much more talkative now.
We've been debating what to do
with them for two days now.
We go around in circles.
Tell you what.
Why don't you put us
and them out of our misery
and make a call?
I'll put rounds
in them right now.
Or beat 'em up
a little more.
Strap them to the front.
We'll let them go
after a couple of days.
Flip the coin if you like.
Would you stand with them?
- Stand with them?
- Yeah.
I'd like to take your picture.
Okay.
Stand over there?
Yeah.
Where do you want me?
Uh, between the two.
Got you.
I didn't take a photo.
I didn't take a single photo.
I didn't even remember
a camera's on me.
Like, oh, my God, like,
why didn't I
just tell him not to shoot them?
They're probably
gonna kill them anyway.
- How do you know?
- He doesn't know,
but that's besides the point.
Once you start asking yourself
those questions, you can't stop.
So we don't ask.
We record,
so other people ask.
Wanna be a journalist?
That's the job.
- Hey, Lee.
- What?
Back off.
What am I saying
that's wrong?
I'm not saying it's wrong,
she's just shook up.
Lee doesn't understand
shook up.
Whoa, huh?
I'm not being protective of her?
You're the idiot
who let her in this car.
What happened back there
is nothing in comparison
to what we're heading into.
You need to understand...
Shit, she's crying.
The back seat
is both kindergarten
and an old people's home.
How did this happen?
Lee, what the fuck?
Lee's right.
I won't make
that mistake again.
...on the so-called peace summit
could only be rejected,
duly rejected by all
free thinking Americans.
To the secessionists,
I say only this.
I pledge allegiance to the flag
of the United States of America.
We stand ready to fulfill
the promise of our forefathers,
to the flag, to the nation,
and to God.
Stop here a minute.
This feel like a good place
for a toilet break?
Just pull in.
Come with me.
Shoot it.
- Shoot the helicopter?
- Yeah.
It's gonna make
a good image.
FE2s.
You don't see them
around much.
Yeah.
They're my dad's
cameras actually.
No worries,
not dead.
He's...
sitting on his farm in Missouri
pretending like none of this
is happening.
Lee,
I'm sorry for jamming my way
into your ride, okay?
I know
you're really angry about it,
and I know you think
I don't know shit, but...
I'm not angry
about that, Jesse.
I don't care what you do,
or don't know.
Okay, but you are
angry with me.
There is no version of this
that isn't a mistake.
I know, because I'm it.
Joe and Sammy
are it.
- It's my choice.
- Right.
Then I'll remember that
when you lose your shit,
or you get blown up or shot.
Would you photograph
that moment if I get shot?
What do you think?
Every time I survived
a war zone,
and got the photo,
I thought I was sending
a warning home.
"Don't do this."
But here we are.
So it's existential.
What is?
What's eating you.
Don't worry about me, Sammy.
Am I allowed to say
I remember you at her age?
And I wasn't so different?
You weren't so different.
You think
you're being hard on her,
and I think
you're being hard on yourself.
- Okay, Rider.
- Damn it, Lee.
Stop.
I'm speaking truth.
And for the record, sure,
I'm worried about that girl.
And I'm worried
about you too.
What are you worrying
about Lee for?
Lee's lost her faith
in the power of journalism.
State of the nation is QED.
I can't answer
to that, Sammy.
But I can tell you,
this gunfire,
is getting me
extremely fucking hard.
Look at that shit
light up the sky.
It's not our story.
Yeah.
But you know,
bang bang.
We're not going anywhere
near that in the dark.
But sunup?
If they're still at it,
we'll take a look.
Cool.
Thanks.
Action tomorrow.
We're going down there?
Yeah.
But not you.
You're gonna...
You're gonna hang back.
I don't wanna hang back.
You have to hang back.
I'm not hanging back.
You should see your face.
Stomach doing turns. Right.
You don't get
a minute of sleep tonight.
My advice,
don't expect to sleep.
That way if you do, it's a...
It's a nice surprise.
You're gonna sleep?
I got a little bit Ativan.
Got plenty.
I can give you some if you like.
I know, it's okay.
Or, I can stay up with you.
Keep you company.
No, I...
I don't wanna be
a burden or whatever.
You sure?
But seriously,
if you do get freaked out
or something, just wake me up.
It's not nice
being scared alone.
Thanks, Joe.
You bet, doll.
No!
I said surround the building!
No! Fuck!
Come on!
Get me the fuck
out of here!
I said don't slice
the fucking building!
Got it.
Dude, jump in!
Get ready to move.
- Get the smoke.
- I gotta get the fuck out of here!
- Fuck!
- Slow down!
Count of three.
Three, two, one.
Count of three!
Fuck!
You all right?
- I'm gonna get him!
- Forget him.
- Yeah!
- Yeah, move it!
You gotta move!
You gotta get it right now!
Move back!
Got you. Hang in.
Stay over there.
Fuck! Give me gauze.
I need help.
Holy fucking shit!
What a fucking rush!
- You're press?
- Yes, ma'am.
IDs.
Okay. Are you guys
staying the night?
Yeah, just one.
Park over there.
There's a canteen
where you can eat.
And no tents available.
Thanks, ma'am.
You look good.
Eight, nine, ten.
Hey, get in there.
I'm gonna show these kids...
Check this out. Okay!
- Left, right.
- Here you go.
Yeah.
Your turn, son.
Hey, wait up.
Brought you something.
Thanks.
Don't forget to eat.
Yeah, I'm starving.
I'll eat once I handle this.
Developing negs on the road.
Yeah, I got myself
a pretty neat travel kit.
I'm impressed.
Want to know the secret
of getting the developer just right?
Hmm.
Body temperature.
- Smart.
- Thank you.
So how about you tell me the story of
how you became a photo journalist?
You don't know?
I thought I was
one of your heroes.
Yeah, I do.
When you were in college,
you took the motherfucking
legendary photo
of the Antifa massacre.
Then you became
the youngest ever magnum photographer.
That would be
my Wikipedia page.
What's missing
from it?
I don't know. A lot.
Well, that's gotta
sit here for ten minutes.
So you might as well
expand a little.
What about your folks?
Well, actually
they're on a farm too.
- Oh?
- Except, Colorado.
Also pretending
this isn't happening.
No shit.
Hey, these are dry.
You should check them out.
Sure.
Still need a phone even though
you can't get a signal.
I don't want you
to see these.
Um...
They're not even in focus.
Like...
- Exposure is all wrong.
- Just keep looking.
Figure the strike rate
for keepers is 30 to one.
It's a great photo, Jessie.
Did we just
drive through a time portal?
It's a twilight zone.
Hey there. Welcome.
Feel free to look around.
Hey.
Out of interest,
are you guys aware
there's like
a pretty huge civil war
going on
all across America.
Oh, sure, but,
we just try to stay out.
Stay out?
With what we see on the news,
seems like it's for the best.
Yeah.
Well, let me know
if you want to try anything on.
Thanks.
- Lee.
- Mm.
What?
You're so war torn,
you can't try on a dress?
Jesus.
When you haven't
seen yourself in the mirror...
- Oh, my God. - in a few days.
- Shut the fuck up.
Turn around.
I want to take your photo.
No.
Come on.
Yes.
You're gonna
take the photo?
You told me not to rush.
Yeah, but there's a sweet spot,
and you're missing it.
No one will miss
your sweet spot.
Well, no, that was
not the moment.
Okay.
One more.
- Lee.
- Yes.
You're pretty
when you smile.
There you go.
Hey.
How about this?
Yeah, nice.
Not gonna
take a picture?
Right.
You know what, though,
running a little low on film.
You're mean.
I'm out.
I'm gonna go try this on.
You actually
bought something?
She did.
She's paying now.
So weird.
This place is like
everything I'd forgotten.
Funny.
I was thinking
it felt like everything I remembered.
Look at the tops
of the buildings.
Be subtle.
Wouldn't have suited us
anyway, Lee.
We'd have gotten bored.
I remain ready
to accept the full...
and unconditional surrender
of the secessionist forces.
Deliberate the people
of the subjugated states
and start rebuilding
our great nation.
Enough of this shit.
Words might as well be random.
What do you think
he'll actually say
if I do get a microphone
over to him?
Not much.
The ones that get taken,
Qaddafi, Mussolini, Ceausescu.
they're always lesser men
than you think.
At the end,
they let you down, Joe.
Just as long as he isn't dead
before I get there.
Hold up.
There was a turn off
three or four miles back.
Maybe we should turn around,
take another route.
Can you see anything?
No.
Nothing, no shapes,
no movement, nothing.
No.
Okay. I'm gonna drive forward,
I think.
Should I keep going?
Shit!
Where you going?
Sammy.
Don't be
such a hotshot.
Just keep
your head down.
No shit.
You want to try
drivin' on?
This guy's a good shot.
Hey.
What's going on?
Someone in that house,
they're stuck.
We're stuck.
Who do you think they are?
Hmm.
No idea.
Hey.
We're press.
Cool.
Now I understand why it's written
on the side of your vehicle.
Are you WF?
Who's givin' you orders?
No one's giving us
orders, man.
Someone's trying to kill us.
We're trying to kill them.
You don't know
what side they're fighting for?
Oh, I get it.
You're retarded.
You don't understand
a word I say.
Yo!
What's over there
in that house?
Someone shooting.
Guys.
Shut the fuck up.
I got good news.
Why don't you
put your head down then?
Thank you, Sammy.
I'm good.
Take it from an old hand.
Sleep any chance you get.
You never know
what's coming around the next corner.
Yeah, all right.
Sammy.
What?
Got a car
comin' up on us pretty fast.
What do you think?
I don't know.
Maybe they're just in a hurry.
Oh, they're in
a hurry, all right.
He smoked his tires
on the last corner.
Okay.
Well, we're not gonna
outrun anyone in this thing.
So slow down a little, Lee.
Let 'em pass.
Roger that.
Don't look out at 'em.
They just roll on by.
Oh, shit. They keep going.
What the fuck?
Tony?
- Fuck you!
- What the fuck!
How are you guys doing?
You just scared
the shit out of me.
Good. That was
the idea.
What the fuck
are you doing here?
I don't know, Joe.
What are you doing here?
Fuck you!
God, small world.
Small world, my ass.
They were following us.
Did you tell them
where we were headed back in New York?
Fuck no.
Hey, Tony, did Joe tell you
where we were going back in New York?
I don't know, Lee.
He was pretty drunk
when he was hitting on that girl
you got on the back seat.
- Oh...
- You're a dick.
Look, I must've been
so wasted.
Lee, I'm done with Bohai.
He's not good company.
He drives like a maniac.
Dude, what are you doing?
I come over to your car.
- Tony!
- Dude.
Are you fucking crazy, Tony?
- Dude...
- Keep the car steady.
No! Fuck!
Don't worry.
I've done this before.
What the fuck!
Keep the car
steady, Lee.
Give me a hand.
Get out of here.
Fucking mad.
You're crazy.
No way. That's so fucking...
I gotta do it.
What?
I'm doing it.
Jesus, Lee.
Don't turn the wheel.
My new passenger.
Much better, much better.
Pull over.
Bye bye, Tony.
Bye bye. See you in Washington.
Fuck you!
I told you
he drives like a maniac.
Where did they go?
This feel funny?
Where did your guy go, Tony?
He's just fucking around,
that's all.
I don't want him
fuckin' around.
I want Jessie
back in this car.
Relax, Lee.
He's just showing
how fast he can drive.
- The girl's fine.
- How the fuck do you know if she's fine?
Can you see her?
Whoa!
Fuck!
Oh, fuck.
Shit.
We need to go down there. Now.
If we go down there,
they're going to kill us.
No.
Those aren't government forces.
Not up here.
We got our press passes.
We're cool.
Those people do not want to be
seen doing what they're doing.
Tell us, Lee.
They're talking.
They're probably
just giving them a scare.
They killed all the people
in that fucking truck.
They could've killed
the whole town,
but they will stop now?
Who knows
where those bodies are from?
Are the bodies in uniform?
No, they're not.
I'm going down.
- I'm coming with you.
- Me too.
I'm telling you
every instinct in me says
this is death, okay? Death.
You stay. You stay 'cause you're old
and you can't run.
Fuck it.
Shit.
Fuck this.
Just doing the talking.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
White,
there's one hung up in there.
Hey!
Hey, guys.
What's happening?
Guess there's some kind
of misunderstanding here.
Yeah?
Yes, sir.
Those two guys over there,
they're my colleagues.
What kind of colleagues?
Journalists, sir.
We're actually just...
We're passing through.
Passing through to where?
Charlottsville.
Charlottsville?
What's in Charlottsville?
Good hiking.
I hear.
Actually we are...
No, we're covering
the university campus there.
They started the new program.
They are re-opening the school,
which is a surreal
feel good story.
Mm-hmm.
And I guess we all need that.
Right?
Yeah.
This guy
is your colleague?
Yeah.
- This guy here?
- Yes, he's my...
That guy?
Sir.
Just...
Just what?
- Just what?
- You know what?
- This... Just, please.
- What?
Just, please.
- Sir, please.
- Please. Sure.
- Yes, speak.
- Let us...
We're American journalists.
You told me that already.
Okay, we...
We work for Reuters.
Reuters doesn't
sound American.
It's a news agency.
I know
what Reuters is.
Sir. Okay.
- I'm just saying...
- Just saying, just what?
We're American, okay?
Okay.
What kind of American
are you?
Central American,
South American?
What?
Florida.
Florida?
Central?
What about you?
Where are you from?
Tell him, Jessie.
Missouri.
Missouri?
The "Show-Me" state, right?
Yes.
You know what they call it?
Why do they call it
the "Show-Me" state?
I don't know.
You don't know?
It's American.
It is American. 100 percent.
What about you?
Where are you from?
Colorado.
Colorado, Missouri.
That's what I'm talking about.
It's American.
Who is this guy
hiding over here?
Hey. Buddy.
What's your deal?
Where are you from?
Huh?
What?
You can't speak?
Are you mute?
You can't speak English?
Yes, you can?
Yes, you can.
Okay.
You open your mouth
and tell me where you're from.
Just make sure
it's clear fucking English.
Okay?
Where are you from?
I'm from... I'm from Hong Kong.
Oh, China?
China.
- No!
- What?
- You stop it, okay?
- Stop?
No, no, no!
- Who the fuck...
- Stop it!
Who do you think you are...
Get in the car!
Get in the fucking car!
Go, go, go, go!
Go!
We gotta stop.
What are you talking about?
I can't drive.
We can't stop.
You gotta fucking drive.
- Joe.
- I can't.
He's been hit. He's bleeding.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Fuck!
Fuck! Okay, get up.
Get up.
Let's go.
Come on. Let's go, Sammy.
- Okay.
- Come on.
Fuck!
We just heard about Sammy.
And the other two guys.
Tony. Bohai. Their names.
Lee, I'm really sorry.
I know what he was to you.
It's so fucked up.
Oh, it's so fucked up.
Now you wait until you hear what these two
embattled motherfuckers have to say.
Joe, I'm just trying to talk to Lee
about Sammy.
I know. Yeah, I heard.
Your condolences means a lot.
Now just tell her.
We loved Sammy, everyone did.
Thank you, Anya.
Fuck. The Western Forces
are moving to D.C.
Earlier today, the government,
military, basically surrendered.
Yeah, that's true.
This is the only protection now.
Few do or die soldiers,
handful of secret service.
WF's gonna roll right in.
So you and I, we're too late.
We missed the story.
And Sammy didn't even die
for anything good.
Where's Joe?
Processing.
Me, too.
Hardly knew Sammy
compared to you, but...
Yeah, you knew him.
The man you were with,
that's who he was.
It may sound fucked up,
but there are so many ways
that it could've ended for him.
And a lot of them were worse.
He didn't want to quit.
These last few days,
I've never been scared
like that before.
And I've never
felt more alive.
Sniper!
Man down!
Move! Move, move, move!
Danger detection!
Move, move, move!
- Come here!
- Move, move, move!
Lee?
Let's go!
- Go, go, go!
- Come on. Come on.
Got him,
got him, got him.
Go, go, go, go, go!
Go! Go!
Get to the back!
In position now! Go! Go!
Fire!
Come on, stay down.
Stay down.
Walk you down.
We're here to help.
What do you need?
We got two over
and two on the tower.
I bet we can send a round
right through that tower.
Yeah, just fuckin' do it,
do it.
Get back. On me.
Drop that bitch.
Lee, get your head down!
What tower? On whose side?
Move, move, move!
Move, move!
Let's just go,
let's go, let's go!
Lee, you gotta move, okay?
You have to move.
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go!
Get down,
get down, get down.
They'll fall again.
Push it back, push it back.
Get back!
Staying clear!
Move it! Move it!
Fuck, Lee.
Let's move.
Move, move, move.
Move!
Get over here, now!
Come here!
Let's go!
Go, go, go.
Move, move.
Back here, back here.
Kill on the forehead!
I don't...
Keep it going.
Move it. Let's go. Let's go.
Go, go, go, go, go!
- Go now, fast.
- Go, go, go!
You're ready? On my count.
Oh, my God.
So fucking close.
Come on, let's go.
Again.
Western Forces have reached
the White House perimeter.
The president is now surrounded.
We have...
Just give me a minute.
We're gonna have to go again.
You get new shit?
Lincoln Memorial.
You?
WF rappelling out of a chopper
out on the roof
of the fucking Pentagon.
There's really
only one shot go, huh?
You know he's in there?
They got intel from the generals
that surrendered yesterday.
The president's right
in that fucking building.
Fuck.
What do you hear
they're gonna do with him?
Kill.
No capture.
Whoever gets a fucking gun
to his head first.
Hey, Lee!
Don't be mean
about the money shot, huh?
Got the beast.
Two support men
right outside.
President's on the move.
Fuck yeah.
He's bustin' out.
Vehicle coming through!
Beast, beast, beast!
I'm going to war!
His vehicle
has been stopped...
Go!
...by Western forces
as it attempted to escape.
He's not in there.
What?
Okay.
- Let's go.
- But...
- Let's go, Jessie.
- What do you mean? What?
Come on! Now!
Follow me. Follow me.
I think POTUS is movin' out.
Don't shoot, don't shoot.
Don't...
This place is empty.
Just stay the fuck
out of our way.
Secret Service agent,
Joy Butler.
- Drop it.
- I'm unarmed. I'm here to talk.
- Take it?
- Flood it.
I'm here to negotiate
the surrender of the president.
He's here.
You the WF?
Take a wild guess.
Can the president be entrusted
into your safe care?
Yes, ma'am. We'll take
real good care of him.
Just bring him out here.
We're not bringing him anywhere
until we have agreed terms.
You need to guarantee a safe
passage for the president.
And we need extraction
to a neutral territory.
We request Greenland or Alaska.
Nah, no terms.
Bring him out here.
We gotta move, sergeant.
Ma'am, the President
is willing...
Gunter! Poi! Jack!
Move him!
Come on, get back!
Just go. Go!
Out! Reloading!
- Get back!
- Look out!
- I got him!
Give it up!
Ready to crash!
Sir!
I'm out. Reloading, reloading.
Press back.
Sir!
Crash it!
Go! Go!
Move it.
Wait! Wait!
Don't move!
Chief, clear way!
Roger that!
Fuck the cross!
Check.
Forward.
Cutter, I'm moving across.
I need you to lead us in fire.
Charger,
you're going left.
Follow me. I'm going left.
You move when I move.
Copy you!
- Guys ready to move?
- Ready, ten!
Move! Move back!
Move!
Let's go!
You good?
Stay down.
Beacon flare!
Move! You gotta move on!
Move, move, go!
- Move it!
- Moving.
Ready.
Break out, break out,
break out.
Shakir! Shakir! Shakir!
- I'm out. Reloading.
- Changing.
Perfect crash!
Wait!
I need a quote.
Don't let... Don't let them
kill me.
Yeah, that will do.