You don't like flying, do you?
What gives you that idea?
You wanna know the secret
to surviving air travel?
After you get where you're going,
take off your shoes and socks.
Then you walk around on the rug barefoot
and make fists with your toes.
Fists with your toes?
I know. It sounds crazy. Trust me.
I've been doing it for nine years.
Yes, sir! Better than a shower
and a hot cup of coffee.
OK.
It's OK. I'm a cop.
Trust me. I've been doing this for 11 years.
The captain and the crew
would like to welcome you to Los Angeles.
Have a very merry Christmas.
Flight 247 to Tucson
now boarding at gate 14.
Ladies and gentlemen...
Ladies and gentlemen!
I want to congratulate all of you for
making this one of the greatest years
in the history of the Nakatomi Corporation.
On behalf of the Chief
Executive Officer, Mr Ozu,
and the Board of Directors,
we thank you one and all and wish you
a merry Christmas and a happy New Year!
Merry Christmas! Happy New Year!
Hey, Holly. What about dinner tonight?
Harry, it's Christmas Eve.
Families, stockings...
Chestnuts?
Rudolph and Frosty?
Any of these things ring a bell?
Actually, I was thinking more of
mulled wine, a nice aged Brie,
and a roaring fireplace.
You know what I'm saying?
Ginny, it's 5:40. Go join the party.
Have some champagne.
You're making me feel
like Ebenezer Scrooge.
Thanks. Do you think the baby
can handle a little sip?
That baby's ready to tend bar.
Last chance.
Bye.
McClane residence.
Lucy McClane speaking.
Hello, Lucy McClane.
This is your mother speaking.
Mommy! When are you coming home?
Pretty soon. You'll be in bed
when I get there, though.
Let me talk to Paulina, OK, hon?
And no snooping around the house
looking for presents.
Is Daddy coming home with you?
Well, we'll see what Santa
and Mommy can do, OK?
Put Paulina on. Bye, honey.
Paulina!
Hola, Mrs Holly.
Um, did Mr McClane call?
No, Mrs Holly. No telefono.
He probably didn't have time
before his flight.
It might be a good idea to make up
the spare bedroom, just in case.
Si, Mrs Holly. I do that already.
What would I do without you, Paulina?
California!
Hey, I'm John McClane.
Argyle. I'm your limo driver.
Nice bear.
OK... Argyle. What do we do now?
I was, uh, hoping you could tell me.
It's my first time driving a limo.
That's OK. It's my first time riding in one.
Relax. We got everything in this mug, man.
Look at this - CD, CB, TV,
telephone, full bar, VHS.
If your friend's hot to trot, I know
a few mama bears we can hook up with.
- Or is he married?
- He's married.
OK.
Oh, sorry about that. It's the girl's day off.
I didn't know you were gonna sit up front.
Your lady live out here?
About the past six months.
Meaning you still live in New York?
You always ask this many questions, Argyle?
Sorry. I used to drive a cab
and people would expect a little chitchat.
- So, you divorced?
- Just drive the car, man.
Hey, come on. You divorced?
You separated? She beat you up?!
She had a good job.
It turned into a great career.
- That meant she had to move here.
- You're very fast, Argyle.
So, why didn't you come?
Well? Why didn't you come with her?
What's up?
Because I'm a New York cop.
I got a backlog of scumbags
I'm still trying to put behind bars.
I can't just go that easy.
You thought she wasn't
gonna make it out here,
and she'd come crawling back to you
so why bother to pack, right?
Like I said, you're very fast, Argyle.
Mind if we hear some tunes?
Hey, that'll work.
No Christmas music?
This is Christmas music.
So your lady sees you,
you run into her arms,
the music comes up
and you live happily ever after, right?
I can live with that.
So, if it doesn't work out,
you got a place to stay?
I'll find a place.
I tell you what. I'll wait in the garage.
You score, give me a call on the car phone.
I'll take your bags to the desk.
You strike out, I'll get you a hotel.
- You're all right, Argyle.
- Remember that when you sign for the tip.
- Hi.
- Good evening.
I'm here to see Holly McClane.
Just type it in there.
Cute toy.
Yeah, if you have to take a leak,
it'll even help you find your zipper.
Christ!
- 30th floor?
- The party.
They're the only ones left.
Take the express elevator.
Get off where you hear the noise.
Thanks.
- Champagne, sir?
- Yeah, thanks.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Hey! Merry Christmas!
Jesus.
Fuckin' California!
I couldn't agree with you more.
Why don't I talk to him right now?
Hi. I'm looking for...
- Holly Gennero.
- Yeah.
Then you must be John McClane.
Joe Takagi. How was your ride in?
Nice. I have you to thank for that?
Seemed the least we could do.
- Quite a place you have here.
- It will be if we ever get it finished.
Still several floors under construction.
Holly went to fax some documents.
She should be back any minute.
In the meanwhile, her office is back here.
Ellis?
I was making a call.
This was the nearest phone.
I want you to meet John McClane,
Holly's husband.
Holly's policeman.
Ellis is in charge
of international development.
Heard a lot about you.
You missed some.
Can I get you anything?
Food? Cake?
Some watered-down champagne?
No, thank you. I'm fine.
You throw quite a party.
I didn't realise they celebrated
Christmas in Japan.
We're flexible. Pearl Harbor didn't work out,
so we got you with tape decks.
It's a double celebration. We closed
a big deal today, mainly due to Holly.
I'll be out in a couple of minutes.
John.
- Have you met everyone?
- We've been sticking him with spears!
Of course he has.
She was made for the business.
Tough as nails.
I was hoping you made that flight.
Show him the watch.
Later.
Show him. Are you embarrassed?
It's a token of appreciation
for all her hard work. It's a Rolex.
I'm sure I'll see it later.
Is there a place where I could wash up?
Sure.
You have to forgive Ellis.
He gets very depressed this time of year.
He thought he was
God's greatest gift, you know?
I know the type.
I think he's got his eye on you.
That's OK. I have my eye
on his private bathroom.
Where are you staying?
Things happened so fast
I didn't get a chance
to ask you on the phone.
Cappy Roberts retired out here.
- He said I could bunk with him.
- Cappy retired, huh? Where's he live?
- Romona.
- Ha! Pomona.
- Huh?
- Pomona.
- Yeah.
You'll be in the car half the time.
Why don't we make it easy?
I have a spare bedroom.
It's not huge or anything, but...
the kids would love
to have you at the house.
They would, huh?
I would, too.
Ooh!
Sorry.
I missed you.
Didn't miss my name, though, huh?
Except maybe when you're signing cheques?
Since when did you start using Ms Gennero?
This is a Japanese company.
They figure a married woman's...
You are a married woman.
- This conversation again?
- We never finished this conversation.
- I had an opportunity. I had to take it.
- No matter what it did to our marriage.
- It changed your idea of our marriage.
- You have no clue what my idea...
I know exactly what your idea
of our marriage should be.
Ms Gennero, I...
Excuse me.
Hi.
Mr Takagi is looking for you.
He wants you to say something to the troops.
Thank you.
Speech time.
Be back in a few minutes.
That was great, John.
Good job. Very mature.
So Kareem rebounds. Feeds Worthy
on the break, over to AC, to Magic,
then back to Worthy.
Boom! Two points.
We're in.
Links. ..
Re ch ts,
und wieder links.
Son of a bitch.
Fists with your toes.
Yeah, Argyle?
How's it going?
OK. Where are you?
At the garage.
What's with you and your lady?
The vote's not in yet.
- He, Bruder.
- Moment.
Nein! Nein! Nein!
Warte doch. Nicht!
Argyle?
Mac, you there? Hello?
You know the number. Use it.
Stay calm. Everything's going to be fine.
Everything's going to be fine.
Shit!
Think.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Due to the Nakatomi Corporation's
legacy of greed around the globe,
they're about to be taught a lesson
in the real use of power.
You will be witnesses.
Now,
where is Mr Takagi?
Joseph Yashinobo Takagi,
born Kyoto, 1937.
Don't move.
Family emigrated to San Pedro,
California, 1939,
interned at Manzanar, 1942 to '43,
scholarship student,
University of California,
1955.
Law degree, Stanford, 1962.
MBA, Harvard, 1970.
President, Nakatomi Trading.
Vice Chairman, Nakatomi Investment Group...
Enough.
And father
of five.
I am Takagi.
How do you do?
It's a pleasure to meet you.
OK, 32... construction, 33... computers.
Nice suit.
John Phillips, London.
I have two myself.
Rumour has it Arafat buys his there.
- This way?
- On the left.
"And when Alexander saw
the breadth of his domain
he wept, for there were
no more worlds to conquer."
The benefits of a classical education.
Oh, that's beautiful.
I always enjoyed to make models
when I was a boy.
The exactness, the attention
to every conceivable detail.
It's beautiful.
Is this what this is all about?
Our project in Indonesia?
Contrary to what you people may think,
we're going to develop
that region, not exploit it.
I believe you. I read the article in Forbes.
Mr Takagi...
I could talk about industrialisation
and men's fashions all clay,
but I'm afraid work must intrude,
and my associate here
has some questions for you.
Sort of fill-in-the-blanks questions.
I don't have that code.
You broke in here to access our computer?
Any information you get,
when Tokyo wake up, they'll change it.
You won't be able to blackmail
our executives...
Sit... down!
Mr Takagi, I'm really not
interested in your computer.
But I need the code key
because I am interested in the $640 million
in negotiable bearer bonds
that you have locked in your vault
and the computer controls the vault.
You want money?
What kind of terrorists are you?
Who said we were terrorists?
The bonds represent, at most,
ten days' operating capital
for your parent organisation.
It's really no more
than a temporary inconvenience.
Now...
the code, please.
It's useless to you.
There are seven safeguards on our vault.
The code key's only one.
You won't get it open.
Then there's no reason not to tell it to us.
- I told you.
- It's not over yet.
It's a very nice suit, Mr Takagi.
It would be a shame to ruin it.
I'm going to count to three.
There will not be a four.
Give me the code.
One,
two,
- three.
- I don't know it.
Get on a jet to Tokyo and ask the chairman.
You'll have to kill me.
OK.
We do it the hard way.
Tony, dispose of that.
Karl, check on Heinrich's work
on the machine floor.
Nothing.
See to Heinrich.
Now...
you can break the code?
You didn't bring me along
for my charming personality.
Argyle, tell me you heard the shots.
You're calling the police now.
Of course I'm still coming by later.
Sweetheart have I ever lied to you?
My boss thinks I'm on my way to Vegas.
Uli, get up on the pipes.
Marco, you go through here.
I'll throw you the cord.
Hans, we're on the roof.
Here.
Uli.
30 minutes to break the code,
two and a half hours
for the five mechanicals, at the minimum.
The seventh lock, however,
is out of my hands.
I'm sorry?
The seventh lock... the electromagnetic seal.
The circuits cannot be cut locally.
Trust me.
Why the fuck didn't you stop him, John?
Cos then you'd be dead, too, asshole.
Think, goddamn it! Think!
We've got a fire alarm.
Call 911.
Give them the guard's name
and cancel the alarm.
Then disable the sys...
Eddie, on what floor did the alarm go off?
Shall we go?
Nein.
Yes.
Hello, baby. Come to Papa. Come on.
Ah-ha-ha-ha!
Come on, baby.
Come on, baby. Come to Papa.
I'll kiss your fuckin' Dalmatian.
You stupid motherfuckers! No! No!
Turn the fuckin' truck around!
The fire has been called off, my friend.
No one is coming to help you.
You might as well come out
and join the others.
I promise I won't hurt you.
Drop it, dickhead. It's the police.
You won't hurt me.
Yeah? Why not?
Because you're a policeman.
There are rules for policemen.
Yeah, that's what my captain
keeps telling me.
Bet your ass I wish to proceed.
Nine million terrorists in the world
and I gotta kill one with feet
smaller than my sister.
I wanted this to be professional,
efficient, adult, cooperative.
Not a lot to ask.
Mr Takagi did not see it that way
so he won't be joining us
for the rest of his life.
We can go any way you want it.
You can walk out of here or be carried out,
but have no illusions - we are in charge.
So... decide now, each of you,
and please remember,
we have left nothing to chance.
Get them back!
"Now I have a machine gun."
"Ho... ho... ho."
A security guard we missed?
They're usually tired, old policemen.
No, this is something else.
Was hab' ich dir gesagt?
lch will, daB es keiner sieht.
We have to do something, Hans.
Yes, we do.
Tell Karl his brother is dead.
Tell him to come down.
Karl... komm soforz'.
Franco, Fritz,
take the body upstairs and out of sight.
I don't want the hostages
to think too much.
Komm sofort. Schnell.
I want blood!
You'll have it, but let
Heinrich plant the detonators
and Theo prepare the vault.
After we call the police,
you can tear the building apart
looking for this man,
but, until then, do not alter the plan!
And if he alters it?
What do you think?
Something's wrong.
COpS?
- John.
- John?
He can fuck this up.
What does he think he's doing?
His job.
Bullshit. His job's 3,000 miles away.
Without him, we still have
a chance to get out of here.
Tell that to Takagi.
Mayday, anyone copying channel nine.
Terrorists have seized the Nakatomi
building and are holding 30 people hostage.
I repeat.
Unknown number of terrorists,
six or more armed with
automatic weapons at Nakatomi Plaza,
Century City.
Where's the best place to transmit?
The roof! Go! Go!
It's the same address
as that fire signal.
I'll handle it.
Attention, whoever you are, this channel
is reserved for emergency calls only.
No shit!
Do I sound like I'm ordering a pizza?
No one kills him but me.
They have already killed one hostage.
They're fortifying their positions
while you're jerkin' me off!
Sir, I've already told you.
This is a reserved channel.
If this is an emergency call,
dial 911 on your telephone.
Otherwise, I'll report this as an FCC violation.
Fine! Come the fuck down here
and arrest me! Just send the police now!
See if a black-and-white can drive by.
Thought you guys just ate doughnuts.
- They're for my wife.
- Yeah.
- She's pregnant.
Bag it.
Big time.
Thanks.
Dispatch to 8-Lincoln-30. Over.
This is 8-LinC0ln-30.
Investigate a code two
at Nakatomi Plaza, Century City.
8-Lincoln-30 to Dispatch. I'm on my way.
Girls.
...auf dem Dachboden.
Shit! Where the fuck is it?
Oh, my God.
He's in the elevator shaft.
Perfect. The elevators are locked off.
He can't escape.
Shut him in and come back down.
Oh, fuck.
Karl, the police are probably
on their way already. Karl?
Christ.
I can stall them,
but not if they hear gunshots.
If you lock him in, he'll be neutralised...
Come out to the coast!
We'll get together, have a few laughs.
Now I know what a TV dinner feels like.
Such!
Karl, komm! Die Polizei!
Karl, die Polizei!
Well, it's about time.
No signs of disturbance, Dispatch.
Roger. Possible crank call.
Check the area again and confirm.
Who's driving this car - Stevie Wonder?
I do see a guard inside.
I'm gonna go in for a closer look.
Use caution.
Eddie?
I had a feelin' you'd be calling.
Evenin', officer. What can I do for you?
Wieviele sind es?
Nur ein Mann.
We had that false alarm.
You ask me, that goddamn computer
sent you on another wild-goose chase.
They been chasing bugs
ever since they installed it.
..Notre Dame on top of USC.
Aw, shit!
I got 5O bucks bet on them assholes.
Come on, come on,
where's the fuckin' cavalry?
Marco, er ist am 34. Geh, schnell, 34.
Bah!
..was good for 52 yards.
Mind if I look around?
Help yourself.
27 seconds left in this first period.
Seven to nothing, Notre Dame.
- Freeze, motherfucker! Drop it!
- Don't shoot!
- Put the gun down!
- OK! Don't shoot!
Drop that fuckin' gun!
Marco, down!
Ah, to hell with this!
You are done!
No more table! Where are you going, pal?
Next time you have a chance
to kill someone, don't hesitate.
Thanks for the advice.
- Sorry to waste your time.
- No problem at all.
- Merry Christmas.
- Merry Christmas to you.
Oh, for the love...
8-Lincoln-30 to Dispatch.
Go ahead.
A wild-goose chase at Nakatomi Plaza.
Everything here's OK. Over.
Shit!
Goddamn it! Jesus H Christ!
Welcome to the party, pal!
Get someone here now!
Policeman under automatic
rifle fire at Nakatomi!
I need backup assistance now!
Now, goddamn it! Now!
Monica, I can get us a table.
Wolfgang and I are very close friends.
I interviewed him!
..Nakatomi.
Repeat. Officer needs assistance at...
I'm at Nakatomi Plaza.
They're turning my car into Swiss cheese!
I need backup assistance now!
Now, goddamn it! Now!
Never thought I'd love to hear that sound.
All of you relax. This is a matter
of inconvenient timing, that's all.
Police action was inevitable...
and, as it happens, necessary.
So, let them fumble about outside
and stay calm. This is simply the beginning.
I told you all I wanted radio silence until...
I'm sorry, Hans. I didn't get that message.
Maybe you should have put it
on a bulletin board.
I figured since I waxed Tony,
Marco and his friend,
you and Karl and Franco might be lonely
so I wanted to give you a call.
How does he know so much about us?
That's very kind of you.
I assume you are
our mysterious party crasher.
You are troublesome
for a security guard.
Eeeh! Sorry, Hans. Wrong guess.
Would you like to go for double jeopardy
where the scores can really change?
Mm, these are very bad for you.
- Who are you, then?
- Just the fly in the ointment, Hans.
The monkey in the wrench,
the pain in the ass.
Whoa!
Check on all the others. Don't use the radio.
See if he's lying about Marco
and find out if anyone else is missing.
Mr Mystery Guest...
are you still there?
Yeah, I'm still here, unless you
wanna open the front door for me.
No, I'm afraid not,
but you have me at a loss.
You know my name, but who are you?
Just another American
who saw too many movies as a child?
Another orphan of a bankrupt culture
who thinks he's John Wayne,
Rambo, Marshal Dillon?
I was always partial to Roy Rogers, actually.
I liked those sequinned shirts.
Do you really think you have
a chance against us, Mr Cowboy?
Yippee-ki-yay, motherfucker.
I'll beat everyone if I get a remote.
I don't have the new pages.
Harvey, keep your pants on.
Sam, I'm begging Yo"-
Simon's with the remote.
I'll tell him to swing by.
I won't sit on this!
This is my story! I'm going out there!
Look, Sam. Tell you what.
You don't give me a truck, I'll steal a truck.
- Give us a break, Thornburg.
- Eat it, Harvey!
...four, three, two,
0H3.
Harvey, we're on the air.
Good evening. This is Harvey Johnson.
And I'm Gail Wallens.
This is Nightline News at Ten.
Our top stories on this Christmas Eve...
Take truck number five and get outta here.
He wasn't lying about Marco.
He's down on the street.
The other man was Heinrich,
and his bag is missing.
He had the detonator.
Theo.
Yo!
We may have some problems.
How's our schedule?
- Three down, four to go.
- Then don't waste time talking to me.
This is Sergeant Al Powell
of the LA Police Department.
If the person who radioed can hear me,
acknowledge this transmission.
I say again,
if the person who radioed
for help can hear me,
acknowledge this transmission!
I read you, pal. You the guy in the car?
What's left of him.
- Can you identify yourself?
- Not now. Maybe later.
This is a party line.
The neighbours got itchy trigger fingers.
Here's the deal. You got 30 or so
hostages on the 30th floor.
The leader's name is Hans.
We have to shut him up.
He's telling them everything!
Let him. I'm waiting for the FBI.
He can waste as much time as he likes
but we must find the bag.
- They have a freakin' arsenal here.
- We must have the detonators.
They got missiles and enough plastic
explosives to orbit Arnold Schwarzenegger.
They're down to nine,
counting the skydiver you met.
These guys are mostly European,
judging by their clothing labels, and...
cigarettes.
They're well-financed and very slick.
How do you know that?
I've seen enough phoney IDs
to recognise the ones they got
must have cost a fortune.
Add all that up, I don't know what it means,
but you got some bad-ass perpetrators
and they're hereto stay.
I hear you, partner. LA's finest are on it,
so light 'em if you got 'em.
Way ahead of you, partner.
So what do I call you?
Call me...
Roy.
Listen up, Roy, if you think of anything else,
don't be shy, OK?
In the meantime, find a safe place
and let us do our job. Understand?
They're all yours, AI.
Who's talking to 'em?
I am, sir. Sergeant Powell. Al Powell.
Dwayne Robinson. What's the deal?
What do these pricks want?
If you mean the terrorists,
we haven't heard from them.
Who have you been talking to?
We don't know. He won't give us his name.
But he appears to be the one who phoned.
He's killed one terrorist
and claims he capped off two others.
He claims?
Powell, has it occurred to you
he could be one of the terrorists,
or some nutcase in there?
I don't think so. In fact, I think he's a cop,
maybe not LAPD,
but he's definitely a badge.
- How do you know that?
- A hunch. Things he said -
like being able to spot a phoney ID.
Jesus Christ, Powell!
He could be a bartender for all we know!
TV's here.
Oh, shit.
- I have a request.
- What idiot put you in charge?
You did...
when you murdered my boss.
Now everybody's looking to me.
Personally, I'd pass on the job.
I don't enjoy being this close to you.
Go on.
We have a pregnant woman.
Relax. She's not due for a couple of weeks,
but sitting on that rock
isn't doing her back any good.
So I would like permission to move her
to an office with a sofa.
No, but I'll have a sofa
brought out. Good enough?
Good enough.
And unless you like it messy, I'd start
bringing us in groups to the bathroom.
Yes. You're right. It will be done.
Was there something else?
No, thank you.
Mr Takagi chose his people well, Mrs...?
Gen nero.
Ms Gennero.
We interrupt this programme
for a special bulletin.
This is Richard Thornburg
live from Century City.
Tonight, Los Angeles has joined
the sad and worldwide fraternity of cities
whose only membership requirement
is to suffer the anguish
of international terrorism.
Approximately two hours ago,
an unidentified group of men
seized control of the Nakatomi building,
sealing off all entrances and exits.
All telephone lines have been cut
and the only communication now possible
has been through the use
of CB communicators
which the group brought with them.
According to official sources,
the perpetrators of this building siege...
Unit five, hold your position.
We got Charlie unit in position
by the parking structure.
Let me ask you... does
this stairway go up to the escalator?
- Yeah.
- Tell them to go ahead.
What's going on?
What's it look like? We're going in.
Going in? That's crazy! There could be
over 30 hostages in there for all we know.
We don't know shit, Powell.
If there's hostages, how come
there are no ransom demands?
If there's terrorists in there,
where's their list of demands?
All we know is that
somebody shot your car up.
It's probably the same silly son of a bitch
you've been talking to on that radio.
Excuse me, sir,
but what about the body
that fell out the window?
- Maybe a stockbroker got depressed.
- We're ready.
- Light 'em up. Let's go.
- Hit your lights.
- Blue units, go.
- Lights on!
Powell?
Powell, you still with me, babe?
What's going on?
Yo, AI.
I'm here, Roy, but I'm busy right now.
I'll talk to you later.
- Al, what's wrong?
- I'll talk to you later.
If you are what I think you are,
you'll know when to listen, shut up, and...
and when to pray.
Jesus Christ! You're coming in, right?
I told you what kind
of people you're dealing with!
Let's load them up.
They'll be coming. Everyone get ready.
Theo, you are the eyes now.
- Rivers.
- Yo.
Begin your reconnoitre.
Let's go.
Shit!
Come on. Let's go.
Ow! Jesus!
All right, spread out.
Shut up.
Let's go.
You macho assholes. No! No!
Ahem... all right.
Listen up, 9W5-
'Twas the night before Christmas,
and all through the house,
not a creature was stirring, except
the four assholes coming in the rear
in standard two-by-two cover formation.
We're all set.
We're ready.
Kick ass.
Go!
Right. Let's do it.
Take cover!
They're shooting at 'em.
- It's panic fire. They can't see anything.
- They're shooting at the lights.
They're going after the lights. Call them back.
It's not happening.
Mike, burn it.
Don't be impatient.
Just wound them.
- Get them back. They're sitting ducks.
- They're almost in.
Send in the car. Send in the car.
Jesus Christ!
Rivers, Rodriguez, report.
Wait a minute.
What have we here, gentlemen?
The police have themselves an RV.
Southeast corner.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Get back! Get the fuck back!
Get over there.
Schnell! Schnell!
Mach schnell!
Weiter! Weiter! Weiter!
Mach schnell! Mach schnell!
Weiter!
Mach los! Mach los!
I see him!
- Feuer!
- Clear!
Oh, my God! The quarterback is toast!
Hang on, Rivers. That's an order.
Hit it again.
All right, you made your point!
Let 'em pull back!
Thank you. I'll take it under advisement.
Hit it again.
Fire.
Fuck me.
Get them out of the car! They're burning!
Fuck it.
Mach schnell! Mach los!
Let's see you take this
under advisement, jerkweed.
Geronimo, motherfucker.
Oh, Shit!
- They're using artillery on us!
- You idiot, it's not the police.
It's him.
Holy shit.
My God!
- Tell me you got that.
- I got it.
Eat your heart out, Channel 5.
We've had an update on the terrorist
takeover of the Nakatomi building.
Sources say the terrorist leader, Hans,
may be this man, Hans Gruber.
A member of the radical
West German Volksfrei movement.
The Volksfrei leadership
issued a communique an hour ago,
stating that Gruber had been
expelled from that organisation.
AI, do you copy?
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
W-what was that?
Remember that plastic
explosive I told you about?
There you go. ls the building on fire?
No, but it's gonna need a paint job
and a shitload of screen doors.
Our spotter said you got two with that blast.
- Is that him?
- Yes, sir.
I don't know who you think you are,
but you just destroyed a building.
We do not want your help. ls that clear?
We don't want your help.
I've got 100 people down here
covered with glass.
Glass? Who gives a shit about glass?
Who the fuck is this?
This is Deputy Chief of Police
Dwayne T Robinson,
and I am in charge of this situation.
Oh, you're in charge?
I got some bad news for you, Dwayne.
From up here it doesn't look
like you're in charge of shit.
Listen to me, you little asshole...
Asshole?
I'm not the one who just got buttfucked
on national TV, Dwayne.
Ah-ha-ha!
Listen to me, jerk-off,
if you're not part of the solution,
you're part of the problem.
Quit being part of the problem
and put the other guy back on!
Hey, Roy, how you feeling?
Pretty fucking unappreciated, Al.
Hey, look. I love you.
So do a lot of the other guys.
So hang in there, man, you hear me?
You hang in there.
Yeah, thanks, partner.
What are you doing?
I'm tired of sitting here waiting to see
who gets us killed first,
them or your husband.
What are you going to do?
I negotiate million-dollar deals for breakfast.
I think I can handle this Euro trash.
Hey, sprechen sie talk, huh?
If you'd listened to me,
he would be neutralised already.
I don't want neutral. I want dead.
- Hope I'm not interrupting.
- What does he want?
It's not what I want. It's what I can give you.
Look, let's be straight, OK?
You're not some dumb schmuck
up here to snatch a few purses.
You're very perceptive.
I watch 60 Minutes.
I say to myself, these guys are professional,
they're motivated, they're happening.
They want something.
I couldn't care less about your politics.
Maybe you're pissed off at the camel jockeys.
Maybe it's Northern Ireland.
It's none of my business.
- You're here to negotiate, right?
- You're amazing.
You figured this all out already?
Hey, business is business.
You use a gun, I use a fountain pen.
What's the difference?
In my terms,
you're here on a hostile takeover.
You grab us for some greenmail but didn't
expect a poison pill to be running around.
Am I right?
Hans,
bubbee, I'm your white knight.
I must have missed 60 Minutes.
What are you saying?
The guy upstairs
who's fucking things up, huh?
I can give him to you.
Oh, God...
Roy? Roy, you all right?
Just trying to fire down
a 1,000-year-old Twinkie.
What do they put in them?
Sugar-enriched flour,
partially hydrogenated vegetable oil,
polysorbate 60, and yellow dye number five.
Just everything a growing boy needs.
How many kids you got, Al?
As a matter of fact,
my wife is working on our first.
How about you, cowboy?
You got any kids back on your ranch?
Yeah.
Two.
Sure hope I can see them swinging
on a jungle gym with Al Jr someday.
Well, now, that's a date,
but you bring the ice cream.
Touching, cowboy. Touching.
Or should I call you... Mr McClane?
Mr Officer John McClane
of the New York Police Department?
Get on the phone to Harry in New York.
Get a hold of somebody at Dispatch.
Sister Theresa called me
Mr McClane in the third grade.
My friends call me John,
and you're neither, shithead.
I have someone who wants to talk to you.
A very special friend
who was with you at the party tonight.
Hey, John boy.
Ellis?
Yeah.
Listen, John, they're giving me
a few minutes to talk sense into you.
I know you think you're doing your job,
but you're dragging this out.
No one gets out of here until these guys
can talk to the LA police.
That won't happen until you stop
messing up the works. Capisce?
Ellis, what have you told them?
That we were old friends
and you were my guest at the party.
Ellis, you shouldn't be doing this.
Tell me about it.
All right, John, listen.
Tell them where the detonators are.
They know people are listening.
They want the detonators,
or they're gonna kill me.
John, didn't you hear me?
Yeah, I hear you.
John, get with the programme!
The police are here now. It's their problem.
Tell them where the detonators are!
I'm putting my life on the line for you, pal!
Ellis, listen to me carefully.
John...
Shut up, Ellis! Just shut your mouth!
Put Hans back on the line.
Hans, this shithead doesn't know
what kind of man you are, but I do.
Then you'll give us what we want
and save your friend's life.
You're not part of this equation.
Hey, what am I, a Method actor?
Babe, put away the gun.
This is radio, not television.
Hans, this asshole is not my friend!
I don't know him!
Jesus Christ, Ellis! These people
will kill you! Tell them you don't know me!
How can you say that after all these years?
John? John?
Do you hear that?
Talk to me! Where are my detonators?
Where are they,
or shall I shoot another one?
Sooner or later,
I might get to someone you do care about.
Go fuck yourself, Hans.
He just let the guy die.
He gave him up. Give me that headset.
That's like pulling the trigger yourself.
Can't you see what's happening?
Can't you read between the lines?
He did everything he could to save him.
If he gave himself up,
they'd both be dead right now!
No way, man. They'd be talking to us.
You tell this partner of yours
to stay out of this from now on.
Because if he doesn't,
I'm really going to nail his ass.
The man is hurting. He is alone, tired,
and he hasn't seen diddly-squat
from anybody here!
You're gonna tell me he'll give a damn
about what you do to him
if he makes it out of there alive?
Why don't you wake up
and smell what you shovelling?
You listen to me, Sergeant.
Any time you want to go home,
you consider yourself dismissed.
No, sir. You couldn't drag me away.
Attention, police.
- This is Sergeant Al Powell...
- Give me that.
This is Deputy Chief Dwayne Robinson.
Who is this?
This is Hans Gruber.
I assume you realise the futility
of direct action against me.
We have no wish for further loss of life.
What is it you do wish for?
I have comrades in arms
around the world languishing in prison.
The American State Department
enjoys rattling its sabre for its own ends.
Now it can rattle it for me.
The following people
are to be released from their captors.
In Northern Ireland,
seven members of the New Provo Front.
In Canada, the five imprisoned leaders
of Liben de Quebec.
In Sri Lanka, the nine members
of the Asian Dawn.
What the fuck?
Asian Dawn?
I read about them in Time magazine.
When these revolutionary
brothers and sisters are free,
the hostages in this building
will be taken to the roof
and they will accompany us in helicopters
to LA International Airport
where they will be given further instructions.
You have two hours to comply.
Wait a minute. Uh, Mr Gruber. This is crazy.
I don't have the authority.
Two hours is not enough.
Hello? Hello!
Did you get all that?
We got to make some calls.
Do you think they'll even try?
Who cares?
Theo, are we on schedule?
One more to go, then it's up to you.
You better be right,
because the last one will take a miracle.
It's Christmas, Theo.
It's the time of miracles,
so be of good cheer
and call me when you hit the last lock.
Karl,
hunt that little shit down
and get those detonators.
Fritz is checking the explosives.
I'll check the explosives.
You just get the detonators.
Hey, Powell, you out there?
I'm here, John. I'm here.
You gotta believe me.
There was nothing I could do.
Well, it's gonna be
both our asses if you're wrong.
I hear you.
Did you catch that bullshit
Hans was running?
It doesn't make sense, man.
Don't ask me. I'm just a desk jockey
who was on my way home when you rang.
The way you drove that car,
I figured you for the street, Al.
In my youth. In my youth.
...and author of "Hostage Terrorist,
Terrorist Hostage: A Study in Duality."
Dr Hasseldorf, what can we expect
in the next few hours?
Well, Gail,
the hostages should be going through
the early stages of the Helsinki Syndrome.
As in Helsinki, Sweden.
Finland.
Basically, it's when the hostages
and the terrorists
go through a psychological transference
and a projection of dependency.
A strange sort of trust and bond develops.
We've had situations where the hostages
have embraced their captors after release
and even corresponded with them in prison.
No, no, darling. Asian Dawn. Dawn.
D-a-w-n.
- Sir?
- Yeah?
Sir, the FBI is here.
- The FBI is here now?
- Yes, sir. Right over there.
Hold this.
Want a breath mint?
How you doin', man?
I'm Agent Johnson.
This is Special Agent Johnson.
- Oh, how you doing?
- No relation.
I'm, uh...
I'm Dwayne Robinson, LAPD.
I'm in charge here.
Not any more.
Hi, there. How you doing?
Ohh...
Please, God. No.
You're one of them, aren't you?
You're one of them.
No! Don't kill me! Please!
Don't kill me, please! Please, please!
Whoa. Relax. I'm not gonna hurt you.
I'm not gonna hurt you!
Oh, God.
What are you doin' up here?
What were you lookin' for?
I managed to get out of there and...
I was just trying to get up on the roof...
and see if I could signal for help.
It's through here. Come and help.
Hold it. Forget the roof.
Forget the roof. They got people all over it.
You wanna stay alive, you stay with me.
The best we can figure it,
we've got maybe 30 or 35 hostages up there,
probably on the 30th floor,
and maybe seven or eight
terrorists up there.
Sounds like an A-7 scenario.
Thank you. We'll handle it from here.
When we commandeer your men,
we'll try and let you know.
- Aren't you forgetting something?
- Such as?
What about John McClane?
He's the reason we have any information.
He's also the reason
you're facing seven terrorists, not twelve.
He's inside? Who is he?
He might be a cop. We're checking on that.
- One of yours?
- No, no way.
You smoke?
Yeah.
Thanks.
You don't work for Nakatomi.
And if you're not one of them...
I'm a cop from New York.
New York?
Yeah.
Got invited to
the Christmas party by mistake.
Who knew?
Better than being caught
with your pants down, huh?
I'm John McClane.
You're, uh...
Clay.
Bill Clay.
Know how to use a handgun, Bill?
I spent a weekend at a combat ranch.
That game with the guns that shoot red paint.
Probably seems stupid to you.
Nope.
Time for the real thing, Bill.
All you got to do is pull the trigger.
Come on.
33. Stockwerk. Kommt sofort.
Put down the gun
and give me my detonators.
Well, well, well.
Hans.
Put it down now.
That's pretty tricky with that accent.
You oughta be on fuckin' TV with that accent.
But what do you want with the detonators?
I already used all the explosives.
Or did I?
- I'm going to count to three.
- Yeah. Like you did with Takagi?
Oops.
No bullets.
What, do you think I'm fucking stupid, Hans?
You were saying?
Karl.
SchieB auf das Fenster.
Shoot the glass!
Jesus Christ!
Smile, Karl. We're back in business.
...is the last resort of diplomacy,
then couldn't we say that terrorism
has an equal claim on being that, too?
Tell me you got something.
McClane's name, badge number,
employment record, vital statistics,
and his family's home address...
right here in LA.
Whoo!
Go to work.
Got it.
God, that man looks really pissed.
He's still alive.
What?
Only John can drive somebody that crazy.
Hans, heat up that miracle because
we just broke through on number six,
and the electromagnetic
came down like an anvil.
Have a look at what our friends
outside are doing and I'll be right up.
Hey, John.
John McClane, you still with us?
Yeah.
But all things being equal,
I'd rather be in Philadelphia.
Chalk up two more bad guys.
The boys down here will be glad to hear that.
We got a pool going on you.
What kind of odds am I getting?
You don't want to know.
Put me down for 20. I'm good for it.
Hey, pal, you got flat feet?
What the hell you talking about, man?
Something had to get you off the street.
What's the matter? You don't think
a desk job is a noble effort for a cop?
No.
I had an accident.
The way you drive, I can see why.
What'd you do?
Run over your captain's foot with the car?
I shot a kid.
He was 13 years old.
It was dark. I couldn't see him.
He had a ray gun, looked real enough.
When you're a rookie, they teach you
everything about being a cop
except how to live with a mistake.
Anyway, I just couldn't bring myself
to draw my gun on anybody again.
Sorry, man.
Hey, man, how could you know?
I feel like shit anyway.
Well, this won't matter. The LAPD is
not calling the shots down here any more.
The Feds?
You got it.
Those are the city engineers.
Wait.
They're going into the street circuits.
The guys in suits, I don't know who they are.
That's the FBI.
They're ordering the others
to cut the building's power.
Regular as clockwork.
Or a time lock.
Precisely.
The circuits that cannot be cut
are cut automatically
in response to a terrorist incident.
You asked for miracles, Theo.
I give you the FBI.
- I want the building shut down.
- I got a switch...
I don't care about your switch.
I want it out. Dark! D-a-r-k.
You can't do it from here.
- Yeah, you could.
- It can't be done from here.
I could... I got the radio...
You can't do it from here.
It's got to be done from downtown.
They've gotta take out a whole city grid.
We're talking 10 blocks.
Ten blocks? Johnson, that's crazy.
There's thousands of people...
You have to go wider.
- I need authorisation.
- How about the United States government?
Lose the grid, or you lose your job.
- Yeah, Central?
- Yeah?
This is Walt, down at Nakatomi.
Would it be possible for you
to turn off grid 212?
Are you crazy?!
Maybe I should call the mayor.
No shit it's my ass. I got a big problem here.
Shut it down now.
Emergency lighting activated.
Al, talk to me. What's going on here?
Ask the FBI.
They got the universal terrorist playbook
and they're running it step by step.
It's gonna go. It's gonna go!
Yes!
Merry Christmas.
- They must be pissing in their pants.
- The mayor is gonna have my ass.
Whoo!
What are we gonna do now?
- Arrest them for not paying their electric bill?
- We've shut them down.
We let them sweat for a while,
then give them helicopters.
Right up the ass.
This is Agent Johnson.
No, the other one.
I want air support
ready to lift off in five minutes.
Damn right. Fully armed. We're on the way.
9h, yes!
I Wish to talk to the FBI.
This is Special Agent Johnson.
The State Department has arranged
for the return of your comrades.
Helicopters are en route as you requested.
I hear you. We'll be ready.
When he figures out what hit him,
he'll be in a body bag.
When they touch down, we'll blow the roof.
By the time they figure it all out,
we'll be sitting on a beach earning 20%.
Ah! Jeez!
Powell?
Yo, Powell, you got a minute?
I'm here, John.
Listen, I'm starting
to get a bad feeling up here.
I want you to do something for me.
Um...
I want you to find my wife.
Don't ask me how. By then you'll know how.
Uh, I want you to tell her something.
I want you to tell her that...
um...
Tell her it took me a while to figure out
what a jerk I've been,
but, um...
that...
that when things started to pan out for her,
I shoulda been more supportive.
And, uh...
I just should have been behind her more.
Oh, shit.
Tell her that, um...
that she's the best thing
that ever happened to a bum like me.
She's heard me say "I love you"
a thousand times.
She never heard me say "I'm sorry."
I want you to tell her that, Al.
Tell her that John said that he was sorry.
OK?
You got that, man?
Yeah, I got it, John.
But you can tell her that yourself.
You just watch your ass
and you'll make it out. You hear me?
I guess that's up to the man upstairs.
John?
What the fuck
were you doing upstairs, Hans?
John?
No, Al, listen. Just lay off for a while.
I gotta go check on something.
One minute, that's all I'm asking.
One minute to speak to them.
All right. Get back. Get back.
All right, look.
You let me in right now,
or I call the INS, comprende?
This is the last time these kids
are gonna have to speak to their parents.
All right?
All right. Come on. Come on.
What were you doing, Hans?
What were you doing?
Jesus, Mary, mother of God.
Al, listen to me! It's a double-cross!
The roof is wired to...
John?
John!
John, come in!
- Did you get that?
- Something about a double-cross.
Tell me about it.
We are both professionals.
This is personal.
They're coming!
Choppers are coming.
Time to gather your flock, Miss Gennero.
Your mom and dad
are very important people.
They're very brave people.
ls there something you'd like
to say to them, if they're watching?
Come home.
Mrs McClane.
How nice to make your acquaintance.
On your feet, everyone! To the roof!
Lock them up there and come right back.
You should have heard your brother squeal
when I broke his fucking neck!
What do you figure the breakage?
I figure we take out the terrorists,
lose 20, 25% of the hostages, tops.
I can live with that.
Get this thing on the deck.
They're expecting transports, not gunships.
Move it! Come on! Move!
Come on! Come on!
Move it!
Go! Move!
Theo.
A little bonus for us.
Please, sit down. Sit down!
A policeman's wife might come in handy.
McClane, I have some news for you.
McClane?
Move!
Come on!
Motherfucker! I'll kill you!
Armed.
- The truck?
- The truck.
After all your posturing,
all your little speeches,
you're nothing but a common thief.
I am an exceptional thief, Mrs McClane.
And since I'm moving up to kidnapping,
you should be more polite.
You motherfucker!
I'm gonna fuckin' cook you,
and I'm gonna fuckin' eat you!
I don't like this, Sarge.
Yee-hah!
Just like fucking Saigon, eh, Slick?
I was in junior high, dickhead.
Where's Holly?
Where's Holly Gennero?
Holly Gennero? Where's Holly?
Where's Holly? Where is she?
- They took her!
- Where?
The vault!
- Where is the vault?
- The 30th floor!
They just took her!
Get downstairs!
The whole fucking roof
is wired to blow! Get down!
Get down! Get the fuck downstairs!
They made us, Bureau.
You got a terrorist shooting hostages.
I see him! Break left!
Nail that sucker!
I'm on your side, you assholes!
Swing around again!
I'll bag this little bastard.
What the fuck...
Oh, John, what the fuck are you doing?
How the fuck did you get into this shit?
There's something wrong!
They're coming back down!
- Blow the roof.
- But Karl's up there!
Blow the roof!
I promise I will never even think
about going up in a tall building again.
Oh, God, please don't let me die!
Holy Christ!
We're gonna need
some more FBI guys, I guess.
Jesus fucking Christ!
Fuck!
What the fuck is going on?
What are you gonna do?
Sit here while the building falls down?
Shit!
All right!
Hey! Hey!
Hang on, baby.
Hang on, honey.
Oh, God.
Hans'.!
Jesus.
Hi, honey.
So that's what this was all about?
A fuckin' robbery?
Put down the gun.
Why'd you have to nuke the whole building?
Well, when you steal $600,
you can just disappear.
When you steal 600 million,
they will find you,
unless they think you're already dead.
Put down the gun.
Nein. This is mine.
You got me.
Still the cowboy, Mr McClane.
Americans... all alike.
This time, John Wayne does not walk off
into the sunset with Grace Kelly.
- That was Gary Cooper, asshole.
- Enough jokes.
You'd have made a pretty
good cowboy yourself, Hans.
Oh, yes. What was it
you said to me before?
Yippee-ki-yay, motherfucker.
Holly!
Happy trails, Hans.
Aah!
I hope that's not a hostage.
Gimme water hook-ups
for engine companies 5, 3, 9, 6.
Over here. It's a better angle.
Keep it going, now. Keep it going.
- Come on. We're going to miss it!
- OK. Hand me my notes!
What was it like in there?
How did they treat you?
Al, this is my wife Holly. Holly Gennero.
Holly McClane.
Hello, Holly.
You got yourself a good man.
You take good care of him.
McClane!
McClane, I want a debriefing!
You got some things to answer for, mister.
Ellis' murder, for one thing. Property damage,
interfering with police business.
Go inside,
see if there's anybody else!
No. This one's with me.
Mr McClane, Mr McClane!
Now that it's all over and after this
incredible ordeal, what are your feelings?
Well, well, well.
- Merry Christmas, Argyle.
- Merry Christmas.
Did you get that?
If this is their idea of Christmas,
I gotta be here for New Year's.