Perfect.
No. Not like that.
-Voila. -Voila.
It's nice, right?
Beautiful.
It's nice.
Your father is talented.
It's so mysterious.
His pictures are both powerful and sad.
I can see why you're obsessed with him.
I'm not obsessed.
You've hung his photos everywhere.
He's my father. Why shouldn't I hang them?
They're everywhere. It's too much.
Where is he?
My father?
I'm not sure. Maybe San Diego or Florida.
That's a step down, isn't it.
To go from Paris and New York to San Diego.
I said he could be in Florida.
Florida is even worse.
Don't be an asshole!
I should meet him one day.
Really? If you behave.
He could be my father-in-law one day.
You wanna get married?
Maybe not.
Come on. I'm kidding.
He could take our wedding photos.
Everything okay, sir?
No. It's disgusting.
I'm sorry, sir.
The sauce tastes like detergent.
Is the cook blind?
Let me get you something else.
I've lost my appetite. This is the worst meal I've ever had.
At least take our menu.
If I wanted food this bad, I would have visited my sister.
We lost another customer.
-What? Why? -It's the sauce this time.
- What's wrong with it? - Taste it. It's gross.
Oh God! What happened here?
-What's the problem? -What's the problem?
- It tastes like a dead man's balls.
Lucy. Stop.
This is the second time today. I can't make a living like this.
I'm sorry. Lucy, okay.
Your apology isn't going to feed my kid.
Lucy, relax.
I just need fresh cream.
You don't need cream. You need cooking lessons.
Back off! It was a mistake!
Your existence is a mistake.
This is your mother's fault for having you.
- Lucy, please stop. - Why don't you fire him?
Go back to work. I'll take care of this.
There are no tables. The floor is empty.
Go!
No one wants to eat here anymore. I don't blame them.
Are you okay?
What have you done?
Nothing.
- Did you cut yourself? - It happened awhile back.
-What happened? -I wrecked my motorcycle.
When?
The It's okay.
Can you work?
Of course. I'll be right there.
Don't get blood in the food.
Maybe blood would improve your cooking.
Hey man. Pardon me.
Do you have any spare change?
Back up, man.
I'm trying to get to Brooklyn.
I'm staying with my friend.
I have nothing.
I just need a little... a little...
I just need a few dollars.
I said, "I have nothing."
I brought you some fish.
It's fresh from the restaurant.
Did you find an apartment?
I've been working. I haven't had the time.
When will you find one?
I'll put this in the fridge.
Stick it up your ass.
Hello dad.
How are you?
I'm fine and you?
I'm coming to New York.
When will you be here?
Monday?
I'm afraid I won't be here.
I'm leaving for Stockholm tomorrow.
For work.
I can't cancel. It's an important meeting.
Two days and then I fly to Berlin to meet a friend.
Yes, he'll be here. It could be weird for you.
He can't afford a hotel. He's not
even making his motorcycle payments.
I pay for everything. It's a catastrophe.
I don't want to talk about it.
So you're coming Monday?
I'll leave the key at the front desk.
Come and go as you please.
Okay, dad. I love you.
- Shit, why did you do that? - Stop pretending.
My father is coming to visit.
-How long? -As long as he wants.
Can't he stay somewhere else?
Why should he? This is my home.
When is he coming?
Monday.
That still hasn't healed?
No. It reopened at work.
You should probably see a doctor, no?
Do you want kids?
I don't know. Not at the moment.
Possibly one day.
I'm in no rush.
No rush? Does that mean one year? Two?
When do you think you'll be ready?
I haven't given it any thought.
So who knows?
You're not saying good-bye?
When I get back you better be gone.
Back up.
I'm leaving. Don't touch me.
Listen closely. If you leave anything. I'll burn it.
Why are you treating me this way?
Please stop.
-Excuse me? -Yes.
I wanted a rare steak.
It's not rare?
It's like a diamond.
-I'm sorry. -I'm sorry too.
Another complain.
What is it this time?
The meat is overcooked and the potatoes are too salty.
I'm sorry.
You can't keep repeating that.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Stop being sorry and learn how to cook!
Stop talking to me like that!
Things aren't easy for me.
I have a fucking child at home.
Why do you let him cook here?
Send him to McDonalds.
Lucy, I'll talk to him.
There's no need. I've said all I needed to say.
Hey loser!
Stop ruining my orders!
Stop pressuring me!
The problem? You hired an ass to cook.
-I'm not the ass, okay? -Yes, you are!
Good night.
-Nice dreams, Andy. -Good night, Andy.
Don't drink all my beer.
Too late.
I think Andy's going to close the restaurant.
Why do you think that?
People are talking. You haven't noticed?
If I lose this job, I'm in deep shit.
You'll find another one.
-I need money now. -That's true.
-Did you find an apartment? -No.
The West Village is so expensive.
-The West Village? -Sure, why not?
You'll never afford a place there.
Try Sunset Park.
I don't like Brooklyn.
Try Ridgewood. It's nice there.
-No way. -Why not?
My friend lives there. She takes care of people.
She could take you in.
Take me in? What are you suggesting?
She helps people in need.
Desperate people, beaten wives, the disabled.
That's what you think of me? I'm not a tramp.
That's not what I meant.
But if you need help she's there for you.
That's a beautiful bike, man.
Thank you.
Really beautiful.
I used to have the same bike.
Exactly like this.
Same color. Same style.
How fast does it go?
-It's fast. -I know it is.
I love to go fast.
You wanna sell it?
It's not for sale.
Everything has a price.
- I said it's not for sale. - Just wait, dude...
Name your price. I'll buy it tonight.
Did you not hear me? I said "no."
I'm keeping it. Sorry.
Wait a second.
- Wait. What's your hurry? - I need to get home.
Wait, let's discuss. I love this bike.
It's in my blood.
Sorry, I have to go.
You live in a fancy place. You're lucky to have money.
Let's negotiate. I'll give you a ride, huh?
Come on!
Shit.
Hello?
But I do speak French.
Your French is excellent.
Thank you.
I was but I decided to come early.
I didn't have a chance to clean up.
Don't bother. A little dust never hurt anyone.
We all come from dust.
And to dust we'll all return.
-Who is your friend? -I'm so sorry...
He lives here now but he'll be moving out soon.
I'm sorry, we were hungry, so we raided the fridge.
It's okay.
But whoever cooked that fish should be murdered.
Come. Have some wine.
No. I'm very tired.
Wine is good for the heart.
You dated Marie for years. We've only just met.
- You know we broke up, right? - Yes, she told me.
It's sad to see people break up.
But I knew it wouldn't last.
That's why I was in no hurry to meet.
I'm still friends with my second wife.
Really?
How many wives have you had?
Three
I never married.
Good choice
Are you friends with your third wife?
Why not?
She's a whore.
What about the first?
-No. -Why not?
She died.
Sorry for your loss.
Yes.
We'd still be together if she was alive.
How did she die?
Cancer.
Tumor in the brain.
I was holding her hand when she died.
Don't move.
Stay still.
Just like that.
Where do you think you're going?
To bed.
Where?
To my room.
I'm sleeping up there.
No, that's my room.
It most certainly is not. It's my daughter's room.
You're on the couch.
You've been sleeping there anyway so you can stay there.
You're both sitting here. I want to go to sleep.
Fine. We'll move and you can go to sleep.
Come on, Roger. Let's talk over there.
Bring the wine too, please.
Now you can make up your bed...
...on the couch.
-Do you mind if I eat this? -Help yourself.
You've got such an interesting face.
So did John Merrick.
Your face is tragic.
I can see you've experienced pain.
In fact...
...the second I saw you, I wanted to take your picture.
That's why I introduced myself.
That's why you invited me here? To take a photo?
No.
I had other things in mind.
You don't know each other?
Yeah, we know each other.
You said you just met today.
I know who he is. He was once well-known.
- I'm still well-known. - I guess that's true.
Marie wouldn't like you bringing strangers home.
Marie already lives with a stranger.
- What does that mean? - You know what it means.
No more, no less.
You're not the person she thought you were.
-That's cruel. -Oh really? Cruel?
It's cruel that you still live here.
It's cruel that you only think of yourself.
If you had any dignity, you would move out.
Now forget the fish and look at me.
Are you going to take it?
I can't.
-It disappeared. -Disappeared?
It's gone. That look, your wife, the loss.
The look?
The memory of your deceased wife.
You were haunted by it.
Now it's gone.
I told you, that's my room.
I'm just going to the toilet.
The toilet is clogged.
-Clogged? -It wasn't me.
Yes, it's clogged.
-Unclog it. -How?
With the fucking plunger.
I can't do that.
This happens a lot. My shits are very big.
Perhaps it's my diet. Maybe genetics.
But I'm not ashamed, Roger.
In fact, I'm proud.
Good morning, sleepy head.
Did you sleep well?
Fine.
-You snore. -What?
You snore.
I know.
It could be sleep apnea.
You could die in your sleep.
You should see a doctor.
You were sitting there watching me sleep?
Not at all.
I was admiring my photo.
It pleases me that Marie hung so many of my pieces.
And the frames are very nice.
We were never close when she was young.
Excuse me.
The toilet is clogged again.
- I unclogged it last night. - I unclogged it this morning.
Then use the plunger.
I can't do that.
I use my hands for creation.
I have nightmares that my hands are amputated.
I wake up and...
...they've gone numb.
It's terrifying.
You're my only friend, my only friend, my only friend.
You're my only friend, my only friend, my only friend
Hey Leonard.
Do you know of any photo studios?
No.
I have a meeting at a gallery and I need help.
- It's in the East Village. - Take the subway.
The subway is a pain and it's too far to walk.
Can you assist me?
-Fine, but I'm leaving now. -I'll hurry.
Will you wait for me?
-I have to be at work. -It won't take long.
- I'm leaving in ten minutes. - Of course. Very nice of you.
I didn't go to business school.
Oh, look there!
A clown. It reminds me of childhood.
-Let's get closer. -I don't care. Let's go.
-Come on. -I don't like clowns.
-Stop! -Hey. Over here!
She's coming.
-She loves clowns. -Stop it. I don't.
But look...
She likes you.
-Hello? -You arrived safely?
My plane got hijacked. I'm being held hostage.
Are you serious?
Has my dad arrived?
He arrived last night.
How is he?
He brought some strange guy home.
Okay.
You don't find that odd?
Who cares? You have one-night stands.
Remember?
He can do what he wants.
You two can compare your conquests.
I haven't fucked anyone since we broke up.
It's my apartment. If you don't like it, leave!
Okay, big guy! Big kiss! Bye now!
Hey. Leonard, wake up.
-How did it go? -Superb. He loved it.
Now let's grab a drink.
I have to work.
We'll find a bar close to work.
-I can't. -One drink. Don't be a pussy.
I'll take a cab home.
It will relax us both.
We can get to know each other.
These photos are good, right?
They're okay.
They're better than okay.
You have to study a photo to really see it.
You have to search for meaning.
I really don't care.
You don't make art so you can't appreciate it.
I'm not in the mood.
I can see you're unhappy.
It's obvious.
Marie's not happy either.
You made each other unhappy.
We were good together.
If so, why did you cheat?
It was just once.
I've had problems with monogamy too.
People should fuck who they want, when they want.
We are the same.
-I'm not drinking to that. -Come on.
You like to fuck. I like to fuck.
Let's drink to the fuckers who fuck!
Regardless, please don't bring any more strangers home.
Would you rather I brought women instead of men?
Just stop. It's weird.
Enough already.
You've never fucked a man?
-No. -You're not curious?
- No.
You're about to turn forty. You're unmarried.
That's suspicious.
-And you. What are you? -What do you mean?
-Are you gay? Straight? Bi? -I'm gay.
Roger didn't seem gay.
He doesn't act like a queen so he can't be gay?
Well, explain how you fathered Marie?
Sometimes, gay men sleep with women.
I met Marie's mother, I took her photo. We had sex.
One year later, she told me she had a child.
-Marie used to write songs. -I know.
She could have had a great career.
She decided to work for a large corporation instead.
She ruined her life.
How can you say this behind her back?
I'll say it to her face.
She wrote one song that was so beautiful.
That's not how it goes.
Stop it. That sounds awful.
You're making my ear drums bleed.
You're the worst!
No, that's not it.
Your singing is as bad as your French.
No. I speak French very well.
-Your French sucks. -Sucks?
When I ate your fish I almost vomited.
You should be exiled from every kitchen in New York.
-My kitchen is great. -You're deluded!
Your food tastes like a dead pig's cunt!
Well, your photos are a joke!
They're absolutely shit!
Leonard. Where have you been?
- What are you doing here? - You don't return my texts.
- I'm not a piece of meat. - Why are you so mad?
You're acting crazy.
You think I let anyone fuck me?
-It was a mistake, okay? -A mistake?
You've got some nerve. I'm nobody's
You have to stop.
-Fuck me. -Stop.
I knew it. You're a faggot.
Listen.
Stop. Look at me.
It was a mistake, okay?
It meant nothing. It's finished.
Now move on.
Rape! Rape! Rape! Rape!
How is it going, Leonard?
Hello.
Yes.
It's done.
Thank you.
Something's wrong with Andy!
John, I need help!
-Andy's having a seizure! -What?
What the hell is wrong with you?
- Have you gone nuts? - We have customers waiting.
Hey man. Any spare change tonight?
I'm trying to get to Brooklyn.
Is it a bad time? I need a train ticket.
I just need a couch to rest on for a few days.
After that, I'm done with this city.
-Did you fuck her? -No. I swear.
-Did you? -I'm telling the truth.
Stop! I don't like this!
-Listen to me! -Stop! Please!
You have to stop!
Calm down!
Why did you do it?
I don't know. It was stupid!
Just tell me why.
Okay. William. Smile.
You're like a cherub.
-Hi Leonard. -What's this?
I'm working on some new photos.
But the toilet is clogged again and the fridge is fucked.
It's difficult working under these conditions.
This is madness!
You're paying me.
Go ahead.
This gets you off - taking photos of dicks?
It takes more than this to get me off.
You know, if you need more models...
...I have lots of friends.
-Good evening. -Good evening.
I'm a friend of Tuey's.
She said you might be able to host me.
How do you know Tuey?
We work together.
Okay. Please come in.
Thank you.
-Take off your shoes. -Of course.
I'm sorry to hear you're having trouble.
Thank you.
Anne, here's your tea.
A lot of people need help right now.
Isn't that always the case?
Yes, but strange things are happening.
It's like there a virus in the air.
A virus?
It's hard to explain but
something's wrong. I can feel it.
- Yes, I feel it too. - So you know what I mean?
-I've been hallucinating. -Yeah, me too.
Yesterday, I noticed a large beast sitting in a cafe.
He was grotesque and he was shoveling
large snakes into his mouth.
I almost screamed.
Then I realized it was only
Gerard Depardieu eating spaghetti.
I'm seeing strange things too.
Maybe we've all losing our minds.
It's because of the theta waves.
-What? -Theta waves.
Well, no one knows the side effects.
- What are theta waves? - You haven't seen the boxes?
- They're all over town. - They emit a signal.
-What signal? -Theta waves.
They say it's for high-speed internet.
You can download movies faster, make
video calls in super high definition.
But at lightning speeds.
The government hasn't released any information about this.
These theta boxes just mysteriously appeared overnight.
I'm so unaware of this.
The media is ignoring this.
Theta waves will destroy humanity as we know it.
You and your conspiracy theories.
No one has studied this technology.
She believes in the Illuminati.
It's real.
You also think Tupac is still alive.
He is!
That's enough! I'm sick of this shit!
Leonard.
Yes?
Tell us your story.
My story?
We're here because we need help. We all have a story.
I don't really have a story.
My sister hit me with a brick.
That's horrible.
We were renovating the house.
My sister got angry and threw a brick at me.
Did you finish the renovation?
We were one brick short.
Someone threw acid in my face.
Now tell us your story.
That's enough, Betty. He doesn't want to talk.
It's okay.
I don't really have a story.
I just made a mistake.
A mistake that cost me everything.
We all make mistakes.
I'd rather not talk about it.
I'm tired and I want to go to bed.
Of course. I understand.
Unfortunately, all my rooms are occupied.
You'll sleep on the couch.
The couch?
Who was that?
It's not important.
Spread your asshole.
I hope you're not embarrassed.
I'm from Quebec. I have no shame.
-What's your name again? -Louis.
Louis, come over here.
Blondie... Hey Blondie!
Blondie, what's your name again? Hey Blondie.
This is the third time.
Stand next to each other.
Now put your hand on his dick.
No, I don't do things like that.
It's okay.
This guy used to be famous.
Hold on buddy.
You talk like I'm a has-been.
I'm still well-known!
I don't care if you're Spencer
Tunick, no one's touching my dick.
Don't worry, pretty boy. You're safe here.
I'll spread my asshole but nothing more.
-You're not gay? -What does that matter?
The party's over. Everyone out!
Did you hear me? It's over!
- I want everyone out! - You're blocking my shot.
Get dressed and get out!
-You're angry. Relax. -Angry?
It's like a Turkish bathhouse in here.
And who is this?
That's where I sleep.
-Get up! -I'm reading about Bitcoin.
-I said, "Get up!" -Don't touch me!
Get your dirty ass off my bed!
-Get your hands off me. -Get up!
Chill out, man. It's all good.
This guy's getting shit on my couch!
-There's no shit! -I can smell it!
This guy's nuts.
What's this?
This is very Warhol, no?
Smell is linked to memory.
One time, I lost my keys.
I couldn't find them anywhere.
And then I farted...
...and I remembered where they were.
Okay, but this is weird.
Get up! You're going to get shit everywhere!
Leonard, smell his dick.
Stop taking pictures!
-Dude, are you okay? -My head feels funny.
- It's the theta waves. - I've heard about that.
- They're everywhere. - My head feels clogged too.
Sinus infection?
Please leave. I'm begging you.
Take a deep breath.
Now exhale.
Breathe in.
Breathe out.
I wonder if this is what it's like for Liberace in Heaven.
Now this? What a pussy.
A man shouldn't cry like that.
It's good to express your emotions.
-I can't watch this. -Where are you going?
I need some fresh air.
Can I go too?
Go ahead.
-Where are you going? -To the restroom.
- Where am I supposed to piss? - In the shower.
You should fix the toilet. Everyone is eating cheese.
-Can I ask you a question? -Sure.
Why are you here? This isn't your kind of thing.
Let me explain.
I like to watch golf.
I watch it all the time. I love Tiger Woods.
And your point?
I don't play golf.
Why are you taking photos of his face?
I'm searching.
I cried like that when I saw Amour.
Leonard, look at me.
What?
My daughter... is done with you.
It's over.
I'm leaving. My car has surgery tomorrow.
What kind of surgery?
Castration.
Oh, poor guy. What's his name?
Marine Le Pen.
I'm leaving too.
No one is going anywhere!
Look at this guy. He wants us out.
Are we supposed to just sit here and watch him cry?
Dance! Let's dance! Voila.
Here we go. Everyone dance!
- What about Marine Le Pen? - Fuck Marine Le Pen.
It's better to dance. Go ahead, dance.
Hey queens. Time to dance!
Come on. Everyone dance now.
-I really loved her. -I know.
Can I have another beer?
In the fridge.
I'm worthless. My food is shit.
I'm worthless!
That's not true.
He's right. He's worthless.
-The beer is warm. -The fridge is broken.
The fridge. The toilet. This guy. It's all falling apart.
-You need a tissue? -Yes.
He needs a tissue!
-What's your name again? - Bernard!
- Bernard, grab a tissue from the bathroom.
It's disgusting up there.
You.
Tissue. Bathroom. Go.
And dance, boy, dance.
As you wish, sir.
Hey Mr. Morose. You're not dancing.
I don't dance.
You're too cool to dance?
- No, I just choose not to. - Maybe you can't dance.
I've got rhythm, but dancing is a delusional act.
What a pretentious thing to say.
People dance to forget their impending doom.
Well, when you die, I'll attend your funeral.
Really? Why?
So, I can dance on your grave.
The bathroom smells like shit.
I threw up everywhere.
I hope you didn't puke in the toilet.
I threw up in the sink.
Now there's vomit in the sink, piss
in the shower and shit in the toilet.
Let's party!!!
Hold on.
Zachary, I need to see.
Don't move.
Stay still.
Dance. Go. Leave us be.
-But he needs me. -No. Get up. Go.
I want everyone dancing like the world is ending!
Macho man! Dance!
Look at me, Leonard.
Do you remember the man from last night?
He was broken from the loss of his wife.
-Roger. -That's right.
I tried to capture his pain but I failed.
But you...
I've seen this look before.
From my mother.
I came home from school.
I walked into the house.
She was sitting alone.
She was smoking a cigarette.
Something was off. I said, "Good morning. mother."
She looked at me but her eyes were empty.
They were stripped of all humanity. And now...
...you have the look.
Zombie.
Death.
He's bleeding.
What happened?
Marie stabbed me.
Oh, my sweet Marie.
Maybe she does love you.
-What should we do? -Call for help.
What's the number?
Wait!
This is absurd.
-What? -This?
- Why?
- Because.
Put him on the couch?
I need a darkroom.
A darkroom? Impossible.
They've been replaced by pharmacies.
Do pharmacies still develop film?
It's all digital now.
There's a darkroom in Bushwick.
The WIFI here is really fast.
Theta waves!
I must go there. Can anyone drive a motorcycle?
I can.
Great. Let's go. Hurry.
I must get this film developed tonight.
But he has a fever.
Will you take care of him? This is more important.
Thank you all for such a lovely evening.
You're all so kind.
And so very handsome.
Thank you.
What a nice guy.
That's rare for an artist.
Asshole. Turn around.
Your sauce is shit!
It's like licking puss out of an open wound. Disgusting.
Your food tastes like death.
I almost puked all over my shirt.
So fucking gross.
Rape!
Hey, man.
I guess so.
-You feeling better? -Yes.
How is your wound?
The same.
I've never cared for photography.
But I can't stop looking at these.
I'm transfixed.
What does it mean?
It's a message.
We are meat. Nothing more, nothing less.
Like a bucket of KFC.
It's reassuring.
We are soulless.
You even said so last night.
We are worthless.
I said that?
Yeah.
Dennis took these?
Where is he?
I have no idea.
He took his stuff and left this morning.
Seriously?
Thank God, it's over.
He took your motorcycle.
What?
It just keeps getting worse.
Last night was fun.
And you seem to be feeling much better than last night.
Stay hydrated. You'll be fine.
I need to go to work.
- Let's have breakfast. - I said I have to work.
The theta box lets you download 4K videos instantly.
Theta waves will give us a brave new world.
Follow me and observe.
Hey, hey!
Wake up!
I'm awake.
You're like a zombie. Concentrate.
-I'm focused. -Okay then. Let's go.
-Ladies. -Good morning.
Today we have raspberry duck with asparagus.
It's served with mushroom soup or pineapple salad.
I'd like the burger and fries, please.
And for you, madame?
The lemon chicken pasta.
-Don't order that. -Why not?
It's supposed to be awful.
You've had it?
My friend ordered it.
He said it was so gross, he vomited.
We fired that cook.
First your server number.
The menu items appear.
Hamburger and lemon chicken pasta.
Press "#43 pound" for special instructions.
Press 2 for onions. If caramelized, press  twice.
If raw, press  once. Pound for grilled. 13 for mushrooms
-You got all that? -Believe so.
Today we have a raspberry duck with broccoli.
- Asparagus, not broccoli. - My mistake, asparagus.
The meal comes with...
-Mushroom soup. -Mushroom soup and...
-A green salad. -A pineapple salad.
I meant pineapple salad.
- It's one or the other. - It's one or the other.
He's new.
Leonard, I want you to meet someone.
This is Paula, the new line cook.
Good morning.
What the fuck are you doing?
Wake up. We're in the weeds.
Move your ass.
You must go faster, numb nuts.
You're like a quadriplegic.
Soup for the lady.
And for the gentleman.
Excuse me, sir.
I didn't order this.
Are you sure?
I ordered a steak.
They wanted sauce on the side.
It's not on the ticket.
It should be. Look at it.
Look. I pressed "pound 45"
You did it wrong.
I did. "Pound 45"
You must press it at the same time.
-You didn't say that. -I did!
Your salad.
Steak for you.
-I need another whiskey. -Coming.
You still haven't brought our bread.
And where's my sauce?
Faster, fuckhead. Faster!
It's like teaching calculus to a cadaver.
-Where is this going? -Table 3.
-This is for table 2. -I was told table 3.
It's table 2.
-Where is table 2? -Next to table 3.
My sauce, sir. Where's my sauce?
You don't have sauce?
I need sauce and a steak knife.
This is a butter knife.
I don't mean to demoralize you...
But it's like you've had a lobotomy.
My grandma could go faster and she has dementia.
Damn it!
Excuse me. We need more water.
And where's my fucking soup?
We don't have all day, shithead.
This is disgusting! I can't eat this!
You've won an Oscar for the "worst waiter!"
Get a new job!
You're the fucking worst!
You're ruining everything!
Middle-aged moron!
You should kill yourself!
You're an incompetent fool.
Your life is over!
You don't exist!
Your sauce is shit.
Great job, Leonard!
Standing ovation!
Stop! Stop! No, no!
Hello, my friend.
Do you have any change? I'm heading to Brooklyn.
Surprise!
Yea, happy birthday!
Happy birthday!
Friends! Photo!
Make a wish!
I want to freeze this moment.
I never want it to end.
Do it then.
Do what?
Take a picture.
Marie? Where are you?
Where are you hiding? Come out now.
This isn't funny.
Stop fucking around. Marie.
Marie, stop this!
Hey! Get off my bike!
Hey! Come back!
This isn't happening.
Yes?
Roger?
-Who are you? -What are you doing here?
I live here.
But this is my home.
-You're confused. -This is my place.
Hold on now.
-Who are you? -This is absurd. I'm Leonard.
Stop fucking with me.
-Get out of my way. -What's wrong with you?
-Let me in. -I'll call the cops.
Fuck this!
Thank you so much. So kind of you.
Good evening. Thanks again.
Thanks for coming. Have a lovely evening.
The next show will be bigger.
Dennis?
Dennis.
Someone is in our house.
Excuse me?
There's someone in our house.
I don't understand. Do I know you?
- There's someone at Marie's. - Do you know Marie?
But of course.
I am her boyfriend. We live together.
- You're making no sense. - What is he saying?
He says he's Marie's boyfriend.
-You don't recognize me? -No.
You were at my apartment. Naked as the day you were born.
I'm never that naked.
This one got shit on my couch.
And you...
You clogged my toilet.
You clogged my toilet!
He has shit this big coming out of his intestines.
Enormous shit!
Yeah, baby. Yeah.
-What is he talking about? -I wish I knew.
You see this picture?
I took this myself.
I took this. It's mine!
It belongs to me!
Look. Can't you see?
We are a couple there. We were a couple!
This is me! Can't you see?
What's wrong with you?
Get out of here, you lunatic!
Leave now! Go!
Go! Now!
You stole my bike!
Those are my bags!
No! Fuck all of you!
I'm warning you! Go!
Hit the road, shithead.
Now!
He's a madman!
You don't look so good.
It's been a shitty day.
It will be okay.
Would you like some soup?
Thank you but I just want to sleep.
Leonard?
Oh, Leonard, you've arrived.
Anne.
Anne, Leonard is here.
Leonard? You've come back.
Thank God.
We were terribly worried.
Don't worry. Everything will be okay.
We need you here.
You are home now.
Stay as long as you like.
- What about the rent? - Don't worry about that now.
When you're back on your feet, you can make a contribution.
You're all being so kind.
I don't know what to say.
You don't have to say anything.
It's our pleasure.
-Try to get some sleep now. -Okay.
-One last thing, Leonard. -Yes?
Someone else is arriving tonight.
Don't be alarmed if you find him on the coach.
Okay.
Good night.
-Good night. -Good night.
Why do you want kids? You have a great career.
Life is not only about work.
It's about building a family, a life of meaning.
But we are a family, and we're free.
We can do whatever we want.
I bust my ass to make you happy!
Put down the knife!
You know I love you, but I'm not mature.
I feel like a loser.
Your sauce is shit.
Marie is dead.
You're the guy with the motorcycle.
That's me.
-You live here? -Just temporarily.
You are lucky to have a room.
Excuse me. I have to use the bathroom.
Go ahead, man. It's your place.
Does it work?
-What exactly? -The toilet.
The toilet. Yeah, I just used it.
It works perfectly.
What are you watching?
I'm not sure.
It's a silent film?
No. I didn't want to wake anyone.
So I turned off the sound.
You can learn so much by studying the pictures.
The images speak.
Have a seat.
I will. Thank you.
You know...
It sucks being homeless.
There's no television.
Everything sucks.
Life.
Health.
How did you become homeless?
It's a shitty story.
I had a fight with my mom.
We hated each other.
After that...
One thing led to another.
I started taking drugs.
In a moment, everything changed.
And you?
What's your story?
Today's my birthday.
Really? Today?
Yes.
How old are you?
Forty.
Happy birthday.
Thank you.