Just grab what you can!
- What the...
- I don't know.
She said the driver
ran in front of her.
Nothing she could have
done to avoid hitting him.
What was he running away from?
Just one last question
and then you're free to go.
After the accident, did
you notice anyone else?
Chasing the driver, or—
Frankie?
Did you see anything?
Hey hun, how was your day?
Oh, good idea.
Ah, boy.
What a day.
Hope yours was better.
Did you get a lot
of studying done?
Dumb question.
Your exam's only a few days
away, of course you did.
You'll be able to relax soon.
Because once you pass
your LSAT, we're home free.
You at law school, me teaching
at the Junior College.
By the time you graduate,
I'll have my PhD.
And then, it's off
to San Francisco.
City of brotherly love.
We can get a house, and a
dog, all those other things,
meet my dad.
It's too bad I can't
meet your parents, but...
after that, that's the next
five years all mapped out.
It's everything you ever
wanted, isn't it, Frankie?
Hello.
No.
No!
That crate needs to be
recovered immediately.
Insurance?
I don't give a damn
about the insurance!
It won't cover
the cost of another life.
Up in the news today,
two murders and a robbery
in less than 24 hours.
Wish you'd let me do that.
One police officer was killed—
Hey, so I called Hector.
One of his guys is going to be
by later on to tow your car
to the shop.
Sound good?
Police say the wounds
were inflicted during
a daring escape.
Police officers—
Did you see anything?
Yeah, Hector sent me?
I'm gonna need the keys.
For the car?
Yeah, right, let me just...
Here.
Thanks, I'll have
the car back to you—
Frankie?
What is it, what's wrong?
So, the guy's truck
gets jacked, he runs,
then you hit him.
What are you even doing here?
You should be at home resting?
Well, Steve had a thesis
meeting with his PhD
advisor and I just—
Yo, were you on your phone?
You know, when you
killed the guy?
Were you texting someone,
or distracted?
Okay, that's enough.
Hey, the guy's ghost
could be haunting her right
- now, you don't know.
- Lewis!
What?
This is why you'll always
be single.
Okay, let's get another round
of birthday
shots for the birthday douche.
Yeah, boy!
Alright, shots, shots, shots,
shots, shots, shots, shots,
shots.
There was someone in the house.
Or something.
You don't believe me.
Look, it's still fresh.
I'm sure once the shock
wears off everything will—
What, go right back to normal?
Hey you,
do you want to dance?
Ew.
Well, Lewis got himself
kicked out.
We're heading
back to the house.
Hey, Frankie!
See that guy over there?
I think he's gonna make
a move really, really soon.
Can you stay with me?
Like, 30 minutes max, please?
I'll catch up
with you guys in a bit!
Here.
Helps chase it down.
Chase what down?
The answer to all your problems.
Thanks, Molly,
but one pill
isn't going to magically make
everything better.
But what if it does?
I'm not feeling well.
I think I'm gonna be sick.
Hey, what's your name?
You want to dance?
Molly?
Molly, is that you?
Who are you?
Molly!
Molly, please help!
Your birthday's
always the worst.
Where'd Frankie
and Molly get off to?
They're smart, probably bailed.
Frankie
wouldn't do that.
Not to Jonah!
Would she, lover boy?
Frankie's got a boyfriend,
Steve, remember?
Besides, I could never—
Hey, Frankie, we were
just talking about you.
Everything alright?
So, you said
the killer was a mannequin?
Like a Bloomingdale's
mannequin?
How is this happening?
What exactly did happen?
Frankie said Molly's
throat was slit, but—
So you actually believe her?
Drake,
can you shut him up for us?
I mean, people have been
dying around her,
two nights in a row.
I've never seen
her like this before.
Not even when
her parents died.
I mean with what she's been
through in the past 24 hours,
it's enough to make anyone—
See a mannequin?
Yo, Jonah,
you alright, man?
I'm calling it a night.
Come on, let's go.
Hey, I got your dog!
Excuse me,
I said I got your dog!
Can I help you with something?
Mm-mm.
Look.
The police are gonna
catch whoever did this.
That's their job.
No they won't.
They don't believe me,
they think I'm crazy.
You are not... crazy.
Something did happen last
night, something awful.
But there's an
explanation for it.
A gas leak?
Bad drugs?
I don't know, but whatever
it is, it isn't a...
I'll go talk to my advisor.
Tell him I need
a few days off.
That way I can
be there for you.
Help you through this.
Sound good?
Yeah.
Steve?
Yes?
I need
you to believe me.
I ran all night.
No matter where I went,
it was there.
I don't know
why it didn't kill me.
Maybe it was just
toying with me.
Whatever it is—
It kills.
I wasn't sure at first,
but I saw it the night
I hit the driver.
Then at the club.
Molly, and now you.
It's coming or us.
All of us.
This is ridiculous.
We're talking like this is one
of those Reddit Creepypasta
things, like Slenderman.
What if it is?
What is it?
I lost...
anywhere.
It's killed—
I know— I'm so tired!
No matter what I do,
he finds me.
Police didn't believe us.
No one did.
I don't know what
to do anymore.
I've tried everything,
but it can't be stopped.
I know that this sounds crazy,
but if you think you're being
stalked by a mannequin,
don't—
Don't, don't what?
No idea.
The video just ends there.
Okay.
This is a joke, right Jonah?
Jonah?
Come on, guys, it's just
some crappy viral video.
Probably a marketing gimmick
for a new horror movie.
They do it all the time.
Yeah, like what they
did for Blair Witch Project ,
or Selfie From Hell .
No, no, what she
said in that video was exactly
like what's happening to us.
Frankie, we love you, but—
How does it kill?
This Mannequin?
It can do things.
It moves without moving.
One minute it's there,
the next—
It follows.
And even if you can't see it,
you feel it.
It's everywhere.
And nowhere at the same time.
Watching, waiting, until...
Alright, cut it out.
Too far, seriously.
Way too far.
Wow, I got to hand it
to you two.
This is really good.
This is sick,
like seriously poor taste.
Molly died yesterday.
I've had enough, I want to go.
No, please,
you have to believe us.
We tried to tell you.
It was right there,
how could it just disappear?
What the hell?
Hey, guys.
Steve, look, it's back.
Oh, no, Frankie,
we went over this.
But it was right there.
Um, I'm so sorry, everyone,
but I'm gonna have
to ask you to leave.
Frankie and I need to talk.
Steve, she's not—
I'm really disappointed
in you, Jonah.
I thought you
had better sense.
Maybe it's mass hysteria.
Frankie saw it at the window,
puts the idea in our minds,
and then our imagination
takes over.
I bet the mannequin looked
different to all of us.
Arms at its side,
sunken eyes, creepy smile?
That's the same one I saw.
Me too.
Drake?
Yeah, looked the same to me.
What if there was someone else
inside the house
and they planted
a second mannequin
when we weren't looking?
What, and then somehow
managed to make it
disappear in the blink
of an eye?
What if it's not a mannequin?
What if it's a person
in a mannequin costume?
They waited until we weren't
looking, and ran off,
snuck in through the back.
Now that makes a lot of sense.
Makes a lot more sense than some
supernatural mannequin.
Lewis, you saw it
with your own eyes.
Jonah, come on, man.
I'm a scientist.
I believe in logic and...
Look, can we just talk
about this later?
I gotta move.
Clear my head a little.
My grandmother and
I could hold conversations
entirely without ever
opening our mouths.
She called it 'shining'.
blood, blood,
blood, there was blood—
Steve?
Who are you talking to?
Is everything alright?
I uh— I had the most
terrible nightmare.
It was the most...
horrible dream I ever had.
I dreamed that...
You became so obsessed
with the mannequin that...
that you left me.
And I got so jealous
that I, uh...
I strangled you until you
were dead, and butchered you.
I cut you up into little
pieces, and I, my work,
I think it's starting
to drive me out of my mind.
Steve.
Are you happy?
I will be, when
all this is behind us.
What if it never is?
What if it follows
me wherever we go?
Did Jonah put that idea
in your head?
No.
You're not lying to me,
are you, Frankie?
No, Steve.
Good.
Because I love you.
I love you so much.
I love you more than anything
in the whole wide world.
And I'd never let
anything hurt you.
You know that, right?
Yeah.
Good.
It's okay, baby.
I'm scared too.
Take it.
Just in case.
Where are you going?
I'll see you.
Let me know if
you need anything.
Okay.
Who is this?
Listen to me and do exactly
as I say.
Someone responded to my post.
Post?
What are you talking about?
That girl's video,
I commented asking if anyone
could help,
and someone responded.
This guy, Victor Malick,
he said he was having the
mannequin shipped to himself.
Can it be stopped?
Malick's on the next flight out.
He can explain
everything then.
Right now we need to get
everyone back to your place
or more people are gonna die.
Hello?
Oh, thank God you're alright.
Wait, I'm getting
another call from Lucy,
can you hold on a sec?
No, you need to patch
her through right now.
This concerns all of us.
Where are you two right now?
Government and Yates.
I'm in Trounce Alley.
Okay, we're close.
Let's meet at Washington Plaza.
Drake.
Listen, you gotta grab
Madison and get to
Frankie's house right away.
What are you going on about,
Jonah?
Our lives are in danger!
No, enough with this mannequin!
You're freaking everyone out.
Trust me, Drake, or this
thing'll get you and Madison.
Hey, Jonah,
mind your own business.
Madison and I are
gonna be just fine.
It's just what I needed.
I do love her.
My girlfriend.
I'd do anything to
make that woman happy.
I try to make her happy.
But lately...
I'm not so sure.
Recent events have
complicated things.
Isabelle?
Thanks.
I really needed this.
But, it's time for me
to get back
to the old ball and chain.
She'll be wondering
where I am.
Or uh...
maybe she won't be.
Oh, God.
Uh, can I have another one?
Please.
Madison's not answering.
Same with Drake and Lewis.
When's Malick getting here?
I don't know.
He said to just stay put
and make sure none of us—
You!
Jonah, don't!
Back off, man!
It's not fair,
we didn't do anything!
It was her,
Frankie's the one who brought
things thing into our lives!
What happened, where's Madison?
I'm so sorry, Drake.
Tell me everything you know.
What is this thing?
Why is it after us?
'Cause we've all seen it.
Then why isn't Frankie dead yet?
- Drake!
- Seriously, she saw it first!
That doesn't mean anything!
Lucy, he's right.
It had plenty of chances
to kill me but it didn't.
What else did Malick tell you?
So we're screwed, right?
Man, I'm not waiting around
for some freak you met online
to show and do what exactly?
Perform an exorcism?
Pft.
Come on, man.
Drake, you can't leave.
Look bro, if I'm gonna die,
I'm gonna die
on my own terms, you dig?
Don't touch me!
If you go out there,
you bring it with you wherever
you go, and whoever sees
it it'll follow them too.
That's why Malick told me
to get everyone together.
We need to stay here or we'll
be exposing more people to it
and this'll never stop.
So that's why
it hasn't killed me.
The girl in that video,
she was trying to warn others.
She knew the mannequin needed
people to see it, and I...
No.
I did exactly what it wanted.
It's not your fault,
you didn't know.
He's right, Frankie, you can't
put all this on yourself.
Hey guys.
What's up?
People are dying, Steve.
It got Madison, and Isabelle,
and we think Lewis, too.
It's coming for us.
I know you don't believe us
but if you'd seen
what we've seen—
Jonah!
It's so good to see you, buddy.
I've seen a lot more of you
these days since Frankie
started spending all
of her time with you!
I'm really happy.
Look, I didn't want
to believe this either,
but it's real, bro.
It's real, bro?
Oh, bro.
That's so crazy, bro.
Look, whatever you think is
happening between me and Jonah,
it's not.
The only thing that's going
on right now is that that—
thing is out there somewhere
and it's coming for us.
Please don't.
It's not like you, Steve.
And what is... like me,
Frankie? Hmm?
Yeah, that's what I thought.
Mm.
Just like your mother.
Guys?
Steve, no!
Don't go near it!
Listen to her, man!
Steve, please!
I told you.
There's nothing
to worry about.
Nothing to worry about—
argh!
Steve!
Idiot.
It's just a fuckin' mannequin.
Check this out.
Yeah, and?
Think about it.
Every time we look away
it seems to disappear,
but for some reason
it's still there.
Not everyone looked away.
Come on, let's get this
somewhere safe before
anyone else sees it.
There's no way
I'm touching that.
I'll do it.
I think the mannequin's
only able to move
when we're not looking at it.
So as long as you
don't take your eyes off it
it won't be able to kill anyone?
We can't watch it forever.
We're gonna need
to sleep eventually.
We watch in shifts.
Steve?
I... wanted to check in
and see—
Why I'm such a jerk?
Look, we're both under a lot
of stress with
everything that's
going on right now.
You know, your thesis,
the accident, the deaths.
The mannequin.
So you believe me?
Hey, why don't I come back later
with some coffee, and maybe—
I just want to finish my work.
Okay.
This is probably the first time
we've stayed up late
like this since senior year.
Yeah, well, we grew up.
And real life began.
And then you started seeing
Steve, and...
would have been weird anyway.
What would have been weird?
I don't know, us three going
to the movies together.
Steve sitting right there
while I'm just finger blasting
you through your jeans.
Jonah!
No, I remember why we stopped
hanging out so much.
Hey, remember sophomore year
when we had that history sub
for like, three months?
Ms Corbis?
Yeah.
Do you remember her face
when you asked her when
she was expecting?
Okay, we all thought
she was pregnant,
you more so than anyone.
Yeah, well she
really did look pregnant.
Yeah, and it was driving
you crazy,
so you know, I had to ask.
No harm in asking, right?
Then, why didn't
you ever ask me to—
The coffee should be
ready by now.
Careful, Frankie.
Steve, no!
It's over, Frankie,
it's all over.
You don't know what you've done.
Don't know what I've done?
I'm a PhD candidate, Jonah.
I know things you couldn't
even begin to comprehend.
I saw your thesis, Steve.
You need help.
Well, what about you, Frankie?
Hmm?
What about you?
Has it ever occurred
to you that I'm in a highly
competitive academic program?
Does it even matter to you
that my advisor and colleagues
rely on me?
Do you have the slightest
ideal what a moral and ethical
principal is?
Do you?
I don't know
who you are anymore.
You never did.
What's happening?
Whatever you do,
don't look away.
Listen to Jonah, Frankie, go on.
You're so good at
listening to him.
What did I tell you?
It's just a mannequin.
Sorry, was...
just a mannequin.
I should get back
to my thesis.
Oh, Frankie, thanks
for the inspiration.
I always knew that guy was nuts.
Does anyone see it?
No, but it's here,
I can feel it.
We need to call the police.
And bring more people
to the house,
more people who might
see the mannequin?
We can't take that risk.
Where the hell is it?
It's hiding.
We know its weakness.
Weakness?
That thing's unstoppable.
No, we do know how to stop it
and it knows that.
We need to find
it, and remember,
as soon as you set your eyes
on it, do not look away.
What if it doesn't show?
It disappears and
reappears anytime it wants.
We've stayed alive this long.
Because it let us.
Like Frankie said before, it
needed more people to see but
now that we know its secret—
It doesn't need us anymore.
Let's split up.
This isn't Scooby-Doo, Jonah!
Use your phones.
There, I saw it!
Where?
It could be anywhere!
My phone's about to die!
I can't do this much longer.
Frankie,
where's the fuse box?
The basement!
Jonah,
I'm coming with you.
Down here, come on.
Come on, man, we gotta go.
Hey, Drake,
give me a hand here.
Hold this.
I'm getting dizzy.
Okay, come
up against the wall.
Come on, man, hurry it up.
Higher!
Damn, Jonah,
that was close.
What took you so long?
Oh, thank
God you're okay.
Where's Drake?
Just gearing up.
Drake!
Here.
Thank you.
Hey, Mr Malick—
Victor.
Call me Victor.
Alright, Victor.
Where did this thing come from?
The mannequin?
Only the Devil himself knows.
But it can be stopped, right?
I did it before.
I can do it again.
That thing, what you call
a mannequin has tormented me
for 30 years.
My daughter was the first
to see it.
Then my wife.
Soon others from our circle
began to see it too.
And the same fate befell
them and their friends,
and every other poor soul
who happened to set their eyes
upon it.
Fortunately I couldn't.
But there was no
mistaking its presence.
Darkness unlike
anything I'd ever felt.
Tracked it as far as Moscow.
But it kept evading me.
Until a week ago.
I found it not
too far from here.
I was having it shipped to
my estate where I can bury it
away forever, spare others
from suffering the same tragic
demise as my loved ones.
I swore on their graves I
would put an end to this and
by God I will!
I have to.
Good coffee.
I'd kill for some more.
So Victor, when do we start?
When it returns.
What if it doesn't?
You're the only ones
who've seen it?
The only ones still alive, yes.
Then it'll only be a matter
of time.
It can't resist its urge
to kill.
I need something to drink.
Lucy, want anything?
What do you think?
The blind leading the blind.
What was her name?
Your daughter?
Madeleine.
Maddy, for sort.
And yours?
Lucy.
Short for Lucille.
I'm so sorry.
No, I am.
Get Victor.
Now!
Victor, it's back!
What are you doing?
What's happening in there?
Jonah? Lucy? What's going on?
Jonah?
No, it's me, Victor.
Where's Jonah and Lucy?
Do you have your eyes on it?
Yes.
Whatever you don't,
don't look away,
no matter what happens.
What is it we're doing,
exactly?
Ending this,
once and for all.
Argh!
What are you doing,
you came here to help us!
I wish I could.
Unfortunately,
the moment you and your friends
laid eyes on it,
you were cursed.
There was no saving you.
But you can help me
save others.
You're the last one who's
seen it, and once you're dead,
its powers will be lost,
unless someone else sees it.
But I'm not gonna
let that happen.
Not again.
How could you do this?
Someone has to.
Argh!
Ah!
Open the door!
Argh!
Ahh!
Jonah!
Jonah,
Jonah, enough!
We need to get you
to a hospital.
It's behind you.
Come on, Jonah,
it could be anywhere!
Jonah?
No, no, no,
Jonah, hey, hey, hey.
Hang in there.
No, no, no,
you're good, you're good.
You're okay, you're okay.
Jonah?
Jonah!
9-1-1, what's your emergency?
Hello?
on the line.
Can you hear me?
What's your location?
Hello?
Is anyone there?
How'd it go?
Your LSAT?
- Did you—
- I passed.
What's wrong?
I miss them too.
Listen, about
you moving to Stanford—
I'm not.
I deferred my acceptance
to next year.
Frankie,
this is your dream.
I just want to take some time
for myself.
And...
dreams can change.
So, what happened?
Where is it?
Careful with that.
Somebody paid the big bucks
to get that thing where
it's going.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Great, that's the third one
this month.
Well, at least it's insured.
Hey, Joey, you okay?
Yeah, that thing's just creepy.
Let's clear this up.
Hey, where'd it go?