Mmm num ba de
Dum bum ba be
Doo buh dum ba beh beh
Pressure pushing down on me
Pressing down on you, no man ask for
Under pressure That burns a building down
Splits a family in two
Puts people on streets
Um ba ba be
De day da
Ee day da
That's okay
It's the terror of knowing What this world is about
Watching some good friends screaming
“Let me out!"” Pray tomorrow gets me higher
Pressure on people, people on streets
Careful with this, it's highly toxic.
Come on, lads, keep it moving.
Keep it moving.
Go, go, go!
Is this double pay or what?
It's toxic waste.
What are you doing sitting there, mate?
Get amongst it.
I want this filth off my ship as fast as possible.
What you doing, then?
Naughty.
Help! Help!
Shh.
Keep your little beak shut.
-Not very nice. -Otherwise, you'll go for a swim.
Help! Help!
Help me! Help me!
Hey.
Uh, well done.
I'm here from the home office.
Bullshit.
Here checking on security protocols...
...and, um, taking a few pictures, SO smile.
What are you doing in here?
- Not very nice. - What's going on?
That's him!
I'll get you!
Hey, hey! Get at this!
Get him!
You two, go left! Cut him off!
I want him caught, dead or dead.
Not there! Go around! Go around!
There you go, mate. End of the line.
Okay.
You're all under arrest.
For the illegal dumping of radioactive materials.
Yeah, you, you, you, you and you.
What, me and... And him and him?
And him?
-Kill him. -Wait, wait, wait.
I know. You want to see the warrant.
It's right in my pocket.
I'll see you in court, yeah?
We're out of shipping lanes, and you're 200 miles from shore.
So enjoy your swim.
I've got him. Just off the port side.
He's like a green James Bond. I like it.
Oh, no, my hat!
Hello, suckers.
Looks like he's been making friends.
Wherever he goes, people just love him.
God knows why.
Have you got this?
We'll see.
Maybe this wasn't the best idea.
Maybe this isn't the best idea.
This is gonna be awesome.
Define "awesome."
I'm about to.
Opening hatch.
Next time, put a little more air in this thing.
It's like breathing through a straw.
Worked, didn't it?
You okay?
If you love your job, you'll never work a day in your life.
Okay, bring in Test 15.
Initiating suit power-up.
Clear.
Promising.
The exo suit is performing way beyond what we expected, Jiuming.
21% increase in power.
Not bad, huh?
So cool.
I can't wait to use these in the trench.
Hi.
-Maybe 25. Mm? -Okay.
I mean it, don't be late!
I cannot believe you got this far in life
without knowing how to tie a tie.
First, let's not overstate how far I've gotten in life.
Second, never involved wearing a monkey suit.
-Perfect. You look great. -Thanks.
Ah. Maybe this is the start of something.
Don't count on it.
Hi.
That guy look familiar to you?
No.
- I don't like him. - You don't like anyone.
I like you.
That's 'cause I save your life all the time...
I buy you beers and I back you up in bar fights.
It's 'cause you're a special guy.
You're both special.
-Wish me luck. -Good luck.
- Thanks for the money. - Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the 10th anniversary of the Oceanic Institute.
I'm Hilary Driscoll.
Thank you for coming tonight, and for joining me
in funding this incredible work.
Stop. Don't fidget.
Why exactly do I have to be up here anyway?
'Cause you're a team player.
Great.
Please give a warm welcome
to the director of the Institute.
Zhang Jiuming.
Thank you, Hilary.
Thanks to the generous donations from our supporters,
we have been able to create the technology
to pass through the thermocline,
a thermal layer of freezing cold water
that separates Haiqi's world from ours
and into a trench 6,000 meters below sea level.
Thanks to you, we have the ability to go further than ever before.
And thank you. Zhang Jiuming.
So, thank you all
for being part of protecting this incredible ecosystem.
Thank you for coming.
Who wants to get a selfie with the man
who fought a megalodon and lived to tell the tale?
We give you, ladies and gentlemen, Jonas Taylor.
There he is! There he is.
I know this was your idea.
I'm gonna kill you.
Smile and pretend you love it.
Go on, give him a hug. Give him a tickle.
Oh, he loves people.
I wanna go to Mana One with you.
I want to dive the trench.
No.
Sorry, Meiying.
Why not?
Mom was diving all the time at my age.
Not to 25,000 feet.
Saying it's too dangerous?
Too dangerous for you.
But not dangerous.
In psychology, they call that "cognitive dissonance."
In the real world, they call it "parenting."
You need to start taking me seriously as a scientist.
-You're 14. -Exactly.
I know every system on Mana One, every dive protocol,
and every animal we've seen down there.
Hey, look. You can come to Mana One.
To observe the dive.
And that's it.
Jiuming is swimming with the meg.
Uncle.
Haigi's vitals are elevated.
Be careful, she's definitely aware of you.
Why are you swimming with the meg, Jiuming?
I'm conducting an experiment.
Is the experiment "Do I taste good?"
It's okay.
I've been training Haiqi since she was a pup.
A meg is not trainable, Jiuming.
But if you wanna be eaten in front of your niece, go ahead.
Fifty bucks says this is gonna end badly.
I'll take that action.
I am all in for team shark.
What? You can't bet on a shark, man.
That's bad karma.
Come on, guys, focus. That's not cool.
Jiuming...
I'd like to respectfully suggest that this is truly a terrible idea.
Megs and humanity were never meant to mix.
Haiqi and I have a special bond.
Watch this.
One click to come. Two clicks to go.
Whoa, I think she's looking at us.
You see?
She's coming around. Heart rate is up.
Moving in fast.
Four hundred meters.
- Jiuming, she's not responding. - Come on, Haiqi.
Two hundred meters.
One hundred meters.
Jiuming, move.
It's too late. She's coming in too fast.
Fifty meters.
Pull the cord.
Twenty meters.
- Jiuming, get out of there! - Uncle, no!
Did it get him?
I don't know. I couldn't watch.
I don't see him.
I knew this was a bad idea.
Huh?
That was exciting, huh?
I can't figure out what's wrong with her.
She's been acting strangely all week.
You can clickety-click all you want.
The problem is, that it's a meg.
And you're a snack.
Yeah.
For the record, you scared the hell out of Meiying.
You're one to talk. What were you doing on that ship?
Actually, don't tell me. I don't wanna know.
Well, the Institute's mandate is to protect the oceans, right?
We can't be a part of any illegal activity.
Oh, I abhor lawlessness.
Oh, good.
Especially the illegal dumping of radioactive waste.
You're taking bigger and bigger risks each time you go out.
Well, I guess we both know about that.
It's not the same.
With me, there's a calculation of risks.
Not that I see.
Do you miss your mom, big fish?
Dr. Howard.
Are you ready for Mana One?
Say.
What?
Ground crew, we're approaching Mana One.
Hey, Rigas. Good to have you back.
I missed you guys.
Are you ready to do some diving?
You know it.
Morning, everyone. Let's get this show underwater.
Dive 1 and Dive 2, descend to 25,000 feet.
We're exploring Area 19.
Collecting rock samples and logging any new species.
Diving in T-minus 20 minutes.
All eyes open for a straightforward sweep and scan. The usual.
Yeah. There's no usual down there.
System's up.
What's with all these toys you have hanging around your console, Lance?
They're not toys, they're figurines.
They are definitely toys, Lance.
Thank you.
Ready for the drop, guys?
So, are you and Sal, like, Comic-Con guys or what?
Uh...
Absolutely right, yeah.
Do you, um, dress up?
Uh, yeah.
Don't get him started, unless you want to see a million photographs.
Oh, yes, please.
Stay focused, guys.
Passing 17,000...
Telemetry's good.
It's a beautiful day in the neighborhood.
Passing 18,000 feet.
All systems nominal.
Looking good, team. Let's pull up the grids we're gonna map today.
Area 19.
When are we going to look at something different?
Yeah, there's like 100 more sectors to explore.
Jonas, can you confirm O2 levels?
Consumption is 11% over mission spec.
Guess Rigas is nervous.
More like you're a mouth breather.
He totally is.
Can feel the breeze from over here.
Yeah.
Firstly, it's called a deviated septum.
Second, I distinctly remember deviating it
while saving your ungrateful ass
from a 70-foot megalodon.
Passing 20,000 feet.
Approaching the thermocline.
Checking O2 lines and tank pressure.
If there was a leak,
there would be a fluctuation on the readings.
I'm not seeing anything here.
Check the pressure on the auxiliary O2 tanks.
Okay, I'll check.
That's not the problem.
Uh, Jonas?
Meiying?
You gotta be kidding me.
I see that you're angry.
But I believe that this is a reasonable and responsible decision.
Stop the dive.
Full stop.
But before you start yelling, can I just say...
I did all kinds of stupid things when I was 14.
And look how I turned out.
We're surfacing.
But I don't see what the problem is.
This is your 26th trench dive without incident.
Subs have electric predator countermeasures,
and emergency dive suits.
Which you don't have.
Actually...
I packed one while you were doing the pre-dive meeting.
You know,
now's maybe a good time to sit down and be quiet for a minute.
I can do a seatbelt by myself, you know.
I know you can.
Jonas.
It's not your call, Jiuming.
We've got company.
Guys, it's a meg.
Approaching fast.
That's not possible, they can't go through the thermocline.
It's not coming from the thermocline. I'm tracking it from the shore.
Dive! Flank speed!
Engaging. Rerouting battery array.
Hold on.
Charging the predator countermeasures.
We'll be dead before they're online.
Thermocline's our only hope.
I'm reading Haiqi's tracker.
Impossible.
Well, impossible just got possible.
Five hundred meters to the thermocline.
Haiqi's closing fast.
One hundred meters.
She's right above us.
Come on, come on!
Entering the thermocline.
Dive 1, Dive 2.
Switch to low-frequency light,
you don't want to attract any more megs.
I've lost her. She can't follow us through.
Can she?
Going dark.
I've never crossed the thermocline at 60 knots.
Careful, you don't want to burn out the engines.
Don't worry, I'm not gonna break the pretty toys.
Yes.
She's still on us.
Thirty seconds...
For the countermeasures.
Evasive.
She must have followed our heat signature.
How did your pet shark get down here, Jiuming?
She must have escaped. How did that happen?
Predator countermeasures active.
Proximity alert.
Megs.
No way.
That's the biggest meg I've ever seen.
Biggest meg anyone's ever seen.
That's gotta be the apex predator.
Incredible. Megs are solitary.
It's like they're being called.
I'm changing the dive plan. We have to see what they're up to.
And what about Meiying?
Well, I vote we go.
I wasn't asking you.
Oxygen reserves are at maximum.
Predator countermeasures are deployed.
Right now we are perfectly safe.
Right now, yeah.
If I see anything dangerous, I'm pulling the plug.
Mac, we're changing the mission profile.
Proceeding on heading 227.
Now they're already off mission. They need to stay on course.
Jonas, you're going way outside the sector we have already mapped.
This is an exploration mission.
Let's explore.
Copy that.
Eyes open, watch your backs.
Really, Mac?
We're gonna follow some giant sharks to a unknown sector?
Man...
This some dumb-ass shit, mark my words.
Entering Sector 21.
Commencing geographical scan.
It's so beautiful.
Your mom loved this place more than anything.
I'm glad I finally get to see it.
Don't get used to it.
You're grounded for the rest of your life.
I love you, too.
Haiqi 400 meters ahead and holding.
Where are we going now?
/Into the unknown.
That's what we came for.
I've got Haiqi's tracker ahead.
Looks like she's circling.
Look up.
It's some instinctual gathering.
Incredible.
They're here to mate.
This is why Haiqi has been acting strangely.
Oh, great. More megs.
The scanner's detecting an abnormal structure.
No way.
Is that a wreck?
It's some kind of sea floor station.
What could they be doing down here?
Rigas, run all spectrums.
No, that's no wreck. I'm getting heat signatures off it.
Just can't see what's inside.
Multiple airlocks, power generation.
The resources needed is staggering.
Who would even have that technology?
Sonar says there's something above us.
It looks like a submarine.
Let's take a look.
Charges set. Priming zone for detonation.
Come on. We need to blow this ridge.
Yeah, okay, okay.
We don't wanna be down here any longer than needs be.
Yeah, well, this is the only place to mine this stuff.
Slow and steady.
Hey, Montes. Why do you get to stay in the submarine?
It's good to be the king.
Incoming object detected.
Zoom in 400%.
Mana One crew is below us.
There's no way they haven't seen the station.
What are we gonna do?
I'm arming the explosives right now.
- You have to get out. - What? Wait.
No, you can't do that.
There isn't time. You know there isn't time.
It will take ten minutes to get clear.
Montes!
- Sorry, guys. - Montes! Montes, don't do it!
What was that?
Landslide!
I can't get ahead of it. I'm gonna have to go through.
Guys? What's happening?
I'm reading a thermocline breach.
Something's ripped a giant hole in it.
Rerouting the thrusters. This is all we've got.
Vertical control is down.
Hydraulics are non-responsive.
We're pinned.
Coming in.
- Hold us steady. - Yeah.
Jiuming. Sixty degrees down.
Two feet forward.
Jiuming!
Go, go, go!
Full thrust! Full thrust!
Jiuming!
No!
There's no telemetry.
Dive 1,
Dive 2. Do you copy?
Dive 1, Dive 2. Do you copy?
We've got nothing here.
Keep trying, DJ.
Jess, prep the rescue sub. Stat.
-Ugh, what happened? -I don't know.
How do we know if they're still alive?
Prep the rescue vehicle.
Dive 1,
Dive 2. Do you copy?
Come on, Jonas.
Meiying.
- Meiying. - What happened?
Took a nasty hit.
Uncle Jiuming?
Where's Uncle Jiuming?
-Where is he? -We can't raise him.
Hey. We work the problems one by one.
We do what's in front of us, and then we do the next thing.
We're gonna be okay.
Mac!
The rescue sub isn't working.
The battery array was deliberately shorted out. It looks like sabotage.
How's that possible?
This isn't a secure area, there are 30 people who work here.
Well, how long to fix it?
It's the control boards, Mac. There is no fixing it.
- Try it now. - What's our status?
No comms, no heat.
We're losing air fast.
- This isn't working. - Flood in my extra O2.
Already done.
Yeah, I have got one last idea.
Route the power through the heating cell.
I got Dive 1. Mac.
- I got Dive 1. -Jonas?
Good to hear your voice, Mac.
Not as good as it is to hear yours, brother.
Talk to me.
It ain't good.
Almost every system is down and we're losing air fast.
We'll get into the emergency dive suits, and we're gonna need a ride up.
Jonas...
it's not gonna be possible.
What are you talking about?
The battery array.
It shorted out the control board in the rescue sub.
We're investigating it now.
Jonas?
Jonas, can you hear me?
Jonas, we can't get to you.
We're gonna walk.
We're gonna walk back across the trench. Make it into that sea floor station.
And we're gonna get inside. And then we're gonna get to the surface.
Those suits have two hours of air tops.
They're only designed for brief extravehicular work.
We'll go slow and steady. They'll hold.
It's three kilometers.
You'll be defenseless out there.
What do you want from me, Mac?
This is what we got, and this is what we're gonna do.
Half our team is dead...
and I'm not losing the other half.
Beginning suit initialization.
Joint actuators functioning.
Ultrasonic signal communications online.
Initialization complete.
Abandoning Dive 1, Mac.
The radios won't relay to the surface, so we're going dark.
Talk to you on the other side.
Godspeed, Jonas.
Emergency escape initiated.
Hey. Whoa.
Almost killed you.
The hell are you doing?
Saving your ass.
And walking back to that station.
What are you doing?
Saving your ass. And walking back to that station.
-Don't have much time. -Let's get going.
-Jiu. -Oh!
Hey.
Hey. Let me check.
Air left...
Hey, you need to calm down or you're gonna run out of oxygen, Lance.
I don't think I can.
Think of it as cosplay.
Or we could be paintballing.
Like the ultimate team-building exercise.
We need to cover distance while the megs are still occupied.
Three kilometers to destination.
Away from the megs is fine by me.
We're a strong group. We can do this.
Amazing.
Lighting courtesy of Mother Nature.
It's incredible, there are new species all around us.
Hey. Look.
Look at this. It's beautiful.
Hello, my little biolum...
There's a snake! There's a snake!
Get this monster off my head!
No touching stuff.
He started it.
Everyone clear the station. DJ, what's our time on Jonas?
Forty-one minutes since they went dark.
At best, it'll take another hour
for them to cover the distance.
Listen up.
We know there's some kind of rogue operation in the trench.
Now some bastard's got his fingers in our operation here.
That sub was definitely sabotaged, so we've got a mole on the station.
DJ, I want you to pull all surveillance footage
from the sub bay for the last 24 hours.
Jess, run the personnel files on the crew,
look for anything suspect.
We're gonna get these sons of bitches, but we have to watch our own backs.
One of us mans the DCC at all times, understood?
Yes.
Is it just me,
or does walking three kilometers underwater
sound like hard work?
It certainly wasn't on my to-do list.
Baby octopi.
So many colors, it's incredible.
Anybody wanna play a game?
- A game? - This isn't a game.
She means to keep our minds occupied.
Right now, my mind is pretty damn occupied.
There's a, there's a, it's...
Lance?
What was it?
- I didn't see. - Where's Lance?
Is it a meg?
Something's happened to him, I know it.
Lance?
No. Oh, no.
We have to keep moving.
No, we can't just leave him out there.
We need to find him! Please!
-Jiuming. -I'm sorry.
He's gone.
Rigas, cover our six. Shoot anything that moves.
You bet your ass I will.
Comms online.
What happened to you?
The Mana One crew stumbled upon our station.
I took them out with a landslide.
Okay, this is out of control.
You authorized me to do
whatever's necessary to protect our operation.
No.
They are not dead. They are walking right now
to the station.
If they get there,
we are screwed.
There's still a kilometer to go, straight through that valley,
and we don't have the bioluminescence to cover us.
We're going to be totally exposed out there.
We don't have a choice.
We only have enough air to go straight through.
Let's keep our lights on low spectrum.
Yeah, we don't want to attract the megs.
One kilometer to destination.
- 02 check? - 65%.
50.
26%.
It's not gonna be enough.
Look at me. Look at me.
Look at me, okay? Focus, okay?
You can do this. Remember the training.
Anything on sonar?
I got something, right at the edge of my range.
Keeps going in and out.
Stalking us.
Proximity alert.
What is it?
It's just a shoal of fish.
Stay calm, everyone.
- Are you okay? - Yeah.
Keep moving.
Ayo, Mac.
We got jack on the security footage. Somebody deleted it.
-For the sub bay? -For the whole damn station.
They're good, but they don't know everything.
There's a satellite uplink with an encrypted backup.
I'm gonna go to the server room, see if I can pull it down.
Time?
One hour, 50. They'll be out of air soon.
I'm scanning all channels, but nothing yet.
That's it. Maybe 400 meters.
Warning. Entering oxygen reserves.
You can do this.
- Yeah? - Yeah.
I'm getting a reading.
Many contacts to our right.
Coming in fast.
What, megs?
No. Smaller. Faster.
Everybody make it to the station! Go, move!
Warning. Oxygen level low.
- Come on. - I'm out of air.
They're coming over the ridge!
What are those things?
It's too far.
We need to make a stand!
Turn and fight!
Come on! Get off!
Meiying!
Help! Shoot their head!
-Meiying! -Uncle!
I've got you!
They're biting through the suit.
Meiying!
-No. No. -Hold on, Curtis!
Too many! We don't have a chance!
Everybody stay back!
Keep going!
Jiuming!
There's no choice.
You really wanna die, don't you?
Gotta make it to the airlock!
Warning. Low air.
-It's no use. I'm holding you back. -Low air.
It's not too far.
You can make it!
Warning. Low air.
Air depleted.
Uncle!
Visor failure imminent.
Jiuming!
Okay. We gotta go. We don't have a choice.
He's coming back around!
- Oh, God! - Go, go, go!
We have to do the override.
Come on, hurry up.
Rigas, come on!
You can do it. Get in!
Shut the door!
Curtis, you'll be okay.
Suit implosion imminent.
- Almost there. Almost there! - Oh, my God.
It's gonna implode.
Depressurize the room!
No, no, no.
- Implosion imminent. - No!
Son of a bitch!
I hate these things!
Hey, Rigas.
Let's try to keep it together.
We ain't out of the woods yet.
Rigas.
Where is everybody?
What is that smell?
Divers.
Nobody home.
I'll cover the door.
Whoever's running this...
is not our friend.
We need to contact Mana One ASAP. Think you can handle it?
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
What is this that they're mining?
Whatever it is, they're sending it up to the surface
with these pods.
Mm. Rare earth metals.
They're used in superconductors, aerospace and quantum computing.
This box alone could be a billion dollars.
"Billion" with a "B"?
Yes.
Mana One.
Jonas. Comms are live.
Come in.
-It's Jonas. Getting this? -Hey, you're alive.
What's your status?
We lost Lance, Sal, and Curtis.
We're at the station.
It's a rogue mining operation.
Is there anyone down there?
Not that we've seen so far.
They've infiltrated Mana One. The rescue sub was sabotaged.
-By who? -We're working on it.
But check this out.
I was going over the video of when you went over that station before.
Look at the north side.
Looks like emergency escape pods.
It's the opposite side from where we are.
- Feels dead in here. - Stay close.
These are my designs.
How do they have this?
Looks like this is it.
On three.
Three.
- Again. - It's not gonna work.
After you.
Ah, this is more like it.
Let's crack open a pod and get out of here.
Nothing here.
These controls ain't working.
We need to close the hatch.
On it.
Guys, that wasn't me.
Jonas, now that I have you here,
we need lo talk candidly.
I have full control of the station and I've locked down this room.
-Jess? -Your life is in my hands.
What are you doing, Jess?
These are your friends.
They've been with you for years.
I know it hurts. And we're talking
because I'd prefer we were on the same side.
All making so much money, it ceases to have meaning.
You're offering us money?
Three of our friends are dead because of you.
You think I'm gonna forget about that?
No, no, no! That's the first escape pod!
Son of a bitch!
Rigas? Rigas, you can save Meiying.
Take that speargun and shoot Jonas in the heart.
Don't shoot him.
Do it.
Go ahead.
It's the only way Meiying survives.
Do it.
Rigas!
Do it!
-Do it! -No. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, I can't, I can't, I can't.
That was the last pod.
I told you that wouldn't work.
Put me on.
Sorry it had to come to this.
So...
we'll be back at work in a week
using your technology to take whatever we want.
Your institute'll be a platform that we use
to plunder the ocean for decades.
And before you start whining about the ecosystem...
Who cares? We'll make billions.
And no one is going to see the damage we do.
Jess, I've already dispatched a clean-up crew to Mana One.
Finish this.
How do we open the door?
If we could cut the comm link to the surface...
she couldn't control anything.
But it's back in the first room
and there's no getting through this door.
This airlock still works!
Why would you go through the airlock? There's no pod.
I'll swim to the airlock where we came in
and do the override.
You have no suit. How could it work?
Water doesn't compress under pressure,
so if he can force water in his sinus cavities,
he could survive 30, maybe 60 seconds before he passes out.
It is possible.
We work the problems one by one.
We do what's in front of us, then we do the next thing.
If anyone can do this, it's you.
Won't he be crushed by the pressure?
It doesn't work like that.
You don't see fish wearing metal suits, do you?
It's about air. It reacts under pressure.
And that's why he has to blow it out of his sinuses.
Hey there, tree hugger.
Jonas Taylor, eco-warrior,
fighting the good fight.
Well, guess what? You lost.
I spent two years in a Manila prison
after you and your eco-freak buddies had our ship seized.
I thought about you every single day.
You don't even remember me, do you?
Hmm?
No?
Montes.
There's a million scumbags in this world.
It's hard to keep track of all of 'em.
Meiying!
Clean up crew approaching Mana One.
About time. We are on alert.
Everyone confined to their quarters.
We need to get control of Mana One and dispose of any liabilities.
What's the emergency?
I got into the security backup.
Look at this.
Jess disabled the rescue sub.
-What? -Watch.
Like she could be repairing it, right? But no, wait.
It's Montes' sub.
That's our ride out of here.
There's a leak in the hydraulics.
Predator countermeasures are down.
We'll never make it past the megs.
We need a distraction.
Light up the station. The megs will attack it.
Yeah. And kill us.
Not if we're fast enough.
Jiuming!
-Hey, Rigas. -Yep?
For a moment, I thought you were gonna kill me back there.
Well, she did say to shoot you in the heart.
And I know for a fact you ain't got one of those.
Gotta close the hatch, Jonas.
We're all gonna die.
-He's gonna make it. -No, he's not.
-He's gonna make it. -No! We have to close the hatch!
Close it! Jonas!
I'm here!
That's him!
That was close.
Too close.
You should have shut the hatch.
Yeah. Meiying would have killed me.
You thought about it, though.
Yeah. We thought about it.
Didn't we, Rigas?
Shut up.
Just a little bit.
Explosives?
Check this out.
Look what else.
Is that gonna be a problem?
It's a hole in the thermal layer.
It must have been caused by the mining explosions.
It will seal up eventually.
Eventually?
Yeah. Within an hour.
Can the megs follow us through?
I hope not.
Boys, I don't want to harm you, but I do need you to come out of this room.
It's Jess. She's got three soldiers.
Yeah. It's go time.
Take this.
-The hell is this? -It's a Taser.
Open up.
They tried to kill Jonas, they're definitely gonna Kill us.
Okay, listen. Here's the plan.
On the count of three,
you'll open the door and I'mma pepper spray 'em.
Right, and you'll shut the door and you're gonna wait.
Then go out there and use the Taser.
One, two, three.
No, Mac, no!
No, Mac!
It burns! It burns!
I'm sorry!
Sleepy time.
What's that?
Trouble.
So, we're walking fast and with a lot of determination, which is great.
But what exactly is the plan here?
They're armed and we're not.
All righty. So what are you thinking?
What are you thinking?
You and I find Mac and DJ.
Rigas, grab what you can.
Secure a Zodiac so we can get off this thing.
Rock and roll.
Safest if Meiying goes with you.
I'll protect her with my life.
And I'll protect her with mine.
No.
Let's go.
I told you to wait before you went out that door.
-How's your eyes? -My eye stings.
If we climb up to the communications array,
we can bypass the DCC and we can call for help.
What are we supposed to say?
Um... Terrorist action?
-Yeah, good. Terrorist action. -Yeah, terrorist action.
-Okay. -You got a better idea?
Freeze!
Oh, no.
DJ! DJ!
What the hell?
Wow! Yeah, baby! Get some!
- Hey. - Run, Mac, run!
Go, go, go!
Spread out! Find 'em.
You got Tasers? Now you can swim?
All of a sudden you're running around like you're Batman.
Hell yeah.
After last time, y'all begged me to come back.
"DJ, Oh! We family, DJ."
"DJ, we need you." Yeah, all right. Bet.
But I ain't stupid.
I trained up, I learned how to fight, I learned how to swim,
and I will never go anywhere without my survival pack.
-Survival pack? -Yeah.
Check this out.
Come here, baby. Come here.
Bam.
Yeah, I even made poison-tipped bullets
just like Jaws 2.
Come on, DJ! Let's go, let's go.
This is insane.
Freeze, assholes.
Yeah, freeze.
You got this?
That was some unfortunate shit back there.
No, please! Don't shoot!
What?
Sucker.
I thought you were dead.
Wishful thinking, Mac.
If it ain't the deviated septum.
- Boat's leaving. - Huh.
What's our status?
Bravo team are inbound. ETA, ten minutes.
Excellent.
What are you doing here?
-Are you okay? -Yeah.
Jonas is on Mana One.
We need to lock this place down now.
Search the station top to bottom.
Secure personnel in their quarters, kill anyone else.
Go! Go!
Oh, my God.
Guys?
We've got a big problem.
We tracked three megs that escaped
before the breach closed.
We're gonna need a good cover story for this.
Well that shouldn't be hard.
Everyone knows Jonas and Jiuming were reckless.
No, we need a hero.
Someone to emerge from this unforeseeable tragedy...
who can step into a leadership position at the Institute.
Jess, are you ready for promotion?
I appreciate your confidence.
Jess!
It's from the thermocline breach. But you can relax. This place?
Meg-proof.
I mean, Jonas was always afraid of this, but I think
between trackers and gunships, we can solve the problem
and come out the other side with a significant positive PR spin.
Yeah, I'm on it.
I was also thinking--
What now?
It's our only way off. We have to take it.
But that thing doesn't have the range to get us to the mainland.
You're worried about the destination? What about the first hundred yards?
That's where we're gonna die.
We paddle out slow.
No engines. Minimal motion.
We won't look like food.
When we're clear, we make a run for it. Huh?
Let's do it.
I still think we look like food.
Shh. Quiet, everyone. Paddle slowly.
This feels unpleasantly familiar.
Let's just hope it goes better than last time.
What happened last time?
You don't wanna know.
Oh. Here he comes.
Go, go, go!
Let's not bring 'em back alive.
You do know how to drive this thing, right?
Stop! Stop the engine right now.
Or you will attract the megs.
Okay. Be still.
No motion whatsoever.
I have the shot.
Take it.
- Get down! - Come on, mate, do your job.
-Take the bloody shot. -It's not easy as it looks.
He got 'em! He ate 'em! He ate the whole boat!
What happened?
Jess is dead.
-What? -We stabilized Mana One,
but Taylor and Zhang have escaped.
What do you want me to do?
Fix it! Kill them!
You do this, you write your own ticket.
You are set for life.
Okay.
There's only a couple places they could make it to.
Are you crying, Montes?
Any sign of the megs?
Negative.
There's no way this thing's gonna work.
It's gonna work.
Look, you got more chance of blowing up yourself than one of the megs.
At least I won't get eaten.
Ha! I hear that.
Jo...
can you make me one?
I got you covered, Mac.
We have to find a way to warn people.
In case the megs move towards land. There's an island
60 klicks south east of us.
It's listed as inhabited.
Inhabited by who?
The name more or less translates to...
Fun Island.
Fun Island?
Yeah!
Welcome to Fun Island. Our resort has everything.
The restaurant, amazing.
The disco, incredible.
And our spa, to die for.
Oh.
OMG.
It's our special dish. Seafood Surprise!
Wow, I wouldn't know where to start.
Well, just don't miss out on the grilled shark.
Pippin! Pippin! Pippin!
-Whoa! What is that? -Pippin!
What are they running from?
Your first time at the rodeo?
I worked with your dad since before you were born.
I never had this kind of trouble from him.
Yeah, and I yelled at him too.
I'm sitting in paradise and you are ruining it!
Who does that? Who ruins paradise for other people?
Hey, baby.
Wanna rub some oil on my back?
No?
How 'bout my front?
Ew.
Hey.
Yaoyao.
Yaoyao!
This doesn't look good.
Rigas, get us there fast!
Kill the cellphone uplink.
There's a lot of exposure for us on this.
Take care of Jonas and his team quickly and quietly.
Everybody out of the water!
- Shark! Shark! - Get back on the beach!
Get out of the water!
Get back on the beach!
Mobile comms are down, over.
You copy, guys?
Crocodile!
What is that?
-Move, move! -Get into the chopper.
Now! Go with her!
Mmm. Mmm.
Everybody out!
- Shark! - Shark!
Get on the beach!
Go back!
We have to save them.
-I'm not leaving ya. -Cell phone's down.
Hello? Hello?
-No signal. -There's no choice.
-She's right. -We got no signal, guys.
Hey, you two! Find a way to call for help.
Let everyone know what happened.
Come on, come on! This way, this way!
You're gonna hide.
See that lifeguard tower?
-Yeah. -You go there and you stay there.
This is not one of those things where I tell you to do something,
you say "yes," and then you do whatever you want.
Understand?
Yes.
-You're not messing with me? -No.
I can't do what I need to do if I'm worried about you.
I'll be fine.
Promise me you'll come back.
You know I love you.
Oh, shit.
Sonny.
Check that out.
Hey, yo, my man. You got a phone?
What's everyone running from?
What the hell was that?
Three megs. Three of us.
We each grab a jet ski.
Get them to chase it away from these people and out to sea.
Then we harpoon them.
Oh, you mean with those jerry-rigged,
maybe they work, maybe they kill us harpoons?
Yeah.
It's a terrible idea.
-You got a better one? -No? No.
-Then we're agreed. -Yeah.
-Good. -Great.
Montes!
Shit.
Let's go old school.
The landline's down, too.
Okay, coast is clear. Let's go.
They can walk?
Shit.
It's those things.
They haven't spotted us yet.
Okay.
What else you got in here?
Emergency stuff.
Okay.
Really? Condoms?
Different kind of emergencies.
Hand me that.
Now hand me that gum in your mouth.
Thank you.
There's only one ski.
Give me your harpoons.
You sure?
Oh...
- I got this. - Good luck.
We need more firepower.
Yeah.
I have an idea. Let's go.
Not this time, Taylor.
This should be the place.
Come on.
What are we looking for?
Ammonium nitrate.
You're making a bomb?
This stuff is as powerful as TNT.
Hey!
Get in! Get in!
Freeze!
Come on!
Come on, let's see if he's got a phone.
I got the sat phone. I got the sat...
I got the phone, why you stealing his money?
What? He's not gonna need it.
Uh-oh.
Nice doggies. Nice doggies.
Okay, Rigas.
On the count of three, we're gonna bolt.
One. Two. Three!
What the hell? Hey!
Wait for DJ! Wait for DJ!
-They're right behind us! -Let's hide in here!
Come on, come on. Come here, come here.
-What the hell? -Hi, DJ. Hi, Rigas.
All of you together. Up against the wall. Hands up!
I wouldn't point that at me if I were you. Trust me.
Shut it! Keep your hands in the air.
Hands up!
Don't want to hurt you...
so I'm going to give you one chance.
Put those weapons down.
Or you'll do what?
Stay still, little guy.
No, no! Joe, Joe, door!
Stay where you are!
- Go, go! - Get to cover!
Damn!
I got signal.
Call for help!
To get down to the beach and help people!
Where are you going?
- Stealing a chopper. - What chopper?
Global rescue?
We need rescue! We need you to send everybody you got!
The National Guard, the lifeguard, the Coast Guard, anybody!
Just come now!
Ugh! Looks like someone else had the same idea.
We need a plan.
We have to lead it away and steal the chopper.
Okay, you lead it away, I'll steal the chopper.
-You distract it, I'll get the chopper. -Why me?
Can you fly a chopper?
Yeah, I can.
-You have a license? -Yes, I do!
-I didn't know that. -What?
Okay, good plan.
Mac!
Jiuming! We gotta go!
Fuel! Get the fuel!
Gas! We need gas!
Get up!
Get the fuel!
Lizard incoming!
Hold on!
Jiuming? Jiuming!
Run!
Go!
Whoa, yay!
Man, I didn't think you were gonna make that one.
Run!
No.
Where are you going, Jonas?
Get lower! That's Meiying!
Are you sure it's Meiying?
Get lower!
Okay, okay! Hold on!
Meiying!
Over here!
Leap up!
Jonas is still alive?
Get me over there!
Help!
Taylor!
Come on!
Come out from under the bridge, little troll!
End of the line, no?
I guess it is.
You got the gun.
I won't be needing this.
I knew you couldn't do it.
See you later, chum.
Jiu!
Meiying!
Where?
Hold on! I'm coming!
Meiying!
Jonas! Over here!
-You okay? -Yeah.
Uncle Jiuming and Mac's in trouble.
Stay here. I'll be right back.
Mac! Are you okay? Mac?
Come on, you ugly bastard!
Come on, come on, come on!
Come on, come on. I got you, I got you. Come on, come on!
Meiying, what are you doing here?
I had to save the dog!
What?
Mommy's here.
-Thank you, thank you, thank you! -You're welcome.
- Oh, no, you don't! - Meiying! Come!
Hell yeah!
Get some!
Who says a .50 caliber is an impractical round?
Hey! Wait, wait, wait!
Everyone stay still. No motion.
No, it's okay.
That's Haiqi.
Who cares which one it is?
She'll listen to me.
Let's spread out so that thing don't get us all.
I got this!
Yes! I knew it!
I told you! We have a special bond.
-It went after the dolphins. -No!
-She obeyed my command. -Ridiculous.
I didn't believe it before and I don't believe it now.
Hey, Mac, back me up.
I'm getting out of here before she changes her mind.
Mac!
You guys stay there and argue.
She obeyed my command!
-Dolphins. -No!
It's not my fault.
Sometimes, there's a situation and bad things are happening,
and you just have to get involved.
I'm glad you finally understand.
I'm proud of you.
Rescue One to Fun Island, over.
Oh, it's good to hear your voice, man.
We got a lot of people who need help.
Yeah, I used to didn't know how to swim, but then, you know...
You out there chasing sharks, you better learn how to swim quick!
The water was cold, it wasn't that cold, but yeah...
- I was just having fun! - What about Haiqi?
She's still out there. Maybe pregnant.
Preferably not.
That's tomorrow.
Today, we count our blessings.
Here's to being alive.
Here's to dolphins.
To Meiying being safe.
And here's to Sal, Lance, and Curtis.
So...
am I still grounded?
-Absolutely. -Absolutely.
You two are ridiculous.
But I love you anyway.
Looks like you got a little reckless out there.
No, everything was totally under control.
Yeah, right.
Well, everything's about to be totally not under control.
Give me some.
Mmm.
Yeah, that's the good stuff.