Provided by explosiveskull https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
You're lying.
Julie.
You know I can't, Sara.
Can't or won't?
- That's not fair. - C'mon,
I know I don't need to tell you this,
but Mom and Dad aren't getting any younger.
And lately, Mom...
I don't know. She's not the same. She...
Mom is just fine.
And so is Dad and so am I
and all is right and well in the universe, Sara.
Stop creating issues where there aren't any.
Julie, it's their anniversary.
I just know they'd love it if you came.
I got them a bouquet.
They're renewing their wedding vows, Julie.
Mom's wearing a wedding gown
and you're sending flowers in your place?
I'm not.
I'm sending you to send flowers in my place.
Well, that's convenient.
- Julie. - Oh, sorry.
Uh, Sara, actually...
I'm gonna need you to pick 'em up for me.
What? Your flowers?
Oh, hang on.
Yeah. Yeah.
Okay. Hold on.
Sara, I gotta run.
Are you serious?
Yup. We'll talk soon.
- Bye. - Okay, I love...
You.
Hey!
Sorry, I'm late.
Got Julie's flowers.
Took me forever.
The girl at the flower shop was having issues
with her boyfriend and she wanted advice,
well, you know...
Oh, my God.
This looks amazing.
Mom?
Where are you guys?
Daddy?
Mom?
Hello?
What's wrong, darling?
It's okay,
it's what he wanted.
Don't be scared.
Everything's gonna be different now.
Mom?
No.
Sara?
Sweetie.
Hey.
How you feelin'?
Uh...
I don't know.
But I still can't remember anything.
Everything just seems...
Like...
Can you remember your name?
Sara.
I don't know if I remember
or if it's because that's what you called me.
They said that might happen.
You lost a lot of blood.
Blood?
You don't remember?
Remember what?
I have to tell you something and it's not easy.
But I need you to know that you are completely safe now.
What?
I found you in the tub, Sara.
You tried to kill yourself.
No...
No, I didn't.
I wouldn't.
It's okay.
- I wouldn't. - Honey.
I'm sorry,
I'm so sorry.
Sara, take a breath.
This is off.
- Everything's just off. - Just try to breathe
and we'll go through it.
But...
I don't remember anything.
Go slow.
They prepared me for this.
He said you'd more than likely lose any recollection.
- I would remember... - Sara.
It happened.
This doesn't make sense.
I am so sorry, I feel terrible.
And I was so busy with...
my writing and I knew that you were down
but I never thought...
It's okay now.
I'm here for you.
Completely.
I'm scared.
Just rest.
I love you so much.
Everything is going to be different now.
Nick?
Hey!
Run!
Sh...
It's okay. Come here.
- Hey. - I had the worst dream.
Nah, it's okay. I'm here.
It was just a dream, all right?
It was just a nightmare.
It seemed so real.
Here.
You take one of these.
Doctor gave them to me for you.
Help you relax.
I'll get you some water.
Hello?
Sara?
Yes. This is Sara.
Are you there?
I'm so sorry...
- Sara. Are. You... - Nick!
Stop bothering my wife!
- Oh, God, you scared me. - I'm sorry, darling.
I just couldn't let them bother you like that, not right now.
- I didn't not what to do... - No, it's all right.
It's all right. I mean, I should have ripped
that old phone from the wall years ago.
None of that matters now.
Just happy to see you up.
How's your memory?
I only remember little things.
Oh yeah? Like what?
Family.
I know I have a sister.
And my parents.
Do you remember your parents?
I think so.
Have they come to see me since I've been home?
You don't remember?
No, I don't.
Mom...
Sara, your parents are gone.
They died last October.
Sara...
It's your sister. She...
My parents are dead and so is my sister?
No, she's not dead, she's just...
All right, look, I'm not gonna say
I blame her entirely for your accident
but the way that she handled your parents' will,
she manipulated them into giving her
almost everything and leaving you with nothing
but this big, empty house. I...
I just can't imagine a more selfish,
deplorable thing to do and to you,
her flesh and blood.
You spiraled down from there.
You spiraled and yes, I blame her,
I blame her for a lot of this.
She is not to be trusted, Sara.
But that, all of that is in the past.
From now on, we're moving forward,
not looking back. You understand?
Sara?
Nick, you startled me.
I'm sorry, darling,
that certainly wasn't my intention.
Who was that woman?
I think I saw you talking with her yesterday.
Oh, Rose?
I hired her to help me take care of you
while doing my writing.
She's been here?
Yes, of course.
She's been taking great care of you.
You've been sleeping...
which is a good thing.
Are you okay?
I... I think I remember you're my husband
but I don't remember any of our experiences.
I'm sorry.
What about our trip to Costa Rica?
Christmas dinner in Ojai?
Your mum's drunken confession? You were scarred for weeks.
The day that we moved in together
was the best day of my life.
I'm so sorry, Nick.
It's okay, It'll all come back to you.
Gotta get back to work.
Nick.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Nick?
What are you doing?
The third floor is off limits.
I... I was...
Nick gave explicit orders to keep this door locked.
But why?
The third floor has access to the roof.
I've put fresh sheets on your bed.
You must continue to rest.
Rose...
Where's the clock?
- The clock? - The grandfather clock.
I've been into all these rooms and I can't find it.
There's no grandfather clock.
Perhaps you were dreaming it.
No, I've heard it when I've been awake,
I heard it just now.
I've been through all the rooms in this house
and if there was a grandfather clock,
I would have seen it.
Now you must rest.
That's all you need to do.
I'll tend to you soon.
You smell good.
I took a shower.
Nick, where there photographs in the hallway?
There were.
But I had them removed.
Why?
You don't have to think about those things right now.
But I'd like to see them, they might help me rememb...
Sweetheart, you just went through
a very intense experience.
Your sister, your parents,
I just want you to clear your head of all of that.
Just give it some time.
We'll put 'em back up.
And what tub?
What's that?
You said you found me in the bathtub when I...
There's no tub in the bathroom.
Oh, that.
I had it removed.
There was no need for that bad memory
to cement itself in this house.
What's wrong, Sara?
Don't you believe me?
No, it's not that.
This all just feels like a strange dream.
I don't know what's wrong with me.
You're so beautiful.
I'm sorry.
Give it some time, okay?
If you need me, I'll be right here.
You must continue to rest.
I just don't know what's wrong with her.
What is wrong with you...
There she is.
See, it's so strange.
My God.
I told you.
What is it?
Ah...
What's wrong with her?
What is wrong with you!
Go.
Sara,.
Who was that?
That was your sister.
The other person... They were in here and
- he was like, examining me... - Wait, what?
- I met them at the door. - Then how did they get up here?
No, I didn't let them in, Sara.
They were here.
I know that you've been having very vivid dreams, Sara,
but I'm not gonna ignore this one.
Your sister has gotten herself into some things.
She's done things behind my back in the past,
things that I don't agree with.
That's why I headed them off at the door.
But I can assure you, darling, they were not up here.
And they won't be as long as I'm around.
Dr. Simms, let's just say...
I don't agree with his practices and leave it at that.
My face looked horrible.
You're so fragile, Sara.
I can't find you like that again.
I won't let it happen.
I need you.
Do you understand?
Yes.
We have each other.
We don't need anyone else.
I love you.
I will never leave you.
You're good.
I didn't know you can play the piano.
Yeah, well, you...
Right.
How are you?
What do you mean?
I miss you.
Who?
Who was I?
I just feel like such a burden
trying to find out.
You were everything.
You were funny.
And kind, honest.
Everything I could never be.
But you still are,
still will be...
even if you don't get your memories back.
What if we could start again?
A new life
with new memories.
I would love that.
Like a second chance.
That's exactly what this is.
We're lucky
I didn't know you could play the piano.
Well, there's a lot about me you don't know.
I can't wait to find out.
I can hear you with me.
Give her strength.
Hi.
How you feeling?
I think I feel good.
Why good?
I don't know.
Something about you.
That look you give me.
What look?
Like, I belong here.
With you.
You know what I think?
You're feeling it.
Your power.
which is why I was thinking...
you're ready.
Ready for what?
What would you say to a dinner party here?
A few of our closest friends? A simple evening.
Some wine, some laughs.
It'd be good for you.
They've been asking about you.
They're concerned about you.
Just want to see you well.
I think this will be really good.
Oh, Rose, let me get that.
No, it's okay. I've got it.
- Let me help you. - Nah, it's nothing.
It's nothing.
I'm s-sorry, Rose, I just wanted...
When a woman says she doesn't need help,
she doesn't need help.
It looked heavy.
Is something the matter with Rose?
Nick?
I don't think so.
Why?
Well, we were outside and I was trying to help her
and she just...
Snapped at me.
I didn't know what to do.
- Snapped? - Yes.
She snapped at me.
Snap back.
No, that's not me.
Sara, you can't let people walk all over you.
That's the anger boiling inside.
I mean, if you're gonna get healthy, Sara,
you have to, you've gotta let it out.
- But not at Rose. - Why not?
She's the hired help. Not your mother.
She's an employee.
To be perfectly honest, it doesn't sound like
something she'd do but if you say she snapped at you,
- I believe you.. - It wasn't that big of a deal.
- I just... - I'll tell you what,
the next time she gives you shit, you let her have it.
Let's practice right now.
What are you smiling at?
You think I'm joking?
Nick..
Are you gonna let that old bitch
get the best of you?
- Nick, I can't... - Can't?
Can't is a word for weaklings, Sara.
- Are you a weakling? - Please don't call me that.
I didn't call you anything. I asked if that's what you are.
- You're being mean. - The world is mean, Sara.
You can't survive the world.
You almost didn't...
Good.
Nick?
- Sara? - I...
I woke up and you weren't there.
What are you doing down here?
Oh, my God. I'm so sorry.
Hello.
Hi, Sara.
You are Sara Wright.
Who are you?
My name is Tom and I'm a friend of your sister's.
Nick?
She thought I could maybe help you.
Why?
She's worried about you, quite worried.
We could all use a little help from time to time.
Sometimes we get so lost,
we don't even realize we need help.
But there's always crumbs, Sara,
always leading us home,
you just have to find them.
Sometimes the voices in our head
are there to guide us.
Follow us, Sara.
Follow us.
What are you doing?
There was a knock and you weren't there and...
There was a man.
No, there wasn't.
I came downstairs and you were standing there
- with the door open. - But this was real, Nick.
There was no one there, Sara.
You saw it for yourself.
I can't do this.
I'm trying to help you. But if you don't trust me
- then I ca- - No, no... I trust you.
Just please, please don't leave.
Sara?
You understand that I'm doing this for your benefit.
Right?
The world...
has always taken advantage of your kindness, Sara.
This is what the world does.
It takes people like you
and it sucks the marrow out and it leaves the rest to rot.
I love you...
I love you too much to lift you out of another fucking tub.
Do you understand?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I have something for you.
- Do you like it? - Oh, my goodness.
It's beautiful, Nick.
Oh, my goodness.
I was thinking you could wear it
to the dinner party tomorrow night.
The party.
We'll be ready.
Sara?
You there?
Sara!
Ah!
Sara?
Sara!
Who are you?
Sara.
Listen to me.
You know you.
Sara!
Stay with me.
Stay with me, you little bitch!
Everything's going to be all right.
You're with me now.
No, no!
Sara, Sara, it's over.
It's over. It's over.
I'm here.
You're looking well.
I don't feel well.
Nick told me to prepare a ham.
I hope you're well enough to receive guests.
How do you get here?
I take the bus.
I've never seen a bus pass this house.
It drops me off down the road
and then I walk up.
- Where do you live? - In town.
Do you live alone?
I'm a widow.
Rose, I'd like you to make sure
the dining room is spotless tonight.
I believe that the dining room is up to Nick's standards.
What about my standards?
Rose.
Well, if you're so concerned about it,
maybe you should do it yourself.
All I'm saying is if you want it done right...
I could do it, Rose.
Nick would never fuck you then.
What did you just say?
Rose.
- Rose. - As a matter of fact,
you're not looking well at all. Perhaps you should lie down.
Rose, what did you just say?
I watch him in the shower sometimes,
when you're sleeping.
He's caught me a few times.
He doesn't seem to mind.
Just keep lathering chest.
- Stop. - I think he enjoys it.
Sara?
Are you all right, dear?
You're not looking well at all.
Perhaps you should lie down.
Don't ever talk about him like that.
About who, dear? What are you talking about?
Please, please just go.
Are you all right, dear?
Please go.
What about the laundry?
You're fired.
Sara!
We can call the whole thing off.
Just say the word.
No.
I went out to the garden.
I couldn't find...
whatever it was that you described.
It was just a pile of weeds.
I'm sorry about Rose...
Don't apologize about Rose.
You are the woman of the house
and you did what needed to be done.
I'm proud of you.
I'm nervous.
Pre-dinner courage?
Thank you.
Mm.
That's strong.
Like you.
I'm gonna head downstairs. You'll be fine.
Sara?
Yes?
I may show off a little tonight.
Just been so long and I want everyone
to think that we're back to normal.
Or at least close to it.
I hope that's okay.
I understand.
I love you.
I love you, too.
You look fantastic.
Thank you.
Friends, I would like to reintroduce you
to Mrs. Sara Wright.
Um, thank you.
Thank you all for coming.
I may not remember who you are but I'm glad you're here.
What's that?
Well, that's for you. After dinner.
Here, sit right here.
Sara, why don't you get reacquainted with everybody?
I'm gonna go check on the pork.
It's so good to see you, Sara.
You are looking very fine.
- Thank you... - Is it true?
You don't remember a thing?
Things are slowly coming back to me.
Surely, you remember Madeleine and I.
Wow. Is that the first...
Nick, that looks amazing.
Sure does.
It's gonna taste even better.
Isn't that right, Bobby.
I think I deserve a little credit.
Hi.
Nick.
Sara, she said that she didn't say anything to you.
Plus, I had no idea how to cook the pork.
Mm, pork.
I'd eat my own body weight, if I could.
You know, it's funny, you put it like that, Bobby.
I was reading something earlier
for this thing I'm working on about cannibalism.
Do you know what cannibals call human flesh?
They call it long pig.
That's it, Bobby. And they say
human flesh tastes like pork.
Now, apparently, cannibals do what they do
to acquire the power of the person they're eating.
They don't eat the whole person, mind you,
just the important bits.
The Korowai tribe of New Guinea still practice it.
I mean, really, people have been practicing cannibalism
since the beginning.
Neanderthal eating Neanderthal
then modern man shows up and eats Neanderthal.
And obviously modern man eats modern man.
Huh?
When you think about it, though,
nothing's really changed.
Your husband has a gift
for dinner conversation, doesn't he?
Well, I would like to propose a toast
to our lovely Sara.
May your recovery be swift
and may this night mark a rebirth for you.
- Salud. - Salud...
Oh, and to Nick
for cooking this extravagant meal
and hosting this...
very special evening.
- Salud. - Salud.
To all of you for coming up and supporting us.
It has not been an easy process
but I feel confident that we're on the homestretch.
But mostly to my wife...
without whom I wouldn't have a home.
Or purpose.
Watching you strengthen lately has really filled my heart.
To never looking back.
Sara.
Someone's outside.
Sorry, what did you see?
- I thought... - Sara.
There's nobody outside.
How many of these have you had?
Sara, maybe you saw
your reflection in the glass or something.
Sara, where did you get that dress?
It's spectacular.
Um.... Nick.
Oh... Handsome, charming and great taste.
Come on. What are you waiting for?
Dig in.
Can I help you, Rose?
The key.
Mm.
Yeah. Everybody, we need to loosen up.
Drink. I want to see empty glasses. Come on.
Somebody get me another drink.
Now, that's the spirit. I mean, this is a party, right?
It's a party.
Get your hand off my leg.
Don't you ever touch me again, you filthy, fucking pig.
- I hate you! - I hate you!
There she is.
- Inappropriate. - Too much to drink, Bobby.
Come on. Get him out of here.
This is what I call a party.
Woo!
Sara.
Look.
What you've done.
So beautiful.
I didn't.
You did.
No. I didn't.
You took the final step.
Now, we can truly begin.
You bit the apple, Sara.
This is your Eden.
Your baptism, the place of your rebirth.
What?
- What's going on? - Do you remember
sitting in this very tub and letting go?
Do you remember calling to me?
I have never heard music sweeter than
the sound of the razor kissing your wrists.
But you...
don't worry about anything.
I didn't kill him.
I just wanted him to stop touching me.
You don't have to be scared. Anymore.
Just let me get you home and I'll explain it all.
I am home.
No.
No, please.
What's wrong, darling?
Oh, honey, you can't leave us.
Sara, open the door!
What are you?
I'm your husband.
Sweetheart.
Sara, you're not well.
You just stabbed Bobby in the neck with a fork.
Get out!
Follow us.
Sara?
Hmm?
Sara.
Listen to me.
She thought I could maybe help you.
Do you really want to die?
Is that what you want?
Sara.
Sara! Follow us.
The key's in your hand!
You wouldn't do it, would you?
Sara, Sara, just listen to me,
my voice. No one else.
Sara. What do you see?
You can hear him.
Don't let them do this to you.
Sara, just listen to me.
I won't pick up your dead body again.
I can't.
The voices led the razors to your wrists.
Sara, he's lying.
I'm your husband.
I love you.
So, please, please don't do that to me again.
This is exactly what they did to you the last time.
Amen.
You are seeing things that aren't there, Sara.
Sara, hey.
I'm with you now.
I love you so much.
Trust me, I'll keep you safe.
Everything is going to be different now.
Amen.
Sara, he's lying!
Leave her now!
Leave this earth!
In the name of God Himself!
Take me!
I cast you out.
Out, demon!
I cast you out!
Out!
It is done.
Her vitals are fine.
Everything seems to be okay, here.
Thank for your help, Mike.
Ladies.
Well, I've never heard of anything like this before.
Victims of possession
don't usually remember being possessed.
It seemed so real. He...
felt like my husband.
It, Sara. Not he.
You mustn't continue to give strength to its illusions.
This isn't over yet.
The entity is purged but you're still vulnerable.
When a demon, or in this case demons,
exit the host,
they don't leave the soul as it was before the invasion.
A hole is left behind, a void,
a pocket of darkness.
You can feel it, can't you?
It will eventually go away.
Be cautious, Sarah.
Strengthen your faith.
Fill that hole
with light.
And, Julie, watch over her.
Take care of her.
Be her lighthouse.
Sara, I'm gonna make some tea.
You want some?
That sounds good, actually.
Doc gave me these to give to you.
Sara.
I was the one who found you.
In the bathtub with a razor blade.
I can't even begin to describe what that did to me.
I know living here must be a constant reminder
of what happened to Mom and Dad
but, you know, you can always talk to me
about whatever, whenever, right?
Come to me when you're feeling sad.
Let's talk it out together, okay?
Julie, I am so sorry.
I know. Don't apologize.
- I never... - You don't need to apologize.
Just know from now on everything is gonna be alright.
You're with me now.
The doctor gave them to me for you, help you relax.
Take me!
Everything's gonna be different now.
Provided by explosiveskull https://twitter.com/kaboomskull