AH AH AH AH
WHERE THE NORTHWIND MEETS THE SEA
THERE'S A RIVER
FULL OF MEMORY
SLEEP, MY DARLING, SAFE AND SOUND
FOR IN THIS RIVER, ALL IS FOUND
IN HER WATERS
DEEP AND TRUE
LIE THE ANSWERS
AND A PATH FOR YOU
DIVE DOWN DEEP INTO HER SOUND
BUT NOT TOO FAR OR YOU'LL BE DROWNED
YES, SHE WILL SING TO THOSE WHO HEAR
AND IN HER SONG, ALL MAGIC FLOWS
BUT CAN YOU BRAVE
WHAT YOU MOST FEAR?
CAN YOU FACE WHAT THE RIVER KNOWS?
WHERE THE NORTHWIND
MEETS THE SEA
THERE'S A MOTHER
FULL OF MEMORY
COME, MY DARLING, HOMEWARD BOUND
WHEN ALL IS LOST
THEN ALL IS FOUND
AH AH AH AH
YES, THE WIND BLOWS A LITTLE BIT COLDER
AND WE'RE ALL GETTING OLDER
AND THE CLOUDS ARE MOVING ON
WITH EVERY AUTUMN BREEZE
PETER PUMPKIN JUST BECAME FERTILIZER
AND MY LEAFS A LITTLE SADDER AND WISER
THAT'S WHY I RELY ON CERTAIN CERTAINTIES
YES, SOME THINGS NEVER CHANGE
LIKE THE FEEL OF YOUR HAND IN MINE
SOME THINGS STAY THE SAME
LIKE HOW WE GET ALONG JUST FINE
LIKE AN OLD STONE WALL THAT'LL NEVER FALL
SOME THINGS ARE ALWAYS TRUE!
SOME THINGS NEVER CHANGE
LIKE HOW I'M HOLDING ON TIGHT TO YOU
THE LEAVES ARE ALREADY FALLING
SVEN, IT FEELS LIKE THE FUTURE IS CALLING
ARE YOU TELLING ME TONIGHT YOU'RE
GONNA GET DOWN ON ONE KNEE?
YEAH, BUT I'M REALLY BAD AT
PLANNING THESE THINGS OUT
LIKE CANDLELIGHT
AND PULLING OF RINGS OUT
MAYBE YOU SHOULD LEAVE ALL THE
ROMANTIC STUFF TO ME!
YEAH, SOME THINGS NEVER CHANGE
LIKE THE LOVE THAT I FEEL FOR HER
SOME THINGS STAY THE SAME
LIKE HOW REINDEERS ARE EASIER
BUT IF I COMMIT AND I GO FOR IT
I'LL KNOW WHAT TO SAY AND DO!
RIGHT?
SOME THINGS NEVER CHANGE
SVEN, THE PRESSURE IS ALL ON YOU
THE WINDS ARE RESTLESS
COULD THAT BE WHY
I'M HEARING THIS CALL?
IS SOMETHING COMING?
I'M NOT SURE I WANT
THINGS TO CHANGE AT ALL
THESE DAYS ARE PRECIOUS
CAN'T LET THEM SLIP AWAY
I CAN'T FREEZE THIS MOMENT
BUT I CAN STILL GO OUT AND
SEIZE THIS DAY!
AH
OH
THE WIND BLOWS A LITTLE BIT COLDER
AND YOU ALL LOOK A LITTLE BIT OLDER
IT'S TIME TO COUNT OUR BLESSINGS
BENEATH AN AUTUMN SKY
WE'LL ALWAYS LIVE IN A KINGDOM OF PLENTY
THAT STANDS FOR THE GOOD OF THE MANY!
AND I PROMISE YOU
THE FLAG OF ARENDELLE WILL ALWAYS FLY!
OUR FLAG WILL ALWAYS FLY!
OUR FLAG WILL ALWAYS FLY
SOME THINGS NEVER CHANGE
TURN AROUND AND THE TIME HAS FLOWN
SOME THINGS STAY THE SAME
THOUGH THE FUTURE REMAINS UNKNOWN
MAY OUR GOOD LUCK LAST
MAY OUR PAST BE PAST
TIME'S MOVING FAST, IT'S TRUE
SOME THINGS NEVER CHANGE
AND I'M HOLDING ON TIGHT TO YOU
HOLDING ON TIGHT TO YOU
I'M HOLDING ON TIGHT TO YOU
AH AH AH AH
WHERE THE NORTHWIND MEETS THE SEA
THERE'S A RIVER
FULL OF MEMORY
SLEEP, MY DARLING, SAFE AND SOUND
FOR IN THIS RIVER, ALL IS FOUND
AH AH AH AH
AH AH AH AH OH
I CAN HEAR YOU
BUT I WON'T
SOME LOOK FOR TROUBLE
WHILE OTHERS DON'T
THERE'S A THOUSAND REASONS
I SHOULD GO ABOUT MY DAY
AND IGNORE YOUR WHISPERS
WHICH I WISH WOULD GO AWAY, OH
AH AH AH AH
OH OH
YOU'RE NOT A VOICE
YOU'RE JUST A RINGING IN MY EAR
AND IF I HEARD YOU
WHICH I DON'T
I'M SPOKEN FOR, I FEAR
EVERYONE I'VE EVER LOVED
IS HERE WITHIN THESE WALLS
I'M SORRY, SECRET SIREN,
BUT I'M BLOCKING OUT YOUR CALLS
I'VE HAD MY ADVENTURE
I DON'T NEED SOMETHING NEW
I'M AFRAID OF WHAT I'M RISKING
IF I FOLLOW YOU
INTO THE UNKNOWN
AH AH AH AH
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
"CAUSE YOU'VE BEEN
KEEPING ME AWAKE
ARE YOU HERE TO DISTRACT ME
SO I MAKE A BIG MISTAKE?
OR ARE YOU SOMEONE OUT THERE
WHO'S A LITTLE BIT LIKE ME
WHO KNOWS DEEP DOWN
I'M NOT WHERE I'M MEANT TO BE?
EVERY DAY'S A LITTLE HARDER
AS I FEEL MY POWER GROW
DON'T YOU KNOW THERE'S PART OF ME
THAT LONGS TO GO
INTO THE UNKNOWN?
INTO THE UNKNOWN!
AH AH AH AH
OH OH OH
ARE YOU OUT THERE?
DO YOU KNOW ME?
CAN YOU FEEL ME?
CAN YOU SHOW ME?
AH AH AH AH
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
DON'T LEAVE ME ALONE
HOW DO I FOLLOW YOU
INTO THE UNKNOWN?
AH AH AH AH
WHAT WAS THAT?
SAMANTHA?
THIS WILL ALL MAKE SENSE
WHEN I AM OLDER
SOMEDAY I WILL SEE
THAT THIS MAKES SENSE
ONE DAY WHEN I'M OLD AND WISE
I'LL THINK BACK AND REALIZE
THAT THESE WERE ALL
COMPLETELY NORMAL EVENTS!
I'LL HAVE ALL THE ANSWERS
WHEN I'M OLDER
LIKE WHY WE'RE IN THIS DARK
ENCHANTED WOOD
I KNOW IN A COUPLE YEARS
THESE WILL SEEM LIKE CHILDISH FEARS
AND SO I KNOW THIS ISN'T BAD, IT'S GOOD
EXCUSE ME.
GROWING UP MEANS ADAPTING
PUZZLING OUT YOUR WORLD
AND YOUR PLACE
WHEN I'M MORE MATURE
I'LL FEEL TOTALLY SECURE
BEING WATCHED BY SOMETHING
WITH A CREEPY, CREEPY FACE
AAH!
SEE, THAT WILL ALL MAKE SENSE
WHEN I AM OLDER
SO THERE'S NO NEED
TO BE TERRIFIED OR TENSE
I'LL JUST DREAM ABOUT A TIME
WHEN I'M IN MY AGED PRIME
"CAUSE WHEN YOU'RE OLDER
ABSOLUTELY EVERYTHING MAKES SENSE!
THIS IS FINE.
AH AH AH AH
DIVE DOWN DEEP INTO HER SOUND
BUT NOT TOO FAR OR YOU'LL BE DROWNED
REINDEERS ARE BETTER THAN PEOPLE
SVEN, WHY IS LOVE SO HARD?
YOU FEEL WHAT YOU FEEL
AND THOSE FEELINGS ARE REAL
COME ON, KRISTOFF
LET DOWN YOUR GUARD
AGAIN, YOU'RE GONE
AGAIN, YOURE GONE
OFF ON A DIFFRENT PATH THAN MINE
I'M LEFT BEHIND
WONDERING IF I SHOULD FOLLOW
YOU HAD TO GO
AND, OF COURSE, IT'S ALWAYS FINE
I PROB'LY COULD CATCH UP WITH YOU
TOMORROW
BUT IS THIS WHAT IT FEELS LIKE
TO BE GROWING APART?
WHEN DID I BECOME THE ONE
WHO'S ALWAYS CHASING YOUR HEART?
NOW I TURN AROUND AND FIND
I AM LOST IN THE WOODS
NORTH IS SOUTH
RIGHT IS LEFT WHEN YOU'RE GONE
RIGHT IS LEFT WHEN YOU RE GONE
RIGHT IS LEFT WHEN YOURE GONE
I'M THE ONE WHO SEES YOU HOME
BUT NOW I'M LOST IN THE WOODS
AND I DON'T KNOW WHAT PATH
AND 1 DON'T KNOW WHAT PATH
YOU ARE ON
I'M LOST IN THE WOODS
UP TILL NOW
THE NEXT STEP WAS A QUESTION OF HOW
I NEVER THOUGHT
IT WAS A QUESTION OF WHETHER
WHO AM I IF I'M NOT YOUR GUY?
WHO AM 1 IF I'M NOT YOUR GUY?
WHERE AM I IF WE'RE NOT TOGETHER?
FOREVER
NOW I KNOW YOU'RE MY TRUE NORTH
CAUSE 1 AM LOST IN THE WOODS
"CAUSE I AM LOST IN THE WOODS
UP IS DOWN, DAY IS NIGHT
WHEN YOU'RE NOT THERE
WHEN YOURE NOT THERE
OH, YOU'RE MY ONLY LANDMARK
SO I'M LOST IN THE WOODS
WONDERING IF YOU STILL CARE
BUT I'LL WAIT
FOR A SIGN
THAT I'M YOUR PATH
"CAUSE YOU ARE MINE
YOU ARE MINE
UNTIL THEN I'M LOST IN THE WOODS
LOST IN THE WOODS
IN THE WOODS
I'M LOST IN THE WOODS
LOST IN THE WOODS
I'M LOST
I'M LOST IN THE WOODS
AH AH AH AH
AH OH AH OH
OH AH OH OH AH
AH AH AH AH
EVERY INCH OF ME IS TREMBLING
BUT NOT FROM THE COLD
SOMETHING IS FAMILIAR
LIKE A DREAM I CAN REACH
BUT NOT QUITE HOLD
I CAN SENSE YOU THERE
LIKE A FRIEND I'VE ALWAYS KNOWN
I'M ARRIVING
AND IT FEELS LIKE I AM HOME
I HAVE ALWAYS BEEN A FORTRESS
COLD SECRETS DEEP INSIDE
YOU HAVE SECRETS, TOO
BUT YOU DON'T HAVE TO HIDE
SHOW YOURSELF
I'M DYING TO MEET YOU
IT'S YOUR TURN
ARE YOU THE ONE I'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR
ALL OF MY LIFE?
SHOW YOURSELF
I'M READY TO LEARN
AH AH AH AH
I'VE NEVER FELT SO CERTAIN
ALL MY LIFE I'VE BEEN TORN
BUT I'M HERE FOR A REASON
COULD IT BE THE REASON I WAS BORN?
COULD IT BE THE REASON 1 WAS BORN?
I HAVE ALWAYS BEEN SO DIFFERENT
NORMAL RULES DID NOT APPLY
IS THIS THE DAY?
ARE YOU THE WAY
I FINALLY FIND OUT WHY?
SHOW YOURSELF!
I'M NO LONGER TREMBLING
HERE I AM
I'VE COME SO FAR
YOU ARE THE ANSWER I'VE WAITED FOR
ALL OF MY LIFE
OH, SHOW YOURSELF!
LET ME SEE WHO YOU ARE
COME TO ME NOW
OPEN YOUR DOOR
DON'T MAKE ME WAIT
ONE MOMENT MORE
OH
COME TO ME NOW
OPEN YOUR DOOR
DON'T MAKE ME WAIT
ONE MOMENT MORE
WHERE THE NORTHWIND MEETS THE SEA
AH AH AH AH
THERE'S A RIVER
FULL OF MEMORY
COME, MY DARLING, HOMEWARD BOUND
I AM FOUND!
SHOW YOURSELF
STEP IN TO YOUR POWER
GROW YOURSELF
INTO SOMETHING NEW
YOU ARE THE ONE
YOU'VE BEEN WAITING FOR
ALL OF MY LIFE
ALL OF YOUR LIFE
OH, SHOW YOURSELF!
AH AH
AH AH AH AH
HERE I STAND IN THE LIGHT OF DAY
LIE THE ANSWERS
AND A PATH FOR YOU
DIVE DOWN DEEP INTO HER SOUND
BUT NOT TOO FAR OR YOU'LL BE DROWNED
I'VE SEEN DARK BEFORE
BUT NOT LIKE THIS
THIS IS COLD
THIS IS EMPTY
THIS IS NUMB
THE LIFE I KNEW IS OVER
THE LIGHTS ARE OUT
HELLO, DARKNESS, I'M READY TO SUCCUMB
I FOLLOW YOU AROUND
I ALWAYS HAVE
BUT YOU'VE GONE TO A PLACE
I CANNOT FIND
THIS GRIEF HAS A GRAVITY
IT PULLS ME DOWN
BUT A TINY VOICE
WHISPERS IN MY MIND
YOU ARE LOST
HOPE IS GONE
BUT YOU MUST GO ON
AND DO THE NEXT RIGHT THING
CAN THERE BE A DAY
BEYOND THIS NIGHT?
I DON'T KNOW ANYMORE WHAT IS TRUE
I CAN'T FIND MY DIRECTION
I'M ALL ALONE
THE ONLY STAR
THAT GUIDED ME WAS YOU
HOW TO RISE FROM THE FLOOR
WHEN IT'S NOT YOU I'M RISING FOR?
JUST DO THE NEXT RIGHT THING
TAKE A STEP
STEP AGAIN
IT IS ALL THAT I CAN
TO DO THE NEXT RIGHT THING
I WON'T LOOK TOO FAR AHEAD
IT'S TOO MUCH FOR ME TO TAKE
BUT BREAK IT DOWN TO THIS NEXT BREATH
THIS NEXT STEP
THIS NEXT CHOICE
IS ONE THAT I CAN MAKE!
SO I'LL WALK
THROUGH THIS NIGHT
STUMBLING BLINDLY TOWARD THE LIGHT
AND DO THE NEXT RIGHT THING
AND WITH THE DAWN
WHAT COMES THEN?
WHEN IT'S CLEAR THAT EVERYTHING
WILL NEVER BE THE SAME AGAIN?
THEN I'LL MAKE THE CHOICE
TO HEAR THAT VOICE
AND DO THE NEXT RIGHT THING