Fixed by UFFE_BSS
www.Undertexter.se
I should have known you would be here
Professor McGonagall
Goose Night Professor Dumbledore
Are the rumors true, Albus?
I'm afraid so Professor.
Both the good and the bad...
And the boy?
Hagrid takes him with him
Do you think it is wise to entrust
something so important to Hagrid?
Professor, I would trust Hagrid with my life.
Professor Dumbledore,
Professor McGonagall...
There was no problem I hope?
No, sir.
The little one fell asleep when we flew over Bristol
So I let him sleep...
Here you go
Albus, do you think it's safe to
leave him here with these people?
I have been observing them all day,
they are the worst Muggles imaginable
They really are...
They are the only family he has
This boy will be famous,
every child will know who he is
Precisely...
He's better off without all that...
Until he is ready
There you go, Hagrid.
It's not goodbye after all
Good luck to you...
Harry Potter
Get up! Step up...
Now!
Get up Potter, we're going to the zoo!
Congratulations, my boy
Finish your breakfast,
and try not to burn anything
Yes, Aunt Petunia
I want everything to be perfect on
...my little Dudley's big day
Bring me my coffee, boy!
Yes Uncle Vernon
Aren't they beautiful, my darling?
How many are there?
36, I counted them myself.
36! But last year I got 37!!!
But some packages are bigger than last year
I don't care how big they are!
Wait, wait, you know what we do...
When we go out, we buy
two more presents, my dear
It will be a good day at the zoo.
I'm warning you now, son...
If you do anything stupid...
If you do something stupid...
In general... How to smoke
all your meals for a week
Jump in!
Get him moving
-Get moving!
Move it!!!
He's asleep!
He is boring
Ignore him
He does not understand how it feels
to lie there day after day,
while people stare at you
Can you hear me?
It's just that... I've
never talked to a snake before
Are you talking about
Often with people?
You are from Burma, right? Was it nice there?
Do you miss your family?
I understand, I didn't know my parents either
Mother! Father! Come and see the snake!
Thanks to
There was so little
A snake!
Momaaa!!!
But Dudley! How did you get in there?!
What happened?
I don't know, I swear!
It's ok.
We need to get you out of these cold clothes.
What happened?
I swear I don't know!
First the glass was there, then it disappeared...
It was like magic!
Magic does not exist!
HARRY POTTER THE CUPBOARD UNDER THE STAIRS
Let's see! Harry has received a letter
Give it to me, it's mine!
Yours? -Who would write to you?
No more letters in this mailbox
Have a nice day at work, my dear
Go now
Nice day, Sunday
The best day of the week in my opinion
You know why, Dudley?
There is no mail on Sundays.
Absolutely right Harry!
No mail on Sundays. -Ha!
No damned letters today!
No, not a single one...
No cursed letters...
Give it to me!
Give me that letter!
Mom, what's going on?
Those are my letters!
Let go of me!
That's enough! We are traveling far away,
where they can't find us!
We travel far away,
where they cannot find us!
Daddy has gone mad, hasn't he?
Make a wish Harry
Who is there?
Pardon my entrance.
I demand that you leave.
This is trespassing!
Relax, Dursley, you old fart!
I haven't seen you since you were a little baby.
Harry.
You've grown a lot. Especially around the belly
I... I am not Harry
I am...
Of course you are!
I have something for you
I think I've mashed it a bit
but the taste is probably the same
I have written the text myself
Thank you.
It's not every day you turn 11, is it?
Excuse me... but who are you?
Rubeus Hagrid, Keeper of the Keys
and estate manager at Hogwarts.
But you know all about Hogwarts.
No, I don't.
Not ... ? Then how do you think
your mother and father learned everything?
Learned what?
You are a wizard Harry
I am a what?
A magician!
And a powerful one at that,
with a little practice.
No, you're probably wrong
I cannot be a T-wizard.
I'm just Harry
...just Harry? Well, "Just Harry," you've never
had anything strange happen
Something you could not explain
when you were angry or scared?
Dear Mr. Potter. We are pleased to inform you
...that you have been admitted to the
Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry.
No he can't go! We don't want to hear about
any more of this nonsense!
You knew that? You knew all along
and you didn't tell me?
Of course we knew that!
How could we avoid it when my
"perfect" sister was who she was.
Her mother and father were so proud when she got her letter.
We have a witch in the family,
isn't that amazing?
I was the only one who saw what she really was.
A freak!
Then she met that Potter,
and then she had you...
Then she met that Potter and had you,
and I knew you would be the same...
And then, you can imagine, she went and got
blown up, and we got you on the neck!
Blown up in a car crash?
You said my parents died in a car accident!
A car accident? Lilly and James Potter dead in a car accident?
car accident?!
It is nonsense! It is a scandal!
He can't leave!
Do you think a Muggle like you can stop him?
"Muggles?
People without magic powers...Ever since he was born
he has been destined for...
to attend the best wizarding school in the country.
And... be trained by one of
Hogwarts' finest wizards, Albus Dumbledore.
I'm not paying some idiot
to teach him magic!
Never insult
Albus Dumbledore
in front of me.
I'd appreciate it if you didn't tell
to anyone at Hogwarts about it.
I'm not really allowed to use magic.
Ok
We are a little behind schedule,
we have to go.
Unless you'd rather stay here, of course?
Each student must have with them
a standard-sized tin cauldron.
And they can also bring
an owl, a cat or a toad
Can we find all that in London?
If you know where to go.
Oh! Hagrid, the usual?
No thanks, I'm on official
mission for Hogwarts
I help Harry with
buying study materials.
My goodness... it's Harry Potter!
Welcome back Mr. Potter.
Doris Crawford, Mr. Potter.
I can't believe I finally get to meet you.
Harry P-Po-Potter. It is truly an
honor to meet you.
Hello Professor! I didn't see you at first.
Harry it's Professor Quirrel.
Nice to meet you.
He will be your teacher in
"Defense Against the Dark Arts at Hogwarts.
Not f-because you need it, right Potter?
We need to move on...
Goodbye
See Harry there? You're famous.
But why am I famous, Hagrid?
How is it that they know who I am?
I am probably not the right person to tell Harry.
Welcome to Diagon Alley Harry.
They have paper and pencils!
They only have magic items.
Wow, look at that! The new Nimbus 2000.
The fastest model....
But Hagrid, how can I pay?
I don't have any money, do I?
There's your money, Harry!
Gringotts. -The magic bank.
There is no safer place,
except Hogwarts.
Hagrid, what are those people?
"Black elves" - Quite cunning
and not very friendly.
You better stay close to me.
Harry Potter wishes to make some withdrawals.
And does Harry Potter have his key?
One moment... I have it here somewhere.
Ha! Here is the little rascal.
Just one more thing...
Professor Dumbledore gave me this
It is about, you probably know "what"
in the vault, you probably know "which"
Excellent.
Valve 687.
The lamp, please.
The key, please.
You didn't think your parents
would leave you empty-handed?
Vault 713
What's in it, Hagrid?
Can't tell you about it.
Hogwarts business, very secret.
Move backwards
Better not mention this to anyone, Harry.
I still need... a magic wand
A magic wand? Go to Ollivanders.
There is no better place.
You slip in there for a moment,
and I'll run a quick errand
Hello?
I was wondering when I would
see you, Mr. Potter.
It feels like it was just yesterday your
parents bought their first magic wand.
Let's see.
Wave it around!
Obviously not the
Maybe...
This one
No, no... definitely not
I wonder...
Strange.
very strange
What is strange?
I can remember all the ones I have sold,
and now it happens to be so-r.
-that the phoenix whose
tail feather is in your staff
Tail feather is in your wand.
left behind one more feather...just one more.
just one more.
It's strange that you decided to do this.
When its brother gave you that scar.
And who owns that staff?
We do not mention his name.
The wand chooses its wizard Mr. Potter.
It is often not known why.
But I think it is fairly certain
that
you will do great things.
The "he" we should not mention
accomplished great things?
Terrible ...
Yes! But magnificent.
Harry! Harry!
Happy birthday to you!
Are you okay, Harry?
He killed my parents, right?
The one who gave me the scar.
You know that, Hagrid. I know you do.
It is important that you understand this.
Not all wizards are good
Some of them turn evil.
A few years ago it was
a wizard who became as evil
as you can possibly get.
His name was V...
Can't you write it?
No I can't spell it.
Well, then... Voldemort
Voldemort?
Those were dark times Harry.
Voldemort gathered companions".
with him to the Dark Side.
He killed anyone who resisted.
Your parents fought against him.
But no one he had decided to kill
to kill, survived....
None.
Besides you...
Me? Did Voldemort try to kill... me?
That's no ordinary scar
you have there on your forehead Harry
Such a mark is only given by
a very strong and evil curse.
What happened to... "You know who"?
Some say he is dead.
Silly nonsense in my opinion.
No he is still somewhere
out there,
too weak to continue...
But one thing is for sure, there was something about
you that knocked him out that night
That's why you're famous,
that's why everyone knows about you.
You are the boy who survived.
What are you looking at?
Damn, is that the time?
I have to run Harry!
Dumbledore is waiting for
Uh... wait for me. Your train leaves in 10 minutes.
Here is your ticket. Do not lose it. It's important,
so don't lose it!
Perrong 9 3/4?
But Hagrid, there must be something wrong
It says platform 9 3/4
but there isn't one, is there?
I beg your pardon
Excuse me for a moment
On your left.
Excuse me but can you tell me where
I can find platform 9 3/4?
9 3/4 - Are you trying to make fun of me?
It's like this every year,
filled with Muggles. Let's go, come on!
Muggles?
Platform 9 3/4 this way!
Okay Percy, you first
Fred, now it's your turn
He is not Fred, I am Fred!
And you call yourself our mother?
I'm sorry, George.
Excuse me, George.
Excuse me!
Can you tell me... How to...
How to get to the platform?
Don't worry
It's Ron's first trip to Hogwarts too.
All you need to do is
walk straight into the wall between platforms 9 and 10
Better run, if you're nervous.
Good luck to you!
I beg your pardon? Do you mind
me sitting here? The others are full.
Not at all
I am Ron, Ron Weasley
I am Harry, Harry Potter.
It is true!
I mean, do you really have a...
A what?
A scar?
Awesome!
Anything from the kiosk cart?
No, thanks, I'm fine. I have my own with me.
We take it all
Bertie's multi-flavor beans?
They come in all flavors
There is chocolate and peppermint,
spinach, liver and cumin.
George thinks he got
a booger-flavored one once.
They're not real frogs, are they?
Just magic, besides it's the card you want
Each pack features a famous witch or wizard.
Watch out!
What bad luck! I myself only have
one who is good at jumping.
I got Dumbledore
I have 6 of him
-He's gone!
You didn't think
he would hang around here all day?
These are Scabbers by the way. Pathetic, huh?
A little bit
-Fred gave me a spell that turns him yellow.
You want to see?
Yes!
Has anyone seen a toad?
- A boy called Neville has lost one.
- No, he didn't.
Oh! Are you doing magic! Let's have a look.
"Daisy, sunshine, nice smooth butter.
This stupid,"
fat rat yellow now do
Are you sure it's a real spell?
It wasn't very good, was it?
I have only tried a few simple ones
myself, and they always work for me.
and they always work for me.
For example,
Oculus Reparus.
That's better, right?
Oh my goodness! You're Harry Potter!
I am Hermione Granger,
and you are... ?
I am Ron Weasley
Pleased to meet you...
You two should probably get changed.
I think we're almost there.
You have dirt on your nose, by the way.
Did you know that?
Right there.
All first year students this way!
Let's go! First-year students.
Hurry up!
Hi Harry
Hi Hagrid
Come on, this way to the boats.
Follow me!
Fantastic!
Welcome to Hogwarts!
In a moment you will
but first you will be divided into your dormitories
They are Gryffindor, Hufflepuff,
Ravenclaw and Slytherin.
While you are here, your
dormitories will be your family.
Your triumphs will earn you points.
Your achievements will earn you points,
and violations will deduct points.
At the end of the year, the school with the
most points will win the Pupil Accommodation Cup.
Trevor!
I beg your pardon
The sorting ceremony
will begin in a moment.
So it's true what I heard...
Harry Potter has arrived at Hogwarts.
Harry Potter?
This is Crabbe and Goyle,
and I am Malfoy
Draco Malfoy.
Do you think my name is funny?
Then I can ask for yours!
Red hair and a torn coat...
You must be a Weasley.
You soon discover, that some
families are better than others.
And you should not associate with the wrong kind.
I can help you with that.
I think I can tell which
variety is wrong myself, thanks!
We are ready now. Please follow me.
It is actually just a roof
with an enchanted night sky.
I've read about it in "Hogwarts History.
Can you wait here, please?
Before we begin, we want to
Professor
Dumbledore say a few words.
I have a few start-of-term notices
I wish to announce.
I have a few practical details.
Note this.
The Dark Forest is forbidden to all students.
And our caretaker,
Mr. Filch would like to remind you
-that the corridor to the right on the
third floor is closed off
for anyone who does not wish to suffer
a very painful death.
Thank you.
When I call out your names, you come forward.
I will put my hat on my head
and you will be assigned to your dormitories
Hermione Granger.
Okay, relax.
She has a screw loose.
Well, yes...
Okay. Gryffindor!
Draco Malfoy.
Slytherin!
It's only the slimy ones
who are in Slytherin.
Susan Bones.
Harry, what is it?
Nothing... I'm fine.
Let's see
I know... HUFFLEPUFF!!!
Ronald Weasley.
Another Weasley, I know exactly where you are going
Gryffindor!
Harry Potter.
Hmm, difficult, very difficult...
Lots of courage I see, no bad head
either.
There is talent.
and a strong desire to show
ability
But where should I put you?
Not Slytherin, not Slytherin.
Not Slytherin, then? Are you sure about that?
You could be great, you know.
And Slytherin would help you on your way
towards greatness, there is no doubt about that
But if you are so sure
It better be...
...Gryffindor!
Your attention please
Let the party begin!
I am half of each.
Father is a Muggle, mother is a witch.
So it was a shock for him
when he found out.
Tell me Percy, who is the teacher
who talks to Professor Quirrel?
It's Professor Snape, Headmaster of Slytherin
What does he teach?
Potions
But his favorite subject is black arts.
He's been after Quirrel's job for years.
Hello there! How are you?
Welcome to Gryffindor!
Look! The Bloody Baron!
Hello Sir Nicholas, did you have a nice summer?
Once again I have been rejected
to participate in the Headless Hunt!
I know you!
You are Almost Headless Nick
I prefer to be called Sir Nicholas!
Thank you, sir.
Almost headless?
How can you be almost headless?
This is how!
Gryffindor, follow me.
Ravenclaw, you are coming with me.
This route takes you directly to your rooms
Watch the steps, they like to move around.
Keep moving forward and follow me
Look at that! ...the paintings are moving!
- Look at that one
- I think she likes you.
- Check it out
- Who is the girl?
Welcome to Hogwarts
password
Caput Draconis.
Come on... hurry up a bit
Gather here
Welcome to the Gryffindor common room
The boys' toilets are on the top right.
Girls' on the left
Your luggage is already checked in
We got him!
Imagine McGonagall's face,
if we were late.
- That was pretty damn cool!
- Thanks for the assignment.
Maybe it would be better if I turned you into a
a clock? So you could arrive on time!
- Then one of you might be on time.
- We got lost.
We got lost - Maybe a map then?
I don't suppose you need one to find your seats?
There is no ridiculous waving
with wands during my lessons.
I do not expect that many of you will achieve full
understanding
of the beauty of these potions.
but on the other hand
I can teach you
to bewitch the mind
and mislead the senses....
I can teach you how to bottle reputation,
brews glory, even corks death.
Then maybe some of you have come to
Hogwarts with one of these
formidable knowledge that makes one so confident
that you are not paying attention!
Mr. Potter.
Our new ... celebrity
What do I get if I add crumbled
root of aphodilla to a decoction of wormwood?
Don't you know?
Let's try again
Where would you look if I asked you
to find me a bezoar?
I do not know...
And what is the difference between
a balaclava and a top hat?
I do not know...
Sin
So fame is not everything
Mr. Potter?
This water shall be turned
and become a cup of rum
What is Seamus trying to do with the water?
Turn it into rum.
He actually managed to
make some tea yesterday for...
Oh! The mail is here!
Can I borrow this?
Check it out! Neville has received a Remembrance Ball
I have read about them. They turn red,
when you've forgotten something.
The only problem is
I can't remember what I've forgotten?
Ron, there's been
a break-in at Gringotts.
"Listen, unknown sorcerers
or witches are believed to be behind...
Gringotts insists that nothing was stolen.
The vault in question, number 713
had already been emptied earlier that day.
It's the same vault that
Hagrid and I were in
- Good afternoon, class.
- Good afternoon, Madam Hooch.
Hello students
Hello Mrs. Hooch
Welcome to your first flying lesson.
Well, what are you waiting for?
Everyone stands to the left of their broom.
Hold your right hand over the broom and resign!
Get up!
Up.
Up, up, up. Up!
With feeling.
Shut up Harry.
Then I want you to sit on it.
Take a firm grip, so you don't slip off.
When I blow the whistle, I want you to
to stomp away from the ground.
Hold the broom firmly,
Float for a moment
and then lean forward
slightly, and then land again.
Ready? 3-2...
Mr. Longbottom.
- Mr. Longbottom!
- Down, down!
Neville!
Come down immediately!
Get out of the way!
Is he ok?
Oh dear, a broken wrist.
Everyone stays on the ground, while I follow
Mr. Longbottom to the hospital wing
I see a single broom in the air
the person sitting on it will
will get out of here
Did you see his face?
If he had this in his hand.
he would have landed on his fat ass.
Give me that, Malfoy.
No, I'll let Longbottom
get it himself.
What about up on the roof?
Something wrong, Potter?
Is it beyond your reach?
Harry! No, no, no, no! You heard what she said.
And you can't fly!
What an idiot!
Give it to me or I'll push you off the broom!
Oh, you do?
Okay, take it then!
Bravo Harry!
Well done!
Harry Potter!
Follow me
You wait here.
Professor Quirrel,
may I borrow Wood for a moment?
Yes, of course.
Potter, this is Oliver Wood.
Wood, I've found you a Seeker.
Harry Potter is the new Gryffindor seeker.
I knew he would do well
A seeker? But first-year students
have never been involved in the dormitory games
- You are the youngest player of this
century according to McGonagall.
Good luck Harry, Wood just told me.
Fred and George are the batsmen of the team.
Our job is to protect you.
Quidditch is a brutal game.
but no one has died in years.
Some have disappeared but
they'll turn up again!
Quidditch is a cool game Harry,
it'll be right up your street.
I've never played Quidditch.
What if I mess up?
You will not make a fool of yourself.
It's in your blood.
Harry, you never told me that
your father was also a Seeker?
I did not know that.
It's scary! She knows
more about you than you do yourself!
Who doesn't?
What is happening?
The stairs sometimes change direction.
Come this way.
Before the stairs move again!
Do you also feel,
that we should not be here?
We MUST not be here!
This floor is forbidden!
Let's get out of here.
It's Filch's cat!
Run!
We are hiding behind that door!
It's locked!
We are now out of business
Get out of the way!
Alohomora!
In!
Alohomora?
Standard spells, chapter 7.
Is anyone here?
Come and join us.
He has gone
Wonder why the door was locked?
What are they thinking? To keep such a
such a monster locked up in a school?
You don't use your eyes, do you?
Did you not see what it said?
I did not look at its feet! I was
more concerned with its heads
Or did you not notice that there were three
It was sitting on a trapdoor
It is guarding something.
Guarding something?
I'm going to bed now,
before you come up with something else
that can kill us
or even worse... Get us suspended.
She needs to get her values in order
her values in order.
Quidditch is simple to understand.
Each team has 7 players.
Three hunters, two hitters,
one guard and one seeker - "you"
There are three balls.
This one is called the clone.
To score points, hunters must try to
to get the clone through the 3 rings.
The guard - 'I', defends the rings.
Do you understand?
I think so.
What is it?
Hold it here.
Be prepared... it will come back.
Excellent Potter. You'd make a great Slagman.
What was that?
A Dunkaree. Mean little bastards.
But you are a seeker.
The only thing you need to think about... is this.
The Golden Heifer.
I like this one.
You do now,
But just wait...
It's very fast and hard to see.
What should I do with it?
Catch it before the other team's seeker.
If you catch it, the fight is over.
You catch that Potter
and we'll win the fight.
One of the many skills of a magician
is levitation
or...the ability to make things float.
Do you have your feathers?
Don't forget the wrist movement
that we have practiced.
Now all of them: Flip and flip.
And remember to pronounce the magic words
Wingardium Leviosa.
Stop, stop. You're going to poke someone's eye out.
By the way, you pronounce it wrong.
It is Leviosa, not Levi-o-sa.
Wingardium Leviosa.
Well done. Look, everybody!
Ms. Granger has done it!
Excellent, excellent
Well done.
I think we need a new spring Professor.
It is called Leviosa! Not Levi-o-sa!
She is a nightmare
No wonder she has no friends.
I think she heard you.
Where is Hermione?
She does not want to come out of the toilet
she has been sitting there
crying all afternoon.
Trolls in the basement!
Thought you should know.
SILENCE!
No panic please!
Now...
to take you back to your dormitories.
The teachers follow me to the basement.
Teachers will follow me
to the dungeons.
Keep up the pace Gryffindors, and pay attention.
How can a troll get in here?
Maybe it's some kind of Halloween joke.
What?
Hermione! She knows nothing!
The troll is no longer in the cellar.
He goes into the girls' toilet.
Hermione, get out of the way!
Help, help
Hey, nutcase
Help and advice
Do something
What is it?
Anything at all!
Hurry up!
Flip and flick.
Wingardium Leviosa.
Cool.
Is it dead?
I don't think so, it's just passed out.
Ööörk! Troll snakes
Oh dear!
Now you two can explain yourselves.
It's all my fault, Professor McGonagall
Miss Granger?
I was looking for the troll.
I thought I would make it.
But I was wrong.
If Harry and Ron hadn't come
I would probably be dead now.
It is very possible
It was a very stupid idea!
I would have expected you to be more sensible than that
5 points deducted for Gryffindor,
for your poor judgment.
And you two gentlemen
I hope you realize how lucky you were
Not many first-year students could handle
a full-grown mountain troll
and survive!
5 points...
For recklessness!
I'm keeping watch. It might wake up.
Have some breakfast.
Ron is right. You need your powers today.
I am not hungry.
Good luck today Potter.
Now that you've dealt with a troll
a Quidditch match shouldn't
be any difficulty for you.
Even if it is against Slytherin.
- This explains the blood
- Blood
I think Snape unleashed the troll
as a diversionary tactic
to get past the three-headed dog,
but he was bitten. That's why he's limping.
Why would anyone go near that dog?
When Hagrid and I were in Gringotts
he took something from the vault
Something secret that had to do with Hogwarts.
So you are saying that...
That's what the dog is guarding!
That's what Snape wants!
Isn't the mail a bit early?
But me, I never get mail?
Let's open it!
It's a broom!
It's not just a broomstick Harry!
It's a Nimbus 2000!
But who...?
Scared, Harry?
A little.
I was also scared before my first match.
What happened?
I don't really remember.
After 2 minutes I got a slap
and woke up in hospital a week later.
Hello and welcome to the first
first Quidditch match of the season.
Match of the day:
Slytherin meets Gryffindor!
Players take their positions
while Mrs. Hooch starts the game!
I expect a nice and fair match!
Of you all!
The batters are on the move followed by
The Golden Heifer
Don't forget that it gives you 150 points.
Whoever catches the Quack wins the match!
The dunk is going off... and the game is on!
Angelina Johnson scores!
10 points for Gryffindor!
Well done
Slytherin takes control of the Dunkirk,
and passes it to Marcus Flint.
Another 10 points for Gryffindor!
Give it to me!
Take that side!
What happens to Harry's broom?
It's Snape, he's bewitching the broom!
Bewitching the broom? What are we going to do?
Leave it to me.
Lacarnum Inflamarae.
Fire! You are on fire!
Let's go!
It looks like he is not feeling well.
He has the Quicken!
Harry Potter gets 150 points for catching the Quack!
Gryffindor wins!
Stupid! Why would Snape
Why would Snape hex Harry's broom?
Who knows, but why did he want to pass by
the dog on All Hallows' Eve?
Who told you about Fluffy?
Fluffy?
Does the creep have a name?
Yes, he does. He's mine.
I bought him from an Irishman.
That's how he became Dumbledore's guard dog.
I should not have said that.
But Snape tried to steal it?
Professor Snape is a teacher at Hogwarts.
Teacher or not. I recognize
a spell when I see one.
You maintain constant eye contact,
and Snape didn't blink!
Precisely
Now you three listen to me
You are interfering in matters that do not concern you.
That is dangerous.
What the dog guards only concerns
Professor Dumbledore and Nicolas Flamel.
Nicholas Flamel?
I should not have said that.
Nicholas Flamel.
Who is Nicolas Flamel?
I do not know.
Merry Christmas Merry Christmas
Ring Hogwart Watch
Knight to E-5.
Queen to E-5.
That is barbaric!
It's wizard's chess.
I see you've packed.
I see that you don't have it.
Change in plans. My parents are going
to Romania to visit my brother Charlie
He studies kites.
That's nice. Then you can help Harry.
He goes to the library to look for
information about Nicolas Flamel.
We have searched 100 times!
Not in the forbidden section.
Merry Christmas.
I think we have a bad influence on her.
Harry, wake up!
Merry Christmas, Harry.
Merry Christmas, Ron.
What are your clothes?
My mother made it.
You have also received something.
Have I received Christmas presents?
Yes!
There they are.
Your father left this in my care before he died.
It is now time for you to get it.
Use it well.
What is it?
Some kind of cloak.
Put it on.
My body is gone!
I know what it is!
It's an invisibility cloak!
Am I invisible?
It is very rare.
Who could have given it to you?
It just said "Use it well".
Famous fire-eaters.Themes about the
15th century
Flamel... Nicolas Flamel.
Where are you?
I know you are there.
You can't hide.
Who is it?... Come out!
You don't want me as your enemy, Quirrel.
What do you mean?
You know exactly what I mean.
We continue our little chat
when you have had time to decide
where your loyalties lie.
I found this ...
in the forbidden section.
It is still warm. That means
that one of the students is not in his bed!
Mother?
Father?
Ron, you have to see this!
Ron, come on, get up!
What's the point?
It's something you have to see!
Come on, let's go!
Look, my parents!
I only see us.
Look carefully, stand there.
Can you see them now?
That's me! I am the organizer.
And I'm holding the Quidditch Cup.
And for goodness sake...
I'm holding the Quiddich trophy
I look good!
Harry, do you think it shows the future?
How could it do that?
My parents are dead.
Here again Harry?
Now you, like many others
discovered the joy of the Erised mirror.
By now you know what it does.
Here is a hint.
The happiest man in the world
would look in the mirror and see only himself
just as he is in real life.
It shows us what we want.
Yes...and no
It shows us nothing less than the deepest and
most burning desire we carry in our hearts.
So, Harry, you never knew your family.
You see them gathered around you.
But remember this, Harry
Gives us neither knowledge nor
Truth.
Many have wasted ages in front of it
even gone mad.
Therefore, it will be moved tomorrow.
And I must ask you
not to look for it again.
One should not sink into dreams
so you forget to live
I made you look in the wrong place.
How could I be so stupid?
I borrowed it several weeks ago,
to have something easy to read.
Is this "easy"?
Here it is!
Nikolas Flamel is the only known
creator of the Philosopher's Stone!
What?
Do you never read?
"The Philosopher's Stone is a legendary substance
that can turn metal into gold
and produce the elixir of life,
the liquid that makes you immortal.
Immortal?
It means that you never die.
I know what it means!
The only existing stone
belongs to Nicolas Flamel
An alchemist who last year
celebrated his 665th birthday.
That's what Fluffy is guarding.
That is what is under the trapdoor.
The Philosopher's Stone!
Unfortunately, I am not able to
receive guests today.
We know the 'Philosopher's Stone'!
We think Snape is trying to steal it.
Do you still suspect him?
We know it's him,
we just don't know why?
Snape is one of the teachers protecting the stone.
He has no intention of stealing it.
What?
I'm a bit busy now so
Wait a minute... One of the teachers?
Of course it is!
Other teachers protect it too
with incantations!
Quite rightly
A waste of time in my opinion.
No one can get past Fluffy.
No one knows how except
me and Dumbledore.
I should not have told you
Hagrid, what is that?
It's... uhh
I know what it is!
But Hagrid, how did you get one?
I won it from a stranger down at the inn!
He seemed happy to get rid of it
Is it
What about dragons?
It's not just a kite.
It's a Norwegian Ridge Kite.
My brother Charlie studies them in Romania.
Isn't it cute?
Look, look, look! He knows who his mom is.
Hello, Norbert.
Norbert?
He must have a name.
Right, Norbert?
He has to be trained a bit, of course.
Who is it?
Malfoy.
Oh dear!
Hagrid has always wanted a kite.
He told me that the first time we met.
That's insane.
And now Malfoy knows it.
I don't understand... is it not good?
Not good at all.
Good evening.
Nothing, and I mean nothing
gives a student permission to
stay up at night.
So as a penalty, you will be deducted 50 points.
50?!
Where!
And to be sure it is not repeated
all 4 of you will receive detention.
Excuse me, professor,
perhaps I heard you wrong.
Excuse me professor, maybe I heard wrong
No, you heard right, Malfoy.
Even if your intentions were good,
you were up at the time yourself.
You may join your peers
company during detention.
It's a shame that the old methods of punishment have been abolished.
Once upon a time, people were hung from chains.
I miss their screaming!
You will receive your detention together with Hagrid.
He has a small mission in the Dark Forest.
Sorry about all this, Hagrid.
You're not still thinking about
about that damn dragon?
Norbert is gone.
Dumbledore sent him to a
colony in Romania.
That way he can be with his own kind.
What if he doesn't like Romania?
What if the other dragons are naughty?
He's just a kid, right?
Pull yourself together, man!
You're going into the forest.
Better get your brain working.
The forest? I thought it was a joke!
Students are not allowed to go there! And there are
werewolves!
There's more than werewolves there, son.
Be sure of it.
Natti, natti
So let's go
Hagrid, what is that?
What we have come here for.
Can you see this?
It is unicorn blood. I found a dead
unicorn a few weeks ago.
This one has been seriously wounded.
So it's our job to find the poor animal.
Ron, Hermione. You're coming with me.
Harry, you go with Malfoy.
But I get Faithful!
Yes, of course. I just want you to know
he's a real coward.
Wait till my father hears about this!
This is a job for servants!
One might think you are afraid.
I'm not afraid, Potter.
Did you hear that?
Come, Faithful
Afraid!
What is it Faithful?
Harry Potter, you must go!
You are known by many creatures here.
The forest is not safe at that time,
especially not for you.
But what was it you saved me from?
A terrible creature!
It is terrible to kill a unicorn.
Drinking its blood keeps you alive,
even if you are a hair's breadth from death.
But you pay a terrible price.
When you kill something so innocent
the moment it touches your lips
your lips, you will have half a life.
A life under a curse.
Who would choose such a life?
Who do you think?
Are you saying that what killed the unicorn
and drank its blood
It was Voldemort!
Do you know what is hidden here in the forest right now
"The Philosopher's Stone"
Harry!
Good evening, Florence.
I see you've met young Mr. Potter.
Are you okay, Harry?
Harry Potter,
I'll leave you here.
You are safe now. Good luck to you.
You mean "You know who"
is out there in the forest?
But he is weak. He lives on
unicorns.
We were wrong.
Snape doesn't want the Stone for himself,
it's for Voldemort.
The Elixir of Life makes Voldemort strong again.
So that he can return.
But if he comes back
You don't think he will
try to kill you, do you?
I think he would have killed me
tonight if he had the chance.
And I, who have only been worried
about my potions exam.
Wait a minute, we're forgetting one thing.
Which wizard is it that
Voldemort has always feared?
Dumbledore. As long as Dumbledore
is around, Harry, you're safe.
As long as Dumbledore is here,
you're safe. he won't get to you.
I thought the Hogwarts exam would be scary,
but it was actually pretty fun.
Speak for yourself.
Are you okay, Harry?
My scar... it burns.
It has happened before!
Not like this.
Maybe you should see a doctor?
I think it's a warning.
It means that danger is coming.
Of course it is!
What is it?
Isn't it strange, that what Hagrid
wants most of all is a dragon
and then a stranger shows up who just happens to have one?
I mean, how many people walk around
around with dragon eggs in their pocket.
Why didn't I think of that before.
Who gave you the egg?
What did he look like?
I don't know, he was wearing a hood.
What were you talking about?
He wondered what kind of animals I had.
I said that after Fluffy,
a dragon should be no problem.
Did he seem interested in Fluffy?
Of course he was!
How often do you see a three-headed dog?
I told him that the trick to dealing with
a beast like that is to know how to calm them down.
Take Fluffy, for example.
Play him some music and he will fall asleep.
I shouldn't have told you that...
Where are you going?
We need to see Professor Dumbledore, now!
But Professor Dumbledore is not here, I'm afraid.
He received an urgent summons from the
Magic Association and flew directly to London.
Has he gone away? But it is important!
It's about the Philosopher's Stone!
How do you know...?
Someone is trying to steal it!
I do not know how you know about the stone.
But I can assure you that it is safe.
Now go back to your rooms.
Quietly and calmly.
It was Snape that Hagrid met!
And now he knows how to get past Fluffy.
And now that Dumbledore has left...
...hello...
What would three young Gryffindors...
What are three Gryffindors like you doing
doing inside on a day like this?
Uh... We, uh...
You should be careful
People might think that you
is doing something.
What do we do now?
We go down through the trapdoor. Tonight.
Trevor.
Trevor, shut up! You can't be here!
Neither can you.
You're going to sneak out again, aren't you?
Neville listens
No you can't!
You're just making trouble for Gryffindor again.
I'll kick your asses!
Neville, I'm sorry about this.
Petrificus Totalus.
You're a little scary sometimes, you know that?
Good... but scary.
Let's go
I apologize for that.
But it's for your own good.
Ouch! You stepped on my foot!
Sorry about that.
Alohomora.
Wait a minute, he
Snoring.
Snape has already been here.
He has cast a spell on the harp.
It has a horrible smell!
We have to move his paw.
What? Uh...
Let's go!
Okay... hugs!
I will go first. Do not follow until I give the signal.
If something goes wrong,
make sure you get out!
Hasn't it become a bit quiet?
harp
It no longer plays.
HOPE!
Luckily, there were plants here.
Don't move! It's the Devil's Snare.
You have to relax...
Otherwise it will just kill us faster.
Killing us faster?
Now I can really relax!
Hermione!
What do we do now?
Just relax!
Hermione, where are you?
Do as I say! Trust me!
Are you alright?
-Yes, I'm fine.
He is not relaxing.
Obviously not.
I have to do something!
What?!
I read something about it in biology!
"Devil's Snare, Devil's Snare...
to get free...
you light a candle, of course!
Of course you do! It hates sunlight!
Lumus Solem.
Ron are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Luckily, we did not panic.
Good thing Hermione listened to the lessons.
What is it?
I don't know... it sounds like wings.
That's strange. I have never seen such birds.
They are not birds.
They are keys.
And one of them probably fits the door there
What is the point of this?
I don't know what it is.
Strange...
Alohomora!
It was worth a try.
What are we doing?
There must be 1000 keys up there!
It's probably an old-fashioned rusty one.
There it is! The one with the broken wing!
Is something wrong Harry?
It is too easy.
Come on, Harry!
If Snape can catch one, so can you!
You the youngest searcher of this century!
This makes it slightly more difficult.
Catch the key!
Hurry up!
I do not like this
Not in the least
Where are we? In a cemetery.
This is not a cemetery.
It is a chessboard!
There's the door!
What do we do now?
Of course it is!
Let's play our way across the room!
Harry, you take the runner's place.
Hermione, you will be the tower
closest to the lady.
And me, I'm a runner!
What happens next?
White always starts first.
and then...
we play.
Ron, do you think it will be the same
...like in real wizard chess?
You there! D-5!
Yes, Hermione...
I think it will be
exactly like wizard chess!
Runners, to E-4!
Farmer, to C-3!
Wait a minute
Listen, Harry.
When I make my move
the Queen will take me.
Then you are free to put the king in check!
No! Ron! Ron, no!
What's happening?!
He is going to sacrifice himself!
You can't! There must be another way!
Don't you want to stop Snape from getting the Stone?
Harry, it is you who must continue!
Not me, not Hermione, but you!
Runner to H-3!
Chess.
Ron!
No! Don't move!
Don't forget that we are still playing.
Checkmate.
Take care of Ron. Then go to the owls
and send word to Dumbledore.
Ron's right.
I have to keep going.
Don't worry Harry
You are a great wizard.
Not as good as you.
Me? Books and wisdom
There are more important things
Friendship and courage.
Be careful now Harry
You?
No, it is impossible! Snape he
He seems to be that type, doesn't he?
Because who would suspect
S-stackars, s-stuttering
Professor Quirrel?
But when we played the Quidditch match,
Snape tried to kill me!
No, my boy. I tried to kill you!
If Snape's cape hadn't caught on fire,
and I lost my eye contact
I would have succeeded!
Even if Snape was muttering counterspells!
Snape tried to SAVE me?
I knew you were a danger to me.
Especially after All Hallows' Eve.
So it was you who let the troll in?
Excellent Potter. Yes.
However, Snape was not fooled.
When everyone went to the basement
he was on the 3rd floor to stop me.
He didn't trust me anymore after that.
He rarely left me alone.
But he doesn't understand.
I am never alone. Never.
Well, what does this mirror do?
I see what I want
I see myself holding the stone.
But how do I get it?
"Use the boy"
Come here Potter! NOW!
Tell me, what do you see?
What is it? What do you see?!
I shake hands with Dumbledore.
I have won the dormitory cup.
"He is lying"
TELL THE TRUTH! WHAT DO YOU SEE?!
"Let me talk to him"
Master, you are not strong enough!
"I have enough strength... for this"
Harry Potter...
...we meet again.
We meet again.
Yes, it is. Do you see what has become of me?
Do you see what I have to do to survive?
Sharing my body with someone else...
Like a parasite.
Unicorn blood can strengthen me.
But not enough to create a body of their own.
But there is something that can.
Something that is just enough. It's in your pocket.
Stop him!
Don't be a fool!
Why face certain death
when you can unite with me
and continue living?
Never!!!
Courage. Your parents had it too.
Tell me, Harry...
Would you like to see your mother and father again?
Together...
we can get them back.
All I ask for is little things in return.
That's right Harry
There is no good and evil.
There is only power.
And those who are too weak to seek it out
Together we can do incredible things
only you give me the stone!
You liar!
Kill him!
What kind of magic was that?
Idiot! Take the Stone!
Good afternoon, Harry
Gifts from your admirers.
Admirers?
What happened between you and
Professor Quirrel is an absolute secret.
So... of course... the whole school knows about it.
I see Ron has saved you the trouble
with
to open your chocolate frogs.
Is he okay?
and what about Hermione?
They are both fine.
What happened to the stone?
Calm down my boy
The stone has been destroyed.
My friend Nicolas and I had a little chat
and agreed that it was for the best.
But won't Flamel die then?
He has enough elixir of life in stock
to get his affairs in order.
And then, well... he will die.
How could I get the stone?
First it was in the mirror
And then in my pocket.
You see, only a person...
Only the one who wanted to find the stone.
But not using it
could get it.
It is one of my better ideas.
Between you and me... that's saying something.
Now that the stone is gone,
Voldemort will never come back?
I am afraid that...
there are possibilities that he can return.
in which he can return.
Harry, do you know why...
Do you know why Professor Quirrel
couldn't stand you touching him?
It was because of your mother.
She sacrificed her life for you.
That kind of action leaves a mark.
No, this mark cannot be seen.
It's under your skin.
What is it, then?
Love Harry. Love Harry
Oh, Bertie's multi-flavor beans!
I had the misfortune in my youth,
to get a vomit-flavored one.
Since then I have not really liked them.
Well, I should be able to feel safe.
with a good caramel taste.
Unfortunately...
Earwax!
Okay, Ron?
Okay, uh... How about you?
Hermione?
Never had it better.
Another year has passed!
My understanding is that
students should be rewarded.
The position is as follows:
In fourth place...
Gryffindor with 312 points.
In third place...
Hufflepuff with 352 points.
In second place...
Ravenclaw with 426 points.
And in first place
with 472 points, Slytherin.
Nice one, mate.
Yes, yes! Bravo Slytherin!
Anyway...New events must be taken into
be taken into account
I have some "last minute" points to share.
Ms. Hermione Granger...
For her use of cold logic...
when others were in great danger
50 points.
Well done.
Second... to Ronald Weasley...
For the best chess game...
ever played at Hogwarts...
50 points.
Thirdly.
...to Mr. Harry Potter...
For his outstanding courage and his great presence of mind
I award on behalf of Gryffindor 60 points.
We are equal with Slytherin
And finally...It takes great courage to
to resist your enemies.
but even more so to resist
against their friends.
I give it 10 points...
to Neville Longbottom.
If my calculations are correct
we need a small change in the decorations.
Gryffindor wins the dormitory trophy!
Come on, come on! Come on, hurry up! You'll be late.
The train is leaving soon! Come on, let's go.
Come on, hurry up.
Just a moment.
You weren't going to leave without saying goodbye, were you?
This one is for you.
Thank you Hagrid.
There you go, off you go. And by the way Harry...
Would your cousin Dudley.
That dork... give you trouble
you can always.....
threaten him with a pair of ears
to match his pigtail.
We're not allowed to practice magic outside Hogwarts.
You know that.
I know that...but your cousin doesn't,
does he?
Doesn't it feel strange to go home?
I am not going home.
Not really.
www.Undertexter.se