l should've known that you would
be here Professor McGonagall.
Are the rumors true Albus?
l'm afraid so professor.
The good and the bad.
-And the boy?
-Hagrid is bringing him.
Do you think it wise to trust Hagrid
with something as important as this?
Ah Professor l would trust Hagrid
with my life.
Professor Dumbledore sir.
Professor McGonagall.
-No problems l trust Hagrid?
-No sir.
Little tyke fell asleep just
as we were flying over Bristol.
Try not to wake him.
There you go.
Albus.Do you really think it's safe
leaving him with these people?
l've watched them all day.
They're the worst sort of Muggles.Imaginable.
-They really are--
-The only family he has.
This boy will be famous. There won't be a child
in our world who doesn't know his name.
Exactly.
He's far better off growing up
away from all of that.
Until he's ready.
There there Hagrid.
lt's not really goodbye after all.
Good luck...
...Harry Potter.
Up. Get up!
Now!
Wake up cousin!
We're going to the zoo!
-Here he comes the birthday boy.
-Happy birthday son.
Why don't you just cook the breakfast
and try not to burn anything.
-Yes Aunt Petunia.
-l want everything to be perfect...
...for my Dudley's special day!
-Hurry up! Bring my coffee boy.
-Yes Uncle Vernon.
Aren't they wonderful darling?
-How many are there?
-36. Counted them myself.
36?! But last year...last year l had 37!
-But some of them are quite a bit bigger than last year's.
-l don't care how big they are!
Oh now now now. This is what we're going to do...
... is that when we go out we're going to buy you two
new presents. How's that pumpkin?
lt should be a lovely day at the zoo.
l'm really looking forward to it.
l'm warning you now boy.
Any funny business any at all...
...and you won't have
any meals for a week.
Get in.
Make it move.
Move!
-Move!
-He's asleep!
He's boring.
Sorry about him.
He doesn't understand
what it's like lying there day after day...
...watching people press
their ugly faces in on you.
Can you hear me?
lt's just l've never talked
to a snake before.
Do you...?
I meanDo you talk to people often?
You're from Burma aren't you?
Was it nice there?
Do you miss your family?
l see. That's me as well.
l never knew my parents either.
Mummy Dad come here! you won't believe
what this snake is doing!
Thanks.
Anytime.
Snake!
Mum! Mummy! Help me!
My darling boy!
How did you get in there?
Who did this? How did you get
in there? ls there a snake?
lt's all right sweetheart.
We'll get you out of these cold clothes.
-What happened?
-l swear l don't know!
One minute the glass was there and
then it was gone it was like magic.
There's no such thing as magic.
And smile!
Vernon just look at him!
l can't believe it!
ln just a week he'll be off to Smeltings.
Caveat Smeltonia.
Proudest moment of my life.
Will l have to wear that too?
What? You? Go to Smeltings?
Don't be so stupid!
You're going to go to the state school.Where you belong.
This is what you'll going to be wearing
when l finish dyeing it.
That's Dudley's old uniform.
lt'll fit me like bits of old elephant skin.
It'll fit you well enough.
Go get the post. Go!
Marge is ill. Ate a funny whelk.
-Dad look! Harry's got a letter!
-Hey give it back! lt's mine!
Yours? Who'd be writing to you?
No more mail through this letterbox.
Have a lovely day at the office dear.
Shoo! Go on.
Fine day Sunday.
ln my opinion best day of the week.
Why is that Dudley?
-Because there's no post on Sundays?
-Right you are Harry!
No post on Sunday.
No blasted letters today! No sir.
Not one single bloody letter. Not one!
No sir not one blasted miserable--
Make it stop please!
Stop it!
Mummy what's happening?
Give me that! Give me that letter!
Get off!
They're my letters! Let go of me!
That's it! We're going away!
Far away where they can't find us!
Daddy's gone mad hasn't he?
Make a wish Harry.
Who's there?
Sorry about that.
l demand that you leave at once Sir!
You are breaking and entering!
Dry up Dursley you great prune.
Mind l haven't seen you
since you was a baby Harry.
But you're a bit more along than l would have expected.
Particularly 'round the middle.
l'm not Harry.
-l am.
-Well of course you are.
Got something for you.
Afraid l might have sat on it at somepoint but l imagine
it'll taste fine just the same.
Baked it myself words and all.
Thank you.
lt's not every day that your young man
turns 11  now is it?
Excuse me who are you?
Rubeus Hagrid Keeper of Keys
and Grounds at Hogwarts.
-Of course you know all about Hogwarts.
-Sorry no.
No? Blimey Harry Didn't you ever wonder where
your mum and dad learned it all?
Learnt what?
You're a wizard Harry.
-l'm a what?
-A wizard.
And a thumping good one l'd wager
once you're trained up little.
No you've made a mistake.
l mean...
...l can't be a wizard.
l mean l'm just Harry. Just Harry.
Well Just Harry did you ever
make anything happen?
Anything you couldn't explain
when you were angry or scared?
''Dear Mr. Potter
We are pleased to inform you...
...that you have been accepted at
Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry.''
He will not be going there! We swore when we took him in
we'd put a stop to all this rubbish.
You knew? You knew all along
and you never told me?
Of course we knew.
How could you not be?
My perfect sister being who she was.
My mother and father were so proud
the day she got her letter.
''We have a witch in the family.
lsn't it wonderful?''
l was the only one to see her
for what she was.
A freak!
Then she met that Potter
and then she had you...
...and l knew you would be the same.
Just as strange just as abnormal.
And then if you please she went and got herself blown up!
And we got landed with you.
Blown up? You told me
my parents died in a car crash.
A car crash? A car crash killed
Lily and James Potter?
-We had to say something.
-lt's an outrage! It's a scandal!
He'll not be going.
Oh and I suppose a great Muggle like yourself's
going to stop him are you?
Muggle?
Non-magic folk. This boy's had
his name down ever since he were born.
He's going to the finest school
of witchcraft and wizardry in the world and...
..He'll be under the finest headmaster that
Hogwarts has ever seen Albus Dumbledore.
l will not pay to have some crackpot
old fool teach him magic tricks.
Never insult Albus Dumbledore...
...in front of me.
Oh um l'd appreciate it if you didn't tell
anyone at Hogwarts about that.
-Strickly speaking l'm not allowed to do magic.
-Okay.
Ooh We're a bit behind schedule.
Best be off.
Unless you'd rather stay of course.
''First year's students will require
three sets of plain work robes...
...one wand.''
Essential bit of equipment Harry.
''One pair of dragon hide gloves.''
Hagrid Do they mean from a real dragon?
They don't mean a penguin do they?
-Crikey. l'd love a dragon.
-You'd like a dragon?
Vastly misunderstood beasts Harry.
Vastly misunderstood.
''All students must be equipped with...
...one standard size 2
pewter cauldron...
...and may bring if they desire
either an owl a cat or a toad.''
Can we find all this in London?
lf you know where to go.
Ah Hagrid! The usual l presume?
No thanks Tom.
l'm on official Hogwarts business.
Just helping young Harry here
buy his school supplies.
Bless my soul.
lt's Harry Potter!
Welcome back Mr. Potter.
Welcome back.
Doris Crockford Mr Potter.
l can't believe l'm meeting you at last.
Harry Potter. Can't tell you
how pleased l am to meet you.
Hello professor. l didn't see you there.
Harry This is Professor Quirrell.He will be your
Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher at Hogwarts.
Oh nice to meet you.
Fearfully fascinating subject.
Not that you need it eh Potter?
Yes well must be going now.
Lots to buy.
Goodbye.
-See Harry? You're famous.
-But why am l famous Hagrid?
All those people back there
how is it they know who l am?
l'm not sure l'm exactly the right person
to tell you that Harry.
Welcome Harry to Diagon Alley.
Here's where you'll get your quills and your ink.
And over there all your bits and bobs
for doing your wizardry.
lt's a world-class racing broom.
Look at it! The new Nimbus 2000!
lt's the fastest model yet.
But Hagrid how am l to pay for all this?
l haven't any money.
Well there's your money Harry.
Gringotts the wizard bank.
Ain't no safer place not one.
Except perhaps Hogwarts.
Hagrid what exactly
are these things?
They're goblins Harry. Clever as they come goblins
but not the most friendly of beasts.
Best stay close.
Mr. Harry Potter wishes
to make a withdrawal.
And does Mr. Harry Potter
have his key?
Oh Wait a minute.
Got it here somewhere.
Ha! Here's the little devil.
Oh and there's something else as well.
Professor Dumbledore gave me this.
lt's about You-Know-What
in vault you-know-which.
Very well.
Vault 687.
Lamp please.
Key please.
Didn't think your mum and dad
will leave you with nothing now did ya?
-Vault 713.
-What's in there Hagrid?
Can't tell you Harry.
Hogwarts business. Very secret.
Stand back.
Best not to mention this to anyone Harry.
l still need...a wand.
A wand? Well you'll want Ollivanders.
There ain't no place better.
Why don't you run along there and wait.
l just got one more thing I gotta do. Won't be long.
Hello?
l wondered when
l'd be seeing you Mr. Potter.
lt seems only yesterday...
...that your mother and father were
in here buying their first wands.
Here we are.
Give it a wave.
Apparently not.
Perhaps...
...this.
No no definitely not.
No matter.
l wonder....
Curious.
Very curious.
Sorry but what's curious?
l remember every wand
l've ever sold Mr. Potter.
lt so happens that the phoenix...
...whose tail feather resides
in your wand gave another feather.
Just one other.
lt is curious that you should
be destined for this wand...
...when its brother
gave you that scar.
And who owned that wand?
We do not speak his name.
The wand chooses
the wizard Mr. Potter.
lt's not always clear why.
But l think it is clear...
...that we can expect
great things from you.
After all He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named...
...did great things.
Terrible...
...yes but great.
Harry! Harry!
Happy birthday.
You all right Harry?
You seem very quiet.
He killed my parents didn't he?
The one who gave me this.
You know Hagrid. l know you do.
First and understand this Harry
because it's very important:
Not all wizards are good.
Some of them go bad.
A few years ago...
...there was a one wizard who went as bad
as he can go. His name was V--
-His name was V--
-Maybe if you wrote it down?
No l can't spell it.
-All right Voldemort.
-Voldemort?
lt was dark times Harry. Dark times.
Voldemort started
to gather some followers.
Brought them over to the Dark Side.
Anyone that stood up to him
ended up dead.
Your parents fought against him.
But nobody lived once
he decided to kill them.
Nobody not one.
Except you.
Me? Voldemort tried to kill me?
Yes. That ain't no ordinary cut
on your forehead Harry.
A mark like that only comes from being
touched by a curse and an evil curse at that.
What happened to V--?
To You-Know-Who?
Well some say he died.
Codswallop in my opinion.
Nope l reckon he's out there still...
...too tired to carry on.
But one thing's absolutely certain. Something
about you stumped him that night.
That's why you're famous.
That's why everybody knows your name.
You're the boy who lived.
What are you looking at?
Blimey is that the time?
Sorry Harry l'm gonna have to leave you.
Dumbledore will be wanting his--
Well he'll be wanting to see me.
Now uh your train leaves in 10 minutes.
Here's your ticket. Stick to it Harry
that's very important. Stick to your ticket.
''Platform 9¾''?
But Hagrid there must be a mistake.
This says platform 9¾.
There's no such thing is there?
Sorry.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Right on your left Madam.
Excuse me Sir Can you tell me where
l might find platform 9¾?
9¾? Think you're being funny do ya?
lt's the same every year
packed with Muggles Of course. Come on!
-Muggles?
-Platform 9¾ this way.
All right Percy you first.
Fred you next.
-He's not Fred l am.
-Honestly woman You call yourself our mother?
Oh l'm sorry George.
l'm only joking. l am Fred.
Excuse me.
Could you tell me how to...?
How to get onto the platform?
Not to worry dear.
lt's Ron's first time
to Hogwarts as well.
All you've got do is walk straight at the wall
between platforms 9 and 10.
-Best do it at a bit of a run if you're nervous.
-Good luck.
Excuse me. Do you mind?
Everywhere else is full.
Not at all.
l'm Ron by the way.
Ron Weasley.
l'm Harry. Harry Potter.
So it's true!
l mean do you really have the...?
-The what?
-The scar?
Wicked!
-Anything off the trolley dears?
-No thanks. l'm all set.
We'll take the lot.
-Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans?
-They mean every flavor.
There's chocolate
and peppermint and there's also...
...spinach liver and tripe.
George sweared he got
a bogey-flavoured one once!
-These aren't real frogs are they?
-lt's just a spell. Besides It's the cards you want.
Each pack's got a famous witch
or wizard. l've got about 500 meself.
Watch it!
Oh that's rotten luck. They've only
got one good jump in them to begin with.
-l've got Dumbledore!
-l got about six of him.
Hey he's gone!
Well you can't expect him to
hang around all day can you?
This is Scabbers by the way.
Pathetic isn't he?
Just a little bit.
Fred gave me a spell as
to turn him yellow. Want to see?
Yeah.
Has anyone seen a toad?
-A boy named Neville's lost one.
-No.
Oh are you doing magic?
Let's see then.
Sunshine daisies butter mellow
Turn this stupid fat rat yellow
Are you sure that's a real spell?
Well it's not very good is it?
Of course l've only tried
a few simple ones myself...
...but they've all worked for me.
For example:
Oculus Reparo.
That's better isn't it?
Holy cricket you're Harry Potter!
l'm Hermione Granger.
And you are...?
-l'm Ron Weasley.
-Pleasure.
You two better change into robes.
l expect we'll be arriving soon.
You've got dirt on your nose by the way.
Did you know?
Just there.
Right then.
First years this way please!
Come on now first years don't be shy.
Come on now hurry up.
-Hello Harry.
-Hey Hagrid.
Right then. This way to the boats.
Come on now follow me.
Wicked.
Welcome to Hogwarts.
Now in a few moments you'll pass through
these doors and join your classmates.
But before you can take your seats
you must be sorted into your houses.
They are Gryffindor Hufflepuff...
...Ravenclaw and Slytherin.
Now while you're here your house
will be like your family.
Your triumphs will earn you points.
Any rule-breaking
and you will lose points.
At the end of the year the house
with the most points is awarded the house cup.
Trevor!
Sorry.
The Sorting Ceremony
will begin momentarily.
lt's true then
what they're saying on the train.
Harry Potter has come to Hogwarts.
Harry Potter?
This is Crabbe and Goyle.
And l'm Malfoy.
Draco Malfoy.
Think my name's funny do you?
l've no need to ask yours.
Red hair and a hand-me-down robe?
You must be a Weasley.
We'll soon find out that some wizarding families
are better than others Potter.
You don't want to go making friends
with the wrong sort.
l can help you there.
l think l can tell the wrong sort
for myself thanks.
We're ready for you now.
Follow me.
It's not real the ceiling. lt's just bewitched
to look like the night sky.
l read about it
in Hogwarts: A History.
All right will you wait along here please?
Now before we begin...
...Professor Dumbledore would like
to say a few words.
l have a few start-of-term notices
l wish to announce.
The first years please note...
...that the Dark Forest is
strictly forbidden to all students.
Also our caretaker Mr. Filch
has asked me to remind you...
...that the third-floor corridor on the right hand side
is out of bounds...
...to everyone who does not wish
to die a most painful death.
Thank you.
When l call your name
you will come forth.
l shall place the Sorting Hat
on your head...
...and you will be sorted
into your houses.
Hermione Granger.
Oh no. Okay relax.
Mental that one l'm telling you.
Ah right then...hmm...right.
Okay. Gryffindor!
Draco Malfoy.
Slytherin!
There isn't a witch or wizard who went bad
who wasn't in Slytherin.
Susan Bones.
Harry what is it?
Nothing. Nothing l'm fine.
Let's see....
l know! Hufflepuff!
Ronald Weasley.
Another Weasley!
l know just what to do with you.
Gryffindor!
Harry Potter.
Hmm...difficult very difficult.
Plenty of courage l see.
Not a bad mind either.
There's talent oh yes.
And a thirst to prove yourself.
But where to put you?
Not Slytherin not Slytherin!
Not Slytherin eh? Are you sure?
You could be great you know.
lt's all here in your head.
And Slytherin will help you on the way
to greatnesses no doubt about that.
No? Well if you're sure.
Better be...
...Gryffindor!
Your attention please.
Let the feast begin.
l'm half and half.
Me dad's a Muggle. Mum's a witch.
Bit of a nasty shock for him
when he found out.
Say Percy who's that teacher
talking to Professor Quirrell?
Oh thats Professor Snape
head of Slytherin house.
-What's he teach?
-Potions.
But everyone knows its the Dark Arts he fancies.
He's been after Quirrell's job for years.
Hello! How are you?
Welcome to Gryffindor.
Look lt's the Bloody Baron!
Hello Sir Nicholas.
Have a nice summer?
Dismal. Once again my request to join
the Headless Hunt has been denied.
l know you.
You're Nearly Headless Nick.
l prefer Sir Nicholas
if you don't mind.
''Nearly'' headless?
How can you be nearly headless?
Like this.
Gryffindors follow me please.
Keep up. Thank you.
Ravenclaw follow me. This way.
This is the most direct path
to the dormitories.
Oh and keep an eye on the staircases.
They like to change.
Keep up please and follow me.
Quickly now come on. Come on.
That picture's moving.
-Look at that one.
-l think she fancies you.
-Oh look! Look!
-Who's that girl?
Welcome to Hogwarts.
Password?
Caput Draconis.
Follow me everyone. Keep up.
Quickly come on.
Gather around here.
Welcome to the Gryffindor common room.
Boys' dormitory is upstairs and down to your left.
Girls the same on your right.
You'll find that your belongings have
already been brought up.
Made it!
Can you imagine the look on old
McGonagall's face if we were late?
-That was bloody brilliant!
-Thank you for that assessment Mr Weasley.
Perhaps lt'd be more useful if l were to transfigured
Mr. Potter and yourself into a pocket-watch.
-That way one of you might be on time.
-We got lost.
Then perhaps a map? l trust you
don't need one to find your seats.
There will be no foolish wand-waving
or silly incantations in this class.
As such l don't expect
many of you to appreciate...
...the subtle science and exact art
that is potion-making.
However for those select few...
...who possess the predisposition...
...l can teach you
how to bewitch the mind...
...and ensnare the senses.
l can tell you how to bottle fame...
...brew glory and even
put a stopper in death.
Then again maybe some of you have
come to Hogwarts in ...
...possession of abilities so formidable that
you feel confident enough...
...to not pay attention.
Mr. Potter.
Our new celebrity.
Tell me what would l get if l added powdered root
of asphodel to an infusion of wormwood?
You don't know? Well let's try again.
Where Mr Potter would you look
if l asked you to find me a bezoar?
l don't know Sir.
And what is the difference
between monkshood and wolfsbane?
l don't know Sir.
Pity.
Clearly fame isn't everything...
...is it Mr. Potter?
Clearly Hermione knows.
Seems a pity not to ask her.
Silence.
Put your hand down
you silly girl!
For your information Potter...
...asphodel and wormwood make a sleeping potion so powerful
it is known as the Draught of the Living Dead.
A bezoar is a stone taken from the stomach of a goat
and it will save you from most poisons
As for monkshood and wolfsbane they are the same
plant which also goes by the name of aconite.
Well...
...why aren't you all
copying this down?
And Gryffindors...
...note that five points will
be taken from your house...
...for your classmate's cheek.
Eye of rabbit harp string hum
Turn this water into rum
Eye of rabbit....
What's Seamus trying to do
to that glass of water?
Turn it into rum. Actually managed
a weak tea yesterday before--
Mail's here.
Can l borrow this? Thanks.
Hey look! Neville's got a Remembrall.
l've read about those. When the smoke turns
red it means you've forgotten something.
The only problem is l can't remember
what l've forgotten.
Hey Ron! Somebody broke into Gringotts.
Listen.
''Believed to be the work
of Dark wizards or witches unknown...
...Gringotts goblins while acknowledging
the breach insist nothing was taken.
The vault in question number 713
had in fact been emptied earlier that very same day.''
That's odd. That's the vault
Hagrid and l went to.
-Good afternoon class.
-Good afternoon Madam Hooch.
Good afternoon Amanda.
Good afternoon.
Welcome to your first flying lesson.
Well what are you waiting for?
Everyone step up to the left side of their broomstick.
Come on now hurry up. Stick your right hand
over the broom and say ''Up.''
Up!
Up.
Up. Up!
With feeling.
Shut up Harry.
Now once you've got hold of
your broom l want you to mount it.
And grip it tight you don't wanna be
sliding off the end.
When l blow my whistle l want each of you
to kick off from the ground hard.
Keep your broom steady
hover for a moment...
...then lean forward slightly
and touch back down.
On my whistle. Three two....
Mr. Longbottom.
-Mr. Longbottom!
-Down down!
Neville!
Come back down this instant!
Everyone out of the way!
ls he all right?
Oh dear it's a broken wrist.
Poor boy. Come on now up you get.
Everyone's to keep their feet firmly on the ground
while l take Mr Longbottom to the hospital wing.
Understand? lf l see
a single broom in the air...
...the one riding it will find themselves out of Hogwarts
before they can say Quidditch.
Did you see his face?
Maybe if the fat lump had given this a squeeze he'd have
remembered to fall on his fat arse.
Give it here Malfoy.
No. I think l'll leave it somewhere
for Longbottom to find.
How about on the roof?
What's the matter Potter?
Bit beyond your reach?
Harry no way!
You heard what Madam Hooch said.
Besides you don't even know how to fly.
What an idiot.
Give it here or l'll
knock you off your broom!
ls that so?
Have it your way then.
-Nice going Harry.
-That was wicked Harry!
Harry Potter!
Follow me.
You wait here.
Professor Quirrell excuse me.
Could l borrow Wood for a moment please?
Oh yes of course.
Potter this is Oliver Wood.
Wood l have found you a Seeker.
Have you heard? Harry Potter's
the new Gryffindor Seeker.
l always knew he'd do well.
Seeker? But first years
never make their house teams.
-You must be the youngest Quidditch player in--
-A century according to McGonagall.
Hey well done Harry.
Wood's just told us.
Fred and George are on the team too.
Beaters.
Our job is to make sure that you
don't get bloodied up too bad.
Can't make any promises of course.
Rough game Quidditch.
Brutal But no one's died in years.
Someone will vanishes occasionally.
But they'll turn up in a month or two.
Oh go on Harry. Quidditch is great. Best game
there is and you'll be great too.
But l've never even played Quidditch.
What if l make a fool of myself?
You won't make a fool of yourself.
lt's in your blood.
Harry you never told me your father
was a Seeker too.
l didn't know.
l'm telling you it's spooky.
She knows more about you than you do.
Who doesn't?
What's happening?
The staircases change remember?
-Let's go this way.
-Before the staircase moves again.
Does anybody feel like
we shouldn't be here?
We're not supposed to be here.
This is the third floor.
lt's forbidden.
Let's go.
-lt's Filch's cat!
-Run!
Quick let's hide through that door!
-lt's locked!
-Thats it We're done for!
Oh move over!
Alohomora.
Get in.
Alohomora?
Standard Book of Spells
chapter seven.
Anyone here my sweet?
Come on.
-Filch is gone.
-Probably thinks this door's locked.
-lt was locked.
-And for good reason.
What do they think they're doing? Keeping a thing
like that locked up in a school.
You don't use your eyes do you? Didn't you see
what it was standing on?
l wasn't looking at its feet!
l was a bit preoccupied with its heads.
Or maybe you didn't notice.
There were three!
lt was standing on a trap door.
Which means it wasn't there by accident.
-lt's guarding something.
-Guarding something?
That's right. Now if you two don't mind
l'm going to bed...
...before either of you come up with another clever
idea to get us killed.
Or worse expelled.
She needs to sort out her priorities.
Quidditch is easy enough to understand.
Each team has seven players.
Three Chasers two Beaters
one Keeper and a Seeker. That's you.
There are three kinds of balls.
This one's called the Quaffle.
Now the Chasers handle the Quaffle and try
to put it through one of those three hoops.
The Keeper that's me
defends the hoops. With me so far?
l think so. What are those?
You better take this.
Careful now it's coming back.
Not bad Potter.
You'd make a fair Beater.
What was that?
Bludger. Nasty little buggers.
But you are a Seeker.
The only thing l want you
to worry about is this.
The Golden Snitch.
-l like this ball.
-You like it now.
Just wait. lt's wicked fast
and damn near impossible to see.
What do l do with it?
You catch it.
Before the other team's Seeker.
You catch this the game's over.
You catch this Potter
and we win.
One of a wizard's most rudimentary
skills is levitation...
...or the ability to make objects fly.
Do you have your feathers? Good.
Now don't forget the nice wrist
movement we've been practicing.
The swish and flick. Everyone.
The swish and flick. Good.
Oh and enunciate.
Wingardium Leviosa.
Off you go then.
No stop stop stop! You're going
to take someone's eye out.
Besides you're saying it wrong.
lt's Leviosa not Leviosar.
You do it then if you're so clever.
Go on go on.
Wingardium Leviosa.
Oh well done! See here everyone
Miss Granger's done it!
Splendid!
Well done dear.
l think we're going to need
another feather over here Professor.
''lt's Leviosa not Leviosar.''
She's a nightmare honestly!
No wonder she hasn't got any friends.
l think she heard you.
Where's Hermione?
Parvati Patil said that she wouldn't
come out of the girl's bathroom.
She said that she'd been in there
all afternoon crying.
Troll! In the dungeon!
Troll in the dungeon!
Thought you ought to know.
Silence!
Everyone will please not panic!
Now...
...prefects will lead their house
back to the dormitories.
Teachers will follow me
to the dungeons.
Gryffindors keep up please
and stay alert.
How could a troll get in?
Not on its own. Trolls are really stupid.
Probably people playing jokes.
-What?
-Hermione! She doesn't know.
l think the troll's left the dungeon.
lt's going into the girl's bathroom.
Hermione move!
Help! Help!
Hey pea brain!
Help!
Do something!
-What?
-Anything!
-Hurry up!
-Swish and flick.
Wingardium Leviosa.
Cool.
ls it dead?
l don't think so. Just knocked out.
Troll bogies.
Oh my goodness!
Explain yourselves both of you!
-Well what it is--
-lt's my fault Professor McGonagall.
Miss Granger?
l went looking for the troll.
l'd read about them and thought l could handle it.
But l was wrong.
lf Harry and Ron hadn't come
and found me l'd probably be dead.
Be that as it may it was
an extremely foolish thing to do.
l would've expected more rational behavior
on your part and am very disappointed in you Ms. Granger.
Five points will be taken
from Gryffindor...
...for your serious lack of judgment.
As for you two gentlemen...
...l just hope you realize
how fortunate you are.
Not many first-year students
could take on a full grown mountain troll...
...and live to tell the tale.
Five points...
...will be awarded to each of you...
...for sheer dumb luck.
Perhaps you ought to go.
lt might wake up.
-Good of you to get us out of trouble like that.
-Mind you we did save her life.
Mind you she might not have needed saving
if you hadn't insulted her.
What are friends for?
Take a bit of toast mate. Go on.
Ron's right Harry.
You're gonna need your strength today.
l'm not hungry.
Good luck today Potter.
Then again now that you've proven yourself against a troll.
A little game of Quidditch
should be easy work for you.
Even if it is against Slytherin.
-That explains the blood.
-Blood?
Listen last night l'm guessing Snape let
the troll in as a diversion...
...so he could try and get past that 3 headed dog.
But he got himself bitten
that's why he's limping.
But why would anyone go near that dog?
The day l was at Gringotts Hagrid took
something out of one of the vaults.
He said it was Hogwarts business
very secret.
So you're saying--
That's what the dog's guarding.
That's what Snape wants.
-Bit early for mail isn't it?
-But l never get mail.
Let's open it.
lt's a broomstick.
That's not just a broomstick Harry
it's a Nimbus 2000!
But who--?
-Scared Harry?
-A little.
That's all right. l felt the same way
before my first game.
-What happened?
-Er l don't really remember.
l took a Bludger to the head
two minutes in.
Woke up in the hospital a week later.
Hello! Welcome to Hogwarts' first
Quidditch game of the season.
Today's game
Slytherin versus Gryffindor!
The players take their positions
as madam Hooch...
...steps out onto
the field to begin the game!
Now l want a nice clean game...
...from all of you!
The Bludgers are up
followed by the Golden Snitch.
Remember the Snitch
is worth 150 points.
The Seeker who catches the Snitch
ends the game.
The Quaffle is released
and the game begins!
Angelina Johnson scores!
Ten points for Gryffindor!
Well done!
Slytherin takes possession of the Quaffle.
Bletchley passes to Captain Marcus Flint.
Another 10 points to Gryffindor!
Give me that!
Take that side!
What's going on
with Harry's broomstick?
lt's Snape.
He's jinxing the broom!
-Jinxing the broom? What do we do?
-Leave it to me.
Come on Hermione!
Lacarnum lnflamarae.
Fire! You're on fire!
Go go go go!
Looks like he's gonna be sick.
He's got the Snitch!
Harry Potter receives 150 points
for catching the Snitch!
Gryffindor wins!
Nonsense! Why would Snape
put a curse on Harry's broom?
Who knows? Why was he trying
to get past that three-headed dog on Halloween?
-Who told you about Fluffy?
-Fluffy?
-That thing has a name?
-Of course he h's got a name. He's mine.
l bought him off an lrish feller l met down at the pub last year.
Then l lent him to Dumbledore to guard the--
Shouldn't have said that. No more questions!
Don't ask any more questions. That's top-secret that is.
But Hagrid whatever Fluffy's guarding
Snape's trying to steal it.
Codswallop. Professor Snape
is a Hogwarts teacher.
Hogwarts teacher or not l know a spell when
l see one. l've read all about them.
You've got to keep eye contact
and Snape wasn't blinking.
Exactly.
Now you listen to me
all three of you.
You're meddling in things that ought
not to be meddled in. lt's dangerous.
What that dog is guarding is strictly
between Dumbledore and Nicholas Flamel.
Nicholas Flamel?
l shouldn't have said that.
l should not have said that.
Nicholas Flamel.
Who's Nicholas Flamel?
l don't know.
Merry Christmas
Ring the Hogwart bell
Cast a Christmas spell
Knight to e5.
Queen to e5.
That's totally barbaric!
That's wizard's chess.
l see you've packed.
l see you haven't.
Change of plans. My parents decided to go
to Romania to visit my brother Charlie.
-He's studying dragons there.
-Good. You can help Harry then.
He's going to go and look in the library
for information on Nicholas Flamel.
We've looked a hundred times!
Not in the restricted section.
Happy Christmas.
l think we've had
a bad influence on her.
Harry wake up!
Come on Harry wake up!
-Happy Christmas Harry.
-Happy Christmas Ron.
What are you wearing?
Oh my mum made it.
Looks like you've got one too.
-l've got presents?
-Yeah.
There they are.
''Your father left this
in my possession before he died.
lt is time it was returned to you.
Use it well.''
-What is it?
-Some kind of cloak.
Well let's see then. Put it on.
My body's gone!
l know what that is.
That's an invisibility cloak!
l'm invisible?
They're really rare.
l wonder who gave it to you.
There was no name.
lt just said ''Use it well.''
Famous Fire-Eaters.
Fifteenth-Century Fiends.
Flamel. Nicholas Flamel.
Where are you?
Who's there?
l know you're in there.
You can't hide.
Who is it? Show yourself.
Severus l....
You don't want me
as your enemy Quirrell.
-l don't know what you mean.
-You know perfectly well what l mean.
We'll have another little chat soon.
When you've had time to decide
where your loyalties lie.
Professors. l found this
in the restricted section.
lt's still hot. That means
there's a student out of bed.
Mum?
Dad?
Ron you've really gotta see this!
Ron you've gotta see this!
Ron Ron come on get out of bed!
-Why?
-There's something you've got to see. Now come on!
Come on! Come!
Come look it's my parents!
l only see us.
Look in properly.
Go on stand there.
-There. You see them don't you?
-That's me! Only l'm head boy.
And l'm holding the Quidditch Cup.
And bloody hell!
l'm Quidditch captain too!
l look good.
Harry do you think this mirror
shows the future?
How can it?
Both my parents are dead.
Do you like yours Ron?
-Ron?
-l'll be right back.
-Wanna play chess?
-No.
-Wanna go and visit Hagrid?
Harry l know what you're thinking
but don't.
There's something not right
about that mirror.
Back again Harry?
l see that you
like so many before you...
...have discovered the delights
of the Mirror of Erised.
l trust by now
you realize what it does.
Let me give you a clue.
The happiest man on earth...
...would look into the mirror
and see only himself...
...exactly as he is.
So then it shows us what we want.
Whatever we want.
Yes. And no.
lt shows us nothing more or less...
...than the deepest and most desperate
desires of our hearts.
Now you Harry who have
never known your family...
...you see them standing beside you.
But remember this Harry.
This mirror gives us
neither knowledge...
...or truth.
Men have wasted away in front of it.
Even gone mad.
That is why tomorrow
it will be moved to a new home.
And l must ask you...
...not to go looking for it again.
lt does not do to dwell on dreams Harry...
...and forget to live.
Hi Hedwig.
Look at you playing with your cards.
Pathetic!
We've got final exams coming up soon.
l'm ready. Ask me any question.
Alright what are the 3 most crucial ingredients
in a Forgetfulness Potion?
l forgot.
And what may l ask do you plan to do
if this comes up in the final exam?
-Copy off you.
-No you won't.
Besides according to Professor McGonagall we're to be given special
quills bewitched with an Anti-Cheating Spell.
That's insulting! lt's as if they
don't trust us! Dumbledore again!
-Leg-Locker Curse?
-Malfoy.
You have got to start
standing up to people Neville.
How? l can barely stand at all!
l'll do the countercurse!
No that's all l need!
You to set my bloody kneecups on fire!
l don't appreciate
the insinuation Longbottom.
Besides if anyone cared to notice...
...my eyebrows have
completely grown back!
l found him!
''Dumbledore is particularly famous for his
defeat of the dark wizard Grindelwald in 1945.''
-Go on!
-''For the discovery of the twelve uses of dragon blood...
...and his work on alchemy with his
partner Nicholas Flamel'' !
l knew the name sound familiar.
l read it on the train that day.
Follow me!
Hey! Wait! Where are you going?
What about the countercurse?
l had you looking in the wrong section.
How could l be so stupid?
l checked this out weeks ago
for a bit of light reading.
This is light?
Of course! Here it is!
Nicholas Flamel is the only known
maker of the Sorcerer's Stone.
The what?
Honestly don't you two read?
''The Sorcerer's Stone is a legendary
substance with astonishing powers.
lt'll transform any metal
into pure gold...
...and produces the Elixir of Life
which will make the drinker immortal.''
-lmmortal?
-lt means you'll never die.
l know what it means!
''The only Stone currently in existence
belongs to Mr. Nicholas Flamel...
...the noted alchemist who last year
celebrated his 665th birthday.''
That's what Fluffy's guarding on the 3rd floor.
That's what's under the trap door.
The Sorcerer's Stone.
Oh hello sorry don't wish to be rude
but l'm in no fit state to entertain today.
We know about the Sorcerer's Stone.
-We think Snape's trying to steal it.
-Snape? Blimey you're not still on about him are you?
Hagrid we know he's after the Stone.
We just don't know why.
Snape is one of the teachers
protecting the Stone. He's not about to steal it.
What?
You heard. Right. Come on now
l'm a bit preoccupied today.
Wait a minute.
''One of the teachers''?
Of course! There are other things
defending the Stone aren't there?
-Spells enchantments.
-That's right.
Waste of bloody time if you ask me.
Ain't no one gonna get past Fluffy.
Ain't a soul knows how
except for me and Dumbledore.
l shouldn't have told you that.
l should not have told you that.
-Hagrid what exactly is that?
-That? lt's....
l know what that is!
But Hagrid how did you get one?
l won it. Off a stranger
l met down at the pub.
Seemed quite glad to be rid of it
as a matter of fact.
ls that...
...a dragon?
That's not just a dragon.
That's a Norwegian Ridgeback.
My brother Charlie works
with these in Romania.
lsn't he beautiful? Oh bless him.
Look he knows his mummy.
Hello Norbert.
-Norbert?
-Yeah well He's gotta have a name don't he?
Don't you Norbert?
He'll have to be trained up a bit
of course.
Who's that?
Malfoy.
Oh dear.
Hagrid always wanted a dragon.
He told me so the first time l met him.
lt's crazy.
And worse Malfoy knows.
-l don't understand. ls that bad?
-lt's bad.
Good evening.
Nothing l repeat nothing...
...gives a student the right
to walk about the school at night.
Therefore as punishment for your actions
50 points will be taken.
-50?!
-Each.
And to ensure it doesn't happen again...
...all four of you
will receive detention.
Excuse me professor
perhaps l heard you wrong.
l thought you said the four of us.
No you heard me correctly Mr. Malfoy.
You see honorable as your intentions were
you too were out of bed after hours.
You will join your classmates
in detention.
A pity they let
the old punishments die.
There was a time detention would find you
hanging by your thumbs in the dungeons.
God l miss the screaming.
You'll be serving detention
with Hagrid tonight.
He's got a little job to do
inside the Dark Forest.
A sorry lot this Hagrid.
Oh good God man you're not still on
about that bloody dragon are you?
Norbert's gone.
Dumbledore sent him off to Romania
to live in a colony.
Well that's good isn't it?
He'll be with his own kind.
Yeah but what if he don't like Romania?
What if the other dragons are mean
to him? He's only a baby after all.
Oh for God's sake pull yourself together man.
You're going into the Forest after all.
Got to have your wits about you.
The Forest? l thought that was a joke.
We can't go in there.
Students aren't allowed.
And there are...
...werewolves.
There's more than werewolves
in those trees lad.
You can be sure of that.
Nighty-night.
Right. Let's go.
Hagrid what is that?
What we're here for.
See that?
That's unicorn blood that is.
l found one dead a few weeks ago.
Now this one's been hurt bad
by something.
So it's our job to go
and find the poor beast.
Ron Hermione you'll come with me.
And Harry you'll go with Malfoy.
Okay. Then l get Fang.
Fine. Just so you know
he's a bloody coward.
You wait till my father hears about this.
This is servant's stuff.
lf l didn't know better Draco
l'd say you were scared.
l'm not scared Potter.
Did you hear that?
Come on Fang.
Scared!
What is it Fang?
Harry Potter you must leave.
You are known to many creatures here.
The Forest is not safe at this time.
Especially for you.
What was that thing you saved me from?
A monstrous creature.
lt is a terrible crime to slay a unicorn.
Drinking the blood of a unicorn will keep
you alive even if you are an inch from death.
But at a terrible price. You
have slain something so pure...
...that from the moment the blood touches
your lips you will have a half-life.
A cursed life.
-But who would choose such a life?
-Can you think of no one?
Do you mean to say that
thing that killed the unicorn...
...that was drinking its blood
that was Voldemort?
Do you know what is hidden
in the school at this very moment Mr. Potter?
The Sorcerer's Stone.
Harry!
Hello there Firenze.
See you've met our young Mr. Potter.
You all right there Harry?
Harry Potter
this is where l leave you.
You're safe now. Good luck.
You mean You-Know-Who is out there
right now in the Forest?
But he's weak.
He's living off the unicorns.
Don't you see? We had it wrong.
Snape doesn't want the Stone for himself.
He wants the stone for Voldemort.
With the Elixir of Life
Voldemort will be strong again.
He'll come back.
But if he comes back...
...you don't think he'll try
to kill you do you?
l think if he'd had the chance
he might have tried to kill me tonight.
And to think l've been worrying
about my Potions final.
Hang on a minute.
We're forgetting one thing.
Who's the one wizard
Voldemort always feared?
Dumbledore. As long as Dumbledore
is around Harry you're safe.
As long as Dumbledore is around
you can't be touched.
l'd always heard Hogwarts' end of the year exams were
frightful but l found that rather enjoyable.
Speak for yourself.
All right there Harry?
-My scar. lt keeps burning.
-lt's happened before.
-Not like this.
-Perhaps you should see the nurse.
l think it's a warning.
lt means danger's coming.
-Of course!
-What is it?
Don't you think it's a bit odd that what Hagrid wants
more than anything is a dragon...
...and a stranger turns up who
just happens to have one?
I mean how many people wander around
with dragon eggs in their pockets?
Why didn't l see it before?
Hagrid who gave you the dragon egg?
What did he look like?
I don't know l never saw his face.
He kept his hood up.
The stranger though You and he
must have talked.
Well he wanted to know what sort
of creatures l looked after.
l told him. l said ''After Fluffy
a dragon's gonna be no problem.''
-And did he seem interested in Fluffy?
-Well of course he was interested in Fluffy.
How often do you come across a
three-headed dog even if you're in the trade?
But l told him. I said ''The trick with any beast
is to know how to calm him.''
Take Fluffy for example. Just play him a bit of
music and he falls straight to sleep.
l shouldn't have told you that.
Where are you going? Wait!
We have to see Professor Dumbledore.
lmmediately!
l'm afraid Professor Dumbledore is not here.
He received an urgent owl from the
Ministry of Magic and left immediately for London.
He's gone? Now?
But this is important!
This is about the Sorcerer's Stone!
-How do you know--?
-Someone's going to try and steal it.
l don't know how you three found out about the stone
but l assure you it is perfectly well protected.
Now would you go back
to your dormitories? Quietly.
That was no stranger Hagrid met in the village.
lt was Snape.
Which means he knows
how to get past Fluffy.
-And with Dumbledore gone--
-Good afternoon.
Now what would three young Gryffindors such as yourselves...
...be doing inside on a day like this?
-We were just--
-You ought to be careful.
People will think you're...
...up to something.
Now what do we do?
We go down the trap door. Tonight.
Trevor.
Trevor shh! go! You shouldn't be here!
Neither should you.
You're sneaking out again aren't you?
-Now Neville listen. We were--
-No l won't let you!
You'll get Gryffindor into trouble again.
l'll fight you.
Neville l'm really really sorry about this.
Petrificus Totalus.
You're a little scary sometimes
you know that?
Brilliant but scary.
Let's go.
-Sorry.
-lt's for your own good you know.
-Ow! You stood on my foot!
-Sorry.
Alohomora.
Wait a minute. He's...
...snoring.
Snape's already been here.
He's put a spell on the harp.
lt's got horrible breath.
-We have to move its paw.
-What?
Come on!
Okay. Push.
l'll go first. Don't follow
until l give you a sign.
lf something bad happens
get yourselves out.
Does it seem a bit quiet to you?
The harp.
lt's stopped playing.
Jump!
Lucky this plant thing's here really.
Stop moving both of you.
This is Devil's Snare.
You have to relax. lf you don't
it will only kill you faster.
Kill us faster?
Oh now l can relax!
Hermione!
-Now what are we gonna do?
-Just relax!
-Hermione where are you?
-Do what l say! Trust me.
-Are you okay?
-Yeah l'm fine.
-He's not relaxing is he?
-Apparently not.
-We've gotta do something.
-What?
l remember reading something
in Herbology.
Devil's Snare Devil's Snare.
lt's deadly fun...
...but will sulk in the sun!
That's it! Devil Snare hates sunlight.
Lumus Solem.
-Ron you okay?
-Yeah.
Lucky we didn't panic.
Lucky Hermione pays attention
in Herbology.
What is that?
l don't know. Sounds like wings.
Curious. l've never seen
birds like these.
They're not birds.
They're keys.
And l'll bet one of them
fits that door.
-What's this all about?
-l don't know.
Strange.
Alohomora!
Well it was worth a try.
What're we going to do?
There must be a thousand keys up there.
We're looking for a big old fashioned one.
Probably rusty like the handle.
There! l see it!
The one with the broken wing.
What's wrong Harry?
lt's too simple.
Oh go on Harry! lf Snape could catch it
on that old broomstick you can.
You're the youngest Seeker
in a century.
This complicates things a bit.
Catch the key!
Hurry up!
l don't like this.
l don't like this at all.
Where are we? A graveyard.
This is no graveyard.
lt's a chessboard.
There's the door.
Now what do we do?
lt's obvious isn't it? We've got
to play our way across the room.
Alright. Harry you take
the empty bishop's square.
Hermione you'll be
the queen-side castle.
As for me l'll be a knight.
What happens now?
Well white moves first.
And then...
...we play.
Ron you don't suppose
this is going to be like...
...real wizard's chess do you?
You there d5.
Yes Hermione.
l think this is gonna be
exactly like wizard's chess.
Castle to e4!
Pawn to c3!
-Wait a minute.
-You understand right Harry.
Once l make my move
the queen will take me.
Then you're free to check the king.
-No. Ron no!
-What is it?
-He's going to sacrifice himself.
-No you can't! there must be another way!
Do you wanna stop Snape
from getting that Stone or not?
Harry it's you that has to go on.
l know it.
Not me. Not Hermione. You.
Knight to h3.
Check.
Ron!
No don't move!
Don't forget we're still playing.
Checkmate.
Take care of Ron.
Then go to the owlery.
Send a message to Dumbledore.
Ron's right.
l have to go on.
You'll be okay Harry.
You're a great wizard. You really are.
Not as good as you.
Me? Books and cleverness.
There are more important things.
Friendship and bravery.
And Harry just be careful.
You?
No it can't be.
Snape he was the--
Yes he does seem the type
doesn't he?
Next to him who would suspect...
...poor stuttering
Professor Quirrell?
But that day during the Quidditch match
Snape tried to kill me.
No dear boy. l tried to kill you!
And trust me if Snape's cloak hadn't caught
fire and broken my eye contact...
...l would have succeeded.
Even with Snape muttering
his little countercurse.
Snape was trying to save me?
l knew you were a danger to me right from the off.
Especially after Halloween.
-Then you let the troll in!
-Very good Potter yes.
Snape unfortunately wasn't fooled.
While everyone else was running about dungeon
he went to the third floor to head me off.
He of course never trusted me again.
He rarely left me alone.
But he doesn't understand.
l'm never alone. Never.
Now what does this mirror do?
l see what l desire.
l see myself holding the Stone.
But how do l get it?
Use the boy.
Come here Potter! Now!
Tell me what do you see?
What is it? What do you see?
l'm shaking hands with Dumbledore.
l've won the house cup.
He lies.
Tell the truth! What do you see?
-Let me speak to him.
-Master you are not strong enough.
l have strength enough for this.
Harry Potter...
...we meet again.
Voldemort.
Yes. You see what l've become?
See what l must do to survive?
Live off another. A mere parasite.
Unicorn blood can sustain me...
...but it cannot give me
a body of my own.
But there is something that can.
Something that conveniently enough
lies in your pocket.
Stop him!
Don't be a fool.
Why suffer an horrific death...
...when you can join me and live?
Never!
Bravery. Your parents had it too.
Tell me Harry...
...would you like to see
your mother and father again?
Together...
...we can bring them back.
All l ask is for something in return.
That's it Harry.
There is no good and evil.
There is only power...
...and those too weak to seek it.
Together we'll do
extraordinary things.
Just give me the Stone!
You liar!
Kill him!
-What is this magic?
-Fool get the Stone!
Good afternoon Harry.
-Tokens from your admirers?
-Admirers?
What happened down in the dungeons between
you and Professor Quirrell is a complete secret.
So naturally the whole school knows.
l see that your friend Ronald
has saved you the trouble...
...of opening your Chocolate Frogs.
Ron was here? ls he all right?
What about Hermione?
Fine. They're both just fine.
-What happened to the Stone?
-Relax dear boy.
The Stone has been destroyed.
My friend Nicholas and l
have had a little chat...
...and agreed it was best all around.
But then Flamel
he'll die won't he?
He has enough Elixir
to set his affairs in order.
But yes he will die.
How is it l got the Stone sir?
One minute l was staring
in the mirror and the next--
You see only a person...
...who wanted to find the Stone
find it...
...but not use it
would be able to get it.
That is one of my more brilliant ideas.
And between you and me
that is saying something.
Does that mean with the Stone gone that is
that Voldemort can never come back?
l'm afraid...
...there are ways
in which he can return.
Harry do you know why...
...Professor Quirrell couldn't bear
to have you touch him?
lt was because of your mother.
She sacrificed herself for you.
And that kind of act leaves a mark.
No this kind of mark cannot be seen.
-lt lives in your very skin.
-What is it?
Love Harry. Love.
Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans.
l was most unfortunate in my youth
to come across a vomit-flavored one.
And since then l'm afraid
l've lost my liking for them.
But l think l could be safe...
...with a nice toffee.
Alas!
Earwax.
-All right there Ron?
-All right. You?
All right. Hermione?
Never better.
Another year gone.
And now as l understand it
the house cup needs awarding.
And the points stand thus:
ln fourth place
Gryffindor with 312 points.
Third place
Hufflepuff with 352 points.
ln second place...
...Ravenclaw with 426 points.
And in first place...
...with 472 points Slytherin house.
Nice one mate.
Yes yes well done Slytherin.
Well done Slytherin.
However recent events must
be taken into account.
And l have a few last-minute points
to award.
To Miss Hermione Granger
for the cool use of intellect...
...while others were in grave peril...
...50 points.
Good job.
Second to Mr. Ronald Weasley
for the best-played game of chess...
...that Hogwarts has seen
these many years 50 points.
And third...
...to Mr. Harry Potter...
...for pure nerve
and outstanding courage...
...l award Gryffindor house 60 points.
We're tied with Slytherin!
Finally it takes a great deal of bravery
to stand up to your enemies...
...but a great deal more
to stand up to your friends.
l award 10 points...
...to Neville Longbottom.
Assuming that my calculations
are correct l believe...
...that a change
of decoration is in order.
Gryffindor wins the house cup.
Come on now.
Hurry up you'll be late.
Train's leaving. Go on.
Come on hurry up.
-Come on Harry.
-One minute.
Thought you were leaving
without saying goodbye did you?
This is for you.
Thanks Hagrid.
Go on. On with you. On with you now.
Oh listen Harry.
lf that dolt of a cousin of yours
Dudley gives you any grief...
...you could always threaten him...
...with a nice pair of ears
to go with that tail of his.
But Hagrid we're not allowed to do magic
away from Hogwarts. You know that.
l do. But your cousin don't do he?
Feels strange to be going home
doesn't it?
l'm not going home.
Not really.