Papa!
While I'm very familiar
with your and your family,
I have no way of knowing
if you are familiar
with who I am.
Are you aware
of my existence?
Yes.
This is good.
Are you aware
of the job
I've been ordered
to carry out in France?
Yes.
Please tell me
what you've heard.
I've heard
that the Fuhrer
has put you in charge
of rounding up
the Jews left in France
who are either hiding
or passing for Gentile.
The Fuhrer couldn't have
said it better himself.
But the meaning
of your visit...
Pleasant,
though it is...
Is mysterious to me.
The Germans looked
through my house
nine months ago
for hiding Jews...
and found nothing.
Yeah.
I'm aware of that.
I've read the reports
of this area.
But like any enterprise,
when under new management,
there's always a slight
duplication of efforts.
Most of it being
a complete waste of time.
But needs to be done nevertheless.
I just have a few questions,
Monsieur LaPadite.
If you can assist me
with the answers,
my department can
close a file on your family.
Now...
before the occupation
there were...
four Jewish families
in this area.
All dairy farmers
like yourself.
The Doleracs, the Rollins,
the Loveitts
and the Dreyfuses.
Is that correct?
To my knowledge,
those were the Jewish families
among the dairy farmers.
Herr Colonel,
would it disturb you
if I smoked my pipe?
Please,
Monsieur LaPadite.
This is your house.
Make yourself comfortable.
Now according
to these papers,
all the Jewish families
in this area
have been accounted
for except...
the Dreyfuses.
Somewhere in the last year
it would appear
they have vanished,
which leads me
to the conclusion
that they've either
made good their escape
or someone is very
successfully hiding them.
What have you heard about the
Dreyfuses, Monsieur LaPadite?
Only rumors.
I love rumors.
Facts can be
so misleading,
where rumors...
True or false,
are often revealing.
So Monsieur LaPadite,
what rumors
have you heard
regarding
the Dreyfuses?
Again, this is just a rumor,
but we heard...
the Dreyfuses...
had made their way
into Spain.
So the rumors you've heard
have been of escape?
Oui.
Uh, Yes.
Having never met
the Dreyfuses,
would you confirm for me the
exact members of the household
and their names?
There were
five of them.
Um, the father,
Jacob.
Wife...
Miriam.
And her brother...
Bob.
How old is Bob?
30, 31.
Continue.
And the children...
Amos...
and Shosanna.
Ages of the children?
Uh, Amos was...
nine or 10?
And Shosanna?
And Shosanna was...
18 or 19.
I'm not really sure.
I guess
that should do it.
However, before I go,
could I have another glass
of your delicious milk?
LaPadite:
But of course.
Monsieur LaPadite,
are you aware
of the nickname
the people of France
have given me?
I have no interest
in such things.
But you are aware
of what they call me.
I'm aware.
What are you
aware of then?
Merci.
That they call you
the "Jew Hunter."
Precisely.
I understand your
trepidation in repeating it.
Heydrich apparently
hates the moniker
the good people of Prague
have bestowed on him.
Actually,
why he would hate
the name "The Hangman"
is baffling to me.
It would appear he's done
everything in his power to earn it.
I, on the other hand,
love my unofficial title,
precisely because
I've earned it.
The feature that makes me such
an effective hunter of the Jews is,
as opposed
to most German soldiers,
I can think
like a Jew...
where they can only
think like a German.
More precisely,
German soldier.
Now if one were to
determine what attribute
the German people
share with a beast,
it would be the cunning and
the predatory instinct of a hawk.
But if one were to
determine what attributes
the Jews share
with the beast,
it would be that
of the rat.
The Fuhrer
and Goebbels' propaganda
have said pretty much
the same thing.
But where our
conclusions differ
is I don't consider
the comparison an insult.
Consider for a moment
the world a rat
lives in.
It's a hostile world, indeed.
If a rat were
to scamper
through your
front door right now,
would you greet it
with hostility?
I suppose I would.
Has a rat ever done
anything to you to create
this animosity
you feel toward them?
Rats spread disease.
They bite people.
Rats were the cause
of the bubonic plague.
But that's
some time ago.
I propose to you any
disease a rat could spread,
a squirrel
could equally carry.
Would you agree?
Oui.
Yet I assume
you don't share
the same animosity
with squirrels
you do with rats,
do you?
- No.
- Yet they're both rodents, are they not?
Except for the tail, they even
rather look alike, don't they?
It's an interesting
thought, Herr Colonel.
However interesting
as the thought may be,
it makes not one bit of
difference to how you feel.
If a rat were to walk
in here right now,
as I'm talking,
would you greet it
with a saucer
of your delicious milk?
Probably not.
I didn't think so.
You don't like them.
You don't really know
why you don't like them,
all you know is
you find them repulsive.
Consequently,
a German soldier
conducts a search of a house
suspected of hiding Jews.
Where does
the hawk look?
He looks in the barn,
he looks in the attic,
he looks
in the cellar...
He looks everywhere
he would hide.
But there's so many places
it would never occur
to a hawk to hide.
However, the reason
the Fuhrer's
brought me
off my Alps in Austria
and placed me in French
cow country today
is because it does
occur to me.
Because I'm aware
of what tremendous feats
human beings are capable
of once they abandon dignity.
May I smoke
my pipe as well?
P-Please, Herr Colonel,
make yourself
at home.
Now...
my job dictates...
that I must have
my men enter your home...
and conduct
a thorough search
before I can officially cross
your family's name off my list.
If there are any
irregularities to be found,
rest assured,
they will be.
That is, unless you have
something to tell me
that makes the conducting
of a search unnecessary.
I might add, also,
that any information
that makes the performance
of my duty easier
will not be met
with punishment.
Actually,
quite the contrary...
It will be met
with reward.
That reward will be
your family
will cease
to be harassed
in any way
by the German military
during the rest of our
occupation of your country.
You are sheltering enemies
of the state, are you not?
Yes.
You're sheltering them
underneath your floorboards,
aren't you?
Yes.
Point out to me the areas
where they're hiding.
Since I haven't heard
any disturbance,
I assume while they
are listening,
they don't speak English.
Yes.
I'm going to switch back
to French now,
and I want you to follow
my masquerade,
is that clear?
Yes.
Shh!
It's the girl.
Au revoir,
Shosanna!
Ten-hut!
My name is
Lieutenant Aldo Raine,
and I'm putting together
a special team,
and I need me
eight soldiers.
Eight Jewish
American soldiers.
Now y'all might've
heard rumors
about the armada
happening soon.
Well, we'll be leaving
a little earlier.
We're gonna be dropped into
France dressed as civilians.
Once we're in enemy territory,
as a bushwhacking
guerilla army,
we're gonna be doing
one thing,
and one thing only...
Killing Nazis.
I don't know
about y'all,
but I sure as hell
didn't come down
from the goddamn
smoky mountains,
cross 5000 miles
of water,
fight my way
through half of Sicily,
and jump out
of a fucking airplane
to teach the Nazis
lessons in humanity.
Nazi ain't got
no humanity.
They're the foot soldiers
of a Jew-hating,
mass-murdering maniac,
and they need
to be destroyed.
That's why any and every
son of a bitch we find
wearing a Nazi uniform,
they're gonna die.
I'm the direct descendent
of the mountain man
Jim Bridger.
That means I got
a little Indian in me.
Our battle plan
will be that
of an Apache resistance.
We will be cruel
to the Germans.
Through our cruelty,
they will know who we are.
They will find
the evidence of our cruelty
in the disemboweled, dismembered
and disfigured bodies of their
brothers we leave behind us.
And the German won't be able
to help themselves
but imagine the cruelty
their brothers endured
at our hands,
and our boot heels,
and the edge
of our knives.
And the German
will be sickened by us.
And the German will
talk about us.
And the German
will fear us.
When the German closes
their eyes at night,
and they're tortured
by their subconscious
for the evil
they have done,
it will be
with thoughts of us
that they are
tortured with.
Sound good?
Yes, sir!
That's what I
like to hear.
But I got a word
of warning
for all you
would-be warriors...
When you join my command,
you take on debit.
That debit you owe me... personally.
Each and every man
under my command
owes me 100 Nazi scalps.
And I want my scalps.
And all y'all will get me
100 Nazi scalps
taken from the heads
of 100 dead Nazis,
or you will die trying.
Hey, Hirschberg.
Send that Kraut
sarge over.
You, go.
Sergeant
Werner Rachtmann.
Lieutenant Aldo Raine,
pleased to meet you.
You know what sit down
means, Werner?
Yes.
Then sit down.
How's your English,
Werner?
'Cause need be, we got a
couple fellas can translate.
Wicki there...
An Austrian Jew who
got the fuck out of Munich
while the getting was good,
became American.
Got drafted, come back
to give y'all what for.
Another one up there
you might be familiar with,
Sergeant Hugo Stiglitz.
Heard of him?
Everybody in the German army
has heard of Hugo Stiglitz.
The reason for
Hugo Stiglitz's
celebrity among
German soldiers is simple.
As a German enlisted man,
he killed 13
Gestapo officers.
Instead of putting him
up against the wall,
the high command decided
to send him back to Berlin
to be made an example of.
Needless to say,
once the Basterds
heard about him,
he never got there.
Sergeant Hugo Stiglitz?
Lieutenant Aldo Raine.
These are the Basterds.
Ever heard of us?
We just wanted to say
we're a big fan of your work.
When it comes
to killing Nazis...
I think you show
great talent.
I pride myself in having
an eye for that kind of talent.
But your status as a
Nazi killer is still amateur.
We all come here to
see if you want to go pro.
Can I assume you know
who we are?
You're Aldo
the Apache.
Hey!
Werner, if you
heard of us,
you probably heard we ain't
in the prisoner taking business.
We in the killing
Nazi business.
And cousin,
business is a-booming.
Oh, yeah.
That leaves two ways
we can play this out.
Either kill you
or let you go.
Whether or not you're
gonna leave this ditch alive
depends entirely
on you.
Up the road a piece
there's an orchard.
Besides you,
we know there's another
Kraut patrol fucking
around here somewhere.
If that patrol were
to have any crack shots,
that orchard would be
a goddamn sniper's delight.
So if you ever
want to eat
a sauerkraut
sandwich again,
you gotta show me
on this here map
where they are.
You gotta tell me
how many they are,
and you gotta tell me
what kinda artillery
they're carrying
with 'em.
You can't expect me
to divulge information
that would put
German lives in danger.
Well, now, Werner,
that's where you're wrong.
That's exactly what I expect.
I need to know about Germans
hiding in trees.
And you need to tell me.
And you need
to tell me right now.
Just take
that finger of yours
and point out
on this here map
where this party's
being held.
How many is a-coming,
and what they brought
to play with.
I respectfully
refuse, sir.
Hear that?
Yes.
That's Sergeant
Donny Donowitz.
You might know him
better by his nickname...
"The Bear Jew."
If you heard
of Aldo the Apache,
you gotta have heard
about the Bear Jew.
I heard
of the Bear Jew.
What did you hear?
Beats German soldiers
with a club.
He bashes their brains in
with a baseball bat
is what he does.
Werner, I'm gonna ask you
one last goddamn time,
and if you still
respectfully refuse,
I'm calling
the Bear Jew over.
He's gonna take
that big bat of his
and he's gonna beat
your ass to death with it.
Now take your wiener-schnitzel-
looking finger
and point out on this map
what I want to know.
Fuck you,
and your Jew dogs!
Actually, we're all tickled
to hear you say that.
Quite frankly, watching
Donny beat Nazis to death
is the closest we ever
get to going to the movies.
- Donny!
- Yeah?
We got us a German here who
wants to die for country. Oblige him.
Did you get that
for killing Jews?
Bravery.
Oh, no!
About now, I'd be shitting
my pants if I was you.
Teddy fucking Williams
knocks it out of the park!
Fenway Park is on its feet
for Teddy fucking Ballgame!
He went yard
on that one!
On to fucking
Landsdowne Street!
You!
Damn it, Hirschberg.
Donny, bring that
other one over here.
Alive!
Get the fuck up!
Batter up! You're on deck!
Two hits... I hit you,
you hit the ground.
- English?
- Nein.
Wicki.
Ask him if he
wants to live.
Ja, sir.
Tell him to point out on this
map the German position.
Ask him
how many Germans.
Round about 12.
What kind of artillery?
When you report
what happened here,
you can't tell 'em
you told us what you told us.
They'll shoot you.
They're gonna want to know
why are you so special
we let you live.
So tell 'em
we let you live
so you could spread
the word through the ranks
what's gonna happen
to every Nazi we find.
Now that you
survived the war,
when you get home
what you gonna do?
He's gonna hug
his mother.
Well, ain't that nice.
Ask if he's gonna
take off his uniform.
He's gonna burn it.
That's what
we thought.
We don't like that.
See, we like our Nazis
in uniforms.
That way you
can spot 'em...
Just like that.
Once you take off
that uniform,
ain't nobody gonna know
you's a Nazi.
That don't sit
well with us.
So I'm gonna give you a little
something you can't take off.
You know, Lieutenant,
you're getting
pretty good at that.
You know how you get to
Carnegie Hall, don't you?
Practice.
- Heil Hitler.
Hallo, Hallo, Hallo,
Frederick Zoller.
- Heil Hitler.
Au revoir.
Au revoir,
Shosanna!
At that time,
35 millimeter
nitrate film
was so flammable
that you couldn't even
bring a reel onto a streetcar.
You can't bring those
there in a public vehicle.
- They're films, ain't they?
- Yes.
Then they're flammable.
Go on, hop off.
Because nitrate film
burns three times faster
than paper.
Shosanna has a collection
of over 350
nitrate film prints.
Right this way, Lieutenant.
Lieutenant Archie Hicox
reporting, sir.
General Ed Fenech.
At ease, Hicox.
Drink?
If you offer me
a scotch and plain water,
I could drink a scotch
and plain water.
Thattaboy, Lieutenant.
Make it yourself
like a good chap, will you?
The bar's
in the globe.
Something
for yourself, sir?
Whisky, straight.
No junk in it.
It says here that you
speak German fluently.
Like a Katzenjammer kid.
And your occupation
before the war?
I'm a film critic.
List your accomplishments.
Well, sir,
such as they are, I
write reviews and articles
for a publication called
"Films and Filmmakers."
And I've had
two books published.
Hmm, impressive.
Don't be modest, Lieutenant,
what are
their titles?
The first book
was called,
"Art of the Eyes,
the Heart and the Mind:
A study of German
cinema in the '20s."
The second one was called,
"24 Frame da Vinci."
It's a subtextual
film criticism study
of the work of German
director G.W. Pabst.
What shall
we drink to, sir?
Well, um...
down with Hitler.
All the way
down, sir.
Yes. Yes.
Are you familiar with German
cinema under the Third Reich?
Yes, obviously I haven't
seen any of the films
made in the last
three years,
but I'm familiar
with it.
Explain it to me.
Pardon, sir?
Well, this little
escapade of ours
requires a knowledge
of the German film industry
under the Third Reich.
Explain to me
UFA under Goebbels.
Goebbels considers
the films he's making
to be the beginning of a
new era in German cinema,
an alternative
to what he considers
the Jewish-German
intellectual cinema of the '20s
and the Jewish-controlled
dogma of Hollywood.
How's he
doing?
Frightfully. Sorry,
sir. Once again?
You say he wants to
take on the Jews
at their own game.
Well,
compared to, say,
Louis B. Mayer,
how's he doing?
Quite well, actually.
Since Goebbels
has taken over,
film attendance has
steadily risen in Germany
over the last
eight years.
But Louis B. Mayer
wouldn't be
Goebbels' proper
opposite number.
I believe Goebbels
sees himself
closer to
David O. Selznick.
Brief him.
Lieutenant Hicox,
at this point in time,
I'd like to brief you
on Operation Kino.
Three days from now,
Joseph Goebbels is
throwing a gala premiere
of one of his new movies
in Paris.
- What film, sir?
- The motion picture is called "Nation's Pride."
In attendance at this
joyous Germatic occasion
will be Goebbels,
Goring, Bormann,
and most of
the German High Command,
including all
high-ranking officers
of both the SS
and the Gestapo,
as well as luminaries of the
Nazi propaganda film industry.
The master race
at play, eh?
Basically, we have
all our rotten eggs
in one basket.
The objective
of Operation Kino...
blow up
the basket.
And like the snows
of yesteryear,
gone from
this earth.
Jolly good, sir.
An American
Secret Service outfit
that lives
deep behind enemy lines
will be your assist.
The Germans call them
the Basterds.
- The Basterds?
- Yeah.
Never
heard of them.
Whole point
of the Secret Service,
old boy, you not
hearing of them.
But the Jerries
have heard of them
because these Yanks
have been them the devil.
You'll be dropped
into France,
about 24 kilometers
outside of Paris.
The Basterds will be
waiting for you.
First thing, you'll
go to a little village
called Nadine.
In Nadine, there's a
tavern called La Louisiane.
There you'll rendezvous
with our double agent.
She'll take you
from there.
She's the one who's going
to get you into the premiere.
It will be you, her, and two
German-born members of the Basterds.
She's also made
all the other arrangements
you're going to need.
How will I know her?
I suspect that won't be
too much trouble for you.
Your contact is
Bridget von Hammersmark.
Bridget von Hammersmark?
The German movie star
is working for England?
Yes, for the last
two years now.
One could even say
that Operation Kino
is her brain child.
Indeed.
Got the gist?
Well, I think so, sir.
Paris when it sizzles.
You didn't say the goddamn
rendezvous was in a fucking basement.
I didn't know.
It said it was
in a tavern.
- It is a tavern.
- Yeah. In a basement.
You know, fighting in a
basement offers a lot of difficulties,
number one being you're
fighting in a basement.
What if we go in there
and she's not even there?
We wait.
Don't worry.
She's a British spy.
She'll make
the rendezvous.
Stiglitz, right?
That's right, sir.
I hear you're
pretty good with that.
You know, we're not
looking for trouble right now,
simply making contact
with our agent.
Should be uneventful.
However,
the off chance
I'm wrong,
things prove eventful,
I need to know
we can all remain calm.
I don't look
calm to you?
Well, now that you
put it like that...
I guess you do.
This Jerry of yours, Stiglitz,
he's not exactly
the loquacious type, is he?
Is that the kind
of man you need?
Loquacious type?
Fair point, Lieutenant.
So, you all
get in trouble in there,
what are we
supposed to do,
make bets on
how it call comes out?
If we get into trouble,
we can handle it.
But if trouble
does happen,
we need you
to make damn sure
no Germans, or French,
for that matter,
escape from
that basement.
If Frau von Hammersmark's
cover is compromised,
the mission is kaput.
Speaking of
Frau von Hammersmark,
whose idea was it for
the death-trap rendezvous?
She chose the spot.
Oh, isn't that
just dandy?
Look. She's not
a military strategist.
She's just
an actress.
Well, you don't got to
be Stonewall Jackson
to know you don't want
to fight in a basement.
She wasn't picking
a place to fight.
She was picking
a place isolated
and without Germans.
Eric, merci beaucoup.
Nein.
Well, if this is it,
old boy...
I hope you don't mind if I
go out speaking the kings.
By all means, Captain.
There's a special rung
in hell
reserved for people
who waste good scotch.
Seeing as I may be
rapping on the door momentarily...
I must say...
damn good stuff, sir.
Now,
about this pickle...
we find ourselves in.
It would appear
that there's only
one thing left
for you to do.
And what
would that be?
- Stiglitz.
- Say auf Weidersehen to your Nazi balls.
You outside!
Who are you?
British?
American?
What?
We're American.
What are you?
I'm a German,
you idiot!
You speak English
pretty good for a German.
I agree.
So, let's talk.
Okay, talk.
I'm a father.
My baby was born
today in Frankfurt
five hours ago.
His name is Max.
We were in here
drinking, celebrating.
They're the ones
that came in
shooting and killing.
It's not my fault!
Okay,
it wasn't your fault.
What's your name, soldier?
Wilhelm.
Now...
is there anybody
alive on our side?
- No!
- I'm alive!
Who's that?
Is the girl
on your side?
Which girl?
Who do you
think?
Von Hammersmark.
Yeah, she's ours.
Is she okay?
Wilhelm!
She's been shot!
But she's alive.
No.
Okay, Wilhelm.
What do you say
we make us a deal?
What's your name?
Aldo.
Okay, Wilhelm,
here's my deal.
You let me
and one of my men
come down there
and take the girl away.
No guns... no guns
me, no guns you.
And we take the girl
and leave.
It's that simple, Willy.
You go your way,
and we go ours,
and little Max
gets to grow up
playing catch
with his daddy.
So what do you say,
Willy?
We got us
a deal?
Aldo?
I'm here, Willy.
I want to
trust you,
but-but...
but how can I?
What choice you got, son?
Okay, okay.
Aldo...
I'm going to
trust you.
Come down.
Hey, Willy, what's
with the machine gun?
I thought
we had us a deal.
We still have a deal.
Now get the girl and go.
Not so fast.
We only got a deal
if we trust each other.
And a Mexican standoff
ain't trust.
You need guns on me for it
to be a Mexican standoff.
You got guns
on us.
You decide to shoot,
we're dead.
Up top,
they got grenades.
They drop 'em down here,
you're dead.
That's a Mexican standoff,
and that was not the deal.
No trust,
no deal.
Wilhelm...
All right, Aldo.
Fine.
Just take that
fucking traitor
and get her
out of my sight.
Not so goddamn fast, doc.
Tell him to go play
with his dogs.
Before we yank
that slug out you,
you need to answer
a few questions.
A few questions
about what?
About I got three
men dead back there.
Why don't you try telling us
what the fuck happened?
The British officer
blew his German act
and the Gestapo major
saw it.
Before we get into
who shot John...
why did you
invite my men
to a rendezvous in a basement
with a bunch of Nazis?
I can see since you didn't
see what happened inside
that the Nazis being
there must look odd.
Yeah, we got a word for
that kind of odd in English.
It's called
"suspicious."
Everybody needs to
calm down!
You're letting your
imagination get the better of you!
You met the sergeant
yourself!
Willy... You remember
him, don't you?
Yeah,
I remember him.
His wife had
a baby tonight.
He had just become
a fa...
a father!
His commanding officer
gave him and his mates
the night off
to celebrate.
The Germans being there
was either a trap set by me
or a tragic coincidence.
It couldn't be both.
How'd the shooting start?
The Englishman
gave himself away.
How'd he do that?
He ordered
three glasses.
We order
That's the German three.
The other looks odd.
Germans would
and did notice it.
Okay, let's pretend
there were no Germans
and everything went exactly
the way it was supposed to.
What was
the next step?
Tuxedos.
To get them
into the premiere
wearing
military uniforms
with all the military there
would have been suicide.
But going as members
of the German film industry,
they wear tuxedos and
fit in with everybody else.
I arranged
for the tailor
to fit three tuxedos tonight.
How'd you intend to
get them in that premiere?
Hand me my purse.
Lieutenant Hicox
was going as my escort.
The other two
were going
as a German cameraman
and his assistant.
You still get us
in that premiere?
You speak German
better than your friends?
No.
Have I been shot?
Yes.
I don't see me tripping
the light fantastique
up at the red carpet
anytime soon.
Least of all,
by tomorrow night.
However...
there's something
you don't know.
There have been
two recent developments
regarding
Operation Kino.
One... the venue
has been changed
from the Ritz
to a much smaller venue.
Enormous change
at the last minute?
That's not very Germatic.
Why the hell is Goebbels
doing stuff so damn peculiar?
It probably has something to
do with the second development.
Which is?
Der Fuhrer is
attending the premiere.
Fuck a duck!
What are you thinking?
I'm thinking of
getting a whack
at planting old Uncle Adolf makes
this a horse of a different color.
What is that
supposed to mean?
It means you getting us
in that premiere.
I'm probably going to
end up losing this leg!
Bye-bye, acting career!
Fun while it lasted.
How do you expect me
to walk the red carpet?
Doggy doc's going to dig
that slug out your gam.
He's gonna wrap it up
in a cast,
and you got a good how-I-broke-my-leg-
mountain-climbing story.
That's German, ain't it? Y'all
like climbing mountains, don't you?
I don't. I like
smoking, drinking,
and ordering in restaurants,
but I see your point.
We fill you up with morphine
till it's coming out your ears
and just limp your little
ass up that rouge carpet.
I know this is
a silly question
before I ask it, but...
can you Americans speak any
other language than English?
We both speak
a little Italian.
With an atrocious accent,
no doubt.
But that doesn't exactly
kill us in the crib.
Germans don't have
a good ear for Italian.
So you mumble Italian
and brazen through it.
Is that a plan?
That's about it.
That sounds good.
Sounds like shit.
What else we gonna do,
go home?
No.
That sounds good.
If you don't blow it,
with that, I can get
you in the building.
Who does what?
Well, I speak
the most Italian, so...
I'll be your escort. Donowitz
speaks the second most,
so he'll be
your Italian cameraman.
Omar, third most.
He'll be Donny's assistant.
I don't
speak Italian.
Like I said,
third best.
Just keep
your fucking mouth shut.
In fact, why don't you
start practicing right now?
See these eyes so green
I can stare
for a thousand years
Colder than the moon
It's been so long
And I've been
putting out fire
With gasoline
See these eyes so red
Red like jungle
burning bright
Those who feel me near
Pull the blinds
and change their minds
It's been so long
Still this pulsing night
A plague I call
a heartbeat
Yes.
See these tears so blue
An ageless heart
that can never mend
Tears can never dry
A judgment made
can never bend
See these eyes so green
I can stare
for a thousand years
Just be still with me
You wouldn't believe
what I've been through
You've been so long
Well, it's been
so long
And I've been putting out
the fire with gasoline
Putting out fire
With gasoline
Been so long
Well, it's been so long
I've been
putting out fire
Been so long
Well, it's been so long
Mm.
Gorlomi?
Gorla...
Lomi?
Gorlomi.
Antonio Margheriti.
Hmm.
Margheriti.
Margheriti...
Dominick Decocco.
Bravo!
Bravo.
Arrivederci.
Arrivederci
Scusi,
scusi.
Pardon,
pardon.
Salute.
Voil.
What's that
American expression?
If the shoe fits,
you must wear it.
Who's that?
Shit!
Fucking shithead
fascist fuck!
Fuck you!
Ge... fascist
shithead fuck!
Fuck you, too!
Fuck!
Goddamn Nazi fucks!
Sons of bitches!
Get your hands off me!
Fuckin' bratwurst-smelling...
God damn you!
Get off!
Hmm.
You Jerry-bangin',
Lindbergh-smellin'...
As Stanley said
to Livingstone,
Lieutenant Aldo Raine,
I presume?
Hans Landa.
You've had a nice,
long run, Aldo.
Alas, you're now in
the hands of the SS.
My hands,
to be exact.
And they've been
waiting a long time
to touch you.
Caught you flinching.
Touch me again,
Kraut-burger.
- Utivich?
- Is that you, Lieutenant?
Yeah.
Do you know what
happened to Donnie?
Omar?
The woman?
No, I do not.
Tell me, Aldo,
if I were sitting
where you're sitting,
would you show me
mercy?
Nope.
What is that English
expression about shoes and feet?
Looks like the shoe's
on the other foot.
Yeah, I was just
thinking that.
So, you're Aldo
the Apache.
So, you're
the Jew Hunter.
I'm a detective.
A damn good detective.
Finding people
is my specialty,
so naturally I worked for
the Nazis finding people
and, yes,
some of them were Jews,
but Jew Hunter?
Just a name
that stuck.
Well, you do have
to admit, it is catchy.
Do you control the nicknames
your enemies bestow on you?
Aldo the Apache
and the Little Man?
What do you mean
the Little Man?
Germans' nickname
for you.
The Germans' nickname
for me is the Little Man?
And as if
to make my point,
I'm a little surprised how
tall you are in real life.
You're a little fellow,
but not
circus-midget little,
as your reputation suggests.
Where's my men?
Where's
Bridget von Hammersmark?
Well, let's just say
she got
what she deserved.
And when you purchase friends
like Bridget von Hammersmark,
you get what
you pay for.
Now, as far as
your paisanos,
Sergeant Donowitz
and Private Omar...
How you know
our names?
Lieutenant Aldo...
if you don't think
I wouldn't interrogate
every single one of your
swastika-marked survivors...
We simply
aren't operating
on the level of mutual
respect I assumed.
No, I guess not.
Well...
back to the whereabouts
of your two Italian saboteurs.
As of this moment,
both Omar and Donowitz
should be sitting in the
very seats we left them in.
0023 and 0024,
if my memory serves,
explosives still
around their ankles,
still ready
to explode,
and your mission...
Some would call it
terrorist plot...
As of this moment
is still a go.
That's a pretty exciting
story. What's next?
"Eliza on Ice"?
However...
all I have to do
is pick up this phone
right here,
inform the cinema,
and your plan's kaput.
If they're
still here...
and if they're
still alive,
and that's
one big if.
There ain't no way you're
gonna take them boys
without setting off
them bombs.
I have no doubt.
And, yes,
some Germans will die
and, yes, it will
ruin the evening,
and, yes,
Goebbels will be
very, very,
very mad at you
for what you've done
to his big night,
but you won't get Hitler,
you won't get Goebbels,
you won't get Goring,
and you won't get Bormann.
And you need all four
to end the war.
But if I don't pick up
this phone right here,
you may very well
get all four.
And if you get
all four,
you end the war...
tonight.
So, gentlemen,
let's discuss
the prospect
of ending the war tonight.
So, the way
I see it,
since Hitler's death
or possible rescue
rests solely
on my reaction,
if I do nothing,
it's as if I'm causing his death
even more than yourselves,
wouldn't you agree?
I guess so.
How about you,
Utivich?
I guess so, too.
Gentlemen,
I have no intention
of killing Hitler
and killing Goebbels
and killing Goring
and killing Bormann,
not to mention winning the
war single-handedly for the Allies
only later to find myself
standing before a Jewish tribunal.
If you want to
win the war tonight...
we have to
make a deal.
What kind
of deal?
The kind you wouldn't
have the authority to make.
However, I'm sure
this mission of yours
has a commanding officer.
A general.
Mm, I'm betting for...
OSS would be my guess.
Oooh!
That's a bingo!
Is that the way you
say it? "That's a bingo"?
You just say
"bingo".
Bingo!
How fun!
But I digress.
Where were we?
Ja, make a deal.
Over there is a very
capable two-way radio,
and sitting behind it is a more
than capable radio operator
named... Hermann.
Get me someone on the other end
of that radio with the power of the pen
to authorize my...
let's call it the terms
of my conditional surrender.
If that tastes better
going down.
You know,
where I'm from...
Yeah, where is that
exactly?
Maynardville,
Tennessee.
I've done my share
of bootlegging.
Up there, if you engage in what the
federal government calls illegal activity
but what we call just a man
trying to make a living for his family
selling
moonshine liquor,
it behooves oneself
to keep his wits.
Long story short,
we hear a story
too good to be true...
it ain't.
Sitting in your chair,
I would probably
say the same thing.
And 999.999 times
out of a million,
you would be correct.
But in the pages
of history,
every once in a while,
fate reaches out
and extends its hand.
What shall
the history books read?
I implore you,
we must destroy
that tower!
Sergeant,
that tower...
Psst!
Scusi.
Pardon.
Scusi, scusi.
Scusi!
Pardon.
Scusi.
So, when the military history
of this night is written,
it will be recorded that
I was part of Operation Kino
from the very beginning
as a double agent.
Anything I've done
in my guise as an SS colonel
was sanctioned by the OSS
as a necessary evil
to establish my cover
with the Germans,
and it was my placement
of Lieutenant Raine's dynamite
in Hitler and Goebbels'
opera box
that assured their demise.
By the way, that last
part's actually true.
I want my full military
pension and benefits
under my proper rank.
I want to receive the
Congressional Medal of Honor
for my
invaluable assistance
in the toppling
of the Third Reich.
In fact, I want all the
members of Operation Kino
to receive the Congressional
Medal of Honor.
Full citizenship
for myself...
Well, that goes
without saying...
And I would like
the United States of America
to purchase property for me
on Nantucket Island
as a reward for all the
countless lives I've saved
by bringing the tyranny of
the National Socialist Party
to a swifter
than imagined end.
Do you have
all that, sir?
I look forward
to seeing you face
to face, as well, sir.
Lieutenant Raine?
Right here.
Yes, sir?
Colonel Landa will put you
and Private Utivich
in a truck as prisoners.
Then he and his radio operator
will get in the truck
and drive to our lines.
Upon crossing our lines,
Colonel Landa and his men
will surrender to you.
You will then take over
driving of the truck
and bring them straight
to me for debriefing.
- Is that clear, Lieutenant?
- Yes, sir.
Over and out.
When I kill that guy, you got
30 feet to get to that guard.
- Can you do it?
- I have to.
Champagne?
Who wants to send
a message to Germany?
I have a message
for Germany.
That you are all
going to die.
And I want you to look
deep into the face
of the Jew
who is going to do it.
Marcel,
burn it down.
Oui, Shosanna.
My name is
Shosanna Dreyfus,
and this is
the face...
of Jewish vengeance.
Hermann, uncuff them.
I'm officially
surrendering myself
over to you,
Lieutenant Raine.
We're
your prisoners.
How about my knife?
Thank you very much, Colonel.
Utivich, cuff the colonel's
hands behind his back.
Aww, is that
really necessary?
I'm a slave
to appearances.
Scalp Hermann.
Are you mad?
What have you done?
I made a deal with your
general for that man's life!
Yeah, they made
that deal,
but they don't give
a fuck about him.
- They need you.
- You'll be shot for this!
No, I don't think so.
More like chewed out.
I've been
chewed out before.
You know, Utivich
and myself heard
that deal you made
with the brass.
End the war tonight?
I'd make that deal.
How about you, Utivich?
You make that deal?
I'd make that deal.
I don't blame you.
Damn good deal.
And that pretty little nest
you feathered for yourself.
Well, if you're willing to
barbecue the whole high command,
I suppose that's worth
certain considerations.
But I do have
one question.
When you get to your little
place on Nantucket Island,
I imagine you're
gonna take off
that handsome-looking
SS uniform of yours,
ain't you?
That's what I thought.
Now, that
I can't abide.
How about you, Utivich?
Can you abide it?
Not one damn bit, sir.
I mean,
if I had my way,
you'd wear
that goddamn uniform
for the rest of
your pecker-sucking life.
But I'm aware
that ain't practical.
I mean, at some point,
you're gonna have to take it off.
So I'm gonna give you a little
something you can't take off.
You know something,
Utivich?
I think this might
just be my masterpiece.