in the morning
So early?
Ye Master, I
You do not recognize me?
Dragons
You teach a child find effort
You told me to grow up and then come
I am here today to formally apprentice
Why should I take you today as Christians do?
Because I will be your most powerful apprentice
Why do you think so?
Because I'm fast enough
How fast?
Not fast enough, young
You can then fast?
Quite fast
But you think that kicked water?
Or kick less than those of water?
Aircraft Lam, cool throat aircraft Lam
Come to someone fighting
Beat him! Beat him!
Come
Wing Chun, Zhang Feng
Wing Chun, Yeh
Stop, do not fight
I've told you not to fight
Will certainly be punished, this time you miserable
Strip the first shell, egg yolk and then out
Why should we put into the ring?
Old people said to go put some silverware
Such valid Quyu
Yes, why they fight today?
Who is the best fight they fight
It's my fault, not optimistic
They were so hurt like this
Ah Zheng we are not good, so naughty
Yes, the parents of the children has yet to be how?
Zhang Feng, he is a new school
Sometimes his father would come to pick him up later this
Zhang Feng, what your father do?
He usually busy?
Pull carts
Sorry, sorry
Huang, embarrassed leaf Master
Because I have something to do martial arts
So late
let me see
Ah Zheng, what happened?
In fact, two children are wrong
So first I would like to ask the parents to find out
For the parents of the children come?
Because I want him to apologize
He told you the same as late
Late it does not matter, work matters
Can not eat
You can not eat down
Children are hungry
Better to this treatment, Huang
I let the children to my house for dinner
Could you inform parents of children
good or not? it is good
Okay, Yongcheng?
it is good
Zhang Feng, to aunt house for dinner, okay?
Come, take the bag
Slowly go back, let's go
Thank you
Thank you, Master leaves you in trouble
Thank you, goodbye Ip
Goodbye
Zhang Feng, eat more, do not be shy
Eat, Zhang Feng
You're welcome, eat
Eat more
His wife, the fish is very fresh today
Zhang Feng
Played well
Who taught you this?
My dad taught, you understand?
a little bit
My father is Zhang Feng
Will my son is not in this wrap?
Yes, here
You're Zhang
Come in, come in
Zhang Feng, your father came
Master
apprentice
what did you do today?
Two children, in school today naughty fight
Children will slowly teach
Positive, come
apprentice
Not with an apology?
A Zheng are wrong
Yeh, I'm sorry
Zhang Feng, sorry
Two people shake hands
The future is a good friend
Could you take a trip up
Sorry, Mr. Zhang
Ye Master, Nice to meet you
I just hit the wooden dummy see Zhang Feng
Played well, well taught
Chaos teach it
You never early
Will not be disturbing
I see you off
Master
Ye Shushu home has wooden dummy
do you know him?
understanding
Yeshu Shu He was known
But one day
Master will be more famous than he
Then the master told Yeshu Shu
Who effort is more powerful?
What do you think?
Of course, is more powerful master
go
Let me see, eyes still hurt?
Do not hurt
About to begin
Come, come
What to buy?
I just want developed a good bet
Following one
Buy pay much much more
Step aside! Do not get in the way!
Zhang Tian Chi, Zhang Tian Chi
You a few right?
Come on, come
Sheng brother, Sheng brother
What boss?
The boss
Promising young
go
Hard point, then quickly
boss
come on
Here, I better come back soon
boss
do not worry
I have managed this, there is no problem
The two-week money
Open it good
You did very well
Thanks for another case of how the business case?
school?
No problem, give me a month
No, two weeks
How could
Well, I love the challenge
promise you
Remember, school is very important
Solve it undo all our efforts
Yes, I understand
What is Kung Fu?
Wing Chun
Very powerful
We'll be here all day martial arts together
Drink tea and chat
Different schools in which reserved a table
Master Tian
Master Chen Tian He young and promising master
There are a lot of students of Master Chen
Master Chen
This station on the powerful
This station is part of the master of masters
This is my station
Master Tian
joke
A real master in this table
This station is Wing Chun
Master Tian
Ali, you master it?
One that went to
Ye Master
Field Master, eaten yet?
No, so you treat
anytime
I do not introduce it? Ye Master
Master leaves, hello, hello small, surnamed Li, hello
Li Sheng hello
He is a newspaper reporter, very heart
We wanted to make a martial arts Interview
Also a group photo shoot
Well can you? Ye master?
Thank you, of course
Master Li do not mention it, you sit here really polite
Ye ask, you sit in the middle is not good, not good
You sit in the middle must be really bad
Sit down, you take the middle course
Ye Master, please answer the phone
I listen to the phone, do not argue with you
Good, good
Help you placeholder
You are sitting in the middle of the
Hey?
Today, you forget about me?
Fourth is not it?
Thursday
Thursday…
I immediately came
I have been waiting for you for an hour
Waiting for you to come, I dance through
You do not come
You pick up A Zheng school
Accident
Ye Master, come here!
This bit is your middle
I really polite, of course not polite
Mental point, looked at here, thank you
preparation
one two Three
Ye Master
Why hello to you today is to pick up the children?
Your wife did not come?
Her busy busy today
Then you teach boxing busy it?
sometimes
Leaves Father, why more and more young?
Ip soup because enough moisture
Yes, this is very important
You two in-laws really happy, which, as I
Ye Master
Mr. Zhang
Hello
The children from? Yes
correct
This active oil bottle, blood stasis
Tell your son with
Thank you, so kind
Feng Tsai nothing, right?
He did not do
That's good
Ye Master
I heard that your Wing Chun
Huashun is modeled after, right?
Correct
That we are the same door
We are gong Foshan Mr. Chan
That we can be regarded as a fellow with the door
Master told me
Huashun master boxing, stick
Than the sword, powerful legs
really?
Each master will be the length of each
Normal
That leaves the master, How about you?
I know everything that every kind
There is a chance
We learn about
Get more days to go
goodbye teacher!
Be careful, walking
Master
apprentice
Today at school what?
Mathematics
Chinese English
I learned so many things?
You naughty or nice? Should not the other
be good
Have you ever read primary school?
No
principal
A gentlemen looking for you
Will anything at all?
Hello sidelined
What do you do? Sit down, do not move
Do not tamper with what is good-looking?
Do not be so noisy you? Fatty
How do I talk so noisy?
Sorry, principals, you scared
what's up? First sit down
Let the open, get out
do not be afraid
You are reading, I also gentle people
We are saying the truth
Where is the need to develop
You sold me to school
They are very reasonable
This school is not for sale
You have not see that he did not sell?
You look at
Not sell
Reading people really troublesome
I do not obey
Be careful, boss
What do you do?
They forced me to sell him to school
That I do not know kung fu?
Ye ask, What is the relationship with you? I do business only
Mind your own business, Qi brother
Hello, here is the primary Zjiren
Could you send a few police immediately
There are rogue in this trouble
Freeze boss let me go
Let go of my boss, can not hear it?
I will kill her
Let go of my brother, hurry put up!
Still hold? put!
Do not worry, said slowly
Describe the incident today
Three people rushed
Staff room down everything
Ye Master, now Hong Kong is only superficial prosperity
In fact, very confusing
Instead, the more people the better economic offenders
You know my folks, to see his wife as monocular guy
A reading
Frankly speaking, we have only so many people
Gas also went every day cough
Hong Kong is now law and order is getting worse
As there is no imperial law
Have! We are imperial law
When our police
Someone must deal with the police
Stolen goods and arrested some people
The bad guys will not let lawlessness
Right, right
The neighbors would take the trouble to you, wave officer
You're welcome, it should be
However, the master leaves
You should understand
The police is not possible here to monitor twenty-four hours
So you have to help
Told neighbors careful
What will matter immediately to the police, do not wrong
I immediately rushed over, okay? it is good! sorry to bother you
You're welcome, receive income team
Slow go first
Goodbye
Ip Man
My enemy
I slowly play with you
Williams
Sheng brother
Help me tonight primary closure
do not worry
No thing
Certainly not something
Please be assured that parents
School classes as usual
principal
Huang
Ye Master
What happened?
I came back is already the case
Teachers who want to dismantle the school?
Our kids can not go to school, how do?
Dad, open the door
Let me help you
You are also very strength
Certainly no effort to thin it?
Also said
I am not often so strong powerful
I Jiaoxu force
They call me Huang
Need help, find me
come in
Morning, her mother
Principal morning
Huang morning
Morning, slowly row
Master
go
They will definitely come back again
Then you stay here tonight
it is good
I had to stay here tonight
Huang, a coincidence? After school?
It is that you can I do?
It's nothing
I would like to ask you have a boyfriend
No
That's good
Have you ever thought to find a boyfriend?
I never thought
Do not misunderstand, the night
You are a person to go home, I'm afraid you have danger
Feel embarrassed
Ye Master
Is Huang
Today is trouble you
you are welcome
My apprentice has not harass you?
No! Master
No
He's just a good thought to send me home
Absolutely, Master
So you might as kindly sent me home
it is good
The original master to send home tonight
Yeah, almost
it is good
Ye Master! I am very grateful you
You go back to rest early
Never mind
Yes, today should be all right
Hey
Start work
You go over there
Help, leaves the master! Take him away
Help
Huang protection
You can also do?
can! But not necessarily be able to send you home
Up
it is good
Help
Away
Brothers, we go
Brother, all the checks good, the fire has been extinguished
Look, do not leave the fire
it is good
You go over there to take another look good
Master
Fire has Quanmie
But a lot of tables and chairs were burned
Principal, principal
You did not do for you?
I did not do
But the bad guys will not think so rampant
Fortunately, the master and his apprentice leaf present
Fortunately, there is something from the master leaves, thank you
Mr. Zhang
Fortunately, you just have to help
I just go through
Just finally personally experience to master Wing Chun Ye
Deserved reputation
In name only
Not anything
I will go back to work
Goodbye
Neighbors wanted me to stay
Community guards
Arson, police nothing?
Tube, how can it matter?
But Po say quickly deal
We have no reason not to believe Po
It can
But the police can not stay twenty-four hours, right?
and so
Next two days
I should come back later
That also do not cook you dinner?
cook
Do not cook what I eat?
Really you can not do without you?
No
But as many as they can help it
bright
So could you help me turn off the light bar
Sorry, sorry
Arrived late for dinner
Come, come to see
Come, look around
This is good feng shui shop
Wang in a quiet
Walls are dirty point
But very clean and tidy under the
apprentice
Here open martial arts master
Then you receive a lot of boxing together with apprentice
Okay?
it is good! I can here later
Boxing here and here
I ask here how much monthly?
One hundred eighty yuan, including hydropower
Then I think about it first, thank you
Prices can be negotiated substandard
So you pull carts
Pull the shop to see what the car?
What martial arts open
Waste my time boss, go?
Return home
Mixed Kyrgyzstan
Police officers, which were last night Zjiren primary case of arson
You see, there is no problem
After the signature, I immediately follow
Is this case you do not control, I personally
Police officers, do not, and this is just a small case
You do not take the trouble, officer
Po must pay more than peace of mind, okay?
You do not understand Chinese?
Investigation of the case of schools
I will personally handle
Because I'm the person in charge here
So please get out
roll
Out
That police officers
what are you doing?
Blind to see someone?
What is the relationship with you? This street is you decide it?
Neuropathy
I just wish you would come back down?
Brothers
Thank you
This morning when I went to buy breakfast
Heard many people say
We are the community manager
Now you just said, do not bother
Master does not care about these gossip
Who said that?
Many people say
Recognize the look?
Mantis?
I ask what you want?
Boss, I often have some recent abdominal pain
Is there any pain medication?
Have
Wujibaifeng
Help qi and blood circulation
Well, I want one
Ip feed
Why happened Tian Master, please sit down
Not such a big thing to tell me?
Sit, sit first
I hear people say in the restaurant
Are you doing here Security
How can this be?
It must be the brats do bad things
Cup of tea
My life is the most wrong Ah Sheng received this apprentice
He learned of my effort went around evil
Full of wicked thing
It degrading door division
look
How do I tell you this?
But I tell you
My apprentice I will teach myself
I immediately went to him
Master Tian
Field Master, you do not impulse
Uncle, come back with your operator
Master Tian
Po a letter
Po will be too late to deal with
Of course, we deal with their own
That will give me face brats
He is no longer that you've disciples
Although he left the door my teacher
But one day as a teacher, father
Rest assured, no matter
Stop, what happened?
I came to Ma Sheng whale
I was his master and told him to come out
Wave officers
Ali, in which your teacher?
He just left the master with Tian
Master Tian just very angry
I do not know why?
Tian master?
You want what?
how?
Ye Master
I gather the old tea master, you control everything?
Master
Sheng
Master has nothing to do with the leaves
I want to come to you
You do not do so many bad things
Do not harass neighbors, your friends close hand
I always teach you
Man to be aboveboard
You look at yourself
You see what you count now?
You earn Jigexiuqian, followed by dozens of people
Do you think now very imposing it?
You try something, they do not give money
Will they follow you?
They are in front of you
Will respect you
Behind you
You say you are lackeys of foreigners
what happened? I want to play?
I lackeys, so what?
I am a lackey, but I earn money
Make money is king
Do the same with you?
Be a beast master, Zimingqinggao
Holding a rotten day cover, worry worry meter firewood
That's good right?
Begging at the gates, what a lofty?
You ask yourself
Have you ever taught apprentice, who still remember you?
Does anyone still care about you?
Your former apprentice
I'm here at all
Brats
Brats, knife?
Brats! You want to kill me?
Wring my hands to see whether you can go out alive
People come back to me
Let him do not talk to me
Give me
Brothers, we on
Come, come
Kuaifang Kai Sheng brother
Release Sheng brother
Police stop hand
Back, back
Forward
Stand back
Who Moved, I'll shoot anyone
what's the situation? Make fun of me?
Out
what did you say?
You do not put a policeman in the eye?
Do you know what is this place?
You point a gun at me? Are you crazy?
How do you account with your boss?
You are so arrogant I arrest you first
Then the seizure of all your site
I want to know how you talk to your boss accountable
you do not believe?
Come on, Shi Hu ghost
Now what are you going to school how to deal with?
Ma Sheng whale bought my boss's boss
Two foreigners and mutual benefit
Close the door Ghost Talk
No way, a certain school can not be protected
Po, I believe you
Because I think you're different from other policemen
Now you're one to talk because foreigners
What you will not care?
Not whether it is unable to manage
So you do not arrest people they arson
So you are no longer protected and neighborhood kids
Now my apprentice
We are doing what you should do
So what?
Leaves you master it can play, but you are not immortal
Can not change the world
You keep vigil day at school what is the use?
How long can?
Hong Kong is the place where you knew the rule of foreigners
Society is not fair
But the moral equality before should
The times for the emperor, not too expensive
Every man is poor, not too cheap
This is not a rich man's world
Nor the right people in the world.
But caring people in the world.
Have you thought about for kids?
Everything we do
Children are seen
We should be ready example for children
Everything we do
Not for immediate
For the future
Mrs. Ye, a preliminary examination
I suspect you have a tumor in vivo
The situation is not optimistic
However, details
To wait for the report to determine
Now do not worry too much
Ye Master
Master leaves, leaf Master
You've worked hard
Ye Master, this is all chipped in for peanut chicken feet soup pot
Very nutritious too kind
Recently you stay here day and night
Not the lack of soup
Your disciples do?
They all drink together
Thank you, thank
You have told me bet
Just do not listen to me, chosen to buy red
Very powerful, but also win
what happened? Playing so frequent
Need money?
Only breadwinner
I have to feed their families
Last time I work at school
You wounded my brother
I did not count with you
What do you want calculate?
Do not count
I appreciate you
I want to be your friend
Sheng brother, what do you mean?
I mean
I was offended
I am very unhappy
Help me to buy from him a hand
In fact, you have so many brothers
Why must find me?
Because he knows kung fu
And you know kung fu
You can play very
If I do not want?
That one place to another begging you
Blue do? Bring it
Money do? Bring it
Sheng brother
Table money
I totally want to
You have to keep to what time?
Woke up?
I do not want to wake you up
Then keep it more than a few days
Which when you come home for dinner?
tonight
Tonight I come back
Okay?
its…
Hey, is not Mr Yip?
Yes, who?
This is the Kowloon Hospital
Is anything at all?
Mr. Tian Aoshan seriously injured sent hospitalized
He'd like to see you
Well, I'll come
Mr Yip informed
thank you
action
Well done
Play it
Fortunately, this time just a hand injury
Otherwise, the big thing
Thank you
I know I hit Ah Sheng sent
I really fail this master
Buy this
Well, buy this
Children
My car wrapped in a cartoon slide
Want to see it?
Free
Come, come, come
Hey
Quick, brisk walking you do?
Help, help save me
Hey
Took
What do you do?
Take your time to save me
Two hours
I called the principal to find shipyard
Otherwise, I will sell all the kids go to Southeast Asia
How do you know I'm in the hospital?
You give me a call Trustee
No
No?
Wife, master it?
what's up?
What happened exactly?
Ye Master
what's up? Huang
Ah Zheng, Feng Tsai and several children were captured bad guys
what?
They say principals see within two hours
The children will be sold to Southeast Asia
You immediately to the principal
Police then notify wave
it is good
I want you to take the principals come to you with a bamboo
Principals do?
Principals are coming
Put children first
Okay?
Daddy, Daddy
be quiet
Son, do not be afraid
Father
Originally, I caught your son?
Really lucky, is the fear catch him
Let him out
Goody
Shut up
Sven point
Children come
Sheng brother
Nothing to do with children
Do not make life difficult for him, okay?
Why should I make life difficult for him
I just want him to eat apples
Do not be afraid, uncle you eat apples
but
Bring your dad put down bamboo
Just talk to me
Ah Zheng, do not be afraid
The bamboo down
We give points
Kneel
kowtow
Ye master?
Hey
Are you doing here?
Today there is no boxing match
You caught my son
Dad, Master
Come and save me
Fung
I caught your son?
Sorry, our own people, let him go
Fortunately, in my hands
Fall on the hands of others in trouble
All right, let's go
Ip Man
Do you really play?
A dozen ten
Today, do not say I did not give you a chance
A ten strokes
One
If you hit a punch
I invited him to eat an apple
Master, my classmates still inside
Why did you come back?
I'll pick the children from school
Chigiriototo
Away
This side
on
Do not come over, I'll kill him
Daddy, Daddy
Bite him
Outrageous
go
Hearing children caught
Over there, hurry up
father
Daddy, Daddy
Williams still standing you doing?
The child catch up
father
Squat, do not move
Squat
do not move
Hear it? I'm not with them a group of
Do not move, do not move all
Police, do not move
All Do not move
Slowly beat you
do not move
Go over there, a lot of people
Multi-point shot to make information materials
Tomorrow was brilliant headlines
One Less
You do not understand it? I told you not to move
mom
A Zheng
School has just had an accident
A Zheng was arrested bad guys
Sorry, Yongcheng
I was wrong
Will not happen again in the future
Okay?
To wash
it is good
be good
All my fault
do not Cry
Husband, I'm scared
never mind
I may have something
what's up?
The doctor said
I might have
Has cancer
Black place has proven to be cancer cells in vivo
That is a tumor
Since the spread of the tumor is too large
We have no way to help Ip surgery
There may be doctors, okay?
Normally we would use drugs
But at this stage
I am afraid that is difficult to control the drug had
Doctor, I have much time?
About six months
I can help you add rice
Well bowl
Do not worry, you're safe
The police are to help you
But if on the emergence of a daily newspaper
Abduction of children
Destruction of homes News
My boss will be very unhappy
My boss happy
I will be unhappy
and so
during this time
All illegal, unfair things
That is what you are now involved
You must also stop
otherwise…
(Wing Chun Yip help police save lives children)
Fei Lanqi
I can not protect you
Listen to what you say
Yes
Fei Lanqi
The dialogue with you very happy
Goodbye
boss
The Thai people are very powerful
Elbows, knees, punches are strong
Formidable
Lifted
I was wrong, boss
I would not think so, I just want to intimidate principal
I also did not expect such a serious
Ye ask, because he
I am sorry
I do not want to see you later
Get out
Ip Man
Solve his
go
Anything to drink?
I want to tell you that the school's case has ended
There should be no problem, you can rest assured
but
Foreigners very treacherous, capricious
A Sheng boss only for you a
You be careful
very smart
Mom, you look
You want to fight me, I'm coming
what do you want?
You are Ip Man?
You can play the most is the Chinese people?
interesting
Well, we deal
I heard that Wing Chun fist is the fastest
But not fast breaking
We look at the contest to see who punches faster
It's you?
still me?
three minutes
If you can still standing
I miss you
Baby, are you okay?
I want to get back balloon
Let it be, do not worry
Buy a new to you, okay?
A new balloon
Boss
I want to rent here
You already said Takayuki phase is greatly enriched
I wish you business is booming, rolling in money
Well, I can learn here after the Wing Chun
Master, please
please
Elegant, so you are also taught Wing Chun it?
Then you must know Yip Man
You see, today's newspaper
Yip Man on newspaper
You see him more power and prestige
Wing Chun is to teach you the same, certainly familiar
If you know, please tell me
Give you the keys, I go first
I know next time introduced to
This story is not what you write?
Yes
I called Zhang Heaven
I always Wing Chun
Can you all help me write a story?
I've seen Ip Man's kung fu
His Wing Chun is not authentic
I would like to publicly challenge him
Leaf Wing Chun Master
Different schools early in the morning to give recognition
Well, even if I can help you write
But I do not know martial arts would deny the same
Master your Wing Chun Zhang qualify
You can master it leaves open challenge?
Sit down, Master
Did you bring a camera?
Today, tea is good
Wing Chun Zhang Heaven, and you want to learn about
Why do you?
Now I qualify it?
Have
Zhang master came
Congratulations, Master Zhang
Looked at here, thank you
Huang boss, Thanks for your support
I most admire you so strive martial artist
Later there any need, even though I told
Thank you
Master Zhang
You have been constantly challenge the martial art
Also let reporters to take pictures
What are we afraid of gossip it?
I know many people think
Everywhere I go I challenge the major sects
Too high-profile
But the effort
It is supposed to compete
And I tell you
Ip Man
Not on behalf of Wing Chun
Everybody
I now declare
I want to publicly challenge Ip Man
Extra, extra
Wing Chun Wing Chun Doo
Come and buy gave me a copy
Wife, this is very interesting
A day saying Mao tea with friends
But everyone also said with a sigh
We are each a henpecked
Do not believe me?
Who henpecked, to sit side
Everyone head down to sit on one side
A Mao only other station
Then everyone said,
A Mao really powerful, not henpecked
What do you say guess what Ah Mau? A Mao said
Yes, my wife said,
Many people do not take place in the past
This funny?
That you do not fear henpecked?
sometimes
Next person
Zhang Yongcheng, is not it?
Why did God want women beautiful and stupid it?
Because the woman doing pretty
Men will like
The woman doing stupid
Women like men only
Look, someone challenge leaf Master
What day? Next month the fifteenth
Hard point
Shoulder loose, fast punches
Zhang master, this table okay?
I want to sit that one
Excuse me
Ye Master, why do you come here?
I'm looking for Chen
Chen wanted to learn to dance?
Dancing is my strength
I'll teach you to dance
You teach me to play kung fu
Well, immediately
it is good
By the way, why the last time would not take me as a disciple?
Lay down your thoughts
I did not say do not charge you for the believers
I opened the door
Do you think I called you go
Thank you
welcome
Wing Chun Wing Chun fighting, struggle with the door authentic
Today is the big day of the contest authentic Wing Chun
People are waiting for this century Enter the Dragon
Yes, what Ip Man Wing Chun worse?
Or Zhang Tian Chi Wing Chun more violent it?
In the end who is the real authentic Wing Chun?
Three pm today
The contest will officially begin
We will wait and see
Wave of police officers, police officers wave
Big Brother Master Tian
Ali leaves master it?
Find him
Play what, where?
Lost?
Do not worry, we will not make Yip disappointed
To begin
Three o'clock, and leaves yet to master?
Time is up
Time is up, is yet to come
Hey, you master it?
Everybody
Today's contest is a three-time KO
Due to time-dependent failure to challenge Ip Man
I now officially announced
This time Wing Chun is authentic contest winner
Zhang Heaven
Daddy, Daddy
We won, we won
Traffic jam wait two hours, can not I?
who are you? We are the authentic
Zhang master, master leaves today to avoid war
What do you want to leave?
Wing Chun ancestors classical record
There is no way to change the sample recovery
Some should not be there
It should not appear
So as not to make the ancestors of regret
Later impaired
I am convinced that the leaves also understand this master
So he chose to abandon the war today
It can be regarded as meritorious
From today
I Zhang Heaven
Hoping authentic Wing Chun
Flourish
Good authentic Wing Chun
Hey, what do you say?
Why do you say that they are authentic?
You do not have qualifications than with my master
Calm, do not stop playing hand
Yongcheng, Yongcheng
Help me call an ambulance, thank you
Yep, your wife's situation is getting worse
Later these days, or stay in the hospital
how was it? Good point yet?
When can we go home?
Doctors say the best
Stay in hospital
Sleep a little longer
Four hundred seventy-three
Eighty-five original pair
To Zhang Feng
Transferred to his father
it is good
Nurses, nurse
Wife, what do you think?
Stomach pain do?
Do not worry, I'll get a doctor
Drink a bowl of chicken soup Tian
Good for your body
Husband
I came to talk to you photo
Recently, I accompany you every day
I was really happy
But not my happiest
I heard people say
Life is yours, nor is yours
I do not understand before
But these days, I began to understand
You are your own
In our family
Also belong here
Some things you should do
I do not want you because of me regrets
My only regret is that good enough for you
But I think
You have very good to me
If I do not get sick
You will not go to fight?
meeting
Ye ask me this is the most want to see
I'm sorry, my husband
I have to help you about him
I have not heard you play sound wooden dummy
Can you call me again?
Wing Chun
Zhang Heaven
Ip Man
Yeh, come with me good
I'm not defeated shameless person
Actually, the most important
Always people around you