The news never ends.
This is 1080 GCR.
You get all the news you need, all day long.
Good morning.
It's 42 degrees at 10:30 on this Thursday, October 15th.
I'm Stan L. Brooks, and here's what's happening.
It's day 18 of the garbage strike,
with 10,000 tons of garbage piling up every day.
Even the nicest sections of the city
are looking like slums.
Health Commissioner Edward O'Rourke is
declaring a city-wide state of emergency
for the first time in decades.
There's no need to wait until somebody dies
or comes down with typhoid fever.
It's already a serious situation.
It's something that affects
almost everyone in the city,
no matter who they are or where they live.
You can't go down no one avenue
without seeing nothing but garbage and rats.
It's starting to affect my business
when customers can't get in here
because of the garbage situation.
I'm not out that long to smell it,
but I think to look at it, it's terrible.
It don't affect me except
for the very bad smell here.
It's horrific.
It's a mess.
I've been in this country for 50 years,
and I've never seen anything like it.
What is this world coming to?
Put 'em in a room,
let 'em sit there and talk until they get it over with.
24 hours, 48 hours, how long it takes.
The idea of the National Guard moving in
and cleaning up is a good idea.
In other news,
the building industry and landlords today
expressed concern over the latest
increase in heating oil prices.
Renters in the metro area
are certain to feel the pinch...
Yo, what's up with your shoes, bro?
Nice outfit, pal.
If you're gonna be a clown, at least you could be
a good one. You know that, right?
- Hey! Hey! - Grab it!
Go, go, go!
Hey!
He's coming!
Come on, clown, let's go! We've got the sign.
- Look at him running. - Let's go!
Stop them!
Go, go, go, go! Watch the car, watch the car!
Where's your sign, clown?
Hey!
Go, clown! Come on!
Stop them!
Go! Come on!
Come on, run!
Hey!
You fucking...
Oh, shit! Good hit.
Come on! Beat his ass up.
Come on! This guy's weak. He can't do nothing.
Harder! Harder!
Beat him up. Take his stuff.
Let's go, let's go! Come on. Let's go!
Ha!
Is it just me,
or is it getting crazier out there?
- It is certainly tense. - Hmm.
People are upset.
They're struggling. Looking for work.
These are tough times.
How about you?
Have you been keeping up with your journal?
Yes, ma'am.
Great.
Did you bring it with you?
Arthur.
Last time, I asked you to bring your journal
with you for these appointments.
Can I see it?
I've been using it as a journal,
but also as a joke diary.
Funny thoughts or observations.
I think I told you
I'm pursuing a career in stand-up comedy.
No, you didn't.
I think I did.
"I just hope my death makes more sense than my life."
How does it feel to have to come here?
Does it help to have someone to talk to?
I think I felt better
when I was locked up in the hospital.
And have you thought more about
why you were locked up?
Who knows?
I was wondering if you could ask the doctor
to increase my medication.
Arthur, you're on seven different medications.
Surely, they must be doing something.
I just don't want to feel so bad anymore.
Subtitle www.movieddl.me
Would you please stop bothering my kid?
I wasn't bothering him. I was...
Just stop.
What? You think that's funny?
I'm sorry. I have a...
I'm sorry.
Happy, did you check the mail
before you came up?
Yeah, Mom.
Nothing.
And finally, tonight,
just when you thought it couldn't get any worse,
authorities are saying
the city is under siege by scores of rats.
And not just any rats,
but super rats, who are hard to kill.
He must not be getting my letters.
Yeah.
It's Thomas Wayne, Mom.
He's a busy man.
Please. I worked for that family for years.
The least he could do is write back.
Here. Don't get all worked up. Eat.
You need to eat.
You need to eat. Look how skinny you are.
Both victims were taken to Gotham General.
Sounds like
the city needs to find the Pied Piper.
He'll make a great mayor. Everybody says so.
Oh, yeah. Everybody who? Who do you talk to?
Well, everybody on the news.
He's the only one who could save the city.
He owes it to us.
Come sit. It's starting.
Yay, Murray.
From NCB Studios in Gotham City,
it's Live with Murray Franklin!
Tonight, Murray welcomes Sandra Winger...
Oh, Sandra Winger's on.
...and the piano stylings of Yeldon and Chantel.
Joining Murray, as always,
Ellis Drane and his jazz orchestra.
And now, without further ado,
Murray Franklin.
Thank you.
We got a great-looking audience tonight.
Yeah!
Wow. Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
So, everybody's heard about the super rats that
- are in Gotham now, right? - Yeah.
Well, today, the mayor said he has a solution.
You ready for this?
Super cats.
But in all seriousness, I mean, these rats are...
I love you, Murray!
I love you, too.
Hey, Bobby, would you put the lights on?
Who is that?
Was that you? You wanna stand up, please?
Stand up for me.
Go ahead.
What's your name?
Hi, Murray. Arthur.
- Arthur? - My name's Arthur.
Oh, okay. Well, there's something special about you,
Arthur, I could tell.
Where are you from?
I live right here in the city
with my mother.
Okay, hold on. Hold on.
There's nothing funny about that.
I lived with my mother before I made it. Just me and her.
I'm that kid whose father went out for a pack of cigarettes,
and he never came back.
Aww.
I know what that's like, Murray.
I've been the man of the house for as long as I can remember.
I take good care of my mother.
All that sacrifice, she must love you very much.
She does.
She always tells me to smile and put on a happy face.
She says I was put here to spread joy and laughter.
Aww.
Wow.
I like that. I like that a lot. Come on down.
Come on. For that, you gotta come down.
Come on! Come on.
Come on.
Okay, we got a big show tonight. Stay tuned.
We'll be right back.
That was great, Arthur. Thank you.
I mean, I loved hearing what you had to say.
It made my day.
Thanks, Murray.
You see all this, the lights, the show,
the audience, all that stuff?
I'd give it all up in a heartbeat
to have a kid like you.
- What's up, ladies? - Hey, Randall. What's up?
Another day in chuckle town.
Yup.
You okay?
I heard about the beatdown you took.
Fucking savages.
It was just a bunch of kids. I should have left it alone.
No.
They'll take everything from you if you do that.
All the crazy shit out there.
They're animals.
You know what?
Here.
What is it?
Take it.
It's for you.
You gotta protect yourself out there.
Otherwise, you're gonna get fucked.
Randall,
I'm not supposed to have a gun.
Don't sweat it, Art.
No one has to know.
And you can pay me back some other time.
You know you're my boy.
Arthur,
Hoyt wants to see you in his office.
Hey, Gary. You know what I've always wondered?
No idea.
Do you people call it miniature golf
or is it just golf to you?
Punch him in the dick, Gary.
Hello, Hoyt.
Gary said you wanted to see me.
How's the comedy career? Are you a famous stand-up yet?
Not quite.
Just been working on my material.
No, don't sit. This'll be quick.
Look, I like you, Arthur.
You know, a lot of the guys,
they think you're a freak, but I like you.
I don't even know why I like you.
But I got another complaint.
It's starting to piss me off. Kenny's Music.
The guy said you disappeared.
Never even returned his sign.
Because I got jumped.
Didn't you hear?
For a sign?
That's bullshit. It doesn't even make sense.
Just get him his sign back.
He's going out of business, for God's sake, Arthur.
Why would I keep his sign?
How the fuck do I know? Why does anybody do anything?
If you don't return the sign,
I gotta take it out of your paycheck.
Are we clear?
Listen, I'm trying to help you.
Okay? And I'll tell you something else.
The other guys,
they don't feel comfortable around you, Arthur,
because people think you're weird.
Okay? And I can't have that around me.
Wait, wait, wait.
Wait.
Thank you.
This building is so awful, isn't it?
This building is so awful, right, Mommy?
Yes, we can hear you, GiGi.
It's so awful, Mommy.
Right, Mommy?
- Good night. - This building's
- so awful, isn't it? - Mmm-hmm.
Hey.
Come on.
The moon is a silver dollar
Shining up in the sky
That's the dream we can buy...
- Look up. - Mmm.
Maybe the mailman's throwing them away.
Mom, why are these letters so important to you?
What do you think he's gonna do?
He's gonna help us.
But you worked for him, what, 30 years ago?
Why would he help us?
Because Thomas Wayne is a good man.
If he knew how we were living,
if he saw this place, it would make him sick.
I can't explain it to you any better than that.
I don't want you worrying about money, Mom.
Or me.
Everybody's telling me
that my stand-up's ready for the big clubs.
But, Happy, what makes you think you could do that?
- What do you mean? - I mean...
Don't you have to be funny to be a comedian?
Zoom, zoom, zoom, zoom
The world is in a mess
With politics and taxes And people grinding axes
There's no happiness
Happiness is not a riddle
When I'm listening to that Big bass fiddle
Slap that bass Slap it till its dizzy
Slap that bass Keep the rhythm busy
Zoom, zoom, zoom Misery, you've got to go...
Hey, what's your name?
Arthur.
Hey, Arthur, you're a really good dancer.
I know.
You know who's not? Him.
Happy, what was that? Are you okay?
Mom, what?
That noise! Did you hear that noise?
I'm watching an old war movie!
Turn it down!
Um...
Sorry, Mom.
You good?
It's nice to see these couples out at my show.
I have a wife. We love to role-play.
- Ooh! - Yes, yes, very sexy.
My favorite one right now is
professor and senior who really needs
to pass my class to graduate.
Yes.
So, I'll tell you how I operate.
I'm a professor at
a prestigious New England university...
...and my wife is a senior in my "intro To Western Civ."
I know. I know.
Why is she a senior in the intro? I didn't buy it either.
So, she comes to me during my office hours.
It's Monday and Wednesday, three to five.
She says, "Excuse me, Professor Lewis."
I can't use my real last name at this college
'cause they don't hire Jews.
It's something I'll address
once I have tenure, but for now...
She says, "Excuse me, Professor Lewis,
I think I might be in danger of failing
your 'intro to Western Civ,'
and I just want you to know
I'm willing to do anything to pass."
And I said, "Anything?" And she said...
- Oh, hey. - Hey.
Were you following me today?
Yeah.
I thought that was you.
I was hoping you'd come in and rob the place.
I have a gun.
I could come by tomorrow.
You're so funny, Arthur.
Yeah.
You know, I do stand-up comedy.
You should maybe come see a show sometime.
I could do that.
Yeah?
Yeah. You'll let me know when?
Yeah.
if you're happy and you know it
Wiggle your ears
If you're happy and you know it
And you really want to show it
Wiggle your ears
If you're happy and you know it
Stomp your feet
And you really want to show it
If you're happy and you know it
Stomp your feet
Shout "hurray"
If you're happy and you know it
And you really want to
Hoyt, please, I love this job.
Arthur, I need to know why
you brought a gun into a kids' hospital.
It's a prop. It's part of my act now.
That's bullshit. Bullshit.
What kind of clown carries a fucking gun?
Besides, Randall told me
you tried to buy a .38 off him last week.
Randall told you that?
You're a fuck-up, Arthur, and a liar.
You're fired!
Jefferson Street.
Next stop, Ninth Ave.
I'm telling you, she wanted my number.
We should've just stayed.
You're dreaming, man. She wasn't interested at all.
Are you nuts? Did you see how close we were dancing?
She was in love.
She couldn't wait to get away from you.
Ryan! Ryan, am I crazy? Tell him what you saw.
Hey, you want some French fries?
Hello?
Talking to you. Hey.
No, thank you.
You sure?
They're real good.
Don't ignore him. He's being nice to you.
Whoo...
Is something funny, asshole?
Bitch!
isn't it rich?
Are we a pair?
Me here at last on the ground
And you in mid-air
Send in the clowns
Isn't it bliss?
Don't you approve?
One who keeps tearing around
And one who can't move
Where are the clowns?
There ought to be clowns
So, buddy, tell us, what's so fucking funny?
Nothing.
I have... I have a condition.
I'll tell you what you have, you asshole.
Whoa!
Please, stop!
We got a kicker, huh?
Hey, hold him steady. Hold him steady.
Stay down, freak!
Hey!
Ninth Avenue.
Next stop, Hunter's Point.
Hey!
Stand clear of the closing doors.
Shit. Shit.
I read it was a guy in full makeup.
No, it says right here it was a mask.
Either way, I think it's good for business.
They got clowns on the front of every newspaper.
Big man, what's the good word?
Hey.
Hey, Arthur, I heard what happened.
Sorry, mate.
Yeah.
It doesn't seem fair,
getting fired like that.
Did you really bring a gun
to the children's hospital, Artie?
What the fuck would you do that for?
Is that part of your new act, Arthur?
If your dancing doesn't do the trick,
you're just gonna shoot yourself?
Why don't you ask Randall about it?
It was his gun.
- What? - I still owe you for that,
don't I?
What the fuck are you talking about?
Stop talking out of your ass, Art.
Oh, no!
I forgot to punch out.
And turns to sorrow
King of all Hear me call
Hear my name Carnival
And as our city tries to make sense
of the brutal triple murder on the subway last week,
we're joined by Thomas Wayne.
Happy, look, Thomas Wayne's on TV.
Yes, Mother.
Thanks for having me on, Chuck.
They're asking him about
those horrible subway murders.
Thank you, Thomas. I know
this is a difficult time for you.
Why him?
Looks like he's gained weight.
Yes, all three worked for Wayne Investments.
Good, decent, educated.
Although I didn't know any of them personally.
Like all Wayne employees,
past and present, they're family.
Did you hear that? I told you, we're family.
There now seems to be
a groundswell of anti-rich sentiment in the city.
It's almost as if our less fortunate residents
are taking the side of the killer.
Yes, and it's a shame.
It's one of the reasons why
I'm considering a run for mayor.
Gotham's lost its way.
What about the eyewitness report
of the suspect being a man in a clown mask?
Well, it makes total sense to me.
What kind of coward would do something that cold-blooded?
Someone who hides behind a mask.
Someone who is envious
of those more fortunate than themselves,
yet they're too scared to show their own face.
And until those kind of people change for the better,
those of us who have made something of our lives
will always look at those who haven't
as nothing but clowns.
Thomas Wayne, thank you for coming in this morning.
It's not funny.
I heard this song on the radio the other day,
and the guy was singing that his name was Carnival.
Arthur...
Which is crazy,
because that's my clown name at work.
And until a little while ago,
it was like nobody ever saw me.
Even I didn't know if I really existed.
Arthur, I have some bad news for you.
You don't listen, do you?
I don't think you ever really hear me.
You just ask the same questions every week.
"How's your job? Are you having any negative thoughts?"
All I have are negative thoughts,
but you don't listen anyway.
I said, for my whole life,
I didn't know if I even really existed.
But I do.
And people are starting to notice.
They've cut our funding.
We're closing down our offices next week.
The city has cut funding across the board.
Social Services is part of that.
This is the last time we'll be meeting.
Okay.
They don't give a shit about people like you, Arthur.
And they really don't give a shit
about people like me, either.
Fuck.
How am I supposed to get my medication now?
Who do I talk to?
I'm sorry, Arthur.
I think... I think most women look at sex like buying a car.
You know, like, "Can I see myself in this long-term?"
"Is it safe?"
"Is it reliable?"
"Could it kill me?"
Most guys, we look at sex like parking a car.
We're like, "There's a spot."
"There's another spot.
"That would work."
"Oh, I have to pay? Never mind."
"Handicapped? I hope no one sees this."
All right, that's my time. Thank you very much, guys.
One more time for Sam Morril, y'all.
All right, now, this next comic describes
himself as a lifelong Gotham resident
who from a young age was always told
that his purpose in life
was to bring laughter and joy into this cold, dark world.
Um... Okay.
Please help me welcome Arthur Fleck, y'all.
Arthur Fleck.
Hello, it's good to be here.
I hated school when I was a kid.
I hated school as a kid.
My mother would say,
"You should enjoy it.
One day, you'll have to work for a living."
"No, I won't, Ma,
I'm gonna be a comedian."
Um...
Here's one.
You know, I was just thinking the other day,
why are the rich people...
Smile though your heart is aching
Smile even though it's breaking
When there are clouds in the sky You'll get by
If you smile Through your fear and sorrow
Smile and maybe tomorrow
You'll see the sun Come shining through for you
You believe that shit?
Fuck 'em.
I think the guy that did it is a hero.
Three less pricks in Gotham City,
only a million more to go.
You'll get by
That's the time you must keep on trying
Smile, what's the use of crying
You'll find that Life is still worthwhile
If you just smile
And, buddy, as always,
thanks for the laughs.
I'm sure we'll see you again.
You know we'll be here, right?
I hope.
Tomorrow night, we have Diana Hudson, Greg Gordon,
and animal expert, Hugh Little.
Thanks for watching.
Good night, and always remember,
that's life.
That's life.
Momma, time to wake up and go to bed.
Hmm? Oh...
Oh, Happy.
Happy, I wrote a new letter.
Come on, dance with me.
For Thomas Wayne. It's important.
You smell like cologne.
It's 'cause I just had a big date.
Oh.
Just don't forget to mail it.
The Murray Franklin Show is taped live
before a studio audience
in beautiful downtown Gotham City.
You're gonna kill me. You're gonna give me a heart attack!
Don't give me your...
No. No.
I'm not talking to you until you stop being angry!
Okay.
I'm not angry, Mom.
I'm not angry.
Please.
Mom, is this real?
He's an extraordinary man, Happy.
He's a very powerful man.
We were in love.
He said it was best that we not be together
because of appearances.
And I could never tell anyone because...
Well, I signed some papers.
And besides, you can imagine
what people would say about Thomas and me.
What they'd say about you.
What would they say, Mom?
Hmm.
Hi.
What's your name?
I'm Bruce.
Bruce.
I'm Arthur.
That's better.
Bruce! Bruce!
Get away from that man.
It's okay. I'm a good guy.
What are you doing? Who are you?
I'm here to see Mr. Wayne.
Well, you shouldn't be speaking to his son.
Why did you give him these flowers?
No, they're not real.
It's magic.
I was just trying to make him smile.
Well, it's not funny, is it?
Do I need to call the police?
No. Please.
My mother's name is Penny. Penny Fleck.
She used to work here years ago.
Can you please tell Mr. Wayne I need to see him?
You are her son.
Yeah.
Did you know her?
I know about the two of them.
She told me everything.
There's nothing to know.
There is no "them."
Your mother was delusional.
She was a sick woman.
Don't say that.
Just go.
Mmm?
Before you make a fool of yourself.
Thomas Wayne is my father.
He left me.
Let go! Let go!
Keep the respirations above 15.
Slow and steady. We got some stairs coming up.
Mom?
What happened?
- Who are you? - I'm her son.
- What happened? - You can probably help us out inside.
We don't know what happened yet.
- Hop in the back of the ambulance. - Step.
One more. We got one more lift.
I'm getting
a little resistance here, Michael.
Lift.
I'm right here.
Excuse me, sir.
Does your mother take any medications?
- No. - Excuse me,
- I couldn't hear you. - No.
Sir, when was the last time you spoke to her?
I don't know.
Mr. Fleck.
Sorry to bother you. I'm Detective Garrity.
This is my partner, Detective Burke.
We had a few questions for you, but you weren't home,
so we spoke with your mother.
Oh.
What did you say to her?
Did you do this?
What? No.
No, no, no. We just asked her some questions,
and she got hysterical.
Hyperventilating,
collapsed and hit her head pretty hard.
Yeah. The doctor said she had a stroke.
We're sorry to hear about that.
But, like I said, I still have some questions for you.
They're about the subway killings
that happened last week.
You've heard about them, right?
Yeah.
It's horrible.
Right.
So, we spoke with your boss over at Haha's.
He said you were fired for bringing a gun
into the children's hospital.
- Is that true, Mr. Fleck? - It was a prop.
It's part of my act.
I'm a party clown.
All right. So, why were you fired?
They said I wasn't funny enough.
Can you imagine that?
If you don't mind, I have to go take care of my mother.
Your boss also gave us one of your cards.
This condition of yours, the laughing,
is it real,
or some sort of clown thing?
- A clown thing? - Yeah.
I mean, is it part of your act?
What do you think?
It's exit only.
She's gonna be okay.
I'm gonna get a coffee.
You want one?
Yeah.
So, the other night, I told my youngest son Billy,
you know, the new one, the not-so-bright one.
I told him, "The garbage strike
is still going on, Billy."
And he says, and I'm not kidding, Billy says,
"So, where are we gonna get all our garbage from?"
And finally, in a world where everyone
thinks they could do my job,
we got this video tape from Pogo's Comedy Club,
right here in Gotham.
Here's a guy who thinks if you just keep laughing,
it'll somehow make you funny.
Check out this joker.
Oh, my God.
I hated school as a kid.
But my mother would always say,
"You should enjoy it.
One day, you'll have to work for a living."
"No, I won't, Ma.
I'm gonna be a comedian."
You shoulda listened to your mother.
Hey, one more. One more, Bobby.
All right, let's see one more. I love this guy.
It's funny,
when I was a little boy
and told people I was gonna be a comedian,
everyone laughed at me.
Well, no one's laughing now.
You can say that again, pal.
All right, we got a great show for you tonight.
Chuck Conby is here, actress Joanne Mulligan,
and new music from Mel Rubin and the Stiffs.
As tensions mount around the metro area,
Mayor Stokes has pleaded for cooler heads to prevail.
City services have been affected,
and some businesses have decided
to remain closed amid the unrest.
Chuck Stevens filed this report.
The anger and resentment
that's been building in the city for weeks
seems close to exploding.
Protesters, many dressed as clowns,
took to the streets today
in one of several planned demonstrations
taking on the city's elite,
including a massive rally outside
tomorrow night's benefit at Wayne Hall.
What's the point of all this?
- the rich. - Thomas Wayne.
That's what this whole thing is about.
the whole system.
Wayne, who recently announced
he is running for mayor,
will be attending the benefit.
You might remember it was Thomas Wayne
who first referred to
many of Gotham's residents as "clowns."
Today, he offered little in the way of an apology.
Well, what I will say is,
there's something wrong with those people.
I am here to help them.
I'm gonna lift them out of poverty,
help make their lives better.
That is why I'm running.
And they may not realize it, but I'm their only hope.
Down with Wayne! Down with Wayne!
Can I help you, pal?
I don't know what to say.
Do you want an autograph or something?
No.
My name is Arthur.
Penny Fleck is my mother.
Jesus.
You're the guy that came to my house yesterday.
Yes.
I'm sorry I just showed up.
But my mother told me everything,
and I had to talk to you.
Look, pal, I'm not your father.
What's wrong with you?
Look at us.
I think you are.
Well, that's impossible
because you're adopted,
and I never slept with your mother.
- I wasn't adopted. - What do you want from me?
- Money? - No, I don't...
I wasn't adopted.
Jesus. She never told you?
Told me what?
Your mother adopted you while she was working for us.
That's not true.
Why are you saying that?
Then she was arrested and committed
to Arkham State Hospital,
when you were just a little boy.
Why are you saying this?
I don't need you to tell me lies.
I know it seems strange.
I don't mean to make you uncomfortable.
I don't know why everyone is so rude.
I don't know why you are.
I don't want anything from you.
Maybe a little bit of warmth, maybe a hug, Dad!
How about just a little bit of fucking decency?
What is it with you people?
You say that stuff about my mother.
She's crazy.
She's...
You think this is funny?
Dad, it's me. Come on.
Touch my son again,
I'll fucking kill you.
Hello, Mr. Fleck. This is Detective Garrity.
We met the other night at Gotham General.
My partner and I had a few more questions for you.
We stopped by your apartment today, but you weren't home.
Please give me a call when you get this message.
Again, Detective Garrity,
and my number is 212...99.
This message is for Arthur Fleck.
My name is Shirley Woods.
I work on The Murray Franklin Show.
I don't know if you're aware,
but Murray played a clip of your stand-up
on the show recently,
and we have gotten an amazing response from our viewers.
Murray asked me to give you a call and see if you're...
Who is this?
Oh, hi, this is Shirley Woods.
I'm the show booker from Live with Murray Franklin.
Is this Arthur?
Yes.
Hi, Arthur. Well, as I was saying,
we've gotten a lot of calls about your clip.
Amazing responses.
And Murray asked if I would reach out to you
to see if you would come on as his guest.
Murray wants me on The Murray Franklin Show?
Yeah. Isn't that great?
He'd love to talk to you, maybe do some of your act?
That sound good to you?
Yeah, that sounds great.
Can we set up a date right now?
Are you available next Thursday?
Hey.
Man, I'm sorry about that, my man.
All records 10 years or older, they store in the basement,
and you're talking about something 30 years ago, so...
Can I ask you a question?
Sure.
How does someone wind up in here?
Have they all, all the people committed crimes?
Well, yeah, some have.
You know, some are just crazy.
Pose dangers to themselves and others.
Some just got nowhere else to go.
Don't know what to do, you know?
- Yeah. I hear you, brother. - Hmm.
Sometimes, I don't know what to do.
Last time, I ended up taking it out on some people.
I thought it was gonna bother me, but it really hasn't.
What's that?
I fucked up and did some bad shit.
You know what I'm talking about,
it's so hard to just try and be happy all the time.
Hey, listen, man.
I'm just an administrative assistant.
Like a clerk, you know.
All I do is file paperwork.
I don't know what to tell you.
But you should see somebody.
You know, they got programs,
city services, stuff like that.
Oh, yeah.
They cut all those.
All right, here it is. Fleck.
Penny Fleck. Let's see.
Diagnosed by Dr. Benjamin Stoner.
Oh. "The patient suffers from delusional psychosis
and narcissistic personality disorder." Mmm.
"Was found guilty of endangering
the welfare of her own child."
What?
You said she's your mother.
Uh...
I'm sorry, man. Like I said, I can't release these records,
you know, without proper forms.
I could get in trouble.
Look, if you want to bring your mom in here to sign,
that'll be much easier,
but I can't let this go without her signature, okay?
I'm sorry.
No, man! Shit!
Come on, man. Give it...
Hey! Hey!
We went over this, Penny. You adopted him.
We have all the paperwork right here.
That's not true.
Thomas had that all made up,
so it stayed our secret.
You also stood by
while one of your boyfriends
repeatedly abused your adopted son
and battered you.
Penny,
your son was found tied to a radiator
in your filthy apartment.
Malnourished with multiple bruises across his body
and severe trauma to his head.
I never heard him cry.
He's always been such a happy little boy.
It's time for bed.
Oh, my God!
What are you doing in here?
You're in the wrong apartment.
Your name's Arthur, right?
You live down the hall.
I really need you to leave.
My little girl is sleeping in the other room.
Please.
I had a bad day.
Can I call someone? Is your mother home?
Shut up!
Hey, Penny.
Penny Fleck.
I always hated that name.
You know how you used to tell me
that my laugh was a condition?
That there was something wrong with me?
There isn't.
That's the real me.
Happy.
Happy. Hmm.
I haven't been happy
one minute of my entire fucking life.
You know what's funny?
You know what really makes me laugh?
I used to think that my life was a tragedy...
...but now I realize
it's a fucking comedy.
A very fine actor.
He's got a new movie called American Playboy
opening this week across the country.
Will you please welcome a good friend
of the show, Mr. Ethan Chase.
Good to see you, Ethan. You're looking great, Ethan.
Thank you very much. You're looking good yourself.
Ah, can't complain.
Hey, Murray. Thanks so much for having...
Hey, Murray.
Thank you so much for having me on the show.
It's been a lifelong dream of mine.
I'm nervous right now.
- You are? - I am nervous.
Hey, Murray. I've been on...
I'm sorry. What's that?
Oh, that's very funny, Murray.
You know, I'm also a comedian.
Would you like to hear a joke?
Yeah? All of you?
Okay.
Knock...
Knock, knock.
That's life
That's what all the people say
You're riding high in April
Shot down in May
But I know I'm gonna change that tune
When I'm back on top Back on top in June
I said, that's life
That's life
And as funny as it may seem
Some people get their kicks
Stompin' on a dream
But I don't let it, let it get me down
'Cause this fine old world
It keeps spinnin' around
I've been a puppet, a pauper, a pirate
A poet, a pawn and a king
I've been up and down and over and out
And I know one thing
Each time I find myself flat on my face
I pick myself up And get back in the race
That's life
I tell ya, I can't deny it
I thought of quitting, baby
But my heart just ain't gonna buy it
And if I didn't think It was worth one single try
Coming.
I'd jump right on a big bird And then I'd fly...
Hey, Arthur.
How's it going?
Oh, hey, guys.
Come on in.
Did you get a new gig?
No.
Oh, you must be going down to that rally at City Hall.
I hear it's gonna be nuts.
Oh, is that today?
Yeah.
What's with the makeup then?
My mom died.
I'm celebrating.
Right. We heard.
That's why we came by.
We figured, you know, you could use some cheering up.
Aw, that's sweet.
But, no, I feel good.
Yeah, I stopped taking my medication.
I feel a lot better now.
Oh, okay. Good for you.
So, hey, listen, I don't know if you heard,
but the cops have been coming around the shop,
talking to all the guys about those subway murders.
- And, um... - They didn't talk to me.
That's because the suspect was a regular-sized person.
If it was a fucking midget, you'd be in jail right now.
Anyway, um,
Hoyt said that they talked to you,
and now they're looking for me,
and I just wanna know what you said.
Make sure our stories line up.
- Seeing as how you're my boy. - Yeah, that's important.
- That makes a lot of sense. - You know what I mean?
Thank you, Randall. Thank you so much.
Arthur!
No!
What?
Why would you do that, Arthur?
Do you watch The Murray Franklin Show?
Yeah.
I'm gonna be on tonight.
It fucking crazy, innit?
Me on the telly.
What the fuck, Arthur?
What?
It's okay, Gary.
You can go.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Oh!
Don't look. Just go.
Fuck.
Hey, Arthur?
Yeah?
Arthur, can you get the lock?
Shit.
Sorry, Gary.
Gary?
Yeah.
You were the only one that was ever nice to me.
Skedaddle.
Hey, Arthur!
We need to talk.
Oh!
Hey! Stop, Arthur!
Arthur!
Watch it! Out of the way!
Move!
Arthur!
Shit.
Hey! Hey!
Arthur, stop!
Go! Go!
Now departing, O-Train, downtown.
Stand clear of the closing doors.
Hold that train! Hold it!
Get out! Get outta here!
Next stop, Bedford Park.
Masks off!
Get your mask off!
Signs down! Now!
Police! Signs down!
Signs down.
What the fuck!
Beat his ass!
Stop fighting! Police!
Police! Get down!
Get down! Get the fuck back!
Police! Get down.
Get the fuck down!
Stay the fuck back! Down!
What the...
Arthur!
Burke!
Don't do it!
Two officers on the train
were violently confronted by the crowd,
and tonight are in serious
but stable condition at Gotham Metropolitan.
We're going live now to
co-anchor Courtney Weathers,
who's standing by outside the Bedford Park Station,
near where the shooting took place.
Courtney, what's the scene there?
Murray.
Hey, hey, hey. It's Mr. Franklin, buddy.
Oh, come on, Gene. That's all bullshit.
Thank you, Murray.
I feel like I know you.
I've been watching you forever.
Thank you.
What's with the face?
I mean, are you part of the protest?
No.
No, I don't believe in any of that.
I don't believe in anything.
I just thought it'd be good for my act.
For your act? Didn't you hear
what happened on the subway? Some clown got killed.
He's aware of that. He's aware of that. Yeah.
No, I hadn't heard.
- Yeah. - You see?
This is what I'm telling you. The audience is gonna go crazy
if you put this guy on.
Maybe for a bit, but not a whole segment.
Gene, it's gonna work. It's gonna work.
We're gonna go with it.
Thank you, Murray.
Couple rules, though.
No cursing. No off-color material.
We do a clean show.
- Okay? - Mmm-hmm.
You'll go on right after Dr. Sally.
I love Dr. Sally.
Good, good. Someone will
- come and get you, okay? - Okay. Perfect.
Good luck.
- Thanks, Murray. - Okay.
- Murray, one small thing. - Yeah.
When you bring me out,
can you introduce me as Joker?
What's wrong with your real name?
That's what you called me on the show.
A joker.
Do you remember?
- Did I? - I don't know.
Well, if you say so, kid, you know, Joker it is.
It's good.
Thanks, Murray.
I'll try it, you know,
but I'm not sure my wife will let me do it.
Maybe my next wife.
You gotta see our next guest for yourself.
I'm pretty sure this guy could use a doctor.
Oh!
Does he have sexual problems?
Oh, he looks like he's got a lot of problems.
All right, Bobby, let's show that clip one last time.
I hated school as a kid.
But my mother would always say,
"You should enjoy it.
One day, you'll have to work for a living."
"No, I won't, Ma.
I'm gonna be a comedian."
Okay. You may...
You may have seen that clip of our next guest.
Now, before he comes out, I just want to say
that we're all heartbroken
about what's going on in the city tonight.
But this is how he wanted to come out,
and honestly, I think we could all use a good laugh.
So, please welcome, Joker.
Are you all right, Doctor?
Well, that was quite an entrance.
You okay?
Yeah.
This is exactly how I imagined it.
Well, that makes one of us.
So, can you tell us about this look?
When we spoke earlier,
you mentioned that this look is not a political statement.
Is that right?
That's right, Murray. I'm not political.
I'm just trying to make people laugh.
And how's that going for you?
So, I know you're a comedian.
You been working on any new material?
You wanna tell us a joke?
Yeah?
Okay.
He's got a book.
A book of jokes.
Take your time. We got all night.
Okay, okay. Here's one.
Knock, knock.
And you had to look that up?
I want to get it right.
Knock, knock.
Who's there?
It's the police, ma'am.
Your son's been hit by a drunk driver.
He's dead.
Oh, no, no, no.
No, you cannot joke about that.
Yeah, that's not funny, Arthur.
That's not the kind of humor we do on this show.
Okay. I'm... Yeah, I'm sorry.
It's just, you know, it's been a rough few weeks, Murray.
Ever since
I killed those three Wall Street guys.
Okay, I'm waiting for the punchline.
There is no punchline.
It's not a joke.
You're serious, aren't you?
You're telling us you killed
those three young men on the subway?
Mmm-hmm.
And why should we believe you?
I got nothing left to lose.
Nothing can hurt me anymore.
My life is nothing but a comedy.
Well, let me get this straight,
you think that killing those guys is funny?
I do.
And I'm tired of pretending it's not.
Comedy is subjective, Murray.
Isn't that what they say?
All of you,
the system that knows so much,
you decide what's right or wrong.
The same way that you decide what's funny or not!
Get him off!
Well, okay, I think I might understand
that you did this to start a movement,
to become a symbol?
Come on, Murray.
Do I look like the kind of clown
that could start a movement?
I killed those guys because they were awful.
Everybody is awful these days.
It's enough to make anyone crazy.
Okay. So, that's it, you're crazy.
That's your defense for killing three young men?
No.
They couldn't carry a tune to save their lives.
Oh, why is everybody so upset about these guys?
If it was me dying on the sidewalk,
you'd walk right over me!
I pass you every day, and you don't notice me.
But these guys, what, because Thomas Wayne
went and cried about them on TV?
You have a problem with Thomas Wayne, too?
Yes, I do.
Have you seen what it's like out there, Murray?
Do you ever actually leave the studio?
Everybody just yells and screams at each other.
Nobody's civil anymore.
Nobody thinks what it's like to be the other guy.
You think men like Thomas Wayne ever think
what it's like to be someone like me?
To be somebody but themselves? They don't.
They think that we'll just sit there
and take it, like good little boys!
That we won't werewolf and go wild!
You finished?
I mean, it's so much self-pity, Arthur.
You sound like you're making excuses
for killing those young men.
Not everybody, and I'll tell you this,
not everyone is awful.
You're awful, Murray.
Me? I'm awful?
Oh, yeah, how am I awful?
Playing my video.
Inviting me on this show.
You just wanted to make fun of me.
You're just like the rest of them.
You don't know the first thing about me, pal.
Look what happened, because of what you did. What it led to.
There are riots out there.
Two policemen are in critical condition,
and you're laughing.
You're laughing.
Someone was killed today, because of what you did.
I know.
How about another joke, Murray?
No, I think we've had enough of your jokes.
- What do you get... - I don't think so.
...when you cross a mentally-ill loner
with a society that abandons him
and treats him like trash?
Call the police, Gene!
- I'll tell you what you get! - Call the police.
You get what you fucking deserve!
Good night. And always remember, that's...
Breaking news.
Popular TV talk show host, Murray Franklin
was shot dead tonight on the live telecast of his program.
The man who was introduced by Franklin
as "Joker" is currently under arrest.
Police led the suspect handcuffed out of the studio.
...merely just a punchline to a joke...
You get what you deserve!
Looting and rioting
have intensified here...
...rioting throughout the city.
...with a society that abandons him
and treats him like trash?
This mob of clowns...
...many wearing clown masks.
If it was me dying on the sidewalk,
- you'd walk right over me. - To all of
those who have been ignored by the system.
And always remember, that's life!
And as you see, Gotham is burning.
In the white room With black curtains near the station
Black roof country, no gold pavements Tired starlings
Silver horses ran down moonbeams
In your dark eyes
Dawnlight smiles on you leaving My contentment
I'll wait in this place Where the sun never shines
Wait in this place
Where the shadows run from themselves
Stop laughing, you freak! This isn't funny.
Yeah, the whole fucking city's on fire
'cause of what you did.
All units, fire reported, north of alley.
Code Four for medical.
I know.
Isn't it beautiful?
Go over there.
Hey, Wayne.
You get what you fucking deserve.
No! Pal!
Come on, get up!
Come on, man, get up.
What's so funny?
Just thinking of a joke.
Do you want to tell it to me?
You wouldn't get it.
That's life
And as funny as it may seem
Some people get their kicks
Stompin' on a dream
But I don't let it, let it get me down
'Cause this fine old world
It keeps spinnin' around
I've been a puppet, a pauper, a pirate
A poet, a pawn and a king
I've been up and down and over and out
And I know one thing
Each time I find myself flat on my face
I pick myself up And get back in the race
That's life
That's life And I can't deny it
Many times I thought of cuttin' out But my heart won't buy it
But if there's nothing shakin' Come here this July
I'm gonna roll myself up in a big ball
And die
My, my
Isn't it rich?
Are we a pair?
Me here at last on the ground
You in mid-air
Send in the clowns
Isn't it bliss?
Don't you approve?
One who keeps tearing around
One who can't move
Where are the clowns?
Send in the clowns
Just when I stopped
Opening doors
Finally knowing The one that I wanted was yours
Making my entrance again With my usual flair
Sure of my lines
No one is there
Don't you love farce?
My fault, I fear
I thought that you'd want what I want
Sorry, my dear
But where are the clowns?
There ought to be clowns
Well, maybe next year