How many times are we going to
keep doing this?
We keep running it
until the hybrid holds.
ANNOUNCER
We are on security level five.
The deregs took.
No sign of rejection.
There's still
mutations in genome seven.
Thank you.
ANNOUNCER
All genetic waste must be taken
to the cremation chamber
by 5:00 p.m.
ANNOUNCER 2
Tank 12 is offline
until genetic modification
stabilizes.
All right.
Let's get this over with.
Here we go.
Oh. Yeah. Sorry. Hold on.
Okay. Yeah.
Three, two, one.
Step up here.
Waiting for authorization.
I didn't see
the labs, but I assume
we upped the soporifics?
Yeah.
I'm gonna have to go as high
as 0.5 milliliters
per hundred pounds.
Okay, guys. You're clear.
Well, we don't want
to kill the thing.
Some days I do.
Oh, God.
ANNOUNCER 2
Tank 12 is offline
until genetic modification
stabilizes.
Alert. Containment failure.
Hey, what's going on?
Alert.
Containment failure.
Oh, God. It's loose!
Run!
Containment is locking down!
- The D-Rex broke free!
- We got to get out of here!
Seal the doors!
We got to get out of here!
Go! Go! Go!
-DeSanto! The door!
- Oh, God. Oh, God.
Oh, no! No, no, no, no!
No, no, no! Come on!
No, no, no! No!
- Okay, it's just...
- No, no, no, no! It's okay.
- Come on. Come on!
- Just stick... Get the key in.
Three, two, one.
Come on!
Three, two--
Open the door!
Please!
Please?
Okay, just turn the key.
It's fine. It's-it's okay.
Just turn the key. Just turn...
Yeah. Just please
open the door.
I'm sorry.
Please open the door for me!
No!
Oh, God, no.
No! Oh, no!
I'm sorry!
Oh, no!
Come on, what is this?
These things
were supposed to be
completely cleared
two years ago.
Yeah, well, I'm not
happy about it either, man.
They're trying to get him up
right now.
I don't know what you want me
to tell you.
What does the mayor do,
sit on his ass all day?
It weighs 40 tons, buddy.
Do you want to move it?
♪ Twelve o'clock radio... ♪
WOMAN
...out of Manhattan.
Uh, the cause of the jam is
none other than Bronto Billy,
thought to be
the last surviving
sauropod in North America.
- Back to you, Bob.
-Thanks, Hailey.
So, yeah,
the aging brachiosaur,
known to be in poor health,
broke out of
the Cobble Hill Park enclosure
where it had been living while
receiving medical attention.
Oh, for God's sake.
Rest in peace already,
but get the hell
out of the way.
Damn, that's cold.
Geez.
I mean, even for New York,
it's pretty cold.
Miss Bennett, I presume?
Hello.
Weren't we supposed
to meet at the, um...
You're not exactly
hard to follow.
- So, how did you hear about me?
- Paulo Pasolini, Blackwater.
Mm-hmm. Does he have
a message for me?
Yes. He said to say,
"Felix isn't himself today."
Um... okay, I'm listening.
Is that some spy stuff?
'Cause that is fantastic.
What is it that you do
at ParkerGenix?
My company is developing
a new medication,
and we have certain needs.
Uh-huh. That sounds vague.
And what does that mean
in this case?
They say you're good
at procuring things
and not asking
a lot of questions.
Do they?
They also say you're untroubled
by possible legal
or ethical implications.
Well, they need to shut up.
Well, take it as a compliment.
Uh, means you get the job done.
I lost a friend on my last job,
so I am not up for procurement.
Well, you don't know
what it is yet.
Yes, but you work for a
pharmaceutical company, right?
So... You called me.
I'm spec ops, so it's covert.
I'm guessing info theft?
I-I'm sorry, I do retrieval
and extractions, not heists.
It's dinosaurs.
They may be through with us,
but we're not
through with them.
Well, they are all...
They're all dead
or dying, so...
Except for on a few islands
around the equator.
Yes, and those are no-go zones
for a reason.
You go there, you die.
Which is where you come in.
Oh.
No, thanks.
Ms. Bennett!
Did you know that
20% of the world's population
will die of heart disease?
That's one in every five people
on the planet.
Now, just imagine.
Take somebody you know,
anybody, and imagine that you
could be the one to give them
- an extra 20 years of life.
- That's very touching.
It's not my field, though.
And we have very deep pockets.
How deep?
For you, extremely.
Well...
I'm gonna need a number.
Ten, six zeros.
Including the one
that's in the ten?
No.
It's a fortune, Ms. Bennett.
The kind of money that would
mean you'd never have to put
your life on the line
ever again.
All right, what's the hitch?
Uh...
Possible criminal charges.
We are going to a place
where every government on
the planet has outlawed travel.
Well, we better not
tell anyone, then.
Yeah, that might be a problem.
He doesn't know it yet,
but we're bringing a civilian.
The Neo-Jurassic Age
has proven lethal
to Dinosauria.
Though some species can survive
in a few isolated oxygen-rich
tropical microclimates
clustered in
equatorial regions,
where interactions with humans
and other incompatible
modern species is...
Banner coming down.
Okay, so this is
the left metacarpal?
Yeah.
Good morning, Doctor.
Sorry to drop in unannounced.
Can we have a word?
Sorry, it's a hell
of a day here.
They're closing us down.
Dr. Henry Loomis, Zora Bennett,
- our mission specialist.
- Hello.
Sorry, what mission?
Uh, guys, why don't
you just take a break
for a minute, okay?
Thanks, guys.
Dr. Loomis has been
advising ParkerGenix
for the past six months
on paleo-coronary health.
We're developing a new drug,
Paleodioxin,
derived from the largest
dinosaur species on record.
Computer modeling suggests
it could forestall
coronary disease
by an average of two decades.
Think what that might have
meant for your mother.
- I'm so sorry for your loss.
-  Okay.
Anybody can read a file.
If you get personal, though,
I'm out.
I'm sorry for overstepping.
This, uh, research is crucial.
We just can't get it to trial.
We're unable
to synthesize the DNA,
so we need samples
from living dinosaurs.
And the species must be
a true colossus.
It's the biggest animals
across three categories:
seagoing, land based and avian.
Why the biggest?
Oh, it's their hearts.
The bigger they were, the
bigger their coronary muscles.
And they lived the longest,
over a hundred years for
some Cretaceous-era sauropods.
Which means the three
dinosaurs they need are
Mosasaurus,
which lives in the ocean,
and Titanosaurus.
You'll find them on land.
And in the sky, Quetzalcoatlus.
It's the largest pterosaur.
Each of them had
an average lifespan
of well over a century,
even before DNA refinement.
Mm.
A drug that could prevent
heart disease would be
the biggest
medical breakthrough
in centuries.
Yeah. And I'm sure it'd be
worth billions, right?
- Trillions.
- Hmm.
The only way for our scientists
to complete the strands now
is with blood
and tissue samples
from living dinosaurs.
Wait. Y-You want
to take blood samples
from these animals
while they're alive?
Hemoglobin deoxygenates
within seconds postmortem.
Lividity and hypostasis
follow immediately.
Fortunately for us,
all these species exist
in one isolated location.
We're putting together a team,
and we'd like
to leave immediately.
We have competitors,
and Mr. Parker does not
tolerate second place.
Can you be ready tomorrow?
Dr. Loomis?
I thought I was just advising.
You are. In person.
We're not qualified
to identify the animals
or predict behavior.
Well...
Why don't you send an army?
You're a rich company.
Confidentiality.
The fewer people know
about this, the better.
I can guarantee your safety.
I mean, you know, more or less.
Oh, no, no. It's not about
my safety. It's just, it's...
- "More or less"?
- Yeah.
What you're proposing
is really illegal.
Oh, did we-- did you tell him
about the zeros?
That's not gonna work with him.
What are you talking about?
You ever seen a dinosaur
in the wild?
I don't mean in a theme park
when you were a kid
or watching some poor creature
wander around town lost.
I mean in its natural habitat.
'Cause until you've done that,
you're just a guy
who visits zoos.
We sold a dozen tickets
all last week.
Five years ago, you'd have
to wait in line for hours,
if you could even get in.
Nobody cares about
these animals anymore.
They deserve better.
I just-- I need a second.
No, yeah.  Take...
Take all the time
that you need.
Take all the minutes.
Not like...
...your entire life has been,
you know, leading up
to this moment.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
Three in a row!
Captain Kincaid.
Martin Krebs.
We spoke on the phone.
Yeah, Krebs, look, I'm sorry.
I thought it over,
and I can't do it.
I'd like to, just as a favor
to Zora, but I can't.
What?
We already agreed on the phone.
You named your price.
It's not that. I just--
It's a little too risky
for my boat.
She's not paid off yet,
so I imagine you understand.
No hard feelings, Z.
Hey. Two double rums. Merci.
What the hell is this?
He's your guy.
Yeah. We spent ten years
in MARSOC together.
Duncan's the best.
Otherwise, I wouldn't be here.
Best at what? Drinking?
Fabrice, not the guns, okay?
All right. Okay.
Moving things and people
in and out of places
they shouldn't be.
Trouble is, I really
can't do it this time, Z.
I'm sorry.
And I'm afraid that's final.
That's a hell
of a setback, Duncan.
You promised me.
Uh, we're screwed now.
I'm sorry.
I hate to see this
all fall apart on you.
I'll tell you what.
Why don't you make some sort
of good faith gesture?
Like, maybe-- you know,
I'm just spitballing here--
but maybe you could
double the number
that you and I spoke about,
and then I can
take care of Duncan
and his crew out of my end.
Oh, I see.
That's very nice.
You guys cook this up
on the phone or just now?
Oh, I'm just trying
to help you out.
I don't have to sit here
and be insulted.
For God sakes, fine. Agreed.
- Great.
We'll loop up toward Barbados
to avoid government patrols,
but there aren't many anyway.
Why's that?
No one's dumb enough
to go where we're going.
Hey! Hey!
Come here!
- Hey.
-Hey.
Over here.
- Hey, Z.
-  Hi.
- Hey, how you been?
- Oh, good.
Bobby Atwater.
He'll be helping
with team security.
Security for...?
Make sure you don't end up
in one of these.
A live one.
Is there anything else?
Yeah, listen, I'm not gonna be
able to do this, you know?
I-I would love to as a favor
for you, Z, but...
- Oh, no, we ran it already.
- All right, cool.
So, when we leaving?
-Hey, LeClerc.
- LeCLERC: What?
Did you see how much
Kincaid's paying us
for this one?
Oh, yeah.
- We're in trouble.
- Hell yeah.
Well, the good news is,
the Mosasaur was tagged
in captivity
and InGen continued to track it
after its escape.
We bought their data
when they entered Chapter 11,
so now we track it.
Nobody else seems to know
much about it.
But...
that's it right there.
So, first sample
in 150 miles or so.
Very close to the equator.
But why...
why near the equator?
Why don't they survive
anywhere else?
The fitness landscape of
the Earth no longer suits them.
Uh, the air is different.
Uh, the solar radiation
is different,
the insects, vegetation.
Everything is different.
But close to the equator,
it's nearly the climate
of 60 million years ago.
It's warmer
and rich with oxygen.
And the Mosasaur
generally circles
the island we're headed to.
There's a complex there
that was R and D
for the original park.
It was abandoned
after an accident.
We're gonna want to get in,
get our three samples
and get out
as quickly as possible.
Because even though
two dozen species
have survived there, alone,
for almost 20 years,
make no mistake, this is by no
means a controlled environment.
Yeah, I think we'll be okay.
What are those?
Neurotoxins.
How fast?
Paralysis within
a couple of seconds.
And then what?
And then you survive.
Is this the part where you, uh,
tell me it's a crime
to kill a dinosaur, Doctor?
No, this is where I tell you
it's a sin to kill a dinosaur.
So, uh, what if
it's us or them? Hmm?
Then we've put ourselves in
a place where we don't belong.
Mm, that's-that's kind of
our specialty, Dr. Loomis.
We have no intention
of harming the animals.
Let's just get our samples
and go home.
Gonna lose the light
before we make contact.
We'll make a run
first thing in the morning.
How does extraction work?
These darts
collect blood samples.
You get one shot with each.
The Mosa has
four inches of hide,
so you must be within
ten meters to penetrate.
And it self-ejects
when it reaches capacity.
It should fire
a couple of hundred feet
in the air,
like a model rocket.
On the day,
a parachute will open,
and it will float back down
to us.
I'll take the shot.
Uh, remote biopsy darting
is pretty basic.
I'm sure I can handle it.
Oh.
Let me show you something.
- You feel that spray?
- Yeah.
Now imagine the boat
rocking at 15 to 20 degrees,
we're moving at 30 knots, you
got sweat running in your eyes,
and you're close enough to look
that thing right in the teeth.
You got this.
Uh, please, be my guest.
Oh, really? If you insist.
I can't take it.
I mean, it's-it's been fun
working with you, Z.
- What?
- But I think we just
found our new team leader.
No offense.
I mean, I don't know anybody
that could be offended by that.
That's mean.
I heard about Booker.
Yeah.
I'm so sorry.
What job were you on?
Um, just a simple
training mission in Yemen.
Couldn't have been more basic.
Just a car bomb.
Out of nowhere.
Quick at least.
Not really.
Shit.
He didn't deserve that.
No.
I had to tell his wife.
It was... it was brutal.
You can't keep this up
forever, Z.
No.
This work...
it breaks you eventually.
What do you think
I'm doing down here?
I'm just trying to,
you know, buy my life back.
Oh, really?
I thought you just missed me.
Well...
You know
what I actually missed?
Hmm?
My own mother's funeral.
Oh, wow.
Yeah.
That's terrible, Zora.
- Yeah, yeah.
- No, seriously.
That's, like, the worst thing
I've ever heard anybody do.
Thank you.
That's so supportive of you.
Oh.
God.
Please tell me
you worked it out with Amelia.
Well...
Whenever we looked
at each other, we just...
...just saw our little boy.
Easier for us both just
to go at it alone, you know?
We are very pathetic.
All right, what do you say
we stay alive?
And, uh, you know,
get rich this time.
Rich is nice,
but it won't be enough.
For sure.
Do something that matters
while there's still time.
Okay.
Don't just brush that off.
I mean it.
Don't wait, Zora.
Do not wait.
♪ We took a vow in summertime ♪
♪ Now we find ourselves
in late December... ♪
You rationing those, honey?
I'm enjoying them.
It's a long way
across the Atlantic.
You're gonna miss them
when you run out.
Can I ask why you have
so many in your pocket?
So she doesn't eat them.
Ah, right.
Hey, honey.
Where's your boyfriend?
It-It's his turn at the wheel.
Is he coming or what?
Uh, I told him.
He's just getting dressed.
Okay.
Do you want to practice?
All right.
Remember, okay?
It's just like Dad showed you.
Under, under, around.
You guys ever wish
you had a boring dad?
- We do.
- Yeah.
Finally.
Good evening, Xavier.
What's up?
6:00.
I know.
I was out cold.
It's, uh, it's your watch.
Oh, I-I slept like a baby.
You've-you've got the wheel?
Man, I am so tired.
I'm gonna be honest.
I'd probably conk out
at the wheel.
I'll take his shift. It's fine.
No, no, no, honey,
we've been through this.
You need sleep. I need sleep.
It's your shift, Xavier.
Come on, man.
Reuben, can't we just anchor,
for once?
Use the anchor.
We haven't done that yet.
We only carry 50 meters
of anchor chain.
It's 2,000 meters
to the bottom.
Oh.
Kind of sounds like somebody
should've thought about that
- before we left.
- Do you have any idea
the weight of two thou--
I built this boat,
okay, Xavier?
- I-I know what I'm doing.
- Oh, so you're good.
- You're good on the wheel.
- You know what?
Just grab another hour.
I'm-I'm fine.
- Yes. Perfect. You're the best.
- I-I got it. I'm fine.
Fist bump?
Give me some.
Never mind. Whoa.
Oh, you got licorice, dude?
I love this stuff.
I didn't say a word.
Not-not one word.
Good.
So don't.
What-- did-did he even
bring a shirt?
Okay, clearly you don't see
the side of him that I see.
The naked side.
Hey.
I mean, I...
I guess I'd hoped it
would just be the three of us.
You know, one last hurrah.
I'm going to NYU, not Mongolia.
I know. You're right.
What are those?
Where?
One o'clock. Moving east.
Dolphins?
No.
No fins.
Sails.
Bella, grab the wheel.
Left, left, left.
Something big sideswiped us.
Sailfish?
Bigger.
Is it the you-know-what?
No, hon,
it's not a you-know-what.
Barely any left.
I hate those things.
I wish they never came back.
I just think we should...
Hold on!
- Dad! Dad!
- Teresa!
- Xavier's inside!
- I'll get him. Get to the top.
Get to the top!
Swim!
Xavier!
- It's not opening!
- Let it fill with water!
- Reuben, it won't open!
- Let it fill!
- Let it fill, then
you can open the door!
- Why?
Get the radio! In the red bag!
The red bag! The emergency bag!
- Get up!
- Okay.
Go!
- Where is it?
- Get it!
- I can't find it!
- It's in the bag!
The emergency bag!
The emergency radio!
Okay.
Dad!
Xavier!
Hey! Just get out!
- Teresa!
- Bella! Bella, hold on!
- Xavier!
- Dad!
Dad!
- Xavier!
- Dad!
Dad!
Honey!
Where's Xavier?
What happened?
- Dad, where is he?
- I don't know.
I'll go back down.
I'll keep looking.
Xavier!
- Xavier, swim!
- Hey! Hey!
Xavier, hurry! Swim!
- Xavier!
- Come on!
- Come on! Come on! Come on!
- Swim, Xavier!
- Faster! Come on!
- Hurry!
Xavier!
Come on!
Dad.
I...
I got the bag.
♪ Money rains... ♪
♪ But keep the change
'Cause I've got enough ♪
♪ A little time... ♪
Am I interrupting?
Oh.
It's fine.
I can't sleep.
Well, they say if
you can sleep the night before,
you should probably quit.
You don't hear that much
in museum work.
You want to sit down?
Can I ask
what was bothering you?
Maybe a little PTSD.
I probably should've taken
some more time off
after my last job.
What are you?
Like a mercenary?
Uh, situational security
and reaction.
So a mercenary, then.
Well, still, sounds way more
exciting than my life.
Yeah?
How exactly?
Well, I have never
been shot at.
- No?
- Mm-mm.
Well...
There's still time.
Good night, Doctor.
Good night.
REUBEN
Mayday. Mayday. Mayday.
This is the Mariposa.
Mayday. Mayday.
Last known position:
24...
I was awake.
What's our distance to target?
43 kilometers.
Just resting your eyes, huh?
Euh, ouais.
I'm coming, I've just gotta pee.
Merci.
No French before breakfast.
REUBEN
Mayday. Mayday. Mayday.
This is the Mariposa.
We are sinking.
Last known position:
24 degrees, 33 north
and 74, 56 west.
We are sinking.
The-the signal was
clear, right?
I mean, you-you sure
you heard a mayday?
-Positive.
- But did you get a location?
Down to ten square meters.
They sent a DSC.
28 miles away.
Well, that's...
that's 28 miles, you know,
in the opposite direction.
What? Bobby, what, do you want
to leave them? Come on.
Nah, of course not.
I'm saying this guy has
a working radio,
and, you know,
he can transmit his location.
It's true. It's not as if
they're gonna freeze to death.
I mean, I'm saying, like,
help is gonna be on its way.
There's probably a coast guard
ship on its way right now.
Two miles!
Look, we are three minutes away
from this Mosasaur, which,
may I remind you,
is what we came here for.
The Mosasaur is tagged.
We found it once,
we'll find it again.
Maybe we can, but, Z,
we're talking about
tens of millions
of dollars here.
And all they need to do
is just float around
for a couple of hours.
I've got visual!
13 degrees off the port side!
That's it.
Okay, I have to agree
with Mr., um...
-Atwater.
- ...Atwater.
- The Mosasaur first.
- Right.
Right?
LeClerc, new course.
24, 33 north, 74, 56 west.
Flank speed.
LeCLERC:
Aye, aye.
We're search and rescue now.
It's my charter.
It's my boat.
Oh, my God.
Is that... is that...
- Oh, my God. Hey.
-Oh, my God.
Hey! Hey!
-Hey, over here!
- Over here!
I don't know. It was,
like, the size of the boat.
Bigger.
50 feet, 70. I-I don't know.
It was a snakelike body
with a large skull
and a long snout?
- Yes. Yes.
- And limbs like paddles?
- A long tail region
with a downcurved end?
Look, man, that's what it is.
- What else it could be?
- What the hell you doing
this far out with a little kid?
Uh, we're just making
a crossing.
Barbados to Cape Town.
We've-we've done it before.
Shouldn't they be in school?
They are.
It's summer break.
Wh-What is your problem?
My problem is
you should've known better.
How?
There are 50,000 boats
on this ocean right now.
One was attacked by a Mosasaur.
Wh-What are the odds?
Duncan, let it go, okay?
You know you're not
pissed off at him.
Okay? These kids are safe now.
All right...
I don't understand.
Why would a Mosasaur attack
a 45-foot sailboat?
It's not food.
Maybe it thought
the boat was a rival,
and it wanted to eliminate
any competition.
- How far off course are we?
- 28 miles.
And how long
to reacquire the target?
Uh, two hours, maybe.
Depends how fast it's moving
and in which direction.
Well, what say
we turn the boat around
and get the mission
back on track?
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
How fast what's moving?
Wh-What mission?
So...  About that.
- It's, uh...
-Okay.
So, exactly what are you guys
doing here?
Uh, we are gonna take a detour
and pick up a few items,
and that's it.
What-what items?
- It's okay, honey. It's okay.
- Wh-What is she talking about?
Hey. That guy?
- Hi. Excuse me.
- Creeping me out.
- What'd I do?
- You're creeping me out.
Can we get
the tracking map up, please?
Uh, all right, look, look.
Uh, we understand
you've got your own business,
and... and, um,
we're very grateful to you.
You pulled us out of the water.
We're not gonna forget that.
- But can you
just drop us off and...
- Is that it?
-That would be great.
-Flip this up. Pardon.
It's hard to tell.
You can leave us
at any convenient port.
Please.
Yeah?
The software's ghosting.
It's doubling the signal.
Maybe it's just echoing
off our boat.
- That's not an echo.
-What?
- What is it you need to get?
- That's two signals.
So we already found it?
No, no.
It found us.
- Oh, no, no. Come on, guys.
-Okay...
-Whoa.
-It's here.
-
Nina, tell me something.
Everything's online. It's fine.
Okay, so we just
got away from it,
and you guys have been
chasing it?
Uh, starboard. Yeah, yeah.
Guys, listen.
We're gonna be
a couple of minutes tops,
then we're all going to this
island like she said, okay?
There's a village complex there
with geothermal energy
that still works.
You can wait there.
You'll be totally safe.
-What?
-Oh, my God.
There. Starboard.
-Okay.
-Let's go!
Take the wheel.
- I'll get a bearing.
- Aye, aye.
Ah! It's beautiful!
-Yes!
- Whoo!
Let's go!
We're losing her!
Loomis! I need you to secure me
- to the bow rail.
-Okay.
Make it tight.
- Like this?
- Yeah.
- The other side.
- Okay.
Remember, don't fire
until it's within ten meters.
Got it.
All right.
Nina, I need command
up here now.
Comm is yours.
Come on. Come on!
We got to be closer! Move it!
Hey. Get up here and spot.
NINA
On my way.
20 meters.
Almost in range!
15 meters.
Copy.
Ah.
Another dart.
Okay.
Come on!
It's coming at us! Turn! Turn!
Quick! It's in range!
Come on!
There, go!
Hey!
Help me up! Help me!
Come on!
Take the shot!
It worked!
Yes! Come down ten knots!
Hard starboard.
Down ten. Down ten.
There it is!
Port side off the stern rail.
I got it! I got it!
Nice shot.
Nice rocket.
- That was fantastic.
- Yeah!
That was genius.
- Yes.
- That was good.
That worked. That worked.
Oh, God.
-Hey.
What if we don't?
What if we don't what?
Well, what if
we get the samples
and we don't give them over
to a company
that makes a lifesaving drug
and then prices it
so 99% of the planet
can't afford it?
Science is for all of us,
not some of us.
Have you thought about that?
No, I guess I haven't.
Well, then maybe
you should start.
- Maybe you should stop.
-Dad, please.
Hey, Xavier.
Head between your legs,
deep breaths.
Hey. Deep breaths.
Deep breaths.
Dad, I think I'm gonna be sick.
It's all right. Just breathe.
Those things from the boat.
They're...
they're-they're back.
- Oh, my God.
-Dad?
What the hell are those?
Sit down, honey. Stay close.
Spinosaurus.
It's mutualism!
Interspecies symbiosis!
Those Spinosaurus,
they help the Mosasaur hunt.
They help it kill!
Well, that's discouraging.
These are our waters now.
Over here! There's another one!
There! Seven o'clock!
Hurry! Quick!
Bobby. Bobby, Bobby.
Look out!
Bobby! Bobby, no!
Dad!
- Dad!
- Bella!
Dad!
Oh, my God. Oh.
What are you doing?
You're heading into the rocks!
I can outrun those things.
The Mosasaur can't go
into shallow water.
Everybody,
hold on to something!
I can't move my leg, honey.
If we hit those rocks,
we're gonna wreck.
Tie these
to everything you need.
Be ready to jump.
It's fast.
LeClerc,
the engine's overheating.
Teresa, get back inside.
Get on the radio.
Mayday three times
and send coordinates. Go!
Three times, send coordinates.
Got it.
Hang on, honey.
Isabella.
Isabella, hey, look at me.
It's gonna be okay. Listen.
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday!
- Okay. Hang on. Hey, hey, hey.
- Is anybody there?
- Mayday! Mayday!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. Stop.
- Please! Hey!
- Stop.
Just stop. Stop for a second.
What do you mean, "stop"?
W-We got
to handle this ourselves.
- What?
- This is the...
- This is the protocol.
- Are you crazy?
- No! Mayday. No. No, no, no.
- Just give me the... Hey.
- No. Whoa. Hey.
- Hey, Mayday! Mayday!
Back off!
Please help me.
Please. Help me, please.
Please.
Please help me.
Grab my hand, please.
Dad!
Sweetie! Teresa!
No!
Teresa!
Teresa! No!
Man overboard!
Listen to me.
We're going in the water now.
Yes. The boat's gonna crash.
We have to.
Your sister's there.
You understand? Hey. Hey.
Hey. I'm here. Okay?
All right? I've got you.
- You're all right.
- Daddy.
Come on. Come on!
Get ready.
On the count of three.
- One, two, three!
- Hey!
Hey! We need to stick together!
Keep going!
Whoa! Get down!
Zora! It can't go
in the shallows!
Jump! Go! Jump!
Told you!
I thought I lost you.
Are you okay?
He let me fall.
- Who?
- The guy on the boat.
He tried to kill me.
I knew he was creepy!
Teresa? Teresa?
Dad!
- I'm okay. I'm okay.
- Yeah?
I got you. Oh, thank God.
- You all right? Are you good?
- You okay?
Let's get out of the water.
Keep moving!
They're amphibious!
LeClerc, you okay?
Next time, I'm driving.
Move! Keep going!
We made it.
-I've got it here.
- Do we still have the case?
You got that side?
-
We're getting there. Pull.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Come on. Grab it.
Keep going. Yeah.
Go on. Grab it.
Keep moving.
It's all right.
Just keep going to the beach.
Nina!
Nina! Nina!
Kincaid!
Nina!
Hey. Hey.
I know. I know.
It's okay, honey.
They said
there's a village here.
We'll find it and get help.
All right?
You don't feel like talking?
It's okay, honey.
You don't have to.
You'll be okay.
She'll be okay, right?
Uh, yeah.
Oh, wow.
So, like...
when an old person
buys a bed...
...do you think,
before they buy it,
they look at it and they go,
"Oh, wow, man, this is...
this is my deathbed"?
Because I'm thinking that...
...right now.
I think we got it.
Come on.
Let's go find this village.
Hurry up.
We can't stay here.
They'll come back.
- They're more like mutations.
- What do you mean, "mutations"?
- Abnormalities, deviations.
- I know what the word means.
What does it mean here,
where we are?
What are you talking about?
This island that we're on,
Mr. Roarke here didn't tell us
everything
that we need to know.
Look, dinosaurs are dinosaurs.
- What difference does it make?
- Okay, okay. Fine.
Don't tell us.
We could just leave you here.
- It's fine.
- Fine.
So, this island was
a laboratory of sorts.
They conducted
experimental work here.
- What kind of experiments?
- Crossbreeding of species.
The theme park owners
were just responding
to what the audience wanted.
They were tired of looking at
the same old thing.
"Engineered entertainments,"
they called them.
Genetically altered freaks?
Yeah. And you don't want
to do that
in the middle of
a theme park, do you?
Ideally, you don't try
weird genetic shit at all.
Well, they learned that
the hard way.
Any that were malformed
or just too damn hard
for anybody to look at,
they left them here.
Well, that's inhuman.
Why not just euthanize them?
The average cost of a
created species is $72 million.
What would you do?
Kill it
and have to tell your bank
or just carry it forward
under R and D?
What would I do
with mutant dinosaurs
from an accounting perspective?
Is that really the question?
Can we please just
hurry this along?
Everybody, please stay cool.
- Our situation hasn't changed.
- Two of our friends just died.
Clearly, the situation's
changed quite a bit.
Yes, and that's horrible.
But this is where
we are now, desperate,
and that's not
any different than before.
We were all desperate
to begin with.
Otherwise, we wouldn't
have come. Right?
You,
you specialize in a subject
nobody cares about anymore.
You're about to be
out of a job.
You need this.
I want the money.
You want the money.
Your company wants
all the money.
We still have that case.
First sample's in it.
Let's get the other two.
That's a great idea.
We have no weapons, Z.
We never did.
I mean, not really.
We had a... a few toys that
would have made us feel better.
They could have worked or not.
We are where
we're supposed to be.
We know what
we're supposed to do.
Let's just get what we need
and get out.
Those kids, the people
who went into the ocean,
they could still be alive.
I say we find them first
and then we get out.
Uh, get out how?
Does anyone want to hear
the backup plan?
She has a backup plan?
She doesn't get out of bed
without a backup plan.
I hired an exfil team
to monitor
our boat's radio frequency.
So if we go silent
for 24 hours,
they'll do a flyby at exactly
sunset on the second night.
But that's tomorrow.
Your plans showed
a village complex
on the southwest ridge
with a helipad.
They'll hover
for exactly two minutes.
If no one shows, they'll leave.
But if they see us...
Why only two minutes?
Why don't they just land?
'Cause pilots want to
live, too.
Oh, great.
Got to find high ground
before the sun goes down.
We have to go now.
Drop anything
you can't carry all day.
What do we do now?
Just try not to die.
Warm.
There's geothermal power.
Must come through these pipes
from hot springs.
It must lead to the village.
Maybe there's a radio?
Great.  Yeah.
We use that to get the guy
who tried to kill me.
Or, you know, to get rescued?
Yeah.
Then we'll get
the son of a bitch.
Right.
Okay, we follow the pipes
to the village.
Unless somebody's got
another idea.
I have some weed.
Might be a little damp,
but, uh, I feel like
we could just chill here, no?
You don't smoke-- Do you smoke?
No?
Okay.
Dad, he's, uh...
he's clearly messing with you.
Ah.
Yo, help me up?
Funny.
All right.
No one help me up. That's fine.
Maybe that family will
know to head for the village.
God, I hope so.
How far to the next sample?
Well, according
to the satellite imagery,
the Titanosaur herd stays
in the central valley.
We should reach them by dawn.
Be careful where you step.
Something just moved
past my leg.
Hey, you want to tell me
how the, uh, girl
fell over the rail?
The thing hit the boat.
You were there.
Oh. Uh, so were you,
on the bridge, next to her.
So there was nothing
you could do?
What are you implying?
This isn't
your first expedition, huh?
No, I've been on digs
since I was 12.
I studied under Alan Grant
as a postdoc.
I suppose you're in this kind
of situation all the time?
Used to be.
I hate the jungle.
I try to avoid it now.
Why is that?
Mm, you can't see
three feet in front of you,
and you always know
you're being stalked.
And the only place to hide
is underwater.
I refuse to die in the jungle.
My dream is
I die in a shallow sea
and I'm buried quickly by silt.
That's beautiful.
It's the best chance
of being fossilized that way.
You're a weirdo.
Thank you.
You got to drop this.
She screamed, I turned around,
and then she was gone.
Okay. All right.
If I find out otherwise,
though, we'll leave you here
and you can rejoin
the food chain.
I'm too smart to die.
You know, intelligence is
massively overrated
as an adaptive trait.
- Oh, yeah?
- Seriously.
Enlighten us.
pretty dumb, right?
And yet they survived
for 167 million years.
And we Homo sapiens,
geniuses by comparison,
only have about
200,000 years so far.
But with
our huge cranial cavities,
we're so smart,
we already have the capacity
to annihilate ourselves.
I doubt we make it
to even one million.
Hold on.
Don't we rule the Earth?
We got to be doing
something right.
We don't rule the Earth.
We just think we do.
I mean, sure,
we're changing the environment,
but that makes us the ones to
worry about, not the planet.
When the Earth gets tired
of us, believe me,
it will shake us off
like a summer cold.
Of all species
that have existed on Earth,
99.9% of them are now extinct.
Survival is a long shot.
Whoa.
You hear that?
Every day could be your last.
All right, everyone,
find a stick.
You'll need it
to clear your way.
Bella?
It's okay.
It's little.
And see?
And it's a plant-eater.
It's okay.
No. No. Go.
Go. Shoo.
Hey, Xavier.
Yeah.
You jumped in after her.
Respect for that.
Whatever, guapo.
Hard to like, honey.
Yeah. Took me a minute, too.
Let's do this.
Let's do this...
but, like,
going that way, though.
What are the last two species?
Uh, Titanosaur
and Quetzalcoatlus,
an 11-ton sauropod
and a pterosaur the size of a
school bus with 30-foot wings.
One of those little
buses like for field trips
or the full thing?
Does it matter?
Just asking.
It's okay.
You get some more sleep
while I take it for a while.
Oh, no. I'm okay.
I know you're okay,
but it's my watch.
You sure?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Uh, the pipes, they just go
right up that way.
Hopefully towards the village.
All right?
You know,
I was wrong about you.
No, you were right.
I'm lazy as hell.
She might be alive
because of what you did.
I don't even kn-know why she
wants to be with me.
Well, she... she sees
who you are.
Thank God she doesn't.
Hey. Hey!
Other people may talk shit
about us,
but we don't have to do
the job for them.
Otherwise, it becomes true.
Well, I got to take a piss.
Come on.
Come.
It's okay.
Come on.
-How much further?
-Not far.
The Titanosaur herd should be
right across this valley.
But they're herbivores, right?
Yeah.
That's good.
But the things
that hunt them aren't.
Oh, great.
KINCAID
Quiet.
Hmm.
You want one? Mm.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Oh.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You're a secret
adrenaline junkie, Henry.
This is our chance.
They're distracted.
Distracted by what?
Oh.
-Oh, my God.
- Okay.
You don't see that every day.
Or ever.
Whoo!
One to go.
Looks like we're climbing.
Hope you're good
with heights, Doc.
The guys on the boat said
there was power at the village.
We just have to trust
that they were right.
Hey, how much further
you think it is?
A mile, maybe two.
Is your leg okay?
Yeah, it just hurts a little.
I'm fine.
It's okay.
And, uh...
are we okay with... that?
It's helping her.
It's okay. I got an eye on it.
Mom's never gonna trust you
with us again.
Oh, God, no.
Hey, guys.
I'm naming her Dolores.
Iz, you're alive?
You talk?
I'm taking her home with me.
That may or may not be
a terrible idea.
Dolores?
Hey, you good?
Yeah, it's, uh...
it's just kind of nice,
you and your dad.
I don't know.
Maybe this whole thing will...
Xavier!
Bella, Bella! Bella, wait!
What's the smell?
What's wrong with her?
What is she scared of?
Help me up.
Uh, we'll follow the river.
That way.
I see a boat.
You can't walk.
Xavier can help you
while I go get it.
All right.
Be careful.
Can I get some more licorice?
Oh, my God.
REUBEN
Teresa. Teresa!
Hurry.
Just go. Come on.
Come on. Come on.
-  Don't wake it up.
- Come on. Come on.
Move! Come back.
Okay.
No.
Shit.
ISABELLA
Dolores.
You have to go. It's not safe.
Please. Go, go, go, go, go.
Shoo, shoo.
Come on. Come on.
- Don't. Don't. Don't.
- No, don't. Don't. Don't.
-
Come on, honey. Come on.
-Teresa.
Come on.
Come on, baby. Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Okay.
Bella.
Come on, honey. Come on.
Help her. Help her.
Let's go, let's go. Come on.
Grab the paddle. Quietly.
Go! Go! Go!
- Paddle!
- Come on!
- Paddle. Come on.
- Paddle!
Dad, it's...
Paddle! Paddle! Paddle!
Paddle!
- Go, go!
- Go!
- Come on, come on, come on,
come on, come on!
- Paddle!
- Hurry! Paddle!
- Come on, come on! Go, go, go!
Dig, dig!
Dig! Dig! Come on!
Come on,
come on, come on!
As hard as you can! Dig!
Dig!
- Come on! Paddle!
-Go!
Paddle! Paddle!
Isabella! Swim! Go! Go!
Bella!
Isabella!
- Dad!
-Keep going.
Come on. Hey.
Bella!
- Bella!
ISABELLA
Dad!
Dad! Dad!
Bella! Bella!
Dad!
Where are you?! Help!
- Dad! Dad!
- No. Isabella!
No! Bella!
Isabella, no!
No. No. No.
Bella. Bella, come on!
Come on! Swim!
Come on!
Dad!
Oh, God. Dad!
- Bella, swim!
- Come on, Bella!
-Bella, it's coming!
-Come on! I got you!
You okay?
You okay? You okay?
Okay.
It's a vertical slab.
Uh...
Looks like some overhang.
It's probably a 5.13, 5.15.
Well, at least
we're going down.
I saw the pterosaur circling
a carved structure
cut into a natural ledge.
They were crevice nesters,
so it's an ideal spot.
Do we have to get a sample
from an egg?
I suppose we could try
and get it from the parent,
but they're a flying carnivore
the size of an F-16.
Hmm. Okay.
Clip him in.
Okay.
Alright, here we go.
See you at the bottom.
- You good?
- Good? Yeah, good.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Ah.
I mean, I have a 20-foot
climbing wall in my gym, so...
Oh. There you go.
It's exactly
like climbing that.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, but 25 times in a row,
and you're 500 feet up,
so if you fall, you die.
Okay, well, that's unhelpful.
Don't worry. I got you.
Oh, God.
It's fun, right?
Krebs.
Check this out.
Rope, rope!
You're doing great.
We got another 40 feet to go.
Time to move.
Okay.
See? Just like the gym.
C'est miraculeux.
Can you move the pitons?
I think we're gonna need
a couple minutes here.
LeCLERC:
Okay, d'accord.
What is this place? Huh?
Some kind of ancient temple?
It won't hurt the embryo.
Um, maybe we should, uh,
make this quick, huh?
Not without breaking
the egg sac.
You're a very impressive
nerd, Henry.
What would the alternative be?
To what?
To handing the samples
over to ParkerGenix.
We open-source it.
We give it to the whole world.
A bunch of people create
the medicine,
nobody owns the patent,
everyone has access,
and tens of millions of lives
are saved.
It's all of us, not some of us.
I don't make any money
in that scenario.
Oh, no, you're broke as hell.
Yeah, I don't love that part.
I've got it.
LeCLERC
Hé, Zora! Attention!
Uh-oh.
Hey!
Shit.
The sample!
Hey!
Oh!
Kincaid! Pull me up!
- Kincaid! Help!
- LeClerc?!
Hey!
Kincaid! Au secours!
Krebs, pull! Pull!
Pull me up! Pull me up!
You okay?
Yeah. You?
Oh, shi--
Oh! Quick!
Henry!
Pull! Up!
Pull me up!
Kincaid!
Henry!
Henry, stop!
I nearly got it!
Henry, it's gonna snap! Stop!
Hold on! Pull!
Pull!
Oh, shit!
Oh, shit! LeClerc!
Come on! Here!
Stop. Henry! It's gonna split!
I've got it!
Oh, no.
Henry! Henry!
No!
Doc!
You okay?
Let's go home.
Isabella.
Honey.
Let's go.
We're almost there.
I see the helipad.
It's in the middle
of a reservoir.
No sign of the kids, though.
Will they even be able
to find this place?
Hey.
Hey, there's footprints here.
Hello?!
Reuben! Teresa!
Zora, they could be anything.
They could be animals.
- It could be...
- In Nikes?
Listen, I appreciate
what you're doing. I really do.
- But we are
in a crunch right now.
- Hello?!
- And we don't even know
if they survived the rocks.
- Reuben!
- Okay?
- Teresa!
The helicopter's coming.
Well, we'll just have
the pilots do a low pass
over the whole island
while there's still light.
That is an incredibly
dangerous idea.
Well, nobody asked you.
Hello?!
Isabella!
Anyone, please!
Hello?!
Is anyone here?!
Hey! Oh, my God.
- You made it! Oh, God.
- Oh, my God!
- Oh, my God.
- Hi.
- You okay?
-
Thank God you're alive.
Where is he?
No, no, no.
Where is that son of a bitch?
- What? Who?
- That guy. The guy--
- He-he let me fall.
- Yeah, he tried to kill her.
Wait, wait. Who let you fall?
Hey, Krebs!
- I'm gonna kill him!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, no.
He's got a gun, Teresa. No.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hey, let's just settle down,
everybody, okay?
You stopped me
calling for help!
You wanted me to die.
What are you talking about?
I tried to catch you.
No, no, no.
You looked right at me
and you let me fall!
She's lying.
If she's lying,
then why do you have a gun?
Because she's hysterical.
No, I-I'm not hysterical.
I'm homicidal!
- Hey, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- Don't rush the guy with a gun.
- Enough.
Whoa. All right.
All right.
Let's everybody just relax.
Why don't I take that?
It looks heavy.
And... I'll keep it safe
with me.
Now, we're all just gonna relax
and wait here
for the helicopter to arrive.
There's a helicopter coming?
Any minute. We just got
to make sure they see us.
Told you we'd made it.
Then we all get on
the helicopter and we forget
any ridiculous stories
about whatever she said.
-
I think we all need to...
- Stop talking! Stop talking.
It's the generator.
They must be on a timer.
The generator sounds angry.
Maybe this place is deserted
in the daytime.
But not so deserted at night?
♪ When the night has come ♪
♪ And the land is dark ♪
♪ And the moon is the only ♪
♪ Light we'll see ♪
- It's okay, honey.
- ♪ No, I won't ♪
It's okay.
♪ Be afraid ♪
♪ Oh, I won't be afraid ♪
♪ Just as long ♪
♪ As you stand ♪
♪ Stand by me... ♪
Whoa!
Oh, not that thing.
Run!
Split up!
Go. Go, go.
Reuben! Reuben!
Teresa, get the rack!
What are they?
I don't know,
but they're mutant as shit!
Come on, get to the back!
The hell is this place?
It's a lab.
Crossbreeding, mutations.
It's where it all happened.
You're missing it!
Give me the gun!
Get off me!
- Dolores.
-Bella.
You found us.
Bella.
Yummy candy.
I'm gonna eat you all up.
It's okay.
Bella!
Yummy candy.
I'm gonna eat you all up.
Come on.
Come on, come on.
That way. Go, go, go.
Give me that.
Hey. There's a tunnel system.
It goes under the whole island.
The tunnel leads to the ocean.
There's a boat.
It's the helicopter.
I'll get the kids.
You get the pilot's attention.
Don't let them leave, Doc.
Don't let them leave!
I can't see anyone.
Okay.
We circle for two minutes,
then get the hell out.
Caution. Pedestrian ahead.
Shit.
REUBEN
Down the tunnel. Quick.
Okay, go, go, go, go, go.
That way, go.
It's okay. It's okay, Bella.
Come on, come on, come on.
You okay?
Which way do we go?
To the left. Hurry!
- Come on. Go, go, go.
-I'm scared.
Okay, I'm gonna call it.
Let's head home.
Hey! Stop! Hey!
Down here!
Come back!
Wait!
There.
Seven o'clock, low.
I see it! Combing left!
Oh, thank God. Come on.
Duncan!
They're coming back!
Hey!
Quick! Down here!
Loomis!
Kincaid, is that you?
- Reuben!
-Hello?!
- Where are you guys?!
-Hey!
-Down here! Hey!
-Here!
- Hey!
Oh, thank God.
-Get us out of here.
-Wait, wait, wait.
Just wait, wait, wait, wait.
- Whoa, whoa.
- Did you...
did you see that thing?
Get inside. Get inside.
Okay, listen up.
This is a drainage tunnel.
Leads down to the sea.
There's a... a dock with
a boat hanging on it. I saw it.
Wh-What about the helicopter?
No helicopter.
What?
- No.
-Wait.
But what if the boat
doesn't work?
Hey. I'm not gonna let you
get hurt, okay?
All right. Come on.
This way.
Let's get to the dock.
- Shut up!
-Caution.
Pedestrian ahead.
Down the tunnel. Quick.
I don't think
this is the right way, Dad.
Yeah, yeah. Come on. Go, go.
Zora!
Go!
- Are you okay?
- Go, go.
Krebs took the jeep.
If he gets
to the boat before us,
he'll take that, too.
Come on, Z, we got to go.
There's the ocean!
Up there!
Hey, I see the boat.
It's that way.
How do we open the gate?
It's there. It's there.
The control panel.
I-I'll go. I'll go.
Can you fit through?
I'm trying!
Shit.
Maybe we can lift it.
Guys? That thing is back!
Again! All together, lift!
One, two, three!
Hey.
- Hey, hey, hey. Isabella.
- Hey!
- No, no, no. No, no!
- Bella! Bella, wait!
- Bella!
- Come back here! Come here!
-
Careful, Bella. Be careful.
-Isabella!
Find the power button!
Hurry! We have to
open the gate!
It's coming! It's coming!
- Hey!
Hey! Bella! Open the gate!
Excess speed. Slow down.
Caution. Pedestrian ahead.
Go, go, go.
We got to go. We got to go.
- Teresa, come on!
- Come on.
Now, Z, now!
Hurry.
The hoist control's
over there. Go.
How do you get the boat down?
Lower the boat.
But where's the power?
-Here, take this!
-I got it. I got it.
Turn it on.
The hoist is broken.
It's jammed!
Come on, come on!
Bella!
Don't move, honey.
It's attracted to light!
Turn it off! Turn it off!
Give me the flares!
- What the hell are you doing?
- I got it.
- I got it. Go!
- No, no, no!
- What the hell are you doing?
- Hey!
Right here!
You want me?
Come on!
No.
Duncan.
This way! Hey!
Get your sister!
Get out of here! Go!
Come here! This way!
- Come on!
-Duncan!
Duncan!
Hey!
Come on.
Don't wait, Zora!
Get the kids! Go!
- Come on!
- Save them.
Come on!
Shit.
Yeah.
Go. Get in the boat.
Get in the boat.
- Take the helm. Take the helm.
- Grab her, grab her, grab her.
Come on. There's no power.
- Check the power!
- Zora!
Duncan!
- Duncan!
- Zora, come on.
Duncan!
- We have to go.
- Hey...
Come on.
Dad, hurry!
-Go. Come on!
- Dad, hurry!
I'm-I'm trying!
- I'm trying!
-
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
I'm trying!
Reuben!
Come on, please!
Go! Go, push it!
Kincaid!
Duncan!
Dad.
Hey! Hey!
Turn the boat around!
There he is. I see him.
There!
Yeah, there! Go!
Hey!
Who do we give it to?
You decide.
We'll give it to everyone.
Look.