Do you find me sadistic?
You know...
I'll bet I could fry an egg
on your head right now.
If I wanted to.
You know, kiddo...
I'd like to believe
you're aware enough, even now,
to know that there's nothing
sadistic in my actions.
Well, maybe towards those other jokers.
But not you.
No, kiddo.
At this moment...
This is me...
At my most... Masochistic.
Bill...
It's your baby.
Coming!
Sarah, I cannot believe you are early.
What you gonna do now, huh?
What you got?
I got your ass!
Remember that? Huh? Remember?
Okay. Come on, bitch.
Come on. Bring it on.
Mommy, I'm home.
Hey, baby.
How was school?
Mommy, what happened to you
and the TV room?
Oh.
That good-for-nothing dog
of yours got his little ass
in the living room
and acted a damn fool.
That's what happened, baby.
- Barney did this?
- Baby...
Now, you can't come in here.
There's broken glass everywhere,
and you could cut yourself.
This is an old friend of mommy's
I ain't seen in a long time.
Hi, honey.
I'm ...
What's your name?
Her name is Nikki.
Nikki.
Such a pretty name
for such a pretty girl.
How old are you, Nikki?
Nikki...
... asked you a question.
I'm 4.
4 years old, eh?
You know, I had a little girl once.
She'd be about 4 now.
Now, baby, me and mommy's friend
got some grown-up talk
to talk about.
So you can go in your room now.
And I want you to leave us alone
till I tell you to come out.
Okay?
Nikkia!
In your room. Now.
You want some coffee?
Yeah. Sure.
This Pasadena homemaker's name
is Jeanne Bell.
Her husband is Dr. Lawrence Bell.
But back when we were acquainted,
four years ago,
her name was Vernita Green.
Her code name was Copperhead.
Mine, Black Mamba.
Do you have a towel?
Yeah.
Thanks.
You still take cream and sugar, right?
Yeah.
So I suppose it's a little late
for an apology, huh?
You suppose correctly.
Look, bitch, I need to know
if you're gonna start any more
shit around my baby girl.
You can relax for now.
I'm not gonna murder you
in front of your child, okay?
That's being more rational
than Bill led me to believe
you were capable of.
It's mercy, compassion,
and forgiveness I lack.
Not rationality.
Look.
I know I fucked you over.
I fucked you over bad.
I wish to God I hadn't, but I did.
You have every right to want to get even.
No, no, no, no, no.
No.
To get even, even Stephen,
I would have to kill you,
go up to Nikki's room, kill her,
then wait for your husband, the
good Dr. Bell, to come home,
and kill him.
That would be even, Vernita.
That'd be about square.
Look, if I could go back
in a machine, I would.
But I can't.
All I can tell you is that I'm
a different person now.
Oh, great.
I don't care.
Be that as it may,
I know I don't deserve
your mercy or your forgiveness.
However, I beseech you for both
on behalf of my daughter.
Bitch, you can stop right there.
Just because I have no wish to murder you
before the eyes of your daughter
does not mean that parading
her around in front of me
is gonna inspire sympathy.
You and I have unfinished business.
And not a goddamn fucking
thing you've done
in the subsequent four years,
including getting knocked up,
is gonna change that.
So when do we do this?
It all depends.
When do you want to die?
Tomorrow? The day after tomorrow?
How about tonight, bitch?
Splendid. Where?
There's a baseball diamond
where I coach our little league
about a mile from here.
We meet there around 2:30 in the morning,
dressed all in black,
your hair in a black stocking.
And we have us a knife fight.
We won't be bothered.
Now...
I have to fix Nikki's cereal.
Bill always said you were one
of the best ladies he ever saw
with an edged weapon.
Fuck you, bitch.
I know he didn't qualify that shit.
So you can just kiss my
motherfucking ass, Black Mamba.
Black Mamba.
I should have been motherfucking Black Mamba.
Weapon of choice? Hey,
if you want to stick with
your butcher knife,
that's fine with me.
Very funny, bitch.
Very funny!
It was not my intention
to do this in front of you.
For that, I'm sorry.
But you can take my word for it.
Your mother had it coming.
When you grow up...
If you still feel raw about it...
I'll be waiting.
Y'all, come on out to Dallas, ya hear?
This is rockabilly rhythms on KTRN, Wichita Falls.
And next, we got some record.
Very own wild man, Charlie feathers.
Well, give me the gory details, son number one.
It's a goddamn massacre, pop.
They wiped out the whole wedding party,
execution style.
Give me a figure.
Nine dead bodies.
And we're talking the whole shebang.
Bride. Groom.
Reverend.
Reverend's wife.
Hell, they even shot that old colored fella
that plays the organ.
It would appear to me
somebody objected to this union
and wasn't able to hold their peace.
Good gravy, Marie.
What'd I tell you, pop?
It's like a goddamn Nicaraguan death squad.
You better shit-can that blasphemy, boy.
You're in a house of worship.
Sorry, pop.
Well, this is definitely the work of professionals.
I'd guesstimate Mexican mafia hit squad.
Four, maybe five strong.
How can you tell?
Well, a sure and steady hand did this.
This ain't no squirrelly amateur.
This is the work of a salty dog.
You can tell by the cleanliness of the carnage.
Now, a kill-crazy rampage, though it may be,
all the colors are kept inside the lines.
If you was a moron, you could almost admire it.
Who's the bride?
Don't know.
The name on the marriage certificate
is Arlene Machiavelli.
That's a fake.
We've all just been calling her "the bride"
on account of the dress.
You can tell she was pregnant.
Man would have to be a mad dog
to shoot a goddamn good-looking
gal like that in the head.
Look at her.
Hay-colored hair. Big eyes.
She's a little blood-spattered angel.
Son number one?
Yeah?
This tall drink of cocksucker ain't dead.
I might never have liked you.
Point in fact, I despise you.
But that shouldn't suggest
that I don't respect you.
Dying in our sleep is a luxury
that our kind is rarely afforded.
My gift to you.
For fuck's sake.
Hello, Bill.
What's her condition?
Comatose.
Where is she?
I'm standing over her right now.
That's my girl.
Elle, you're going to abort the mission.
What?!
We owe her better than that.
Oh, you don't owe her shit!
Will you keep your voice down?
You don't owe her shit!
May I say one thing?
Speak.
Y'all beat the hell out of that woman.
But you didn't kill her.
And I put a bullet in her head.
But her heart just kept on beating.
Now, you saw that yourself
with your own beautiful blue eye, did you not?
We've done a lot of things to this lady.
And if she ever wakes up, we'll do a whole lot more.
But one thing we won't do
is sneak into her room in the night like a filthy rat
and kill her in her sleep.
And the reason we won't do that thing
is because that thing would lower us.
Don't you agree, Miss Driver?
I guess.
Do you really have to guess?
No.
I don't really have to guess. I know.
Come on home, honey.
Affirmative.
I love you very much.
I love you, too.
Bye-bye.
Thought that was pretty fucking funny, didn't you?
Word of advice, shithead.
Don't you ever wake up.
At this moment, this is me...
At my most masochistic.
Bill, it's your baby.
Oh, my baby.
Four years.
The price is $75 a fuck, my friend.
You getting your freak on or what?
Oh, yeah, boy.
20, 40, 60, 75.
Yeah. Now, here's the rules.
Rule number one.
No punching her.
Nurse comes in tomorrow and she got her a shiner
or less some teeth, jig's up.
So no knuckle sandwiches under no circumstances.
And by the way, this little cunt's a spitter.
It's a motor-reflex thing.
But spit or no, no punching.
Now, are we absolutely, positively clear
- on rule number one?
- Yeah.
Good. Now, rule number two.
No monkey bites, no hickeys.
In fact, no leaving no marks of no kind.
After that, it's all good, buddy.
Now, her plumbing down there don't work no more.
So feel free to come in her all you want.
Keep the noise down. Try not to make a mess.
I'll be back in 20.
Yeah.
Oh, shit.
By the way...
Not all the time, but sometimes
this chick's cooch can get
drier than a bucket of sand.
If she dry, you just lube up with this
and you'll be good to go.
Bon appetit, good buddy.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, god damn.
You are the best-looking girl I've had today.
Yo, stud! Time's up, buddy.
Coming in, ready or not.
Hey, buddy, did you have
yourself a good time, man?
Where's Bill?!
Please stop hitting me.
I don't know who Bill is!
Bullshit!
Well, ain't you the slice
of cutie pie they said you was?
Jane Doe, huh? Oh, we don't know
shit about you, do we?
Well, I'm from Huntsville, Texas.
My name is Buck, and I'm here to fuck.
Your name is Buck.
Right?
And you came here to fuck.
Wait a minute. Wait.
"Pussy wagon."
You fucker.
Texas Okay.
Wiggle your big toe.
As I lay in the back of Buck's truck,
trying to will my limbs out of entropy...
Wiggle your big toe.
...I could see the faces of
the cunts who did this to me.
And the dicks responsible.
Members all of the Deadly Viper
assassination squad.
When fortune smiles on something
as violent and ugly as revenge,
it seems proof like no other
that not only does God exist,
you're doing His will.
At a time when I knew the least
about my enemies,
the first name on my death list,
O-Ren Ishii, was the easiest to find.
But, of course, when one manages the difficult task
of becoming queen of the Tokyo underworld,
one doesn't keep it a secret, does one?
O-Ren Ishii was born
on an American military base
in Tokyo, Japan.
The half-Japanese, half-chinese
American army brat
made her first acquaintance
with death at the age of nine.
It was at that age she witnessed
the death of her parents at the hands
of Japan's most ruthless
Yakuza boss, Boss Matsumoto.
Mommy.
She swore revenge.
Luckily for her,
Boss Matsumoto was a pedophile.
At 11, she got her revenge.
By 20, she was one of the top female
assassins in the world.
At 25, she did her part in the killing
of nine innocent people,
including my unborn daughter,
in a small wedding chapel
in el Paso, Texas.
But on that day four years ago
she made one big mistake.
She should have killed 10.
However, before satisfaction would be mine,
first things first.
Wiggle your big toe.
Hard part's over.
Now, let's get these other piggies wiggling.
Welcome to Air O. May I help you?
Okinawa. One-way.
Hi.
You English?
Almost. American.
American. Welcome, American.
Domo.
My English very good.
You said "domo." Can you speak Japanese?
No, no.
Just a few words I learned since yesterday.
Um, may I sit at the bar?
Oh, sure, sure, sure. Please sit.
What other words did you learn?
Oh, just a minute.
Shut up!
Get your ass out here!
Uh, excuse me.
Uh, what other Japanese do you know?
Oh, let's see.
Um, "arigato."
"Arigato." Good!
I already said "domo", right?
"Konn-itch-iwa."
"Kohn-nee-chee-wah."
Konnichi wa. Please repeat.
Konnichi wa.
Perfect.
Good, good, good.
You say Japanese word like you Japanese.
Oh, now you're making fun of me!
No, no, no, no. Serious business.
Pronunciation very good.
You say arigato like we say arigato.
Well, thank you. I mean...
Arigato.
You should learn Japanese.
Very easy.
No kidding. I heard it was kind of hard.
Most difficult.
But you have Japanese tongue.
Okay, okay.
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
Oh. Oh, my god.
I beg your pardon?
Uh, drink.
Oh, yes.
Um, a bottle of warm sake, please.
Warm sake?
Very good!
Do you understand?
Do you understand me?
Sorry.
Oh! Oh, oh. First time in Japan?
What brings you to Okinawa?
I came to see a man.
Oh, yeah.
You have a friend live in Okinawa?
Not quite.
Not friend?
I never met him.
Never?
Who is he?
May I ask?
Hattori Hanzo.
You must have big rats,
you need Hattori Hanzo's steel.
Huge.
May I?
You may.
Wait.
Try the second one down.
Funny.
You like samurai swords...
I like baseball.
Then give me one of these.
These are not for sale.
I didn't say "sell me."
I said "give me."
Why should I help you?
Because my vermin is a former student of yours.
And considering the student,
I'd say you have a rather large obligation.
Domo.
It was one year after
the massacre in el Paso, Texas,
that Bill backed his nippon progeny
financially and philosophically in her
shakespearean-in-magnitude power struggle
with the other Yakuza clans
over who would rule vice in the city of Tokyo.
When the final sword was sheathed,
it was O-Ren Ishii and her powerful posse...
... The crazy 88, that proved the victor.
The pretty lady to O-Ren's right,
who's dressed like she's a villain on "Star Trek",
is O-Ren's lawyer, best friend,
and second lieutenant
the half-French, half-Japanese Sofie Fatale
another former protegee of Bill's.
The young girl in the school-girl uniform
is O-Ren's personal bodyguard, 17-year-old Gogo Yubari.
Gogo may be young, but what she lacks in age,
she makes up for in madness.
See what I mean?
The bald guy in the black suit
and the Kato mask is Johnny Mo,
the head general of O-Ren's
personal army, The Crazy 88.
And just in case you were wondering
how could a half-breed Japanese-Chinese American
become the boss of all bosses in Tokyo, Japan...
I'll tell you.
The subject of O-Ren's blood and nationality
came up before the council only once
the night O-Ren assumed power over the crime council.
The man who seems bound and determined
to break the mood is Boss Tanaka.
And what Boss Tanaka thinks is...
As your leader...
...I encourage you from time to time,
and always in a respectful manner,
to question my logic.
If you're unconvinced
a particular plan of action I've decided is the wisest,
tell me so.
But allow me to convince you.
And I promise you, right here and now,
no subject will ever be taboo.
Except, of course, the subject
that was just under discussion.
The price you pay
for bringing up either my Chinese or American heritage
as a negative is...
I collect your fucking head.
Just like this fucker here.
Now, if any of you sons of bitches
got anything else to say, now is the fucking time!
I didn't think so.
One ticket to Tokyo, please.
Hello.
Gogo.
So, O-Ren...
Any more subordinates for me to kill?
Hi!
Bingo.
Gogo...
I know you feel you must protect your mistress.
But I beg you...
Walk away.
Is that what I think it is?
You didn't think it was gonna be that easy, did you?
You know, for a second there,
yeah, I kind of did.
Silly rabbit.
Trix are for...
Kids.
This is what you get
for fucking around with Yakuzas!
Go home to your mother!
Except you, Sofie!
You stay right where you are.
Your instrument is quite impressive.
Okinawa.
This is Hattori Hanzo steel.
Silly Caucasian girl likes to play with samurai swords.
You may not be able to fight like a samurai...
But you can at least die like a samurai.
Sofie...
My Sofie...
I'm so sorry.
Please. Please forgive my betrayal.
No more of that.
But still...
But still nothing...
Except my aching heart over what she's done
to my beautiful and brilliant Sofie.
I've kept you alive for two reasons.
The first reason is information.
But I am gonna ask you questions.
And every time you don't give me answers,
I'm gonna cut something off.
And I promise you,
they will be things you will miss!
Give me your other arm!
I want all the information on the Deadly Vipers.
If you had to guess...
What they've been doing...
...Why she left you alive...
...And where I can find them.
...What would be your guess?
Guessing won't be necessary.
She informed me.
She... she said I could keep my wicked life
for two reasons.
As I said before,
I've allowed you to keep your
wicked life for two reasons.
And the second reason is...
So you can tell him, in person,
everything that happened here tonight.
I want him to witness the extent of my mercy
by witnessing your deformed body.
I want you to tell him
all the information you just told me.
I want him to know what I know.
I want him to know I want him to know.
And I want them all to know
they'll all soon be as dead as O-Ren.
That woman...
Deserves her revenge.
And...
We deserve to die.
She must suffer to her last breath.
How did you find me?
I'm the man.
One more thing, Sofie.
Is she aware her daughter is still alive?