Show off.
Elder Luna says make your heart still.
The right egg will sing to you.
Elder Luna is elder.
Three.
Only three.
We take them all.
No. Never.
Leave one always.
That is the law.
Bonding day is tomorrow.
These are yours.
You are older.
- By length of a sunset.
- Is older.
Soona.
Which one sings to you?
This one.
Silk.
We will raise them together.
Like we were raised.
It will be the same.
Yes?
Go, go, go.
- Noa!
- Noa, wait!
Whoa!
It's too far.
Find another way.
Noa?
No!
Yeah!
Noa!
Anaya! Soona!
- Noa!
- No!
Do you wonder
what your bird will look like?
Long as it does not look like you,
Anaya.
Scared.
Blanket missing.
What is it, Noa?
Something in trees.
It's getting away.
Outsiders.
Noa scared.
Not Anaya.
Not ape.
Maybe…
Echo?
Echo do not come in from Valley.
Oh.
Were you scared?
Not as scared as Anaya!
They're back! They're back!
Soona!
Did you get your eggs?
- How far did you climb?
- Was it dangerous?
Very dangerous.
Anaya wailed like a newborn.
How many eggs did you honor?
- Show us the egg.
- Did you climb well?
- Show us your egg.
Egg. Egg. Egg.
Show us, Anaya, please?
- Who want?
- Me, me, me!
Aw!
Come on. Come on. Give, give! Hey!
Son.
Show me.
All must wait for bonding.
Even Honored Teacher.
I am your mother.
I knew you would climb well.
He waits.
Broken?
Time for that later.
Your father will want to see.
He will be proud.
- Noa.
Noa, didn't think you'd make it back.
Too firm.
Yes. Yes, Koro.
Father. Master of Birds.
Noa.
Son.
Sun Eagle does not like work
for tomorrow's ceremony.
You climb well?
Above Top Nest.
Huh. All of you?
No.
Only me.
What that smell?
You did not go to the Valley Beyond?
Never.
Is forbidden.
Yet blood of Echo on your blanket.
We did not go to Valley Beyond.
I accept.
You are true, Noa.
Much to learn.
Much to teach.
After tomorrow's bonding.
Now, Elders must know.
Echoes only bring trouble.
Oda will chase the pests away.
May I seek your counsel?
This blanket had the blood
of an Echo on it.
Echo.
And I apologize for that.
This is a bad sign for all of us.
That smell.
And my suggestion would be…
You climbed Top Nest?
Hard climb.
Ah, yes.
Could be dangerous.
Danger.
Anaya!
You see your father?
I do not understand Eagle Sun.
I do. He hate Noa.
Noa.
Your blanket?
With Elders.
They send Oda to scare Echo away.
Yes, Elder.
When mother was small…
dry season shrank creek.
Echo range for food.
She saw a small and a big.
We have good rain.
Her words.
Ride true, Oda.
No.
Our bonding is at sunrise.
Master of Birds will make exception.
They will not make him wait
for next season.
Yes, he will.
He is your father.
And I am his son.
Then I will wait with you.
Anaya wait too.
You cannot.
I must find another.
Noa.
Oda!
There are…
more.
What happened here?
Our scouts.
Killed by him.
Human.
It is her.
Lightning, back on your horse.
Spread out!
Find his clan.
Search in all directions!
The ape's horse!
Lightning, come!
They cannot be far.
Follow the horse! Find his clan!
Find human!
Ride!
Go, go, go!
Round them up!
No! No! Please!
You, prisoner!
Burn it down.
Soona! Anaya!
Noa, help!
Noa!
Anaya! Mother!
Where Soona?
They took her.
They broke my egg.
Mother.
Help your father!
No! No!
Noa!
No!
Run, Noa! Run!
Help your father!
Go, Noa! Run!
No!
He their Elder.
For Caesar!
Take them to Proximus!
Find the human!
Caesar! Caesar!
- Father.
- Son.
I'm sorry. It's my fault.
Noa, free all birds.
Go.
Bend your head.
Noa.
For Caesar.
Father…
I will find them.
I will bring them home.
Mother.
Sun.
Come, Sun.
How young you are.
Without your mask.
Without this.
Speak up.
Not mine.
No mask.
I am not…
them.
Explain yourself.
They killed my father.
Stole my village.
I follow their tracks.
He was my village.
They killed him.
The Masks.
I am Raka.
I am Noa.
Apes falling from the sky. Hmm.
He was outside when they arrived.
Did you see my clan?
No.
I hid.
I survived.
I protected our work.
They are an ancient way to store ideas.
The symbols have meaning.
Apes understood this meaning…
in the time of Caesar.
The Masks, in my village…
said that name…
"Caesar."
Shameful.
The Masks take his name.
Twist his words.
Who is he?
Not "is."
"Was."
Your clan does not know the true Caesar.
Too many have forgotten who he was.
I know Elders of my village.
They made the law.
That is everything.
That is not everything.
Long before your Elders…
it was Caesar who taught us
what it means to be ape.
He was our leader, our lawgiver.
Apes together strong.
Ape shall not kill ape.
We, the Order of Caesar…
follow his words.
To this day…
I follow.
I am now…
the last.
The work continues.
What is this place?
We believe apes built this…
as a refuge for humans.
Now it is rare to see even one.
But in Caesar's time,
there were vast herds of them.
Can you imagine?
Perhaps here,
humans were cared for, fed…
maybe even taught.
What is it?
Echo.
Human.
You have seen one?
One.
They are scavengers.
Like boars.
Only lesser.
Humans are slow-witted, but…
there was a time…
when humans and apes lived side by side.
Yes, it is a puzzle. I know. But…
they were important to Caesar. Hmm.
So they are important to me.
I have to get to my horse.
Of course.
Follow me.
You do not know Caesar.
You do not know books.
You should stay here.
There is much I could teach you.
Go away!
- No! Come back!
- Pest!
Wait! Come back!
There is no danger.
That is the one.
Stole from my village.
She follows you from your village?
Perhaps Caesar bids me travel.
Wait here. The work continues.
I have no time for…
I will not slow you down.
I, too, keep a horse.
Can we not slow down?
No.
I am sure she follows.
I do not know why.
A beautiful bird!
Eagle Sun.
My father's bird.
He follows to taunt me.
This bird follows you too?
We raise eagles, my clan.
Sing to them…
so they know us.
A bond.
Sing the song.
Please.
No.
My father was Master of Birds.
He sang to eagles.
But I am not him.
Shame.
I would have enjoyed a song.
Strange weapons.
Broken.
Raka.
Noa.
She follows because she is hungry.
No, no, no.
This is…
important.
They get cold.
Show mercy.
She is smarter than most.
We will name her Nova.
We name them all Nova.
I do not know why.
It is from Caesar's time.
Why did Caesar care so much for Echoes?
Legend says he was reared by them…
impossible as that may seem.
Caesar legend is important.
He was first Elder.
He led with decency…
morality…
strength…
compassion.
Caesar never had to share camp…
with this Nova.
The smell is potent.
A tunnel that eats light?
She saw what I saw.
It was in her eyes.
She…
reacted.
How?
As ape would.
- If Echo comes, she must ride.
- Hmm.
Is my young companion showing compassion
for our fellow traveler?
She is slow.
Horse.
Then, of course, there is the gibbon.
Very, very long arms.
Is most unfortunate that the human can
only use its feet for walking.
Imagine if you were falling from a tree.
You only have two appendages
to save your life.
But if you were able to use
both of your hands…
and both of your feet…
that's four times the safety.
And I imagine that,
if I came across a special…
What is that?
Horses with stripes.
Quite striking.
We feared the herds ceased to exist.
Will you not say goodbye?
I must find my clan.
The Nova stays with her kind.
You raise them up.
Follow Caesar's word.
To remember…
who he was.
It is important.
They are like you.
Would you like to join them?
He has his journey.
We have ours.
Come.
Nova!
Take them!
Ride them down!
Catch that one!
This one? Hyah!
There!
Spread out.
Lightning.
This way.
Find her!
I know she here!
Raka!
Nova!
Come out!
I smell you!
Raka!
Noa!
Hyah!
Raka!
Caesar will forgive.
Shall we continue?
This should give us time.
What did I miss?
She spoke.
She called my name.
You misheard.
You said this Nova
was smarter than most.
Within reason.
Some intelligence, to be sure, but…
I have a name.
Mae.
I know where they're taking your clan.
It's a human settlement.
It's where I'm headed to.
Looking for more like me.
There are more…
like you?
There used to be more.
You hid the truth?
My mother taught me silence…
for my safety.
You were safe with us.
And still not true.
Where is your mother now?
I am alone.
Huh.
As are we all.
But now…
we have each other.
Ah.
Let us have a fire.
We have much to discuss.
Go back.
Go back!
Noa!
Mae!
No!
Hold on!
Mae!
No! Raka!
Raka!
Together…
strong.
Stand back! Human!
No! No! No!
Welcome home, baby bird.
Go!
Noa?
Noa!
I missed you. Soona. Soona.
No.
You were dead.
I… I saw you fall.
You are not hurt?
No.
Mother?
Anaya?
Vonnegut.
That's a good one.
Not a lot of fiction there.
He's mostly interested in history.
Roman history, especially.
The name's Trevathan.
Where, uh…
Where are you from?
You first.
Well, doesn't really matter, does it?
I left.
Same as you.
Made it almost to the coast
and then I fell and shattered my ankles.
That's where Proximus found me.
And now you read him Roman history.
So, who are you?
I'm the human not helping the apes.
Noa.
Share. Must share.
Good.
Noa?
- Noa!
- You're alive!
Father…
he's…
I know.
We must go.
Come.
Caesar!
Caesar! Caesar! Caesar!
What a wonderful day!
Are we thankful for the words of Caesar?
We are thankful.
Do we bend our heads?
We bend!
Say his words!
Apes together strong!
What a wonderful day!
That felt good.
When I think on those words…
I feel good.
Caesar was first Elder.
Now I am Caesar.
He is not Caesar.
Careful, son. We are his now.
Now, when I think of all the treasures
left inside for us…
Oh…
I feel very good.
It may be difficult to open.
But not impossible…
because we work together.
All as one.
As Caesar wanted.
As Caesar required.
Apes together strong!
Pull!
Pull! More!
Watch this.
- Pull!
Pull!
Yes!
More!
Enough!
Maybe stronger tomorrow.
Don't worry.
Whoever's in there
is either dead or gone.
We've been bangin'
on that door for months.
Do you not know where we are?
When things got bad
and the government went underground,
this is where half of it went.
With all their technology,
and all their weapons…
Don't you understand?
That ape cannot have
what is inside the…
You gotta stop thinking
about the way things were
and start thinking
about the way they are.
This is a good life,
and you have a chance
to be a part of it.
What, and build a world for the apes?
It is already their world.
There's hot water and fresh clothes
in that room back there.
You'll feel better
when you get yourself cleaned up.
You better figure out
how to be useful around here.
Honored Elder…
had to bend.
We had no choice.
You must accept.
It is law.
The Elders did not tell us everything
about this world.
They did not tell us
because they did not know.
They did not want to know.
You are different.
Come.
And that's why
they call it a toga party.
You are a funny little human, Trevathan.
Hey, come.
Come, sit.
Please.
Go.
Wonderful day, yes?
You two have come a long way.
An ape and a human
traveling together is…
quite an adventure.
You are Noa, yes?
Welcome, Noa.
Go.
Mae…
you are familiar with the concept of…
evolution?
That is the human label, yeah?
The advancement
that I crave requires time.
Vast amounts of time that I do not have.
Unfortunately, I am but a mortal ape.
So this is why I need
to get the knowledge inside that vault.
I believe it will deliver
instant evolution.
Hmm. Noa.
You don't understand.
In their time,
humans were capable
of many great things, yes?
They could level mountains.
They could speak across oceans.
They could fly, Noa.
Like eagles fly.
But now, we will learn.
Apes will learn. I will learn, yeah,
from what is inside that vault.
It's impossible.
No one's getting in there.
Mae, Mae, Mae, Mae.
My apes encountered your companions.
I believe this map belonged to you.
You see, Noa,
before she was traveling with you
and that old orangutan,
Mae was with other humans.
But sadly,
my apes did not realize their value,
so I was brought only bodies.
I could not speak to them
like I can speak to you.
I know…
you are coming here
to get inside my vault.
It is not yours!
Oh.
It is now, isn't it?
And I will get inside.
No matter how many apes it costs me.
Noa.
I…
I have heard that you are
a very clever ape, yeah?
Very clever.
He repaired one of your broken staffs,
Trevathan.
I have much use for clever apes.
Now, can you tell me…
did Mae tell you
how to get inside my vault?
She told me nothing.
Told you nothing!
Nothing.
Told you nothing.
Noa.
Come. Come with me.
Come, come.
I have something to show you.
Come. Come.
Come, Noa.
Tell me, what do you see?
Stolen clans.
Not clans.
A kingdom.
Noa, a kingdom for apes.
Humans can never be trusted.
Where there are two that can speak,
there must be more.
Mae has come here to claim
the tools inside my vault.
Tools that make humans strong
and make them dangerous.
That is why I must have them first.
Yeah?
They do not understand
that this is our time.
This is my kingdom.
I must destroy their kind.
Unless we want to live in cages again.
Come.
Come, Noa.
Let us eat.
Trevathan!
Tell us a story.
Make it a funny one.
They will not come.
Why?
Because Eagle Clan…
is gone.
Eagle Clan is here.
We are here.
In land of Proximus.
And Proximus has no need for eagles.
You come to judge me?
I judge myself.
I promised our father
I would bring them home.
I failed.
Eagle Clan belongs
to Proximus Caesar now.
That is the law.
But the law is wrong.
Time for the evening lesson.
It would be very good for you
to be there.
You did not come for Echoes.
And you were not alone.
I'm sorry.
Proximus's apes found our camp.
They killed everyone.
I barely escaped.
I needed your help.
- And I was afraid.
- The more you speak,
the less I believe.
I was wrong not to trust you.
And I know that now.
I trust you only to help yourself.
But that could help me now.
I have questions.
You answer true,
maybe I help.
What do you need inside vault?
It's…
like a book.
- A special book.
- How?
Special?
Humans lost their ability to speak.
And this book might bring it back.
A book can do this?
This one can.
Raka said apes and humans
lived side by side.
True or not true?
Apes were silent.
Like the Echo.
Humans were dominant.
The virus spread…
that we created.
It made apes smarter.
And it almost killed all of us.
You know a way inside, yes?
Yes.
One last question.
Will water destroy what is inside?
Noa.
I need your help.
What help?
A climb.
One I cannot do alone.
Why?
To free our clan.
Anaya scared.
Soona, this is Mae.
Hello, Soona.
What do we do?
We're gonna need all of this.
Follow me.
Careful.
The power runs through, yes?
Yes.
You cannot make hard climb…
without Anaya.
Hello, Echo.
This burns hot.
But under pressure,
it will explode.
How do you know this?
Oh, shit.
"Shit"?
- Take that over there.
- Okay.
I go with Anaya.
Safer that way.
Anaya! Anaya. Stop.
- You're doing it wrong.
- Okay.
You like her.
Soona.
We were born within a sunset.
No. Anaya…
He's just going to rebuild it.
You…
You had an opportunity.
I gave you an opportunity.
But you're fantasizing about a past
that can never come back.
Listen to me.
Trevathan, you don't belong here.
You think it's over,
but it's not.
Nobody is going to blame you
for what happened here.
Just come with us.
Please?
He's gonna skin your monkey alive.
And you…
Well…
you're gonna learn.
Oh, no.
Please!
We need to go.
It'll be light soon.
You said there would be climb!
Mae, wait!
Mae!
There!
We need to go up there.
Now we climb?
Easier than Top Nest.
Keep climbing.
Noa!
Shit?
Mm-hmm.
Wait. Careful.
Oops.
Anaya!
Noa, what is this place?
It smells.
What is that? Noa!
Noa! What happening?
Echo build all this?
Wait here.
Mama!
The symbols have meaning.
Time to go.
Whoa. What are they?
Come!
We'll have to move fast.
You go to your clan
and I'll trigger the explosion.
Noa, you are a very useful ape.
You understand so many things.
And yet, you fail to observe
one of the most important.
You cannot trust a human!
Here comes your clan to bear witness.
You may be fool enough
to put your faith
in such a duplicitous creature.
But I am not.
Tell me, Noa,
ape to ape,
what did Mae have planned
for me inside my own vault?
Okay.
So what do you choose?
A human over an ape?
Your sweet little Soona…
…or that stinky human?
Tell me your plan!
No!
I see.
You can leave, Mae.
You can go.
You're free. Just tell me…
are there more of those in there?
Mae?
Mae.
No.
We cannot.
He can't have it.
Mae.
- I'm sorry.
- Mae!
No!
Mae, no!
Mae!
What have you done?
Climb.
Climb!
- Climb!
- No.
No!
Noa! Noa!
- Soona!
- Behind you!
Climb!
Son! Son!
- Mother!
- Son!
Mother! Mother!
Mother!
Dar!
Grab her!
Dar! Grab my hand!
- Mother!
- Dar!
Dar!
Dar, got you.
Noa, what we do?
This way! Go!
Eagle Clan! Climb!
Follow Soona! Follow Anaya!
- This way! Climb!
- Go. Go.
Climb!
This way!
Hurry!
Follow Soona!
- Hurry! Hurry!
- Go!
- Come.
Climb, Soona!
This the way out!
Hurry!
- Climb!
- Noa!
Mother, go!
- Climb, Anaya!
- Soona, go!
- Lead them!
Go! Climb!
Go! Go, hurry!
You think you can destroy my kingdom?
You think you can destroy what I am?
- Noa!
- Leave him.
Noa.
You showed so much promise.
You are going to stand,
so that you can bend for your king…
before you die.
And you will all bear witness
as Noa bends before his king.
Now stand.
Stand now!
That's it.
Clever ape.
What is this?
Trevathan would love this.
Enough!
Let us go home.
He's coming!
Soft?
Too firm.
- Silk.
- Good.
Noa.
I came to say goodbye.
Proximus was right.
Humans will never give up.
Not until you claim all things
for yourselves.
It was ours.
That silo was a human place
with human things and human ideas.
It was not meant for apes.
What is for apes?
Should we go back to silence?
We will rebuild our home.
Better.
Stronger.
From what we have learned.
If Raka were here,
he would tell us his Caesar
had much to say on this.
Was he right?
Can ape and human live together?
I don't know.
Important.
See you soon.
Come.
Rescaling back down to 20.
New latitude point, 2.722.
Copy that. Spooling up.
Let me know
what that distribution looks like.
Let's get over here.
Readings have been confirmed.
- Link is ready!
- Pulling up now.
Hello.
Is anyone there?
Come on.
Do you hear me?
Yes, hello?
This is Fort Wayne, Indiana.
We read you!
It's good to hear
another voice out there.
Tell me where you are.
What's your location?