Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Ya know Ousmane Dembélé?
I got fifty on Mbappé.
What's up?
Gonna watch the game?
Bet you five that Mbappé scores.
You're crazy.
Double score. Bet you five bucks!
Go the Blues, go the Blues!
I like your hairdo,
real nice.
You use engine oil
or it's naturally greasy?
Know what?
Let's call new guy "Greaser".
Dig it. Approved!
Not a big fan.
Greetings gents.
Go France!
Fuck off!
Greaser, listen up.
We're in the Bosquets, you heard of it?
Before it was inaccessible to us.
A prime drug spot.
There was hash, coke, then heroin.
It ruined the hood.
All the OGs died.
Then the M. bros cleaned things up.
Muslim Brotherhood?
Yeah, the SCU.
As in Street Crime Unit?
Smack Combat Unit.
That's what we call them.
Prostitution is the new plague,
run by Nigerians.
They rent flats for 400 euros.
Hookers turn tricks
for 10 to 20 euros.
Blowjobs are 2 euros.
Got 2 euros?
What's up prick face?
How's Bert and Ernie?
Can't complain.
I left a mess at your house.
Your wife's face broke the armrest...
You fool.
You good?
You didn't pick the winning team.
You're working
with the two biggest clowns.
My advice,
do night shifts,
join the elite force.
Know why you ride nights?
You know?
Cuz you the ugliest.
Know who else rides?
Don't bother calling me!
You keep him. He drives me crazy...
He drives me crazy, get it?
If you had kids, you'd get it.
I keep telling him, over and over.
He messes up, he's on his own now!
What did he do now?
Stole a bag full of hens.
Live chickens?
That's right.
From a gypsy who turned his garage
into a chicken coop.
To sell or eat?
What do I know?
He doesn't care about anything.
You hear me?
Set yourself up over there.
Nice pig collection.
"Pink Pig", that's his nickname
and he's proud of it.
100% swine!
So, not gonna miss the cows?
What?
- The cows.
- No, why?
You from the countryside?
No, not gonna miss it.
New beginnings for you.
You never served with the SCU?
I was a first responder,
then trained with the SCU.
So why did you come here?
My ex, also a cop,
was transferred.
She has custody of our son
and I want see him more,
so I followed her.
That's why.
Don't start!
My favorite read.
Shit life
The backstreet boys!
The matriarch.
Corporal Ruiz.
Captain Chandier, pleasure.
- Treating you well?
- Great.
Perfect.
35ọC forecast for today.
Apply sunscreen.
Well, well.
Family's growing.
30ọC, people would be on the streets,
hanging out, it'd be chaos.
But 35ọC is perfect, they stay in...
and rest.
Smooth.
You shave?
I kept my baby skin.
I'm jealous.
Let's enjoy the victory
while everyone's happy.
Corporal, see me in my office.
France is on its cloud nine.
Chris, come too.
Chris is your unit sergeant.
He has solid field experience.
He's...
Let's see...
What would you say?
Sharp, reactive?
Goes overboard sometimes?
You can't be shy around here.
Know that I don't approve
of inappropriate behavior.
- Understood?
- Absolutely.
Good.
I appeal to your sense of duty,
Corporal Ruiz.
Your team spirit. Solidarity.
No solidarity, no team.
No team, we are alone.
Alone against...
What would you say, Chris?
The brutality of our world.
I couldn't have said it better.
Dismissed.
Greaser,
sit in the back.
Eyes open, mouth shut.
Can we lose the nickname?
Greaser. Told you to zip it.
Beat it! You stink.
Watch your mouth.
Sorry, Pop.
Out of bed now!
I'm on vacation!
Don't argue, vacation or not.
Get up now.
Watch it. Riot Police.
Running away from us?
Young brothers, little food for thought.
Right?
Success now and beyond depends on Allah
and Mohammed's path.
We, Muslim Brothers,
are here to talk. Bismilah.
As-Salaam-Alaikum young brothers.
Y'all okay?
We came today to discuss complaints
regarding your behavior.
At the mosque,
your neighbors complain about you.
In Islam, one's behavior
is very important.
Towards yourselves, your elders, us,
your parents, and your neighbors.
Especially your neighbors.
You must respect your elders,
and most of all mothers and fathers.
Understood?
Yes.
We can count on you?
After the prayer, inshallah,
join us at the mosque for a snack.
Cake, candies, soft drinks...
and a little class.
Does that work for you guys?
Are we good?
Alright little brothers.
See the guy at the bus stop?
That one.
Looks normal, right?
He's a threat to national security.
His beard used to be that long.
Spent three years in Syria
beheading people.
A Quran and an AK on him at all times.
See that guy with the cap?
Don't stare! You crazy?
He threw his chatty wife
out the window.
Thankfully she survived.
Illegals over there.
So cholera, typhus...
Always wear gloves.
You never know.
One of the boys caught tetanus
while frisking.
You fucking with me?
Greaser...
Fun cultural fact.
Know why the school's called
Victor Hugo?
He wrote Les Misérables here.
We got a brain on board.
You read the novel?
I saw it on the town's website.
Things haven't changed much.
Except that Gavroche is now "Gavaracha".
"Gavaracha, come herr."
"Right now."
Cosette is now "Coozette".
Her mom works at the post office.
Always tired...
She works too much.
Coozette...
Check out Owl.
What up, scoundrels?
Owl, they let you out?
It was about time.
How long were you in?
Four years.
We put you in, remember?
Can't forget your face,
I don't like it.
No choice. Just doing our job.
Can't change job?
No. You pretty in that suit.
Looking for a job.
Really? What kind of job?
Landscaping, trimming, pruning...
Okay.
- It rhymes.
- Right.
- You still rap?
- Always, but no trap.
Give us some bars, old school.
Pull trigger, tension bigger
Check my take, state mistake
Politics reprobate, riots create
Misdemeanor at stake
Just the son of an expatriate
State won't renovate
my building, district
Change my ways if that's all it takes
District 93.
- Sounds nice.
- Not bad?
- Wise words you speak.
- Right.
You still need to get a job though.
Of course.
- Your rap is...
- The bomb!
You alright, Owl. Good luck.
Same to you.
Wow, it got to him.
Prison killed him.
An old client.
50 bucks I collar him within six months.
I'll buy you a drink.
Hey, Kirikou!
He keeps at it!
He wants to go to the ER.
He's headed there.
He will, his head's about to bleed.
I forgot to tell you.
When I was back home,
with my family, in my village...
I was falling asleep.
I heard a noise,
a guy tried to steal a scooter.
- No scooters in the bush.
- Of course there are!
Come on, shut up.
Some guys grabbed him.
I was in shock.
They held him down.
Tied him up and set him on fire.
Traumatizing.
Come on...
Swear to Allah.
They burned him alive.
You know how dust blows away?
Same with his ashes.
Crazy dangerous over there.
You get caught stealing, you die.
Told ya so!
What's up?
- How you boys doing?
- Good.
Looking nice.
What can I get you?
Tortillas...
1 panini, 2 grilled cheeses, 2 cokes
- 1 hamburger.
- 1 snickers.
- 2 corns.
- Wait.
That's a big order.
How much you got?
12 euros.
- How much?
- 12 euros.
Not gonna happen.
Go away.
We played sport, we're hungry.
Out of here, scram.
- Come on, Uncle.
- No good.
Goodbye.
Join the circus
and watch international talents.
Acrobats, jugglers, wild animals...
Maybe they'll hire you as a clown.
You're a funny guy.
Look at that.
Let's inspect them.
What did they do?
Wake up, fellows! I smell smoke.
Gwada, U-turn.
Let's palpate...
I'll frisk you
With passion
Gun it.
Let's pop Greaser's cherry.
Hello ladies.
Police check.
What you doing?
Waiting for the bus.
- What?
- Waiting for the bus.
Really?
That yours?
How old are you?
Fifteen.
Fifteen?
And you already smoke?
Smells like hash.
Where'd you hide it?
You have no right!
I do what I want. Where is it?
State of emergency,
I can stick a finger up your ass.
- Sir.
- Shut up!
You have no right.
- Want me to arrest you?
- You have no right!
- Leave it.
- I'll handle it.
Where's it from?
Want me to keep looking?
What's that?
You're breaking the law.
Stop filming!
Happy now?
Bitch!
Beat it!
Quit smoking. It's bad for you.
Buzz!
Get your ass over here.
You filmed me in my room?
No, I swear.
It wasn't your drone at my window?
Didn't know you were home.
Give me your phone.
Give it! Hurry, Buzz!
You filmed all the girls?
You're a real pervert.
I'm shocked.
Oh shit, he filmed Salimata!
That hoe, check it out.
She's pathetic.
Send it to me.
I'll put her on blast.
Me too.
What a hoe!
If you ever try to film me,
I'll fuck you up.
You'd better not.
Send me this video
and delete the others, got it?
What you doing tomorrow?
Nothing.
We got a basketball game at ten.
- Can you come?
- Sure.
You gonna film the game.
Okay.
- Speak up.
- Okay.
Counting on you.
You'd better be there, Buzz.
- Got it?
- Yes.
Let's go, girls.
Jojo. My buddy.
The boys in blue!
- What up?
- Chilling.
What's good with y'all?
Grilling under the sun.
For us?
Want a steak?
Tell me.
We're good. Already ate.
- Okay.
- Be safe now.
Same to you.
Later, Jojo.
Fellas, almost done!
What's with the vests?
They work for the mayor.
When elevators break down,
they bring up groceries
with fishing lines, like in prison.
Anyway...
It's good the mayor does that.
We gotta pay him a visit.
That prick?
Why is he a prick?
The mayor's a prick?
That retard you just saw?
He's the mayor's brother.
The mayor's black?
Yup.
Our very own Obama.
You spoke to the Paki?
Yup, all good.
Starting to bust my balls.
He's alright.
Last time I saw him,
he was talking slick.
And the new fruit vendor.
The new guy?
He's a softie.
Good.
He'll get the Ballon d'Or.
The young Mbappé?
No. Modric will get it.
Not certain.
Mbappé...
He's in another galaxy.
He's a mirage.
See that, all fake.
Knock-offs...
- I can prove it's not.
- Real fake, then?
This one's not bad.
Partial fake.
Half fake, half real?
- I have invoices.
- Really?
How much?
35 euros.
Word? Can I borrow money?
You extended your stand?
Thanks, have a nice day.
How much? 9 yards?
Come on ladies, take advantage.
Everything's on sale.
Here's 22.
For real, an ice cream truck
would be great.
Instant success.
For people here, not 5,
but 1-euro ice creams.
Plus our tax.
Kids would like that.
- What's going on?
- What's happening?
Went well today?
Aside from Amar acting out.
Gonna take care of that guy.
Let him act a fool.
- Alright, brothers.
- Peace.
Look who's coming.
Can't stand that ugly motherfucker.
Mr Mayor, how are things?
Not good, brother.
If Amar keeps busting my balls,
gonna kick him out.
What did he do?
I keep telling him.
He takes up too much room.
Want me to talk to him?
Up to you.
Or I'll handle it my way.
Handle what?
That's our job, not yours.
Talk to him, please.
Handle your detergent,
fake jerseys and watermelons.
Fall back.
Not gonna introduce us?
- Introduce yourself.
- Gentlemen.
Hello.
Go on, don't be shy.
What's your name?
Corporal Ruiz.
- Nice to meet you, Ruiz.
- Pleasure.
Don't look at me. He's talking to you.
Leave the new guy alone.
He won't last long.
You checked for what I asked for?
That thing?
Seeing my cousin later.
I don't want fake shit.
When did I ever give you fake shit?
In its original box. For my wife.
"Ever give you fake shit?"
Shut your trap!
Have a nice day.
Gentlemen.
Red Power Ranger!
Where are the others?
That bum ass.
Matter of time before I fuck'm up.
That's what he wants.
Don't fall for it.
Don't say that.
I'm just supposed to stand here?
Who do you think I am?
Seriously?
He treats me like shit.
You a career counselor now?
Just do your job!
Amar,
my friend!
What's up?
You know what's up,
you're gonna lose your stand
if you keep spreading out.
What are we gonna do?
Like Miss France,
all I want is world peace.
No beef. How can we solve this?
I pay for every inch,
this thug wants more.
You know the drill.
I haven't even made 20,
he wants 50.
Who's the crook?
Fucking queers!
Will bleed you to death!
Give him back!
If not, gonna crucify you!
Gonna crucify y'all faggots!
Let's go.
This way.
...cut your balls.
Break your legs, motherfuckers!
Bitches!
Gonna burn your faggot hood!
Whoever stole Johnny,
gonna eat shit
and the brain of its corpse.
Something happens to him,
he doesn't come back
we'll kill you, dead faggots!
Eat your brains!
Cut your balls off,
eat your ancestors.
Look around.
Put him in the truck first.
What does he look like?
He had a black jersey.
Can't see him anymore.
They're all black here.
Spot him and I bust his head open!
That isn't him?
Nah.
All black in this shit hood.
Do a U-turn at the next block.
Gypsies. Never a good sign.
Wrong highway exit.
Mayor, they look suspect.
What's going on?
Hey guys. What's up?
Yeah, all good.
Just gonna have a chat.
Got a few questions.
What's with the sticks?
Gimme a sec.
I've come for my Johnny.
What d'you mean, gypsy?
Calm down, I'll explain.
I'm calm, man.
They came to my circus
and swiped my Johnny.
What you talking about?
Kidnapped my Johnny.
They swiped him.
I bottle fed him. He like a son.
He's in the projects.
Look for him, here, there.
I don't get it.
- Not here to start shit.
- Me neither.
Do I know your Johnny?
Don't need to.
But I don't know him!
Gonna fuck them up!
Burn them to a crisp!
Calm down, gypsy!
Find him!
- You know him?
- The singer?
He's dead.
One of your guys took him.
You know Johnny?
It's him!
It's you!
Who? I'ma fuck you up.
Go for it.
You're gonna find him!
Where are the Gypsy Kings?
There, on the left.
Do a U-turn.
Well done, Greaser.
We need backup.
We'll handle it.
Calm down.
What's happening?
Back up. Back up!
Calm down!
What's going on?
Good you're here.
You're gonna settle the score.
- Calm down.
- They swiped my Johnny.
They came and stole him.
They kidnapped one of your guys?
Johnny's my lion cub.
I want him back.
Someone stole a lion?
They stole my lion cub.
Who saw what?
You saw something?
He saw. Come here Chino.
A little nigga took the lion
to the projects!
I'll make him fuck his ancestors!
I'll cut off his legs!
- What?
- Calm down.
- You saw him?
- Yeah.
A lil' nigga.
I got it!
Black jersey.
Calm down!
He crazy?
Mayor.
You got 24 hours to find him.
Or I'll be back with a shotgun.
- You old cunt!
- Shut up!
Step back, step back.
Get back.
Son of a bitch.
Step away!
Zorro, take your boys and go.
Let's go.
Slut!
All good.
We'll bring him back.
We'll find him.
Man up, pussy!
I'll take care of it. Go now.
Motherfucker!
Let them bark.
You serious?
Our parents are watching.
- You crazy?
- Let's go into your office.
Thought it was his son, not a lion!
Some real drama.
You fucking serious?
What's up with that?
If they come back,
bullets will fly.
You hear me?
I'll take care of them. Calm down.
Now, do me a favor.
Scope around and find the lion.
- What do I get out of it?
- What do you get?
Them not returning, guns blazing.
Mothers mourning.
Bullshit.
Control the kids. It's your job!
Shut your mouth.
You threatening me?
C'mon, calm down.
Shut the fuck up.
- Calm down.
- Asshole.
No fucks given.
Seriously, I don't give a fuck.
They can come back.
Burn down the block. I don't care.
City hall will pay me
to calm the kids.
Cry me a river.
Knock it off!
'The fuck you talking about?
Seriously.
Do as I say.
Alright, you got it.
Only cuz it's you.
Counting on you.
We're out.
Bozo.
What do you want?
What you looking at?
Wanna suck it?
Beat it!
Ladies, enjoy your day.
Asshole.
Mayor.
Macha.
See how they treat us?
Too confident.
It's over.
They need us
more than we need them.
Fuck their stupid lion.
We're not animal control.
Who cares?
Tase him and it's a done deal.
So where do we start?
Start with Instagram, Facebook, Snapchat.
Why?
They're dummies.
They can't help bragging
on social media.
Greaser!
Quit wanking.
You shy?
Not really.
First mission.
You walk in there.
Greet everyone politely,
and ask for Salah.
Okay?
He knows everything and everyone.
See if he saw a kid with a mini-lion.
Get it Greaser?
They won't bite.
His armband.
Gentlemen.
I was hoping to speak to Salah.
Is he around?
Anyone?
Hello.
My colleagues...
They thought you could help us
regarding a theft.
What information
are your colleagues seeking?
A lion cub was stolen from a circus.
The circus owners...
want to get it back.
They suspect a local kid,
an individual of African descent.
Maybe you, or someone here
heard or saw
something related to the lion.
Does a lion belong in a circus?
In Islam, this majestic animal
embodies force and power.
Man shouldn't cage such a wise creature.
Agreed but...
It'd be best to return it to its owner.
A lion cub is vulnerable.
It needs to be cared for and fed.
Since when do men need to feed lions?
Don't they hunt on their own?
Feed themselves?
Men create unnatural constraints.
That is servitude.
What does a lion say when it roars?
O Allah!
May he who is benevolent
be protected from my claws.
Eat in peace.
On the house.
Greaser.
So?
Very funny.
So I got a free kebab.
Who's Salah?
An ex-thug who grew a beard.
He calls the shots.
We got a lot of dirt on him.
He was a big fish.
You learn anything?
Absolutely nothing.
Issa, what you doing here?
What's that?
Your dad doesn't want you
to come home.
Where you gonna go?
What did Mom say?
She's tired of arguing with him.
She wants you to come home.
Really?
Yeah.
What's in there?
You crazy! Don't bring that back home!
I'm talking to you.
Issa!
Is he aggressive?
Can I pat him?
Aw, so cute.
Let me take a picture.
Hurry, before he wriggles.
Let's go.
What you gonna do with him?
Come.
Let's check with the kids from B5,
maybe they got intel.
SCU style, Greaser.
Slow down.
Here they are.
Watch out! Cops!
Stop! Where you going?
Don't move!
Where you going?
Why you running?
Gents, hands out your pockets.
Are my hands in my pockets?
I'm talking to you.
Come on, hurry up!
Blondie, stay there.
Why you running?
Don't move.
Greaser, watch him.
Hello, police check.
I'm going to frisk you now.
Any sharp items on you?
Any illicit items?
- I'm talking to you!
- No.
Glad to hear you.
Are we done?
Was I disrespectful to you? No.
Lots of lighters.
This yours?
Yeah.
You pay for the bus?
I'm not done frisking, stand still!
Where's the lion?
What lion?
We need it back. Where is it?
No lion.
Go fuck yourself!
Down a notch.
- What did you say?
- Fuck yourself!
You're only fifteen so shut the fuck up!
What's happening?
What's wrong with you?
Get back in here! I already told you!
- Sorry.
- Sorry for what?
- Harassing us every day?
- Sorry.
Enough, down a notch!
This is my home!
Let's go.
- Sorry, ma'am.
- Not accepted.
You out of your mind?
You harass our kids and apologize?
He shouldn't run when he sees us.
Why hit him?
Why?
Congrats.
You get told off and apologize.
You in customer service?
Can't we be polite?
Then work as a butler in a palace.
Any luster or gildings here?
Never sorry, always right.
Take that dumb armband off.
It's obvious we're cops.
Got him!
From this morning.
Little Issa.
Bingo. Let's go!
Police!
Open up, ma'am.
What do you want?
- Hello, ma'am.
- Hello, sir.
- Looking for Issa.
- Not here.
- Where is he?
- Out and about.
- Where?
- I don't know.
Don't you monitor him?
Sir, Issa is not here.
Stop!
Let me look inside.
Stop or I'll call the real police.
I am the real police, ma'am.
You need a search warrant.
I don't need one.
I know my rights. You do.
Where's your husband?
He's not here.
He was at the precinct this morning.
No warrant, no access.
I got this... Ma'am.
Last time Issa misbehaved,
the judge issued a warrant, remember?
We searched your home
for two hours.
Want to do that again?
We agree?
Let us in.
If Issa's not here, we leave.
I don't understand.
Speak French, ma'am.
What is she saying?
I don't understand.
Okay. I'll be back.
Damn.
No clue where her kid is.
She won't let us in.
She's right.
We don't have a warrant.
You'll never be SCU at heart.
Because I don't act like a cowboy?
You don't get it. It's not an act.
- Hello kids.
- Hello.
Where's Issa?
Dunno.
- Really?
- Yes.
Hi real cop.
That's my other son Issaka, not Issa.
Okay. Can I check?
Yes, you can.
We all take turns.
It's our tontine.
- Apologies.
- You're welcome.
- Goodbye.
- Thanks, bye.
Ma'am, don't let your son stray...
Or he'll sail away.
Can't come in.
What were they doing?
A tontine,
a way to borrow without interest.
Everyone pools money,
and one person takes it
for a major expense,
like paying for a wedding
or a trip back home to see family.
Let's check the soccer field.
Issa!
He's there.
Green pants, grey shirt.
Let's cuff him and jet.
Come here!
We did nothing.
Get back!
Rascals!
Get out of here!
Let go!
Give me your hand.
Scram!
Beat it, rascals.
Run, run!
Get away, Issa.
Get back here!
Go home, fool.
Stop right there!
Fuck!
Stop!
Don't move!
On the ground. Hands up!
Making me run? Lil' fag!
Fuck!
Where's the lion?
In the basement.
Which one?
It ran away.
Shitbird! Don't mess with me.
- Where is it?
- It ran away.
Where did it go?
Where is it?
Let me go.
Get up! Shitbird!
Back up!
Greaser!
Take care of him.
Come here.
Scram.
Let him go! He did nothing!
Beat it, faggot!
Get outta here!
Move!
Get away!
Scram!
Let him go!
Move or I'll shoot!
Don't move!
Give it!
Fuck...
Fuck!
It's filming us!
What do we do? Fuck!
He's still breathing.
What you doing?
Calling help.
You stupid?
And tell'm what? We shot a kid?
He needs to go to the ER.
Him later. First, the drone.
The drone?
The kid's unconscious!
Gwada, me,
you, the team.
That's the priority.
If the video gets out, we're done!
Now do what I say. Let's go!
Get in the car!
Fuck...
We're really messing up here.
I'm talking to you, fool!
The cops screwed up.
Pink Pig and his unit.
What now?
We were playing soccer
and they grabbed Issa.
I don't care if they got Issa.
He always fucking up.
He did nothing.
Right, always innocent.
Now, scram.
Beat it.
They flash-balled him.
He might be dead.
You serious?
- Who was there?
- Us.
A drone filmed it all.
- A drone?
- Yup. Filmed it all.
You sure about that?
You know who was filming?
Is that the truth?
Step into the office.
You hungry?
Yup.
Greaser.
Watch him. We'll be back in five.
Is Stingy in?
Where is he?
In the back. I'll go get him.
Chris is here.
With his partners.
Bruh, what's with the screw face?
What's up?
Got a situation.
What happened?
What situation?
- Can we talk here?
- Shoot.
Our last patrol turned sour.
Kids kept pushing us.
A kid got flash-balled in the face.
Bro, that's bad news.
Y'all fucked up, which kid?
Little Issa.
Is he okay?
He's a bit asleep. He'll be okay.
That's not the issue.
A drone filmed us.
You know who has one?
I have no idea.
I need that video or I'm in deep shit.
Make some calls.
- Gotta find him.
- On it.
Go for it.
So?
He's not there.
Where does Buzz hang out?
No idea.
Either the pit...
or the soccer field.
Gotta go check.
Tell our guys to spot the SCU's car.
It's a grey Peugeot.
Trail them.
Gotta straighten you up.
Sorry.
Hold on. Upright.
Little forward.
Sorry, I can't uncuff you.
Need the keys.
It's gonna be okay.
Can you hear me?
Stay still.
Just relax.
You'll be okay.
I know...
Fuck.
Where were you?
At the pharmacy.
How is he? He wake up?
Yeah. Still faint. Uncuff him.
Got a tip on the drone.
Uncuff him.
What you doing?
- He stays here.
- What?
He stays here.
With them?
Let's go.
He must go to the ER.
Not gonna lug him around.
Hop in.
He's safe here.
Don't move!
Stay there!
Open the door!
Grab the drone. Meet downstairs.
The memory card's gone.
He's got the card.
Hear me? Don't lose him.
I lost the shitbird.
Meet at the shops.
He didn't just vanish...
He must've cut through B11.
Is the kid safe with those guys?
Don't worry.
Is Salah here?
Salah?
A kid wants to see you.
I'm in trouble.
Cops looking for me. Help me.
What happened?
Take a deep breath.
Come, sit down.
Calm down.
Hello?
What?
Right.
What's up?
They find the kid? It's good?
He went to Salah's.
Not him. Goddamn!
Let's go.
Fucking hell.
Him of all people.
He can't be far.
Why are they here?
The kid's there. Let's go!
- Let's go!
- Wait.
For what? He's there.
Calling Stingy. How else will we get it?
This is gonna cost us a lot.
Buzz.
Alright bro?
You got something I want.
We could ruin the SCU with that video.
Don't worry.
If we're clever, we can blackmail them.
And get whatever we want
from these assholes.
Dark thoughts as always.
Watch it, Salah.
Don't try to play me.
I could really ruin your life.
A dog barks when he can't bite.
Phony wiseman.
Just give us the video.
Salah,
we're here to make things right.
I don't want that to happen
to my little brother.
They all know us here.
We're good people.
Right, Buzz? Tell him.
- You good?
- You?
Let's cut to the chase.
What do you want?
What do you need? A hookup?
This doesn't even concern you.
Give the video to Chris,
and we're all happy.
That's why you're here?
Business as usual?
What you think?
You brainwash these kids.
It'll start a riot.
Bad for business.
What do you want?
Go sell your poison.
That's what you call it now?
Pretend to be an Imam.
I know your true colors.
Robin Hood, my ass.
Brothers not here to eat,
I suggest you leave.
Lost cause.
Who d'you think you are?
The new sheriff in town?
One call and you're a terror suspect.
This shit eatery folds.
Your dead-end mosque for retards.
Finished.
I'll arrest you tomorrow,
in front of your wife and kid. Get it?
Come with me.
Let him go!
Your hands!
Stop!
Hands behind your back!
Chris!
Let go!
- Taking it too far!
- Breaking my balls?
What?
I am the Law!
What you gonna do?
Can we talk, Salah?
Come with me.
The kid that stole the lion,
we tried to stop him
but his friends cornered us.
It happened so fast.
No harm was intended.
The flash-ball fired involuntarily.
I swear, believe me.
Involuntarily?
What are you saying?
It was an accident?
Not your fault?
As usual.
You don't know
how to use your weapons?
Bad luck?
That's not what I'm saying.
If the video gets out,
this place will burn.
What if voicing anger
was the only way to be heard?
Who did their anger serve in 2005?
No one.
They burned cars,
destroyed bus shelters. What's left?
A bare pole?
Not a bench to sit on. Nothing.
It backfired.
Worst thing is that no one cares.
Let me handle it.
How's the kid?
He'll pull through.
- Sure?
- He'll be okay.
I want to trust you.
But you won't avoid their rage.
Attention units. This is not a joke.
A lion cub has been spotted
at the community garden.
SCU responding, close by. On our way.
Pharaoh. Let's go.
Well done, kiddo.
Zorro.
Look who's here.
Gave you my word.
He brought my little man.
My Johnny.
Is that Daddy?
Come here, my boy.
There...
Careful.
Attaboy!
Happy?
Happy to be home?
I brought you the thief to apologize.
Say sorry.
Sorry.
What happened buddy? You fall?
He slipped.
What a slide!
Come here, let's talk.
You can't do that.
We come here to perform.
We bring the circus. Animals.
You steal from us. Can't do that.
I don't steal in your hood.
Here, go in there.
Zorro! What you doing?
Stop playing!
He's not happy.
Enough with the jokes!
Let him out!
Let the kid out!
Let the kid out or else...
'The fuck away from me.
He pissed himself.
I'm gonna pull the trigger.
Don't believe you!
Let the kid out.
Let him out!
It's a joke...
A joke? Let him out!
It's okay. Don't be scared.
It's a joke.
Put the piece away.
Just a joke.
Sure it is.
- You a real schmuck.
- No, you are.
All good. Go home now.
Go fuck yourself!
Come here little man.
You okay?
Doesn't hurt anymore?
Let's see.
Just a bit red.
You'll be fine.
Listen up.
How did this happen?
If anyone asks, what will you say?
What's the answer?
You fell on the ground.
Know why?
Because Issa won't stop
messing up. Right?
So bad things happen.
It's your fault, understood?
You did this to yourself. Look at me.
You did this to yourself.
Say it.
What happened?
I can't hear you.
I fell over.
Good. Who's fault?
My fault.
Good.
That's enough.
He gets it. Let him go.
Beat it. Go home.
He gets it.
'Fuck out of here.
- What's your problem?
- Leave him alone.
I don't like your tone.
Really?
He gave you the video?
Yes or no?
- I got it.
- Hand it over.
No, fuck you.
- Hands off!
- What did you say?
Easy. Easy.
The video stays in my pocket.
No one will see it, but I'm keeping it.
I'm okay with that.
Okay with what?
How is this okay?
You're under my command!
Not anymore. That's over.
- Come again, fuckface.
- Back off!
Some attitude.
I read your file. You're a cocksucker.
I'm head of this unit
cuz no one rides me.
Back off!
Chris!
What's going on?
Look at his face. He's a fucking rat.
Eager to report us to internal affairs.
Know what?
I didn't shoot a kid.
Shut up.
I'll handle it.
Even if you get the video,
it won't stop him from talking.
I'm warning you.
You leak it,
the entire force will be against you.
Think about it.
You okay?
I'm okay.
I'm good. Already ate.
Already had a bite.
Not hungry. I'm tired, Mom.
Gonna go to bed.
That's good.
Dad, she won't let me play.
Bonnie, let her play.
Give me a go.
I'll just finish this game.
Put them to bed, please.
Girls. Go to bed.
Give it to me.
Go to bed now.
I'll hurt your barbie.
Bonnie, stop that!
Right now!
I was playing.
Go to bed, now.
Lylan.
Go to bed.
Quit stomping.
Whatever.
I'm okay.
My boy, how are you?
How was school?
What did you do?
Want a drink?
Sparkling water, please.
You okay?
You?
I'm okay.
Thanks.
Were you able to unwind?
And you?
Yeah.
Called my son.
Did a few things.
He's okay?
Yeah.
You don't have kids, do you?
Not yet.
It's a good feeling.
So.
I know how a flash-ball trigger works.
You can't fire by accident.
That's not what I told Salah but...
What happened?
I dunno why. I fucked up.
I saw it coming.
I've been stressed out...
With all those kids screaming...
I just lost it.
I lost my temper. Just lost it.
It was their fault? You serious?
We were ambushed by kids.
You shot at close range.
He was handcuffed.
Could've died.
I'm sorry for little Issa.
Really?
Sorry for what?
You told him you were sorry?
Like Chris says, never say sorry.
Listen...
This was the worst day of my life
teamed up with you
and that dimwit Chris.
All you do is screw up.
You just arrived
and you're lecturing us?
We have to act this way.
You saw the night unit?
All Rambo-ed up.
We're the only ones respected.
Respect?
People around here just fear you.
I grew up here.
We've been working
these streets 10 years.
This is our life.
Know what?
Keep it.
Do what you gotta do.
Let's get Haroona.
Get Boodlal.
Get Yussuf.
Cops!
Hide!
Yo, bugs.
It's Pink Pig.
Come here.
What's going on?
Just hanging.
No Club Med today?
Do the Pink Pig.
Go play.
Beat it!
Drive off!
There!
Out of my way!
Stop right there!
Let them have their fun.
Move!
Piss off!
Get out!
Retard, watch your mom cry.
There are kids trailing us.
What are they doing?
Looking for a spanking?
What do they want?
Son of a bitch!
Block the elevator!
We need backup.
Three gremlins. We got this.
Out of service.
Call backup.
SCU to HQ, we need backup.
Location?
Fuck, wait...
This is HQ, your location?
What is your location, SCU?
- 7 Picasso street.
- Say that again.
Come here, asshole!
Motherfuck you!
Beat it!
Scram, asshole!
Stay there!
Let go, asshole!
Motherfucker, let him go!
Get back!
What's going on?
What's the problem?
Move! Get out of my way!
Beat it!
Tough guys, now?
What's wrong?
Who gave you permission?
You tough?
What's your fucking problem?
What are you trying to do?
Driving me crazy,
who gave you permission, fuckers?
Who told you?
What's wrong with you?
You tough now?
Assholes!
Scram!
What do you want?
Motherfuck you, son of a bitch!
Mortar!
Fuck!
Fucking bitches!
- Chris, you okay?
- My eye!
Fucking bugs!
Piss me off!
Move away!
Come...
Motherfuckers!
Open up! Open!
Is there someone there?
Please open up! Help!
Help!
Please open up!
I beg you! Please!
Don't do it, Issa! Please!
Put it down!
Listen, Issa! Put it down!
Listen to me!
Step back!
"Remember this, my friends,
there are no such things
as bad plants or bad men,
there are only bad cultivators."
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org