Some of us was
in the Second Kansas Colored.
We fought the Rebs at
Jenkins' Ferry last April...
...just after they killed every Negro soldier
captured at Poison Springs.
So at Jenkins' Ferry, we decided
warn't takin' no Reb prisoners.
And we didn't leave
a one of 'em alive.
The ones of us that didn't die that day, we
joined up with the 116th U.S. Colored, sir...
...from Camp Nelson, Kentucky.
What's your name, soldier?
Private...Harold Green, sir.
I'm Corporal Ira Clark, sir.
Fifth Massachusetts Cavalry.
We're waiting over there.
We're leaving our horses,
shipping out with the 24th Infantry...
...for the assault next week
on Wilmington.
How long have you
been a soldier?
Two year, sir.
The Second Kansas Colored Infantry
fought bravely at Jenkins' Ferry.
That's right, sir.
They killed a thousand Rebel soldiers, sir.
They were very brave.
And making $3 less each month
than white soldiers.
Us Second Kansas boys--
Another $3 subtracted
from our pay for our uniforms.
That was true, but--
Equal pay now, but still no
commissioned Negro officers.
I'm aware of that,
Corporal Clark.
That's good
that you're aware, sir, but...
Will the Wilmington attack--
...now that white people are accustomed
to seeing Negro men with guns...
...fighting on their behalf, and they tolerate
Negro soldiers getting equal pay...
...maybe in a few years, they can abide the
idea of Negro lieutenants and captains.
In fifty years,
maybe a Negro colonel.
In a hundred years...the vote.
What will you do
after the war, Corporal Clark?
Work, sir.
Perhaps you'll hire me.
Perhaps I will.
But you should know, sir,
I get sick at the smell of boot black...
...and I cannot cut hair.
I've yet to find a man could cut mine
so that it'd make any difference.
- You got springy hair for a white man.
- Yes, I do.
My last barber hanged himself.
And the one before that.
Left me his scissors in his will.
- President Lincoln, sir.
- Good evening, boys.
We saw you, and...
- We were at--
- We was at Gettysburg.
You boys fight at Gettysburg?
No, we just signed up last month.
We saw him
at the cemetery dedication.
We heard you speak... Goddamn.
How tall are you, anyway?
Aw, jeez, shut up.
- Could you hear what I said?
- Not much, sir.
"Four score and seven years ago, our
fathers brought forth from this continent...
...a new nation,
conceived in liberty and dedicated
to the proposition
that all men are created equal."
That's good. Thank you.
"Now we are engaged in a great civil war,
testing whether that nation or any nation...
...so conceived and so dedicated,
can long endure.
We are met on a great
battlefield of that war."
That's good, thank you.
"We come to dedicate
a portion of that field...
...as a final resting place for those who here
gave their lives that the nation might live."
His uncles died
on the second day of fighting.
I know the last part.
Company up! Moving out!
You boys best go and find your company.
And thank you.
Thank you, sir. God bless you.
God bless you, too. God bless you.
"That we here highly resolve that these
dead shall not have died in vain.
That this nation, under God,
shall have a new birth of freedom...
...and that government of the people,
by the people, for the people...
...shall not perish
from the earth."
It's nighttime.
Ship's moved
by some terrible power...
...at a terrific speed.
And though it's
imperceptible in the darkness,
I have an intuition
that we're headed towards a shore.
No one else seems to be
aboard the vessel.
I'm very keenly aware
of my...aloneness.
"I could be bounded in a nutshell
and count myself a king of infinite space...
...were it not that I have
bad dreams."
I reckon it's the speed that's strange to me.
I'm used to going at a deliberate pace.
I should spare you, Molly.
I shouldn't tell you my dreams.
I don't want to be spared if you aren't.
And you spare me nothing.
Perhaps it's...
...it's the assault
on Wilmington Port.
You dream about the ship
before a battle, usually.
How's the coconut?
Beyond description.
Almost two years,
nothing mends.
Another casualty of the war.
Who wants to listen to a useless woman
grouse about her carriage accident?
- I do.
- Stuff.
You tell me dreams, that's all.
I'm your soothsayer.
That's all I am to you anymore.
I'm not to be trusted...
...even if it was not
a carriage accident.
- Even if it was an attempted assassination.
- It was most probably an accident.
It was an assassin
whose intended target was you.
How are the plans coming along
for the big shindy?
I don't want to talk about parties.
You don't care about parties.
Not much, but they're
a necessary hindrance.
I know.
I know what it's about,
the ship.
It's not Wilmington Port.
It's not a military campaign.
It's the amendment
to abolish slavery.
Why else would you force me
to invite demented radicals into my home?
You're going to try to get the amendment
passed in the House of Representatives...
...before the term ends?
Before the Inauguration?
Don't spend too much money
on the flubdubs.
No one is loved
as much as you.
No one's ever been loved
so much by the people.
You might do anything now.
Don't waste that power
on an amendment that's sure of defeat.
Did you remember Robert's
coming home for the reception?
I knew you'd forget.
That's the ship you're sailing on--
the Thirteenth Amendment.
You needn't tell me I'm right.
I know I am.
It's late, Mrs. Keckley.
She needs this for the grand reception.
It's slow work.
Good night.
Did you tell her a dream?
Subtitle
www.movieddl.me
Papa.
Papa, I want to see Willie.
Me, too, Taddie, but we can't.
Why not?
Willie's gone.
It's three years now he's gone.
The part assigned to me
is to raise the flag.
Which, if there be no fault
in the machinery, I will do.
And when up...
...it'll be for the people
to keep it up.
That's my speech.
We are coming,
Father Abraham
Three hundred thousand more
From Mississippi's winding stream
And from New England's shore
We leave our plow and workshops
Our wives--
Even if every Republican
in the House votes yes--
- -Far from guaranteed, since when has our
party unanimously supported anything?
But say all our fellow
Republicans vote for it.
We'd still be twenty votes short.
- Only twenty?
- "Only twenty"?
We can find twenty votes.
Twenty House Democrats who'll vote to
abolish slavery? In my opinion--
To which I always listen.
- Or pretend to.
- With all three of my ears.
We'll win the war soon.
It's inevitable, isn't it?
Well, it ain't won yet.
You'll begin your second term
with semi-divine stature.
Imagine the possibilities
peace will bring.
Why tarnish your invaluable luster with
a battle in the House? It's a rat's nest.
It's the same gang
of talentless hicks and hacks
who rejected the amendment
10 months ago.
We'll lose.
I like our chances now.
Well, consider the obstacles
that we'd face.
The two-thirds majority
needed to pass an amendment.
We have a Republican majority,
but barely more than 50%.
Fifty-six.
We need Democratic support.
There's none to be had.
Since the House last voted on it,
there's been an election.
Sixty-four Democrats
lost their House seats in November.
That's 64 Democrats looking for work
come March.
They're not worried about re-election.
They can vote however it suits them.
But we can't buy the vote for the
amendment. It's too important.
I said nothing of buying anything.
We need 20 votes was all I said.
Start of my second term,
plenty of positions to fill.
Mr. President, may I present
Mr. and Mrs. Jolly from Missouri--
From Jeff City, President.
Mr. Jolly.
Ma'am.
And this here by the fire
is Secretary of State Seward.
Jeff City?
I heard tell once
of a Jefferson City lawyer...
...who had a parrot...
...that'd wake him
each morning, crying out:
"Today is the day the world shall end,
as scripture has foretold."
And, one day...
...the lawyer shot him, for the sake
of peace and quiet, I presume.
Thus fulfilling, for the bird at least,
his prophecy.
There's only one toll booth
in Jeff City, to the southwest...
...and this man Heinz Sauermagen
from Rolla
been in illegal possession
for near two yar...
...since your man General Schofield
set him up there.
But President Monroe give that toll gate
to my granpap...
...and Quincy Adams...
...give my pap a letter
saying it's our'n for keeps.
Mrs. Jolly got the--
Show Mr. Lincoln the Quincy Adams letter.
That's unnecessary.
Just tell me what you want from me.
Mr. Jolly's emphysema
don't care for cigars.
Madame, do you know about the proposed
13th Amendment?
Yes, sir, everybody knows of it.
The President favors it.
- Do you?
- We do.
- You know that it abolishes slavery?
- Yes, sir, I know it.
And that is why you favor it?
What I favor
is ending the war.
Once we do away with slavery,
the Rebs'll quit fighting...
...since slavery's
what they're fighting for.
Mr. Lincoln,
you always says so.
With the amendment, slavery's ended.
They'll give up.
If the war finished first,
before we end slavery--
President Lincoln says the war won't stop
unless we finish slavery.
But...if it did.
The South is exhausted.
If they run out
of bullets and men...
...would you still want your--
Who's your Representative?
Jeff City?
That's Congressman Burton.
"Beanpole" Burton.
I mean, Josiah Burton, yes, sir.
A Republican, undecided on
the amendment, I believe.
Perhaps you could call on him
and inform him of your enthusiasm.
Madame.
If the Rebels
surrendered next week...
...would you,
at the end of this month...
...want Congressman Burton to vote
for the 13th Amendment?
If that was how it was,
no more war...
...I reckon Mr. Jolly much prefer not to have
Congress pass the amendment.
And, uh...
...why is that?
Niggers.
If he don't have to let some Alabama coon
come to Missouri...
...steal his chickens and his job,
we'd much prefer that.
The people. I begin to see why you're in
such a great hurry to put it through.
Would you let me study this letter, sir,
about the toll booth?
Come back to me in the morning
and we'll consider what the law says.
You be sure to...
...visit "Beanpole".
Tell him you support
passage of the amendment...
...as a military necessity.
Thank you.
Oh, Nicolay,
when you have a moment.
If procuring votes with offers
of employment is what you intend...
...I'll fetch a friend from Albany
who can supply
the skulky men
gifted at this kind of shady work...
...and spare me the indignity
of actually speaking to Democrats.
Spare you the exposure
and liability.
Pardon me,
that's a distress signal...
...which I am bound,
by solemn oath, to respond to.
Tom Pendel took away the camera plates
of slaves Mr. Gardner sent over...
...because Mama says
they're distressing.
You had nightmares.
I'll have worse nightmares if I can't
look at the plates again.
Perhaps.
You can't afford a single defection
from anyone in the party.
Not even a single Republican absent when
they vote. You know who you have to see.
Send over to Blair House.
Ask Preston Blair
can I call on him around five o'clock.
God help you. God alone knows
what he'll ask you to give him.
If the Blairs tell them to,
...no Republican will balk
at voting for the amendment.
No conservative Republican
is what you mean.
All Republicans
ought to be conservative.
I founded this party,
...in my own goddamn home,
to be a...
...conservative
anti-slavery party,
...not a hobbyhorse for
goddamn radical abolitionists.
Damp down
the dyspepsia, Daddy.
You'll frighten the child.
You need us to keep
the conservative side...
...of the party in the traces...
...while you diddle
the radicals...
...and bundle up
with Thaddeus Stevens's gang!
You need our help!
Yes, sir, I do.
Well, what do we get?
Blunt!
Your manners, Monty,
must be why Mr. Lincoln...
...pushed you
out of his Cabinet.
- I wasn't pushed!
- Oh, of course you weren't.
He was pushed out to placate
the damn radicals!
- I agreed to resign.
- Oh, Daddy, please! Daddy.
Oh. You don't mind, boy,
do you?
He spends his days
with soldiers.
They taught me a song.
Did they?
Soldiers know
all manner of songs.
How's your brother Bob?
He's at school now,
but he's coming...
...to visit in four days
for the shindy.
At school. Ain't that fine?
Good he's not in the Army.
He wants to be,
but Mama said he cannot.
Dangerous life, soldiering.
Your mama is wise
to keep him clean out of that.
Now, your daddy knows
that what I want...
...in return for all the help
I give him...
...is to go down to Richmond,
like he said I could...
...as soon as Savannah fell...
...and talk
to Jefferson Davis.
Now give me terms I can
offer to Jefferson Davis...
...to start negotiating
for peace.
He'll talk to me.
Conservative members
of your party...
...want you to listen
to overtures from Richmond.
That above all!
They'll vote for this rash
and dangerous amendment...
...only if every other
possibility is exhausted.
Our Republicans
ain't abolitionists.
We can't tell our people
they can vote yes...
...on abolishing slavery...
...unless at the same time
we can tell them...
...that you're seeking
a negotiated peace.
Leo, it's 100 miles
to Richmond.
Get him drunk so he can sleep.
Yes, ma'am.
Here, Daddy.
- Thank you.
- Pull this up.
Where's my hat?
Leo has your hat.
All right?
Go make peace.
Thunder forth, God of War.
We'll commence our assault
on Wilmington from the sea.
Why is this burnt?
Was the boy playing with it?
It got took by a breeze
several nights back.
This is an official
War Department map.
And the entire
Cabinet's waiting...
...to hear what it portends.
A bombardment.
From the largest fleet
the Navy has ever assembled.
Old Neptune,
shake thy hoary locks!
Fifty-eight ships
are under way,
...of every tonnage
and firing range.
We'll keep up
a steady barrage.
Our first target
is Fort Fisher.
It defends Wilmington Port.
A steady barrage?
A hundred shells a minute.
Till they surrender.
Dear God.
Wilmington's their
last open seaport, therefore--
Wilmington falls,
Richmond falls after.
And the war is done.
Here! Here!
Then why, if I might ask...
...are we not concentrating...
...the nation's attention
on Wilmington?
Why, instead, are we
reading in the Herald...
...that the anti-slavery
amendment...
...is being precipitated onto
the House floor for debate?
Because your eagerness,
...in what seems
an unwarranted intrusion...
...of the executive into
legislative prerogatives,
...is compelling it
to what's...
...to what's likely to be
its premature demise.
Here! Here!
You signed
the Emancipation Proclamation.
You've done
all that could be done.
The Emancipation
Proclamation's...
...merely a war measure.
After the war, the courts--
When Edward Bates
was Attorney General,
...he felt confident enough
to let you sign it!
Different lawyers,
different opinions.
It frees slaves
as a military exigent. Not--
I don't recall Edward Bates
being any too certain about...
...the legality
of my proclamation.
Just it wasn't
downright criminal.
Somewheres in between.
Back when I rode the legal
circuit in Illinois,
...I defended a woman
from Metamora...
...named Melissa Goings.
Seventy-seven years old.
They said she'd murdered
her husband. He was 83.
He was choking her...
...and she grabbed a hold
of a stick of firewood...
...and fractured his skull
and he died.
In his will, he wrote,
"...I expect
she has killed me."
"If I get over it,
I will have revenge."
No one was keen
to see her convicted...
...he was that kind
of husband.
I asked
the prosecuting attorney...
...if I might have a short
conference with my client.
She and I went into a room
in the courthouse,
...but I alone emerged.
The window in the room
was found to be wide open.
It was believed the old lady
may have climbed out of it.
I told the bailiff,
...right before I left her
in the room...
...she asked me where
she could get...
...a good drink of water,
and I told her...Tennessee.
Mrs. Goings was seen
no more in Metamora.
Enough justice had been done.
They even forgave
the bondsman her bail.
I'm afraid I don't see--
I decided...
...that the Constitution
gives me war powers...
...but no one knows
just exactly...
...what these powers are.
Some say they don't exist.
I don't know. I decided...
...I needed them to exist
to uphold my oath...
...to protect
the Constitution.
Which I decided
meant I could take...
...the Rebels' slaves
from them...
...as property
confiscated in war.
That might recommend
to suspicion that I agree...
...with the Rebs
that their slaves...
...are property
in the first place.
Of course, I don't.
Never have.
I'm glad to see any man free,
...and if calling
a man property...
or war contraband...
...does the trick, why I
caught at the opportunity.
Now here's where
it gets truly slippery.
I use the law
allowing for the seizure...
...of property in a war...
...knowing it applies
only to the property...
...of governments and citizens
of belligerent nations.
Well, the South
ain't a nation.
That's why I can't
negotiate with them.
So if, in fact, the Negroes
are property,
...according to the law...
...have I the right to take
the Rebels' property...
...from them, if I insist
they're rebels only...
...and not citizens
of a belligerent country?
And slipperier still,
I maintain it ain't...
...our actual Southern states
in rebellion...
...but only the rebels
living in those states...
...the laws of which states
remain in force.
"The laws of which states
remain in force."
That means that since it's
states' laws that determine...
...whether Negroes
can be sold as slaves,
...as property...
...the federal government
doesn't have a say in that.
At least not yet.
Then Negroes in those states
are slaves,
...hence property...
...hence my war powers
allow me to confiscate them...
...as such,
so I confiscate them.
But if I'm a respecter
of states' laws,
...how can I
legally free them...
...with my Proclamation
as I done?
Unless I'm canceling
states' laws?
I felt the war demanded it.
My oath demanded it.
I felt right with myself,
...and I hoped
it was legal to do it.
I'm hoping still.
Two years ago, I proclaimed
these people emancipated.
"Then, thenceforward
and forever free."
Now let's say the courts
decide I had no authority...
...to do it--they might well
decide that.
Say there's no amendment
abolishing slavery,
...say it's after the war...
...and I can no longer use
my war powers...
...to just ignore
the courts' decisions...
...like I sometimes
felt I had to do.
Might those people I freed
be ordered back into slavery?
That's why I'd like to get...
...the 13th Amendment
through the House...
...on its way
to ratification by the states.
Wrap the whole
slavery thing up,
...forever and aye,
as soon as I'm able. Now!
End of this month.
And I'd like you
to stand behind me...
...like my Cabinet's
most always done.
As the preacher said,
"...I could write
shorter sermons,
...but once I start,
I get too lazy to stop."
It seems to me, sir,
you're describing...
...precisely the sort
of dictator...
...the Democrats
have been howling about.
Dictators
aren't susceptible to law.
Neither is he.
He just said as much.
Ignoring the courts?
Twisting meanings?
What reins him in
from...from--
Well, the people do that,
I suppose.
I signed
the Emancipation Proclamation,
...what, a year and a half
before my second election?
I felt I was within my power
to do it,
...however, I also felt that I
might be wrong about that.
I knew the people
would tell me.
I gave them a year and a half
to think about it,
...and they re-elected me.
And come February the first,
...I intend to sign
the 13th Amendment!
Well, Mr. Representative
Ashley.
Tell us the news
from the Hill.
Ah, well, the news--
Why, for instance,
is this thus,
...and what is the reason
for this thusness?
James, we want you to bring
the anti-slavery amendment...
...to the floor for debate,
- ...immediately.
- What?
You are the amendment's
manager, are you not?
I am, of course, but--
Then we're counting
on robust radical support...
...so tell Mr. Stevens
we expect him...
...to put his back into it.
It not going to be easy, but--
It's impossible.
No. I am sorry, no.
We can't organize anything
immediately in the House.
I have been canvassing
the Democrats...
...since the election...
...in case any
of them softened...
...after they got
walloped, but...
...they stiffened,
if anything, Mr. Secretary.
There aren't nearly
enough votes.
We're whalers, Mr. Ashley.
Whalers? As in, uh...whales?
We've chased this whale
for a long time.
And we finally placed
a harpoon...
...in the monster's back.
It's in, James. It's in.
We finish the deed now.
We can't wait.
Or with one flop of his tail,
he'll smash the boat...
...and send us all
to eternity.
On the 31st of this month,
of this year,
...put the amendment
up for a vote.
Whalers?
That's what he said.
The man's never been near
a whale ship in his life.
Withdraw radical support.
Force him
to abandon this scheme,
...whatever he's up to.
He drags his feet
about everything,
...Lincoln--why this urgency?
We got it through the Senate
without difficulty...
...because we had the numbers.
Come December, you'll have
the same in the House.
The amendment will be
the easy work of 10 minutes.
He's using the threat
of the amendment...
...to frighten the Rebels
into an immediate surrender.
I imagine
we'd rejoice to see that.
Will you rejoice
when the Southern states...
...have rejoined
the Union pell-mell,
...as Lincoln intends them to,
and one by one,
...each refuses
to ratify the amendment?
If we pass it, which we won't.
Why are we cooperating
with him?
We all know what he's doing
and we all know what he'll do.
We can't offer up abolition's
best legal prayer...
...to his games and tricks.
He said he'd welcome
the South back...
...with all its slaves
in chains.
Three years ago he said that--
to calm the border states.
I don't!
You said we know
what he'll do--I don't know.
You know
he isn't to be trusted.
Trust? Oh.
I'm sorry, I was under
the misapprehension...
...that your chosen profession
was politics.
I never trusted the President,
never trusted anyone...
...but hasn't he
surprised you?
No, Mr. Stevens, he hasn't.
Nothing surprises you, Asa,
...therefore nothing about you
is surprising.
Perhaps that is why
your constituents...
...did not re-elect you
to the coming term.
It's late.
I'm old.
I'm going home.
Lincoln,
the inveterate dawdler.
Lincoln, the Southerner.
Lincoln, the capitulating
compromiser...
...our adversary, and...
...leader of the godforsaken
Republican party.
Our party.
Abraham Lincoln has asked us
to work with him...
...to accomplish the death
of slavery...in America.
Retain, even in opposition...
...your capacity
for astonishment.
The President is never
to be mentioned. Nor I.
You're paid
for your discretion.
Hell, you can have that
for nothing.
What we need money for
is bribes, to speed things up.
No,
nothing strictly illegal.
It's not illegal
to bribe Congressmen--
...they'd starve otherwise.
I have explained to Mr. Bilbo
and Mr. Latham that...
...we are offering
patronage jobs...
...to the Dems who vote yes.
- Jobs and nothing more.
- That's correct.
Congressmen come cheap--
...few thousand bucks
will buy all you need.
The President would be unhappy
to hear you did that.
Will he be unhappy if we lose?
The money I managed to raise
for this endeavor...
...is only for your fees,
your food and lodging.
If that
squirrel-infested attic...
...you've quartered us in
is any measure,
...you ain't raised much.
Shall we get to work?
The House
recognizes Fernando Wood...
...the honorable
Representative from New York.
Estimable colleagues.
Two bloody years ago
this month...
...His Highness,
...King Abraham Africanus
the First...
...our great
usurping Caesar...
...violator of ha be as corpus
and freedom of the press,
...abuser of states' rights--
If Lincoln really
were a tyrant, Mr. Wood...
...he'd have had
your empty head...
...impaled on a pike!
And the country better for it!
- -Radical Republican
autocrat...
...ruling by fiat
and martial law...
...affixed his name
to his heinous and illicit...
...Emancipation
Proclamation...
...promising it would hasten
the end of the war...
...which yet rages on and on.
He claimed, as tyrants do...
...that the war's
emergencies...
...permitted him to turn
our army into--
The New York delegation is
looking decidedly uninspired.
- -And radical Republicanism's
abolitionist fanaticism!
His Emancipation
Proclamation...
...has obliterated
millions of dollars--
Over in Pennsylvania...
...who's the sweaty man
eating his thumb?
Unknown to me.
Seems jumpy.
Perhaps he'll jump.
But all that was not enough
for this dictator,
...who now seeks
to insinuate--
Jesus.
When's this son of liberty
sum-a-bitch gonna sit down?
John Ellis is gonna break
his watch if he doesn't stop.
We are once again
asked, nay...
...commanded, to consider
a proposed 13th Amendment...
...which, if passed,
sets at immediate liberty...
...four million coloreds
while manacling...
...the limbs
of the white race in America.
If it is passed...
...but it shall not pass!
What's more interesting...
...is how dismal
and disgruntled...
...Mr. Yeaman appears.
Every member
of this House...
He should be cheering
right now.
Looks like he ate
a bad oyster.
- -Party and
the constituents it serves...
...shall oppose--
Point of order,
Mr. Speaker, if you please.
Mr. Speaker,
I still have the floor.
And the gentleman
from Pennsylvania...
...is out of order!
When will Mr. Wood conclude
his interminable gabble?
Some of us breathe oxygen...
...and we find the mephitic
fumes of his oratory...
...a lethal challenge
to our pulmonary capabilities!
We shall oppose
this amendment,
...and any legislation that so
affronts natural law...
...insulting to God as to man!
Congress must never
declare equal...
...those whom God
created unequal!
Slavery is the only insult
to natural law,
...you fatuous nincompoop!
Order!
Procedure, Mr. Speaker.
Mr. Wood has the floor.
Instruct us...
...oh, Great Commoner.
What is unnatural,
in your opinion?
Niggrahs casting ballots?
Niggrah representatives?
Is that natural, Stevens?
Intermarriage?
What violates natural law?
Slavery...and you.
Pendleton, you insult God!
You unnatural noise.
Mr. Colfax, please,
use your gavel!
- You are out of order!
- Order in the Cabinet!
Instruct
the Sergeant-at-Arms...
...to suppress this!
We are in session!
Please don't encourage this!
Don't encourage this!
You're back! You're back!
You're back!
I am. The goat got big.
Help me get
one of these to my room.
- She in there?
- She's asleep, probably.
- You need help, sir?
- No, sir.
They went to see
Avonia Jones last night...
...in a play about Israelites.
Could you give your pa
this letter I read...
...about my
insolvency proceeding?
Deliver your own
goddamn petition.
There's a new book--
Sam Beckwith...
...says it's about finches and finches' beaks,
about how they change.
He's here.
He's here!
Mrs. Cuthbert, he's here!
- Robbie.
- Hi, Mom.
- Oh, Robbie.
- Hey.
- Robbie.
Oh.
You're here a few days--
why'd you pack all that?
Well, I don't know how long--
Go tell your father
Robert's home.
Mr. Nicolay says Daddy's
secluded with Mr. Blair.
Tell him anyway.
Did you forget to eat?
- Exactly like him.
- No.
You'll linger a few days extra
after the reception
before you go back to school.
Well, I don't know
if I'm going to go back--
We'll fatten you up
before you return to Boston.
- All right, Mom.
- All right.
Oh, Robbie.
Jefferson Davis is sending
three delegates.
Stephens, Hunter and Campbell.
Vice President
of the Confederacy...
...the former
Secretary of State...
...and their Assistant
Secretary of War.
They're coming in earnest
to propose peace.
I know this is unwelcome news
for you.
Now hear me.
I went to Richmond
to talk to traitors.
To smile at and plead
with traitors...
...because it'll be spring
in two months...
...the roads will be passable,
...the spring slaughter
commences.
Four bloody springs now.
Think of my Frank,
...whom you've taken
to your heart.
How you'll blame yourself
if the war takes my son...
...as it's taken
multitudes of sons.
Think of all the boys
who will die...
...if you don't make peace.
You must talk with these men.
I intend to, Preston.
In return, I ask you
to push for the amendment--
No, this is not horse trading.
Not now!
Bob. I'm sorry.
- Welcome home.
- Thank you, sir.
Looking fit.
Harvard agrees with you.
- Mr. Blair.
- Fit and rested.
Could you give us a moment,
please, Robert? Thank you.
I will procure your votes
for you, as I promised.
You have always
kept your word to me.
Those Southern men are coming.
I beg you, in the name
of gentle Christ...
I understand.
...talk peace with these men.
I understand, Preston.
We have
one abstention so far.
Jacob Graylor.
He'd like to be
Federal Revenue Assessor...
...for the 5th District
of Pennsylvania.
So the total
of Representatives...
...voting three weeks from
today is reduced to 182...
...which means 122
yes votes...
...to reach the requisite
two-thirds of the House.
Assuming all Republicans
vote for the amendment...
...then, despite
our abstention...
...to reach
a two-thirds majority...
...we remain 20 yeses short.
For which we're seeking...
...from among 64
lame duck Democrats.
Fully 39 of these we deem
unredeemable no votes.
The kind that hates niggers.
Hates God for makin' niggers.
The Good Lord on high
would despair of their souls.
Thank you for that
pithy explanation, Mr. Bilbo.
We've abandoned these 39 to...
...the devil
that possesses them.
We would...
The remaining lame ducks...
...on whom we've been working
with a purpose.
Charles Hanson.
Congressman.
My colleagues and I would like
a moment of your time.
I wonder if you've
given much thought--
Giles Stuart.
Rather clumsy.
Nelson Merrick.
Homer Benson.
My name is Richard Schell.
I wanted you to have a look
at this prospectus here.
And lastly...
...Clay Hawkins. Of Ohio.
Tax Collector
for the Western Reserve--
...that pays handsomely.
Don't reach
for the highest branches,
...they sway in every breeze.
Assistant Port Inspector
in Morristown...
...looks like
the ticket to me.
Boats, same,
they make me sick.
So just stand on the dock.
Let the Assistant Assistant
Port Inspector's stomach...
...go weak.
And, lastly,
Democratic yes vote...
...number six, Hawkins.
From Ohio.
Six?
Well, thus far.
Plus Graylor's abstention.
- From tiny acorns and so on.
- What did Hawkins get?
Postmaster of the Millersburg
Post Office.
He's selling himself cheap,
ain't he?
He wanted Tax Collector
of the Western Reserve.
First term Congressman who
couldn't manage reelection.
I felt it unseemly...
...and they bargained him down
to Postmaster.
Scatter them over several
rounds of appointments...
...so no one notices,
then burn this ledger,
...please, after you're done.
Time for
my public opinion bath.
Might as well let them in.
Seven yeses with Mr. Ellis.
Thirteen to go.
One last item.
An absurdity, but...
...my associates report that
among the Representatives...
...a fantastical rumor's
bruited about...
...which I immediately
disavowed...
...that you'd allowed
bleary old Preston Blair...
...to sojourn to Richmond...
...to invite Jeff Davis
to send commissioners...
...up to Washington
with a peace plan.
I, of course, told them
that you would never...
...not without consulting me,
you wouldn't.
Because why on earth
would you?
Much obliged.
Why wasn't I consulted?
I'm Secretary of State.
And you informally send
a reactionary dotard to--
What will happen,
do you imagine,
...when these
peace commissioners arrive?
We'll hear them out.
Oh. Splendid.
And next, the Democrats
will invite them...
...up to hearings on the Hill.
And the newspapers...oh,
the newspapers.
The newspapers will ask,
"...Why risk enraging
the Confederacy...
...over the issue
of slavery...
...when they're here
to make peace?"
We'll lose every Democrat
we've got...
...more than likely
conservative Republicans...
...will join them,
and all our work...
...all our preparing
the ground for the vote...
...laid waste for naught.
The Blairs promised support
for the amendment...
...if we listen
to these people.
Oh, the Blairs promise,
do they?
You think they'll keep
their promise...
...once we've heard
these delegates...
...and refused them,
which we will have to do...
...since their proposal
most certainly...
...will be predicated on...
...keeping their slaves!
What hope for any
Democratic votes, Willum...
...if word gets out
I've refused a chance...
...to end the war?
You think word won't get out?
In Washington?
It's either the amendment
or this Confederate peace.
You cannot have both.
"If you can look into
the seeds of time,
And say which grain will grow
and which will not,
Speak then to me."
A disaster.
This is a disaster.
Time is a great thickener
of things, Willum.
Yes, I suppose it is.
Actually, I have no idea
what you mean by that.
Get me thirteen votes.
Them fellas from Richmond
ain't here yet.
You drafted
half the men in Boston.
What do you think
their families think about me?
The only reason they don't
throw things and spit on me...
...is 'cause
you're so popular.
I can't concentrate on...
on British Mercantile Law.
I don't care about
British Mercantile Law.
I might not even
want to be a lawyer.
It's a sturdy profession.
And a useful one.
Yes, and I want to be useful,
but now, not afterwards.
I ain't wearing them things,
Mr. Slade.
They never fit right.
The missus will have you
wear them. Don't think--
You're delaying--
that's your favorite tactic.
- Be useful--
- You won't tell me no,
...but the war will be over in
a month, and you know it will.
I've found that prophesying...
...is one of life's
less profitable occupations.
Why do some slaves
cost more than others?
Uh, if they're still
young and healthy,
...or if the women can
still conceive, they pay more.
Put them back in the box,
you scoundrel.
We'll return them
to Mr. Gardner's studio...
...day after next.
Be careful with them now.
These things should have
stayed on the calf.
When you were a slave,
Mr. Slade, did they beat you?
I was born a free man.
Nobody beat me
except I beat them right back.
Mr. Lincoln--
Mrs. Keckley was a slave.
Ask her if she was beaten.
- Were you--
- Tad.
I was beaten
with a fire shovel...
when I was younger than you.
You should go to Mrs. Lincoln.
She's in Willie's room.
She never goes in there.
The reception line is already
stretching out the door.
See, I'll be the only man
over 15 and under 65...
...in this whole place
not in uniform.
I'm under 15.
My head hurts so.
I prayed for death
the night Willie died.
My headaches are how I know
I didn't get my wish.
How to endure
the long afternoon...
...and deep into the night.
I know.
Trying not to think about him.
How will I manage?
- Somehow. You will.
- Somehow?
Somehow. Somehow.
Every party.
Every...
And now...
...four more years
in this terrible house...
...reproaching us.
He was a very sick little boy.
We should have canceled
that reception, shouldn't we?
We didn't know
how sick he was.
I knew. I knew.
I saw that night
he was dying.
Three years ago,
the war was going so badly.
We had to put on a face.
But I saw Willie was dying.
I saw him.
It's too hard.
Too hard.
Oh, gracious saints!
She's just ten feet yonder.
I'd like to keep my job.
Senator Sumner.
It's been much too long.
"Oh, who can look
on that celestial face--"
And?
James Ashley, ma'am.
We've met several times.
Praise heavens,
praise heavens.
Just when I had abandoned hope
of amusement...
...it's the Chairman
of the House Ways...
- and Means Committee.
- Mrs. Lincoln.
Madame President,
if you please.
Don't convene
another subcommittee...
...to investigate me, sir.
I'm teasing.
Smile, Senator Wade.
I believe I am smiling,
Mrs. Lincoln.
As long as
your household accounts...
...are in order, madam...
...we'll have no need
to investigate them.
You have always taken
such a lively...
...even prosecutorial interest
in my household accounts.
Your household accounts have
always been so interesting.
Yes, thank you. It's true.
The miracles I have wrought...
...out of fertilizer bills
and cutlery invoices...
...but I had to.
Four years ago, when
the President and I arrived,
...this was pure pigsty.
Tobacco stains
on the Turkey carpets.
Mushrooms, green as the moon,
sprouting from the ceilings.
And a pauper's pittance
allotted for improvements.
As if your committee joined
with all of Washington...
...awaiting in
what you anticipated...
...would be our comfort
in squalor.
Further proof that
my husband and I...
...were prairie primitives...
...unsuited to the position to
which an error of the people,
...a flaw in the Democratic
process had elevated us.
The past is the past.
It's a new year now...
...and we are all getting
along, or so they tell me.
I gather
we are working together.
The White House
and the other House...
...hatching little plans
together.
- Mother.
- What?
You're creating a bottleneck.
Oh, I'm detaining you.
And more importantly,
the people behind you.
How the people
love my husband.
They flock to see him by their
thousands on public days.
They will never love you
the way they love him.
How difficult it must be
for you to know that...
...and yet how important
to remember it.
Since we have the floor
next in the debate,
...I thought I'd suggest
you might...
...temper your contribution...
...so as not to frighten
our conservative friends.
Ashley insists
you're ensuring approval...
...by dispensing patronage...
...to otherwise
undeserving Democrats.
I can't ensure
a single damn thing...
...if you scare
the whole House silly...
...with talk of
land appropriations...
...and revolutionary
tribunals.
When the war ends,
I intend to...
...push for full equality,
the Negro vote, and much more.
Congress shall
mandate the seizure...
...of every foot
of Rebel land...
...and every dollar
of their property.
We'll use their
confiscated wealth...
...to establish
hundreds of thousands...
...of free Negro farmers...
...and, at their side,
soldiers armed to occupy...
...and transform
the heritage of traitors.
We'll build up
a land down there...
...of free men and free women
and free children and freedom.
The nation needs to know
that we have such plans.
That's the untempered version
of reconstruction.
It is not...
It's not quite exactly
what I intend.
But we shall oppose one
another in the course of time.
Now we're working together,
and I'm asking you--
For patience, I expect.
When the people disagree,
bringing them together...
...requires going slow
until they're ready to--
Shit on the people
and what they want...
...and what they're ready for.
I don't give a goddamn
about the people...
...and what they want.
This is the face of someone...
...who has fought
long and hard...
...for the good
of the people...
...without caring much
for any of them.
And now I look a lot worse
without the wig.
The people elected me
to represent them...
...to lead them, and I lead.
You ought to try it.
I admire your zeal,
Mr. Stevens...
...and I have tried to profit
from the example of it, but...
...if I'd listened to you,
...I'd have declared
every slave free...
...the minute the first shell
struck Fort Sumter.
And the border states
would have gone over...
...to the Confederacy, the war
would have been lost...
...and the Union
along with it,
...and instead of
abolishing slavery...
...as we hope to do
in two weeks,
...we'd be watching, helpless
as infants, as it spread...
...from the American South
into South America.
Oh, how you have longed
to say that to me.
You claim you trust them,
...but you know
what the people are.
You know that
the inner compass,
...that should direct the soul
towards justice...
...has ossified in white men
and women, North and South...
...unto utter uselessness,
...through tolerating
the evil of slavery.
White people
cannot bear the thought...
...of sharing this country's
infinite abundance...
...with Negroes.
A compass, I learned
when I was surveying...
...it'll point you true north
from where you're standing.
But it's got
no advice about...
...the swamps and deserts
and chasms...
...that you'll encounter
along the way.
If in pursuit
of your destination,
...you plunge ahead,
heedless of obstacles...
...and achieve nothing more
than to sink in a swamp...
...what's the use
of knowing true north?
Robert's going to plead
with us to let him enlist.
Make time to talk to Robbie.
You only have time for Tad.
Tad is young.
So is Robert.
Too young for the Army.
Plenty of boys younger
than Robert signing up.
Don't take Robbie.
Don't let me lose my son.
Go away! We're occupied!
Secretary Stanton
is sent over...
...to tell you that
as of half hour ago...
...the shelling of Wilmington
Harbor has commenced.
They cannot possibly maintain
under this kind of an assault.
Terry has got 10,000 men
surrounding the goddamn port.
Why doesn't he answer--
Fort Fisher is a mountain
of a building, Edwin.
It's the largest fort
they have, sir.
Twenty-two big Seacoast guns
on each rampart.
They've been reinforcing it
for the last two years.
They've taken 17,000 shells
since yesterday!
I want to hear
Fort Fisher is ours...
...and Wilmington has fallen.
Send another damn cable!
The problem's their commander,
Whiting!
He engineered
the fortress himself--
...the damn thing's his child.
He'll defend it till his
every last man is gone.
"Come on out, you old rat!"
That's what
Ethan Allen called out...
...to the commander
of Fort Ticonderoga in 1776.
"Come on out, you old rat!"
Of course,
there were only...
...40 odd redcoats
at Ticonderoga.
There is one Ethan Allen story
that I'm very partial to.
No, you're going
to tell a story.
I don't believe
that I can bear...
...to listen to another one
of your stories right now.
I need the B&O side yard
schedules for Alexandria!
I asked for them this morning!
It was
right after the Revolution,
...right after peace
had been concluded.
And Ethan Allen
went to London...
...to help our new country...
...conduct its business
with the King.
The English sneered
at how rough we are...
...and rude and simple-minded,
and on like that,
...everywhere he went...
...till one day he was invited
to the townhouse...
...of a great English lord.
Dinner was served
and beverages imbibed...
...time passed,
as happens, and...
...Mr. Allen found
he needed the privy.
He was grateful
to be directed thence.
Relieved, you might say.
Now, Mr. Allen discovered...
...on entering
the water closet,
...that the only
decoration therein...
...was a portrait
of George Washington.
Ethan Allen done
what he came to do,
...and returned
to the drawing room.
His host and the others
were disappointed...
...when he didn't mention
Washington's portrait.
Finally, His Lordship couldn't
resist and asked Mr. Allen...
...had he noticed it,
the picture of Washington.
He had.
Well, what did he think
of its placement,
...did it seem appropriately
located to Mr. Allen?
Mr. Allen said it did.
His host was astounded.
"Appropriate?
George Washington's likeness
in a water closet?"
"Yes," said Mr. Allen.
"Where it'll do good service."
"The whole world knows nothing
will make an Englishman...
...shit quicker than the sight
of George Washington."
I love that story.
Fort Fisher is ours.
We've taken the port.
And Wilmington?
We've taken the fort,
...but the city of Wilmington
has not surrendered.
How many casualties?
- Heavy losses.
- And more to come.
It sours the national mood.
It might suffice--
To what? To bring this down?
Not in a fight like this.
This is to the death.
That's gruesome.
Are you despairing
or merely lazy?
This fight is for
the United States of America.
Nothing "suffices."
A rumor? Nothing.
They're not lazy.
They're busily buying votes...
...while we hope to be saved
by "the national mood"?
Before this blood is dry, when
Stevens next takes the floor,
...taunt him.
You excel at that.
Get him to proclaim what
we all know he believes...
...in his coal-colored heart.
That this vote is meant
to set the black race on high,
...to nigger ate America--
George, please,
stay on course.
Bring Stevens to full froth.
I can ensure
that every newspaperman...
...from Louisville
to San Francisco...
...will be here
to witness it and print it.
The floor belongs to
the mellifluent gentleman...
...from Kentucky,
Mr. George Yeaman.
I thank you, Speaker Colfax.
Although I am disgusted
by slavery...
...I rise on this sad
and solemn day...
...to announce that
I'm opposed to the amendment.
We must consider what
will become of colored folk...
...if four million are,
in one instant, set free.
They'll be free, George,
...that's what
will become of them.
Think how splendid...
...if Mr. Yeaman switched.
Too publicly against us.
He can't change course now.
Not for some miserable
little job, anyways.
And we will be forced
to enfranchise...
...the men
of the colored race.
It would be inhuman not to.
Now who among us is prepared
to give Negroes the vote?
And...and...
...what shall follow
upon that?
Universal enfranchisement?
Votes for women?
We...
Bless my eyes.
If it isn't the Postmaster
of Millersburg, Ohio.
Mr. LeClerk felt honor-bound
to inform us...
...of your
disgusting betrayal.
Your prostitution.
Is that true,
Postmaster Hawkins?
Is your maidenly virtue
for sale?
If my neighbors hear...
...that I voted yes
for nigger freedom...
...and no to peace,
they will kill me.
A deal is a deal.
You men know better
than to piss your pants...
just 'cause there's talk
about peace talks.
- Look, I'll find another job!
- My neighbors in Nashville,
...they found out
I was loyal to the Union,
...they came after me
with gelding knives.
- I'll find another job.
- You do right, Clay Hawkins.
I want to do right!
But I got no courage!
Wait. You wanted--
What was it?
A tax man
for the Western Reserve?
Hell, you can have the whole
state of Ohio if you want--
Oh, crap.
Eleven votes?
Two days ago, we had twelve.
What happened?
There are defections
in the ranks.
It's the goddamn rumors...
...regarding
the Richmond delegation.
- Yes. The peace offer.
- Groundless.
- And yet the rumors persist.
- They are ruining us.
Among the few
remaining Representatives...
...who seem
remotely plausible,
...there is a perceptible
increase in resistance.
Resistance, hell.
Thingamabob Hollister,
Dem from Indiana...
...I approached him,
sumbitch near to murdered me.
Colorado Territory...
What's this one?
Job description...taxpayers
and--
Oh, shit! Cracky!
Fuck you, you son of a bitch!
Goddamn!
- Perhaps you pushed too hard.
- I push nobody.
Perhaps we need
reinforcements.
If Jeff Davis wants
to cease hostilities...
...who is going to give
a genuine solid shit...
...to free slaves?
Get back to it.
And gentlemen, good day.
We are at an impasse.
Tell Lincoln
to deny the rumors, publicly.
Tell us what you expect of us.
I expect you to do your work.
And have sufficient
sense and taste...
...not to presume
to instruct the President.
Or me.
Is there
a Confederate offer...or not?
Gentlemen.
I suggest you work some
changes to your proposal...
...before you give it
to the President.
We're eager to be on our way
to Washington.
Mr. Lincoln tell you
to tell us this?
It says "securing peace
for our two countries"...
...and it goes on like that.
- I don't--
- There is just one country.
You and I, we're citizens
of that country.
I'm fighting to protect it
from armed rebels.
From you.
But Mr. Blair, he told us,
...he told President
Jefferson Davis that we--
A private citizen
like Preston Blair...
...can say what he pleases...
...since he has no authority
over anything.
If you want to discuss peace
with President Lincoln...
...consider revisions.
If we're not to discuss...
...a truce between
warring nations...
...what in heaven's name
can we discuss?
Terms of surrender.
"Office United States
Military Telegraph,
...War Department.
For Abraham Lincoln, President
of the United States.
January 20, 1865.
I will state confidentially
that I am convinced...
...upon conversation
with these commissioners...
...that their intentions
are good...
...and their desire sincere
to restore peace and union.
I fear now their going back...
...without any expression
of interest from anyone...
...in authority, Mr. Lincoln,
will have a bad influence.
I will be sorry should it
prove impossible for you...
...to have an interview
with them.
I am awaiting
your instructions.
U.S. Grant,
Lieutenant General,
...Commanding Armies,
United States."
After four years of war,
and...
...near six hundred thousand
lives lost...
...he believes
we can end this war now.
My trust in him
is marrow deep.
You could bring the delegates
to Washington.
In exchange for the South's
immediate surrender,
...we could promise them
the amendment's defeat.
They'd agree, don't you think?
We'd end the war. This week.
Or, if you could manage...
...without seeming
to do it, to, uh...
The peace delegation
might encounter delays...
...as they travel
up the James River.
Particularly with the fighting
around Wilmington.
Within ten days' time,
...we might pass
the 13th Amendment.
Here's
a sixteen-year-old boy...
...they're going to hang him.
He's with the Fifteenth
Indiana Cavalry near Bulford.
It seems he lamed his horse
to avoid battle.
I don't think even Stanton
would complain...
...if I pardoned him.
You think
Stanton would complain?
I don't know, sir. I don't
know who you're, uh...
- What time is it?
- It's 3:40 in the morning.
Don't let him pardon
any more deserters.
Mr. Stanton thinks
you pardon too many.
He's generally apoplectic
on the subject.
He oughtn't have done that,
crippled his horse.
That was cruel,
but you don't just hang...
...a sixteen-year-old boy
for that...
Ask the horse what he thinks.
...for cruelty. There'd be no
sixteen-year-old boys left.
Grant wants me to bring
the secesh delegates...
...to Washington.
So there are secesh delegates?
He was afraid,
that's all it was.
I don't care to hang a boy
for being frightened, either.
What good would it do him?
War's nearly done,
ain't that so?
What use is one more corpse?
Any more corpses?
Do you need company?
In times like this,
I'm best alone.
"Lieutenant General
Ulysses S. Grant, City Point.
I have read your words
with interest.
I ask that,
...regardless of any action
I take in the matter...
...of the visit of the
Richmond commissioners...
...you maintain
among your troops...
...military preparedness
for battle...
...as you have done until now.
Have Captain Saunders convey
the commissioners to me...
...here in Washington.
A. Lincoln." And the date.
Yes, sir.
Shall I transmit, sir?
You think we choose
to be born?
I don't suppose so.
Are we fitted to the times
we're born into?
Well, I don't know
about myself.
You may be...
...sir. Fitted.
What do you reckon?
Well, I'm an engineer.
I reckon there's machinery,
...but...no one's
done the fitting.
You're an engineer.
You must know Euclid's axioms
and common notions.
I must have in school, but...
I never had much of schooling,
...but I read Euclid
in an old book I borrowed.
Little enough
ever found its way in here,
...but once learnt,
it stayed learnt.
Euclid's first common notion
is this--
"Things which are equal
to the same thing...
...are equal to each other."
That's a rule
of mathematical reasoning.
It's true because it works.
Has done and always will do.
In his book, mmm...
...Euclid says
this is "self-evident."
You see? There it is...
...even in that
two thousand-year-old book...
...of mechanical law.
It is a self-evident truth...
...that things which are equal
to the same thing...
...are equal to each other.
We begin with equality.
That's the origin, isn't it?
That's balance.
That's...That's fairness.
That's justice.
Just read me back
the last sentence...
...of the telegram, please.
"Have Captain Saunders convey
the commissioners to me...
...here in Washington."
A slight emendation,
if you would, Sam.
"Have Captain Saunders
convey the gentlemen...
...aboard the River Queen...
...as far as Hampton Roads,
Virginia...
...and there wait until...
...further advice from me.
Do not proceed to Washington."
The World, the Herald,
the Times...
...New York, Chicago...
...the Journal of Commerce...
...even your
hometown paper's here.
Say you believe only in legal
equality for all races,
...not racial equality...
...I beg you, sir.
Compromise.
Or you risk it all.
I've asked you a question,
Mr. Stevens,
...and you must answer me.
Do you or do you not
hold that the precept...
...that "All men are created
equal" is meant literally?
Is that not the true purpose
of the amendment?
To promote your ultimate
and ardent dream to elevate--
The true purpose
of the amendment, Mr. Wood...
...you perfectly named,
...brainless
obstructive object...
Now you have always insisted,
Mr. Stevens...
...that Negroes are the same
as white men are.
The true purpose
of the amendment...
...I don't hold with
equality in all things,
...only with equality
before the law. Nothing more.
That's... That's not so.
You believe that Negroes are
entirely equal to white men.
You've said it
a thousand times!
For shame! For shame!
Stop prevaricating and
answer Representative Wood!
I don't hold with
equality in all things,
...only with equality
before the law.
After the decades
of fervent advocacy--
He's answered your questions!
This amendment's
not to do with race equality.
I don't hold with
equality in all things...
...only with equality before
the law, and nothing more!
Who'd ever have guessed
that old nightmare...
...capable of such control?
He might make
a politician someday.
I need to go.
Mrs. Keckley.
Your frantic attempt
to delude us now...
...is unworthy
of a representative.
It is, in fact,
unworthy of a white man!
How can I hold that
all men are created equal...
...when here before me
stands, stinking...
...the moral carcass of the
gentleman from Ohio, proof...
...that some men
are inferior...
...endowed by their Maker
with dim wits,
...impermeable to reason...
...with cold, pallid slime
in their veins...
...instead of hot, red blood!
You are more reptile
than man, George!
So low and flat
that the foot of man...
...is incapable
of crushing you.
How dare you?
Yet even you, Pendleton...
...who should have been
gibbeted for treason...
...long before today...
...even worthless,
unworthy you...
...ought to be treated equally
before the law!
And so again, sir, again
and again and again I say,
...I do not hold with
equality in all things...
...only with
equality before the law.
Mr. Speaker, will you permit
this vile, boorish man...
...to slander
and to threaten me?
And to reduce
these proceedings...
...on this most important
matter into an anarchic...
...and tawdry burlesque?
You asked
if ever I was surprised.
Today, Mr. Stevens...
...I was surprised.
You've led the battle for
race equality for 30 years.
The basis of every hope for
this country's future life...
...you denied Negro equality.
I'm nauseated.
You refused to say that
all humans are...
Well, human.
Have you lost your very soul,
Mr. Stevens?
Is there nothing
you won't say?
I'm sorry you're nauseous,
Asa.
That must be unpleasant.
I want the amendment to pass,
...so that
the Constitution's first...
...and only mention
of slavery...
...is its
absolute prohibition.
For this amendment, for which
I have worked all my life...
...and for which countless
colored men and women...
...have fought and died...
...and now hundreds
of thousands of soldiers...
No, sir, no.
It seems there's very nearly
nothing I won't say.
I'm not going in.
You said you wanted
to help me.
But this is just a clumsy
attempt to discourage me.
I've been to Army hospitals.
I've seen surgeries.
I went and visited
the malaria barges with Mama.
She told me
she didn't take you inside.
I snuck in afterwards.
I've seen what it's like.
This changes nothing.
Well, at all rate, son,
...I'm happy
to have your company.
- Good morning, Jim.
- Hello, Mr. President.
- Good to see you again.
- Good to see you.
Well, boys, first question--
you getting enough to eat?
Hello, sir.
- What's your name, soldier?
- Robert.
- Good to meet you, Robert.
- Nice to meet you.
- What's your name?
- Kevin.
Tell me your names
as I go past.
I'd like to know
who I'm talking to. Kevin.
- Mr. President. John.
- John. I've seen you before.
Mr. President.
Make sure you
get some steak.
I wouldn't mind one myself,
right now.
What's the matter, Bob?
I have to do this,
and I will do it.
And I don't need
your permission to enlist.
That same speech has been made
by how many sons...
...to how many fathers
since the war began?
"I don't need
your damn permission,
"...you miserable old goat,
I'm gonna enlist anyhow."
And what wouldn't those...
...numberless fathers
have given...
...to be able
to say to their sons...
...as I now say to mine,
"I'm Commander in Chief."
So, in point of fact,
without my permission...
...you ain't enlisting
in nothing nowhere, young man.
It's Mama you're scared of,
it's not me getting killed.
I have to do this! And I will!
Or I will feel ashamed
of myself the rest of my life!
Whether or not you fought
is what's gonna matter,
...and not just to other
people, but to myself!
I won't be you, Pa,
I can't do that,
...but I don't want
to be nothing!
I can't lose you.
He'll be fine, Molly.
City Point's a way back
from the front lines...
...and the fighting.
He'll be an adjutant, running
messages for General Grant.
The war will take our son.
A sniper, or a shrapnel shell,
or typhus...
...same as took Willie.
It takes hundreds of boys
a day. He'll die uselessly.
And how will I ever
forgive you?
Most men, their firstborn
is their favorite.
You've always blamed Robert
for being born.
For trapping you
in a marriage...
...that's only ever
given you grief...
- ...and caused you regret.
- That's simply not true.
And if the slaughter
of Cold Harbor's...
...on your hands same
as Grant, God help us.
We'll pay for the oceans
of spilled blood...
...you've sanctioned,
the uncountable corpses!
We'll be made to pay
with our son's dear blood!
Just this once,
Mrs. Lincoln...
...I demand of you to try
and take the liberal...
...and not the selfish
point of view.
Robert will never
forgive himself.
You imagine
he'll forgive us...
...if we continue to stifle
this very natural ambition?
And if I refuse
to take the high road?
If I won't pick up
the rough old cross...
...will you threaten me again
with the madhouse?
As you did when I couldn't
stop crying over Willie.
When I showed you
what heartbreak...
...real heartbreak
looked like.
And you hadn't the courage
to countenance, to help me!
When you refused so much
as to comfort Tad,
...a child who was not only
sick, dangerously sick...
...but beside himself
with grief!
I was holding him in my arms
when he died.
But your grief, your grief,
your inexhaustible grief!
How dare you
throw that up at me?
And his mother wouldn't
let him near her...
...because she's screaming
from morning to night!
I couldn't risk him seeing
how angry I was!
Pacing the halls,
howling at shadows...
...and furniture and ghosts!
I ought to have done it
for Tad's sake...
...for everybody's
goddamn sake,
I should have clapped you
in the madhouse!
Then do it!
Do it! Don't you threaten me!
You do it this time.
Lock me away.
You'll have to, I swear...
...if Robert is killed.
I couldn't tolerate you
grieving so for Willie...
...because I couldn't
permit it in myself.
Though I wanted to, Mary.
I wanted to
crawl under the earth,
...into the vault,
with his coffin.
And I still do.
Every day I do.
Don't speak to me about grief.
I must make my decisions,
Bob must make his, you yours.
And bear what we must.
Hold and carry what we must.
What I carry within me,
you must allow me to do it.
Alone, as I must.
And you alone, Mary,
...you alone
may lighten this burden.
Or render it intolerable.
As you choose.
You think I'm ignorant
of what you're up to...
...because you
haven't discussed...
...this scheme with me
as you ought to have done?
When have I ever been
so easily bamboozled?
I believe you
when you insist...
...that amending
the Constitution...
...and abolishing slavery
will end this war.
And since you are
sending my son into the war,
...woe unto you if you fail
to pass the amendment.
Seward doesn't want me leaving
big muddy footprints...
...all over town.
No one has ever lived
who knows better than you...
...the proper placement
of footfalls...
...on treacherous paths.
Seward can't do it. You must.
Because if you fail to acquire
the necessary votes...
...woe unto you, sir.
You will answer to me.
Thank you.
I know the vote
is only four days away.
I know you're concerned.
Thank you for your
concern over this.
And I want you to know,
they'll approve it.
God will see to it.
I don't envy Him his task.
He may wish He'd chosen an
instrument for His purpose...
...more wieldy than
the House of Representatives.
Then you'll see to it.
Are you afraid of what
lies ahead for your people...
...if we succeed?
White people
don't want us here.
- Many don't.
- What about you?
I don't know you,
Mrs. Keckley.
Any of you.
You're familiar to me,
as all people are...
...unaccommodated, poor, bare,
forked creatures,
...such as we all are.
You have a right
to expect what I expect.
And likely our expectations...
...are not incomprehensible
to each other.
I assume I'll get used to you.
Now what you are
to the nation,
...what'll become of you
once slavery's day is done...
...I don't know.
What my people are to be,
I can't say.
Negroes have been fighting
and dying for freedom
since the first of us was a slave.
I never heard any ask
what freedom would bring.
Freedom is first.
As for me...
...my son died
fighting for the Union...
...wearing the Union blue.
For freedom he died.
And I'm his mother.
That's what I am
to the nation, Mr. Lincoln.
What else must I be?
My whole hand's gonna be proud
in about five seconds.
Let's see how proud
you can be.
Go away.
That watch fob, is that gold?
You keep your eyes off my fob.
Gentlemen, you have a visitor.
- Goddamn!
- Hey, Bill.
Well, I'll be fucked.
I wouldn't bet against it.
Mr, uh...?
W. N. Bilbo.
Yeah, Mr. Bilbo. Gentlemen.
Sir.
Why are you here? No offense,
...but Mr. Seward's banished
the very mention of your name.
He won't even let us
use fifty cent pieces...
...'cause they've got
your face on 'em.
The Secretary of State here
tells me that you got...
...11 Democrats in the bag.
That's encouraging.
Oh, you've got no cause
to be encouraged, sir.
Are we being fired?
"We have heard the chimes
at midnight, Master Shallow."
I'm here to alert you boys...
...that the great day
of reckoning is nigh upon us.
The Democrats
we've yet to bag, sir,
...the patronage jobs
simply won't bag 'em.
They require more convincing,
Mr. President.
Do me a favor, will you?
Sure.
It snagged my eye in the paper
this morning...
...that the Governor Curtin...
...is set to declare a winner
in the disputed...
...Congressional election
for the--
Pennsylvania 16th District.
...District.
What a joy to be comprehended.
Hop on a train to Philadel,
call on the Governor--
Send Latham. Or Schell.
No, he'll do fine.
Just polish yourself up first.
The incumbent is claiming
he won it. Name of--
Coffroth.
- That's him.
- Coffroth.
- He's a Democrat.
- I understand that.
- Silly name.
- A little bit silly.
Uh, tell Governor Curtin
it'd be much appreciated...
...if he'd invite the
House of Representatives...
...to decide who won.
He's entitled to do that.
He'll agree to it.
Then advise Coffroth...
...if he hopes
to retain his seat,
then he'd better pay a visit
to Thaddeus Stevens.
Well,
pity poor Coffroth.
It opens!
You are Canfrey?
Coffroth, Mr. Stevens.
Alexander Coffroth.
Are we representatives
of the same state?
Yes, sir.
We sit only three desks apart.
I haven't noticed you.
I'm a Republican and you,
Coughdrop, are a Democrat?
Well, uh, I, um,
that is to say--
The modern travesty
of Thomas Jefferson's...
...political organization...
...to which you've attached
yourself like a barnacle...
...has the effrontery to call
itself the Democratic Party.
You are a Democrat.
What's the matter with you?
Are you wicked?
- Well, I felt--
- Never mind.
Coffsnot, you were
ignominiously trounced...
...at the hustings
in November's election...
...by your worthy challenger,
a Republican.
No, sir, I was not trounced.
He wants to steal my seat.
I didn't lose the election.
What difference does it make
if you lost or not?
The governor of our state
is... A Democrat?
No, he's, he's a...
Re-...
- ...-pub-...-lic-...
- ...-can.
- ...-can. Republican.
I know what he is.
This is a rhetorical exercise.
And Congress is controlled
by what party? Yours?
Your party was beaten.
Your challenger's party
now controls the House...
...and hence the House
Committee on Elections...
...so you have been beaten.
You shall shortly be sent home
in disgrace. Unless...
I know what I must do, sir.
I will immediately become
a Republican and vote yes--
No!
Coffroth will vote yes...
...but Coffroth
will remain a Democrat
until after he does so.
Why wait to switch?
I'm happy to--
We want to show the amendment
has bipartisan support,
...you idiot.
Early in the next Congress,
when I tell you to do so,
you will switch parties.
Now congratulations
on your victory, and get out.
Now, give me the names...
...of whoever else
you've been hunting.
Aw, hell.
George Yeaman.
Yes. Yeaman.
Among others.
- But Yeaman, that'd count.
- Yeah.
Y-E-A-M-A-N.
I got it.
Kentucky.
I can't vote for
the amendment, Mr. Lincoln.
I saw a barge once,
Mr. Yeaman...
...filled with
colored men in chains...
...heading down
the Mississippi...
...to the New Orleans
slave markets.
It sickened me.
And more than that,
it brought a shadow down.
A pall around my eyes.
Slavery troubled me
as long as I can remember...
...in a way it never
troubled my father...
...though he hated it,
in his own fashion.
He knew no
smallholding dirt farmer...
...could compete with
slave plantations...
...so he took us out
from Kentucky...
...to get away from 'em.
He wanted Indiana kept free.
He wasn't a kind man...
...but there was a rough,
moral urge for fairness,
...for freedom in him.
I learnt that from him,
I suppose.
If little else from him.
We didn't care
for one another, Mr. Yeaman.
Well, I'm sorry to hear that.
Loving kindness, the most
ordinary thing, came to me...
...from other sources.
I'm grateful for that.
Well, I hate it, too, sir.
Slavery, but...
But we're entirely unready
for emancipation.
And there's
too many questions--
We're unready for peace,
too, ain't we?
Yeah, when it comes, it'll
present us with conundrums...
...and dangers greater than
any we faced during the war,
...bloody as it's been.
We'll have to extemporize and
experiment with what it is,
...when it is.
I read your speech, George.
Negroes and the vote...
...that's a puzzle.
No, no.
But, but, but Negroes can't...
...uh, vote, Mr. Lincoln.
You're not suggesting we
enfranchise colored people?
I'm asking only that...
...you disenthrall yourself
from the slave powers.
I'll let you know when...
...there's an offer on my desk
for surrender.
There's none before us now.
What's before us now,
...that's the vote on
the 13th Amendment.
And it's going to be
so very close.
You see what you can do.
I can't make sense of it.
What he died for.
Mr. Lincoln, I hate them all.
I do. All black people.
I am a prejudiced man.
Well, I'd change that
in you if I could,
...but that's not why I come.
I might be wrong,
Mr. Hutton...
...but I expect colored people
most likely be free.
And when that's so,
it's simple truth...
...that your
brother's bravery...
...and his death
helped make it so.
Only you can decide whether...
...that's sense enough
for you or not.
My deepest sympathies
to your family.
We've managed our members
to a fare-thee-well.
You've had no defections...
...from the Republican right
to trouble you.
Whereas as to
what you promised...
...where the hell are
the commissioners?
Oh, my God. It's true.
You...
You lied to me.
Mr. Lincoln, you evaded
my request for a denial...
...that there is
a Confederate peace offer,
...because there is one!
We are absolutely guaranteed
to lose the whole thing.
We don't need a goddamn
abolition amendment!
Leave the Constitution alone!
What if
the peace commissioners
appear today, or worse--
I can't listen
to this anymore.
I can't accomplish
a goddamn thing...
...of any human meaning
or worth...
...until we cure ourselves
of slavery...
...and end this
pestilential war!
And whether any of you
or anyone else knows it,
...I know I need this!
This amendment is that cure!
We are stepped out upon
the world stage now!
Now!
With the fate of human dignity
in our hands!
Blood's been spilt to
afford us this moment!
Now! Now! Now!
And you grousle and heckle
and dodge about like...
...like pettifogging
Tammany Hall hucksters!
See what is before you.
See the here and now,
that's the...
...hardest thing,
the only thing that accounts.
Abolishing slavery
by constitutional provision...
...settles the fate
for all coming time...
...not only of the millions
now in bondage...
...but of unborn
millions to come.
Two votes stand in its way.
These votes must be procured.
We need two yeses,
three abstentions, or...
...four yeses...
...and one more abstention,
and the amendment will pass.
You got a night, and a day,
and a night,
...and several
perfectly good hours.
Now get the hell out of here
and get 'em.
Yes. But how?
Buzzards' guts, man.
I am the President of the
United States of America...
...clothed in immense power.
You will procure me
these votes.
We welcome you,
ladies and gentlemen...
...first in the history of
this people's chamber...
...to your House.
Mr. Ashley,
the floor is yours.
On the matter of the
joint resolution before us,
...presenting
a 13th Amendment...
...to our National
Constitution...
...which was passed last year
by the Senate...
...and which has
been debated now...
by this estimable body
for the past several weeks...
...today we will vote.
By mutual agreement,
...we shall hear brief,
final statements...
...beginning with...
...the honorable
George Pendleton of Ohio.
I have just received...
...confirmation...
...of what previously has
been merely rumored.
Affidavits from
loyal citizens...
...recently returned
from Richmond.
They testify that
commissioners have indeed...
...come north and
ought to have arrived...
...by now
in Washington City...
...bearing an offer
of immediate cessation...
...of our civil war.
Is it true, sir?
Are there Confederate
commissioners in the capital?
I have no idea where they are
or if they've arrived.
They'll arrive.
I appeal to
my fellow Democrats,
...to all Republican
representatives...
...who give a fig for peace,
...postpone this vote!
Until we have answers...
...from the President himself!
Postpone the vote!
- Postpone the vote!
- Gentlemen!
Postpone the vote!
I have made a motion!
Does anyone care to
second my motion?
Gentlemen.
The conservative faction...
...of border and
western Republicans...
...cannot approve
this amendment,
...about which we
harbor grave doubts...
...if a peace offer is being
held hostage to its success.
Joining together with
our Democratic colleagues,
...I second the motion...
...to postpone.
He must deny peace
commissioners are in the city.
Quick, man. Quick.
This is precisely what
Mr. Wood wishes me...
...to respond to?
Word for word,
this is precisely...
...the assurance that
he demands of me?
Yes, sir.
Give this to Mr. Ashley.
Uh, I feel I have to say,
Mr. Lincoln, that...
Could you please
just step outside?
You want a chat now,
...with the whole of the
House of Representatives...
...waiting on this?
Making false representation
to Congress, is--
- It's...
- It's impeachable,
but I've made no such
false representation.
But there are.
There is a delegation
from Richmond.
Give me the note, Johnnie.
Please, deliver that
to Mr. Ashley.
From the President.
"So far as I know,
there are no...
...peace commissioners
in the city...
...nor are there
likely to be."
"So far as I know"?
That means nothing.
Are there commissioners from
the South, or aren't there?
The President has
answered you, sir.
Your peace offer is a fiction.
That is not a denial.
It is a lawyer's dodge!
Mr. Haddam, is your
faction satisfied?
The conservative Republican
faction is satisfied.
And we thank Mr. Lincoln.
I move to table
Mr. Wood's motion.
Tabled!
Mr. Colfax, I order
the main question.
A motion has been made
to bring the bill...
...for the 13th Amendment
to a vote.
Do I hear a second?
I second the motion.
So moved, so ordered.
The Clerk will now--
Quiet, please!
The Clerk will now
call the roll for the voting.
We begin with Connecticut.
Mr. Augustus Benjamin,
...on the matter of this
amendment, how say you?
Nay!
Mr. Arthur Bentleigh.
Mr. John Ellis, how say you?
Aye!
What!
Missouri next.
Mr. Walter Apple ton.
I vote no.
Mr. Josiah Burton.
Beanpole Burton is
pleased to vote yea!
The State of New Jersey.
- Mr. Nehemiah Cleary.
- No!
Mr. James Martinson.
Mr. Martinson has
delegated me...
...to say he is indisposed.
And he abstains.
Mr. Austin J. Roberts.
Also indisposed,
also abstaining.
Illinois concluded.
Mr. Harold Hollister.
How say you?
No.
Mr. Hutton.
Mr. William Hutton.
Cast your vote.
William Hutton,
remembering at this moment...
...his beloved
brother Frederick...
...votes against
the amendment.
Webster Allen votes no.
Webster Allen,
...Illinois, Democrat...
...votes, no.
Halberd Law,
Indiana, Democrat...
...votes no.
Archibald Moran...yes.
Ambrose Baylor, yes.
Mr. Walter H. Washburn.
Votes no.
And Mr. George Yeaman,
how say you?
My vote ties us.
Sir, Mr. Yeaman,
I didn't hear your vote.
I said "Aye", Mr. McPherson!
Aye!
Traitor!
Order!
Order in my chamber!
Mr. McPherson,
you may proceed.
Mr. Clay R. Hawkins of Ohio.
Goddamn it, I'm voting yes.
I don't care,
you shoot me dead!
You shoot me dead!
I am voting yes!
Mr. Edwin F. LeClerk.
No!
Oh, to hell with it.
Shoot me dead, too! Yes!
I mean...
...abstention. Abstention!
Spineless!
Mr. Alexander Coffroth.
I vote...
...yes.
Yea.
James Brooks...
...nay.
Josiah Grenelle...
...yea.
Meyer Strauss...
Nay.
- Mr. Joseph Marstern.
- Nay.
- Mr. Chilton A. Elliot.
- No!
- Mr. Daniel G. Stuart.
- I vote yes.
- Mr. Howard Guilfoyle.
- Yea.
- John F. McKenzie.
- Andrew E. Fink.
- Nay.
- Mr. John A. Castle.
- Yea.
- Mr. Hanready.
- Nay.
- And Mr. Rufus Warren?
- Yea.
The roll call concludes.
The voting is completed. Now--
Mr. Clerk,
please call my name.
I want to cast a vote.
I object.
The Speaker doesn't vote.
The Speaker may vote
if he so chooses.
It is highly unusual, sir.
This isn't usual,
Mr. Pendleton.
This is history.
How does
Mr. Schuyler Colfax vote?
Aye, of course.
The final vote...
...eight absent
or not voting...
...fifty-six votes against...
...one hundred and
nineteen votes for.
With a margin of two votes--
We chose great leadership.
We'll rally
round the flag, boys
We'll rally once again
Shouting the battle cry
of freedom
We will rally
from the hillside
We'll gather from the plain
Shouting the battle cry
of freedom
The Union forever!
Hurrah, boys, hurrah!
Down with the traitor
And up with the star
Shout, shout
the battle cry of Freedom!
Congratulations, Mr. Chairman.
The bill, Mr. McPherson.
May I...?
The Union forever!
Hurrah, boys, hurrah!
That's, that's
the official bill.
I'll return it in the morning.
Creased...
...but unharmed.
Shouting the battle cry
of freedom
We are springing to the call
Of the loyal, true and brave
Shouting the battle cry
of freedom
And we'll fill
our vacant ranks
With a million freemen more
Shouting the battle cry
of freedom
The Union forever!
Hurrah, boys, hurrah!
Down with the traitor
And up with the star
A gift for you.
The greatest measure
of the 19th century,
...passed by corruption...
...aided and abetted by
the purest man in America.
I wish you had been present.
- I wish I'd been.
- It was a spectacle.
You can't bring your
housekeeper to the House.
I won't give them gossip.
This is enough.
This is...
...it's more than
enough for now.
Read it to me again, my love.
- "Proposed--"
- And adopted.
"Adopted...
...an amendment to...
...the Constitution of
the United States.
Section One.
Neither slavery nor
involuntary servitude...
...except as
a punishment for crime...
...whereof the party shall
have been duly convicted...
...shall exist within
the United States...
...or any place subject
to their jurisdiction."
Section Two.
"Congress shall have power
to enforce this amendment...
...by appropriate
legislation."
Let me be blunt.
Will the Southern states...
...resume their former
position in the Union...
...speedily enough
to enable us...
...to block ratification
to this here...
...13th Amendment?
I'd like peace immediately.
Yes, and...?
I'd like your states
restored to...
...their practical relations
with the Union immediately.
If this could be
given me in writing...
...as Vice President
of the Confederacy,
I'd bring that document...
...with celerity,
to Jefferson Davis.
Surrender.
And we can
discuss reconstruction.
Surrender won't be thought of.
Unless you've assured us,
in writing...
...we'll be readmitted in time
to block this amendment.
This is the arrogant demand
of a conqueror.
You'll not be a
conquered people, Mr. Hunter.
You will be citizens.
Returned to the laws and
the guarantees of rights...
...of the Constitution.
Which now extinguishes
slavery.
And with it, our economy.
All our laws
will be determined by...
...a Congress of
vengeful Yankees.
All our rights will be subject
to a Supreme Court...
...benched by bloody
Republican radicals.
All our traditions
will be obliterated.
We won't know
ourselves anymore.
We ain't here to
discuss reconstruction.
We have no legal basis
for that discussion.
But I don't want
to deal falsely.
The Northern states
will ratify, most of them.
As I figure it, it remains for
two of the Southern states...
...to do the same...
...even after
all are readmitted.
And I been working on that.
Tennessee and Louisiana.
Arkansas, too, most likely.
It'll be ratified.
Slavery, sir...
It's done.
If we submit ourselves
to law, Alex...
...even submit to
losing freedoms...
...the freedom to oppress,
for instance...
...we may discover
other freedoms...
...previously unknown to us.
Had you kept faith
with the democratic process,
...as frustrating
as that can be--
Come, sir.
Spare us, at least,
these pieties.
Did you defeat us
with ballots?
How have you held
your Union together?
Through democracy?
How many hundreds
of thousands have died...
...during your administration?
Your Union, sir, is bonded
in cannon fire and death.
It may be you're right.
But say all we done
is show the world...
...that democracy isn't chaos.
That there is a great,
invisible strength...
...in a people's union.
Say we've shown that a people
can endure awful sacrifice...
...and yet cohere.
Mightn't that save at least...
...the idea of democracy
to aspire to?
Eventually to
become worthy of?
At all rates,
whatever may be proven...
...by blood and sacrifice...
must have been proved by now.
Shall we stop this bleeding?
Once he surrenders,
...send his boys back
to their homes...
...and their farms,
their shops.
Yes, sir.
As we discussed.
Liberality all around,
not punishment.
I don't want that.
And their leaders,
Jeff and the rest of them...
...they escape,
leave the country...
...while my back's turned,
that wouldn't upset me none.
When peace comes,
it mustn't just be hangings.
By outward appearance...
...you're ten years older
than you were a year ago.
Some weariness
has bit at my bones.
I never seen
the like of it before,
...what I seen today.
Never seen
the like of it before.
You always knew that.
What this was going to be.
Intimate and ugly.
You must have
needed to see it close...
...when you decided to
come down here.
We've made it possible for one
another to do terrible things.
We've won the war.
Now you have to
lead us out of it.
You have an itch to travel?
I'd like that.
To the West, by rail.
Overseas.
The Holy Land.
Awfully pious for a man...
...who takes his wife out
buggy-riding on Good Friday.
Jerusalem.
Where David and
Solomon walked.
I dream of walking
in that ancient city.
All anyone
will remember of me...
...is I was crazy and
I ruined your happiness.
Anyone thinks that
doesn't understand, Molly.
When they look at you...
...at what it cost to live
at the heart of this...
...they'll wonder at it.
They'll wonder at you.
They should.
But they should
also look at...
...the wretched woman
by your side...
...if they want to understand
what this was truly like.
For the ordinary person.
For anyone other than you.
You must try to be happier.
We must, both of us.
We've both been
so miserable for so long.
I did say some colored men--
The intelligent,
the educated, and the...
...veterans. I qualified it.
Mr. Stevens is furious.
He wants to know
why you qualified it.
No one heard the
intelligent or educated part.
All they heard
was the first time...
...any president has ever
made mention...
...of Negro voting.
Still, I wish I'd mentioned
it in a better speech.
Mr. Stevens
also wants to know...
...why you didn't make
a better speech.
Mrs. Lincoln is
waiting in the carriage.
She wants me to remind you
of the hour, and that...
...you'll have to pick up...
...Miss Harris and
Major Rathbone.
- Am I in trouble?
- No, sir.
Thank you, Mr. Slade.
I suppose it's time to go.
Though I would rather stay.
The President has been shot!
The President...
...has been shot!
At Ford's Theater!
No. No!
It's 7:22 in the morning...
...Saturday,
the 15th of April.
It's all over.
The President is no more.
Now he belongs to the ages.
Fondly do we hope...
...fervently do we pray...
...that this mighty
scourge of war,
...may speedily pass away.
Yet if God wills
that it continue...
...until all
the wealth piled...
...by the bondman's
two hundred and fifty years...
...of unrequited toil
shall be sunk...
...and until every drop of
blood drawn with the lash...
...shall be paid by another
drawn with the sword...
...as was said
three thousand years ago,
...so still it must be said,
"The judgments of the Lord...
...are true and righteous
altogether."
With malice toward none...
...with charity for all...
...with firmness in the right,
...as God gives us
to see the right...
...let us strive on to finish
the work we are in...
...to bind up the
nation's wounds...
...to care...
...for him who shall have
borne the battle...
...and for his widow...
...and his orphan...
...to do all which may
achieve and cherish...
...a just and lasting peace
among ourselves...
...and with all nations.