Whenever I get gloomy
with the state of the world,
I think about the arrivals
gate at Heathrow airport.
General opinion
started to make out
that we live in a world
of hatred and greed,
but I don't see that.
Seems to me that
love is everywhere.
Often it's not particularly
dignified or newsworthy,
but it's always there.
Fathers and sons,
mothers and daughters,
husbands and wives,
boyfriends, girlfriends,
old friends.
When the planes
hit the Twin Towers,
as far as I know, none of the
phone calls from the people on board
were messages of
hate or revenge.
They were all
messages of love.
If you look for it,
I've got a sneaky feeling
you'll find that love
actually is all around.
I feel it in my fingers
I feel it in my toes
Feel it in my toes, yeah
Love is all around me
And so the...
I'm afraid you
did it again, Bill.
It's just, I know the old
version so well, you know.
Well, we all do.
That's why we're
making the new version.
Right, okay, let's go.
I feel it in my fingers
In my fingers
I feel it in my toes
Feel it in my toes, yeah
Love is all...
Fuck, wank, bugger,
shitting ass head and hole.
Start again.
I feel it in my fingers
In my fingers
I feel it in my toes
Feel it in my toes, yeah
Christmas is all around me
All around me
And so the feeling grows
So the feeling grows
It's written in the wind
In the wind
It's everywhere I go
Everywhere I go
So if you
really love Christmas
Love Christmas
Come on and let it snow
Come on and let it...
This is shit, isn't it?
Yep,
solid gold shit, maestro.
God, I'm so late.
It's just round the corner.
You'll make it.
You sure you don't mind
me going without you?
No, really.
I'm just feeling so rotten.
I love you.
I know.
I love you even when you're
sick and look disgusting.
I know. Now, go or
you will actually miss it.
Right.
Did I mention that I love you?
Yes, you did.
Get out, loser.
Karen, it's me again.
I'm sorry, I literally
don't have anyone else to talk to.
Absolutely. Horrible moment right
now, though. Can I call you back?
Of course.
Doesn't mean I'm not terribly
concerned that your wife just died.
Understood.
Bugger off, call me later.
So what's this
big news then?
We've been given our
parts in the nativity play...
...and I'm the lobster.
The lobster?
Yeah.
In the nativity play?
Yeah. First lobster.
There was more than one lobster
present at the birth of Jesus?
Duh.
Best sandwiches in Britain.
Try my lovely nuts?
Beautiful muffin
for a beautiful lady.
Morning, my future wife.
Okay, you can
stop there. Thanks.
I'm gonna need a couple
of orange gels, please, mate.
And by the way, he
introduced me as John,
but actually
everyone calls me Jack.
Fine. Nice to meet you, Jack.
He got me right, though.
I'm just Judy.
Great, Just Judy!
No surprises?
No surprises.
Not like the stag night?
Unlike the stag night.
Do you admit the Brazilian
prostitutes were a mistake?
I do.
And it would've been much better
if they'd not turned out to be men?
That is true.
Good luck, kiddo.
Prime Minister!
Thank you.
Welcome, Prime Minister.
I must work
on my wave.
How are you?
How are you feeling?
Cool. Powerful.
Would you like to meet
your household staff?
Yes, I would like
that very much indeed.
Anything to put off
actually running the country.
This is Terence. He's in charge.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
I had an uncle
called Terence once.
Hated him.
I think he was a pervert.
But I very much
like the look of you.
This is Pat.
Hello, Pat.
Good morning, sir.
I'm the housekeeper.
Right. It should be a lot easier
with me than with the last lot.
No nappies, no teenagers,
no scary wife.
And this is Natalie.
She's new, like you.
Hello, Natalie.
Hello, David.
I mean, sir.
Shit, I can't believe
I've just said that.
And now I've gone and said
"shit." Twice. I'm so sorry, sir.
It's fine, it's fine.
You could've said "fuck"
and then we'd have been in
real trouble. Thank you, sir.
I did have an awful premonition I
was gonna fuck up on my first day.
Oh, piss it!
Right, I'll go get my things and
then let's fix the country, shall we?
Yeah,
I can't see why not.
It's all right.
Did you see what I did?
Yes, I did.
I just went...
Hello, there.
I'm right over here.
Yeah, I'm in here.
Okay. Good. Thank you.
Oh, no.
That is so inconvenient.
In the presence of God, Peter
and Juliet have given their consent
and made their marriage
vows to each other.
They've declared their marriage
by the giving and receiving of rings.
I therefore proclaim that
they are husband and wife.
And you resisted the
temptation for surprises.
Yeah, I'm mature now.
Love, love, love
Did you do this?
No.
Love, love, love, love
There's nothing you can do
that can't be done
It...
There's nothing you can sing
that can't be sung
There's nothing you can say but
you can learn how to play the game
It's easy
All you need is love
All you need is love, love
Love is all you need...
Look, it's Pikey.
Hello! What the hell
are you doing here?
I just popped over
to borrow some old CDs.
The lady of the house
let you in, did she?
Yeah.
Lovely, obliging girl.
All right,
I just thought I'd pop back
before the reception
and see if she's better.
This is good.
Listen, I've been thinking.
I think perhaps
we ought to take
Mum out for her birthday
on Friday. What do you think?
I just feel we've been
bad sons this year.
Okay, sounds fine.
A bit boring but fine.
Hurry up, big boy!
I'm naked, and I want you at
least twice before Jamie gets home.
I am so
happy to see you!
A delicious delicacy?
No, thanks.
Taste explosion?
Food?
No, thanks.
Yeah, a bit dodgy, isn't it?
Looks like a dead baby's finger.
Tastes like it, too.
I'm Colin, by the way.
I'm Nancy.
Wicked.
What do you do, Nancy?
I'm a cook.
Ever do weddings?
Yes, I do.
They should've asked
you to do this one.
They did.
God, I wish you hadn't
have turned it down.
I didn't.
Right.
I've just worked out why
I can never find true love.
Why is that?
English girls. They're
stuck up, you see.
And I am primarily
attractive to girls
who are, you know,
cooler, game for a laugh.
Like American girls. So I
should just go to America.
I would get a girlfriend
there instantly.
What do you think?
I think it's crap, Colin.
That's where you're wrong.
American girls would seriously
dig me with my cute British accent.
You don't have a cute
British accent.
Yes, I do!
I'm going to America.
Colin, you're a lonely, ugly
asshole, and you must accept it.
Never. I am Colin, God of Sex.
I'm just on the wrong
continent, that's all.
Bit of quiet while we
finish the lighting, guys!
I thought I was never
gonna make it here today.
The traffic was just...
Unbelievable.
Judy, could you take
the top off this time?
Lighting and camera need to
know when we're actually gonna
see the nipples
and when we're not.
Yes, okay. Right. At least
it's nice and warm in here.
Yeah. It's not
always the case, is it?
I was standing in for Brad Pitt
once on Seven Years in Tibet...
Yes, yeah.
Bloody freezing.
Sorry, guys, time's pretty tight
and we have to get the actors in.
Fine.
I promise I won't look.
Right, let's have
another look at that one, please.
And Jerry says if you can just
put your hands on her breasts.
All right, okay, yeah.
Is that all right?
Yes. Yeah, fine.
I'll warm them up.
And massage them, please.
Right.
It's junction 13 that's
just murder, isn't it?
Total gridlock this morning.
Jo and I had a lot of time
to prepare for this moment.
Some of her
requests, for instance,
that I should bring Claudia
Schiffer as my date to the funeral,
I was confident she
expected me to ignore.
But others she was
pretty damn clear about.
When she first mentioned
what's about to happen,
I said,
"Over my dead body."
And she said,
"No, Daniel, over mine."
And as usual,
my darling girl
and Sam's
darling mom was right.
So she's going to say her final
farewell to you not through me but,
inevitably, ever so coolly,
through the immortal
genius of the Bay City Rollers.
Subtitle
www.movieddl.me
Do you love him?
What?
No, I just thought I'd ask the blunt
question in case it was the right one
and you needed
someone to talk to about it
and no one had
ever asked you,
so you've never been able to talk
about it though you might've wanted to.
No. No. No is the
answer. No. Absolutely not.
So that's a no, then?
Yes.
This DJ,
what do you reckon?
The worst in history?
Probably.
I think it all hangs
on the next song.
Now here's one
for the lovers.
That's quite a few of you, I
shouldn't be surprised and a half.
He's done it, it's official.
Worst DJ in the world.
Sarah's waiting for you.
Yes, of course.
Great, good, good.
How are you doing, Mia?
Are you settling in fine?
Learning who to avoid?
Absolutely.
Harry?
Sarah, switch off your
phone and tell me exactly
how long it is that
you've been working here.
Two years, seven months,
three days and, I suppose,
what, two hours?
And how long have you been in love
with Karl, our enigmatic chief designer?
Two years,
seven months, three days
and, I suppose, an
hour and 30 minutes.
Thought as much.
Do you think everybody knows?
Yes.
Do you think Karl knows?
That is...
That is bad news.
I just thought that
maybe the time had come
to do something about it.
Like what?
Invite him out for a drink, and
then after about 20 minutes,
casually drop into the conversation
the fact that you'd like to marry him
and have lots of sex
and babies.
You know that?
Yes.
And so does Karl.
Think about it,
for all our sakes.
It's Christmas.
Certainly. Excellent.
Will do. Thanks, boss.
Hi, Sarah.
Hi, Karl.
Excuse me.
Babe.
Absolutely, fire away.
Mia, Mia, would
you turn that down?
What is that?
And that was the Christmas
effort by the once great Billy Mack.
Oh, dear me, how
are the mighty fallen.
I can safely put my
hand up my ass and say
that is the worst record
I've heard this century...
And, coincidentally, I
believe Billy will be a guest
on my friend Mike's show
in a few minutes' time.
Welcome back, Bill.
So, Billy, welcome
back to the airwaves.
New Christmas single,
cover of Love Is All Around.
Except we've changed the
word "love" to "Christmas."
Yes, is that an important
message to you, Bill?
Not really, Mike.
Christmas is a time for people
with someone they love in their lives.
And that's not you?
That's not me, Michael.
When I was young and
successful, I was greedy and foolish,
and now I'm left with no
one, wrinkled and alone.
Wow. Thanks for that, Bill.
For what?
Well, for actually giving
a real answer to a question.
It doesn't often happen here
at Radio Watford, I can tell you.
Ask me anything you like,
and I'll tell you the truth.
Best shag you ever had?
Britney Spears.
Wow.
No, only kidding!
She was rubbish.
Okay, here's one.
How do you think the new record
compares to your old, classic stuff?
Come on, Mikey, you know
as well as I do the record's crap.
But wouldn't it be great
if number one this Christmas
wasn't some
smug teenager
but an old ex-heroin addict
searching for a comeback at any price?
All those young popsters
come Christmas day,
they'll be stretched out naked with
a cute bird balancing on their balls
and I'll be stuck in some
dingy flat with me manager, Joe,
ugliest man in the world,
fucking miserable because
our fucking gamble didn't pay off.
So if you believe in Father Christmas,
children, like your Uncle Billy does,
buy my festering
turd of a record.
And particularly enjoy
the incredible crassness
of the moment when we try to squeeze
an extra syllable into the fourth line.
I think you're referring to,
"if you really
love Christmas..."
"Come on and let it snow."
So, here it is one more time,
the dark horse for this
year's Christmas number one,
Christmas Is All Around.
Thank you, Billy.
After this, the news.
Is the new prime
minister in trouble already?
Okay. What's next?
The President's visit.
Yes, yes. I fear this is going
to be a difficult one to play.
Alex.
There's a very strong
feeling in the party
we mustn't allow
ourselves to be bullied
from pillar to post
like the last government.
Hear, hear.
This is our first
really important test.
Let's take a stand.
Right. Right. I understand
that, but I have decided
not to. Not this time.
We will, of course,
try to be clever.
But let's not forget that America is
the most powerful country in the world.
I'm not going to act
like a petulant child.
Right, who do you have
to screw around here
to get a cup of tea
and a chocolate biscuit?
Right.
Yeah, come in.
These have just come through from
the treasury and these are for you.
Excellent.
Thanks a lot.
I was hoping you'd win,
not that I wouldn't have been
nice to the other bloke, too.
Just always given him the
boring biscuits with no chocolate.
Thanks very much. Thanks...
Natalie.
God, come on, get a grip. You're
the prime minister, for God's sake.
So what do you reckon to
our new prime minister then?
I like him. I can't understand
why he's not married, though.
You know the type,
he's married to his job.
Either that or gay
as a picnic basket.
Excuse me, Judy, if you
could just lower the nipples
and cheat them
a bit to the left?
Okay.
I have to say, Judy,
this is a real pleasure.
It's lovely to find someone
I can actually chat to.
Thank you.
Well, you know...
And ditto.
Thank you.
And the move again,
please, Judy.
Sorry.
God, sorry.
Are you all right?
Yeah, fine.
Exciting news!
What?
I've bought a ticket to the
States. I'm off in three weeks.
No.
Yes!
To a fantastic
place called Wisconsin.
No!
Yes! Wisconsin
babes, here comes Sir Colin!
No, Col! There are a few
babes in America, I grant you,
but they're already going
out with rich, attractive guys.
Tone,
you're just jealous.
You know perfectly well that
any bar anywhere in America
contains 10 girls more beautiful
and more likely to have sex with me
than the whole of
the United Kingdom.
That is total bollocks.
You've actually gone mad now.
No, I'm wise. Stateside I am Prince
William without the weird family.
No, Colin, no!
Yes!
Ja, darling!
Right, the Christmas party,
not my favorite night of the year
and your unhappy
job to organize.
Tell me.
It's basic, really.
Find a venue, over-order on the
drinks, bulk buy the guacamole
and advise the girls to avoid Kevin
if they want their breasts unfondled.
Wives and family and stuff?
Yeah.
I mean, not children.
But their wives and
girlfriends, et cetera.
Oh, Christ, you haven't
got some horrible six-foot,
tight-T-shirt-wearing boyfriend
you'll be bringing, have you?
No. I'll just be hanging around
the mistletoe, hoping to be kissed.
Really?
Right.
He now spends all
the time in his room.
I mean,
he'll be up there now.
That's nothing unusual
about that. My horrid son...
Bernard?
Bernard.
Stays in his room all
the time. Thank goodness.
Yeah, but, Karen,
this is all the time.
I'm afraid that there's something
really wrong, you know?
I mean, clearly
it's about his mom,
but, Christ, he might be injecting
heroin into his eyeballs for all I know.
At the age of 11 ?
Well, maybe
not his eyeballs, then.
Maybe just his veins.
You see, the problem
is it was his mom
who always used to talk
to him, you know, and...
I don't know, this
whole stepfather thing
seems suddenly to somehow
matter like it never did before.
Listen, it was always
going to be a totally shit time.
Just be patient.
And maybe check
the room for needles.
And then when he
sometimes does come out,
it's obvious
he's been crying.
It's just such
a ridiculous waste.
And now if it's going to
ruin Sam's life as well...
I just don't know.
Get a grip.
People hate sissies.
No one's ever gonna shag
you if you cry all the time.
Yeah. Absolutely.
Helpful.
So, what's the
problem, Samuel?
Is it just Mom or
is it something else?
Maybe school?
Are you being bullied?
Or is it something worse?
Can you give me
any clues at all?
You really want to know?
I really want to know.
Even though you won't be
able to do anything to help?
Even if that's the case,
yeah.
Okay. Well...
Truth is, actually,
I'm in love.
Sorry?
I know I should be thinking
about Mom all the time and I am,
but the truth is I'm in love.
I was before she died, and
there's nothing I can do about it.
Aren't you a bit
young to be in love?
No.
Well, okay, well...
I mean,
I'm a little relieved.
Why?
Because I
thought it would
be something worse.
Worse than the total
agony of being in love?
No, you're right.
Total agony.
Night, Sarah.
Night, Karl.
Yeah, absolutely.
Free as a bird. Fire away.
Alone again.
Naturally.
I'll deal with it.
All right.
Natalie.
Sir.
Thanks. Natalie.
I'm starting to feel
uncomfortable about us working
in such close proximity every day
and me knowing so
little about you.
It seems...
It seems elitist and wrong.
Well, there's not much to know.
Well, where do you live,
for instance?
Wandsworth. The dodgy end.
My sister lives in Wandsworth.
Yeah.
So which exactly
is the dodgy end?
Right at the end
of the High Street,
Harris Street,
near the Queen's Head.
Yeah, yeah, that is dodgy.
And you live with your
husband? Boyfriend?
Three illegitimate
but charming children?
No.
I've just split up with
my boyfriend, actually,
so I'm back with my
mom and dad for a while.
Sorry.
No, it's fine.
I'm well shot of him.
He said I was getting fat.
I beg your pardon?
He said no one's gonna fancy a girl
with thighs the size of big tree trunks.
Not a nice guy, actually,
in the end.
No.
You know,
being prime minister, I
could just have him murdered.
Thank you, sir.
I'll think about it.
Do. The SAS are
absolutely charming.
Ruthless, trained killers
are just a phone call away.
Oh, God.
Did you have this kind
of problem?
Yeah, course you did,
you saucy minx.
So, let's go.
We can definitely crack this.
Remember,
I was a kid once, too.
So, come on, it's
someone at school. Right?
Yeah.
Good, good.
And what does she,
he, feel about you?
She doesn't even know my name.
And even if she did,
she'd despise me.
She's the coolest girl
in school,
and everyone worships
her because she's heaven.
Good. Good.
Well, basically
you're fucked, aren't you?
Hi there, and welcome back.
So, Billy, three weeks
till Christmas,
looks like the real
competition is gonna be Blue.
Yeah, I saw them on
the show last week.
They weren't very nice
about my record.
No. Little scamps.
But very, very
talented musicians.
Yeah. Billy, I understand you've got
a prize for our competition winners.
Yes, I have, Ant or Dec. It's
a personalized felt-tip pen.
Great.
It's brilliant. It even
writes on glass,
so if you've got
a framed picture,
like, for instance,
this one of Blue,
you can just write on it.
A lot of kids
watching, Billy.
Yeah.
Hiya, kids.
Here's an important
message from your Uncle Bill.
Don't buy drugs.
Become a pop star and
they give you them for free.
And I do
believe it's a commercial break.
Thank goodness. We'll
see you soon. Bye-bye.
Look at him!
Just a minute.
Actually, they're not
funny. They're art.
Okay, let's say
Thursday, my place.
Great. But for now I've
got Juliet on the other line.
Can I patch you through?
She wants to ask you a favor.
Okay, fine.
Thanks and be nice.
I'm always nice.
You know what I mean,
Marky, be friendly.
- I'm always...
- Mark?
Hi. How was the honeymoon?
It was great. And thanks
for the gorgeous sendoff.
So, what can I do for you?
It's only a tiny favor.
I've just tried the wedding
video, and it's a complete disaster.
It's come out
all blue and wibbly.
I'm sorry.
I remember you
filming a lot in the day
and I just wondered if I
could look at your stuff.
No, look, to be
honest, I didn't really...
Please. All I want is just one
shot of me in a wedding dress
that isn't bright turquoise.
Okay, I'll have a look, but to be
honest, I'm pretty sure I wiped it,
so don't get any hopes up.
Must go.
Any progress with
our matchmaking plans?
No. I've done fuck-all and never
will because he's too good for me.
How true.
Stop.
And, of course,
your mobile goes.
Hello. Hi. How you doing?
So, how's the
Christmas party going?
Good.
Think I've found a venue.
Friend of mine works there.
What's it like?
Good. Good.
It's an art gallery. Full of dark
corners for doing dark deeds.
Right.
Good. Well,
I suppose I should
take a look at
it or something.
You should.
Ah, hello, Eleonore.
Hello, Monsieur Bennett.
Welcome back. And this year
you bring a lady guest?
No. There's a change
of situation. Just me.
Am I sad or not sad?
I think you're not surprised.
And you stay
here till Christmas?
Yeah, yeah.
Good. Well, I find you a
perfect lady to clean the house.
This is Aurelia.
- Er, hello, Aurelia.
- Hello.
I'm happy to have you here.
Unfortunately, she cannot
speak French, just like you.
She's Portuguese.
Ah, ah, good day.
Very good...
I think she's 10 years
too young to remember
there was a footballer
called Eusebio.
And "molto bueno" is Spanish.
Right. Right.
Anyway, it's nice
to meet you and...
Perhaps you can drive her
home at the end of her work?
Absolutely, yes.
With great pleasure.
Which is what? Turkish?
Beautiful.
Er, beautiful.
No, right.
Silence is golden.
As the Tremeloes said.
Clever guys, although I
think the original version
was by Frankie Valli
& the Four Seasons.
Great band.
Shut up.
Mr. President!
Over here, sir!
What will you
be talking about?
Mr. President, welcome.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
Come on through.
I'm sorry your wife
couldn't make it, by the way.
So is she. Although she would
have been kind of lonely, I'm sure.
Yes. Pathetic, isn't it? Just
never been able to tie a girl down.
Not sure that politics and
dating really go together.
Really?
I've never found that.
Yeah, well, the difference is
you're still sickeningly handsome,
whereas I look increasingly
like my Aunt Mildred.
Very jealous of your plane,
by the way.
Thank you. We love that
thing, I'll tell you.
Natalie. Hi.
Morning, ma'am.
How's your day so far?
Excellent.
My goodness, that's a pretty
little son of a bitch, right there.
Did you see those pipes?
Yeah, yeah,
she's terrific at her job.
No, absolutely not. We cannot
and will not consult on that, either.
That is unexpected.
Well, it shouldn't be.
The last administration
made it perfectly clear.
We're just being
consistent with their policies.
Well, with all respect,
sir, they were bad policies.
All right, thanks, Alex.
I don't think we're making progress
here. Let's move on, shall we?
Well, now, that was
an interesting day.
Sorry if our line was firm,
but there's no point in
tiptoeing around today,
then just disappointing you
for four years.
I mean, I have plans and I
plan to see them through.
Absolutely. Now, there is one
final thing I think we should look at.
It's very close to my heart.
Just give me a second.
I'll give you anything
you ask for.
As long as it's not
something I don't wanna give.
Hi.
Pathetic.
It's great Scotch.
I'll...
I'll be going, then.
Natalie,
I hope to see much more of
you as our two great countries
work toward
a better future.
Thank you, sir.
Yes, Peter.
Mr. President,
has it been a good visit?
Very satisfactory indeed.
We got what we came for,
and our special relationship
is still very special.
And, Prime Minister?
I love that word
"relationship."
Covers all manner of sins,
doesn't it?
I fear that this has
become a bad relationship,
a relationship based on the
President taking exactly what he wants
and casually ignoring all
those things that really matter to
Britain.
We may be a small country,
but we're a great one, too.
The country of Shakespeare,
Churchill, The Beatles,
Sean Connery, Harry Potter.
David Beckham's right foot. David
Beckham's left foot, come to that.
And a friend who bullies
us is no longer a friend.
And since bullies only respond
to strength, from now onward,
I will be prepared
to be much stronger.
And the President
should be prepared for that.
Mr. President!
Joe.
It's your sister on line four.
All right.
Yes, I'm very busy and
important. How can I help you?
Have you gone
completely insane?
You can't be sensible
all the time.
You can if you're
prime minister.
Oh, dear, it's the Chancellor of
the Exchequer on the other line.
No, it isn't!
I'll call you back.
No, you won't!
The trouble with being
the prime minister's sister is
it does put your life into
rather harsh perspective.
What did my brother do today? He
stood up and fought for his country.
And what did I do? I made
a papier-mâché lobster head.
What is this
we're listening to?
Joni Mitchell.
I can't believe you still
listen to Joni Mitchell.
I love her and true
love lasts a lifetime.
Joni Mitchell is
the woman who taught
your cold English wife
how to feel.
Did she?
Well, that's good.
I must write to her
sometime and say thanks.
Now, which doll should we
give Daisy's little friend Emily?
The one that looks
like a transvestite
or the one that looks
like a dominatrix?
It's almost
enough to make you feel patriotic,
so here's one for our
ass-kicking prime minister.
I think he'll enjoy this.
A golden oldie
for a golden oldie.
Yeah...
Mary, I've been thinking,
can we move the Japanese
ambassador to 4:00 tomorrow?
Certainly, sir.
Terrific.
Thanks so much.
Would you like the last...
Thank you very much... but no.
If you saw my sister,
you'd understand why.
That's all right,
more for me.
Just don't go eating it all yourself.
You're getting chubbier every day.
I'm very lucky I've got
one of those constitutions
where I never
put on weight.
Hello.
Sorry.
Hello?
Thank you.
No! I am so sorry.
No. Hold on.
It's a disaster.
God, it's half the book. No.
Just leave them, please!
They're not important.
They're not worth it!
Stop! Stop.
It's all just rubbish.
Just leave it.
God, she's in.
Right. And now she'll think I'm
a total spaz if I don't go in too.
Fuck - it's cold!
Fuck, it's freezing! Fuck!
This stuff better be good.
It's not worth it. This
isn't bloody Shakespeare.
I don't want to drown saving some shit
my grandmother could have written.
Just stop. Stop.
What kind of idiot doesn't make copies?
I really must do copies.
There'd better not be eels
in here. I can't stand eels.
Try not to disturb the eels.
Oh, God,
what the hell is that?
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
I know. I'll name one of
the characters after you.
Maybe you could name
one of the characters after me.
Or give me 50% of the profits.
Or I could give you
5% of the profits.
What kind of book is it?
Yes. It's...
Thriller... crime...
Crime. Crime, murder.
Scary? Yes,
sometimes scary.
And sometimes not. Mainly
scary how bad the writing is.
I'd better get back to work.
And then later you'll drive me home?
Sure.
It's my favorite time of day,
driving you.
It's the saddest part of my day,
leaving you.
Sorry.
And coming
up later this morning, it's this guy...
The bad granddad
of rock and roll,
here at 10:30.
Do not switch off.
Banoffee pie?
No, thanks.
Thank God. You would've
broken my heart if you'd said yes.
Right, well, lucky you.
Can I come in?
Yeah, well,
I'm a bit busy...
Well, I was just passing,
and I thought
we might check
that video thing out.
I thought I might be able
to swap it for some pie
or maybe Munchies?
Actually, I was being serious.
I don't know where it is.
I'll have a poke
around tonight then...
Mark, can I say something?
Yeah.
I know you're Peter's
best friend,
and I know you've never
particularly warmed to me.
No, don't argue.
We've never
got friendly.
But I just wanted to say,
I hope that can change.
I'm nice.
I really am.
Apart from my terrible
taste in pie and...
It would be great if
we could be friends.
Absolutely.
Great.
Doesn't mean we'll be able
to find the video, though.
I had a real search
when you first called
and couldn't find
any trace of it so...
Well, there's one here that
says, "Peter and Juliet's Wedding."
Do you think we might
be on the right track?
Yeah, well...
Wow. That could be it.
Do you mind if I just...
I've probably
taped over it.
Almost everything has
episodes of West Wing on it and...
Oh, bingo.
That's lovely.
Well done, you.
That's gorgeous.
Thank you so much, Mark. This
is exactly what I was hoping for.
I look quite pretty.
You've stayed rather close,
haven't you?
They're all of me.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yes.
But
you never talk to me.
You always talk to Peter.
You don't like me.
I hope it's useful.
Don't show it
around too much.
Needs a bit of editing.
Look, I've got
to get to a lunch.
Early lunch.
You can just show
yourself out, can't you?
It's a self-preservation
thing, you see.
Yeah.
Annie, my darling,
my dream, my boat.
Need you to do
a favor for me.
Of course. Anything
for the hero of the hour.
Don't ask me why, and for heaven's
sake, don't read stuff into this,
it's just a weird
personality thing.
But you know Natalie
who works here?
The chubby girl?
Would we call her chubby?
I think there's a pretty
size able ass there, yes, sir.
Huge thighs.
Yeah. Well, whatever.
I'm sure she's a lovely
girl, but I wonder if you could
redistribute her?
It's done.
Hey, Sammo. Can't sleep?
I got some
terrible news today.
Let's have it.
Joanna's going
back to America.
Your girl's American?
Yes, she's American.
And she's not my girl.
And she's going
back to America.
That's the end of
my life as I know it.
That is bad news.
Well, we need Kate
and we need Leo,
and we need them now.
Come on.
Hold on. Hold on.
Keep your eyes closed.
Do you trust me?
I trust you.
Fool!
Get off, you big bully.
All right, open your eyes.
You know, Sammy, I'm sure
she's unique and extraordinary,
but general wisdom
is that in the end,
there isn't just one
person for each of us.
There was
for Kate and Leo.
There was for you.
And there is for me.
She's the one.
Fair enough.
And her name's Joanna?
Yeah, I know. Same as Mom.
Yeah.
Prime Minister.
Thank you very much.
Oh. Apology.
Big, er... big family,
big tradition of Christmas presents.
Stupid.
Well, goodbye.
Thank you.
It was...
I will miss you.
And your very slow typing...
and your very bad driving.
You know I
love Christmas, I always will
My mind's made up,
the way that I feel
There's no beginning,
there'll be no end
Daniel!
I have a plan.
Thank the Lord! Tell me.
Well, girls love musicians,
don't they? Uh-huh.
Even the really weird ones
get girlfriends. That's right.
Meat Loaf definitely
got laid at least once.
For God's sake, Ringo
Starr married a Bond girl.
Whatever. There's this big concert
at the end of term and Joanna's in it.
And I thought maybe if I was in the
band and played absolutely superbly,
there's a chance that she
might actually fall in love with me.
What do you think?
I think it's brilliant.
I think it's stellar.
Apart from the one obvious
tiny, little, baby, little hiccup.
I don't play
a musical instrument?
Yes, sir.
A tiny, insignificant detail.
I suppose I'd better go
and do the duty round.
You're a saint.
Any chance of a dance
with the boss?
Yeah, sure, sure.
As long as your boyfriend
doesn't mind.
Not my boyfriend.
You're looking
very pretty tonight.
It's for you.
Sorry?
It's all for you, sir.
This must be a very
exciting moment for you,
fighting for the
Christmas number one.
How's it looking so far?
Very bad indeed.
Blue are outselling me
five-to-one,
but I'm hoping
for a late surge.
And, if I reach number one,
I promise to sing a song stark
naked on TV on Christmas Eve.
Do you mean that?
Well, of course
I mean it, Michael.
Do you want a preview?
You old flirt.
That'll never
make number one.
I suppose it's his job to
dance with everyone, isn't it?
Some more than others.
Just one dance?
Before we run
out of chances.
Who, me?
Unless you just...
No! No! Good.
Yes. Thanks.
Well, then.
I'd better go.
Okay.
Good night.
Actually,
I don't have to go.
Right. Good.
I mean...
No, that's good.
Just... Would you excuse
me for one second?
Sure.
Just one second.
Okay, that's done.
Why don't you come
upstairs in about 10 seconds?
Ten seconds.
Just tug it.
Okay.
You're beautiful.
I'd better answer that.
Hello. Hi.
Hello, darling.
No, no, I'm not
busy. No, fire away.
Right.
Yes, I... I'm not quite
sure it's gonna be possible
to get the Pope on
the phone tonight but...
Yes. Yes, I'm sure he's
very good at exorcism but...
Well, I'm sure
Jon Bon Jovi is as well,
and I'll definitely look into it.
Okay? Okay,
I'll talk to you later.
All right, bye-bye.
Sorry about that.
No, it's fine.
It's my brother. He's
not well. He calls a lot.
I'm sorry.
No, it's fine. It's fine.
I mean, it's not really
fine. It is what it is,
and sort of there being no parents
now, and us being over here,
it's my job to keep an eye
on him. I mean, not my job.
Obviously,
I'm glad to do it...
That's okay.
I mean, life is full of
interruptions and complications.
So...
Will it make him better?
No.
Then maybe
don't answer.
Hey. How you doing?
Right, right. No, please.
Please, please,
don't, little darling.
Between the two of us we'll find
the answer and it won't hurt anymore.
No, no.
No, I'm not busy. I...
Of course if you want
me to come over I will.
Okay.
That was a good night.
Except I felt fat.
Don't be ridiculous.
It's true.
Nowadays the only clothes I can
get into were once owned by Pavarotti.
I always think
Pavarotti dresses very well.
Mia's very pretty.
Is she?
You know she is, darling.
Be careful there.
Have you been watching
stuff on TV?
Yeah.
Every night.
Good.
And every day.
The nurses are
trying to kill me.
Nobody's trying
to kill you, babe.
Thank you.
Don't do that, my darling.
Don't do that.
Right. Back at 3:00.
Christmas shopping,
never an easy or
a pleasant task.
Are you gonna
get me something?
I don't know,
I hadn't thought.
And where's Sarah,
by the way?
She couldn't make it
in today. Family thing.
There's a word for hangover
I've never heard before.
See you later.
Yes. Looking forward to it.
A lot.
So are you gonna
give me something?
I thought I made
it clear last night.
When it comes to me,
you can have everything.
So, what do you need?
Something along the stationery
line? Are you short of staplers?
No. I don't want
something I need.
I want something I want,
something pretty.
Right.
Sorry I'm late. I had to
drop off Bernie at rehearsal.
Right, well, listen, you keep
yourself occupied for 10 minutes
while I go and do the
boring stuff for our mothers.
Thank you.
Looking for anything
in particular, sir?
Yes. That necklace there,
how much is it?
It's £270.
All right. I'll have it.
Lovely.
Would you like
it gift-wrapped?
Yes, all right.
Lovely.
Let me just
pop it in the box.
There.
Look,
could we be quite quick?
Certainly, sir.
Ready in
the flashiest of flashes.
There.
That's great.
Not quite finished.
Look, actually,
I don't need a bag.
I'll just put
it in my pocket.
This isn't a bag, sir.
Really?
This is so much
more than a bag.
Could we be quite quick, please?
What's that?
It's a cinnamon stick, sir.
Actually,
I really can't wait.
You won't regret it, sir.
Want to bet?
'Tis but
the work of a moment.
There we go.
Almost finished.
Almost finished?
What else can there be?
Are you gonna
dip it in yogurt?
Cover it with
chocolate buttons?
No, sir, we're going to
pop it in the Christmas box.
But I don't want
a Christmas box.
But you said you wanted it
gift-wrapped.
I did but...
This is the final flourish.
Can I just pay?
All we need now...
Oh, God.
...is a sprig of holly.
No, no, no, no.
No bloody holly.
But, sir...
Leave it. Leave it.
Just leave it.
Loitering around the
jewelry section, I see.
No. I was just looking around.
Don't worry. My
expectations are not that high
after 13 years of Mr. Oh-
but-you-always-love-scarves.
Actually,
I do love this one.
Hey!
What are you doing here?
Had to rent out my
flat to pay for my ticket.
You're not actually going ahead
with this genuinely stupid plan?
Yeah. I bloody am.
You think this backpack is
full of clothes? Like hell it is.
It is chock-a-block
full of condoms.
Excellent. Excellent.
Perfect, keep that going.
Look, sorry to be a
bit forward and all that,
but you don't fancy going
for a Christmas drink, do you?
I mean,
nothing implied at all.
Just maybe go and see something
Christmassy or something.
Obviously, if you don't
want to, you don't have to. I...
I'm rambling now, sorry.
No. That would be lovely.
Great.
You know,
that is really great.
Normally, I'm really shy
about this sort of thing.
Takes me ages to get the
courage up, so thank you.
Explain to me again
why you're so late.
For heaven's sake, woman,
can't a man have any secrets?
We've been waiting for hours.
It's the first ever preview.
It was a starry
night in ancient Jerusalem
and the baby Jesus was
in his manger.
Sherlock Holmes is
not a real detective.
I would like
half-pint of sherry.
a one-day travel card.
Oh, my God, I've got a terrible
stomach ache.
It must have been the prawns.
Milton Keynes has
many roundabouts.
My goodness, this is a very big fish!
It tastes delicious!
You'll come back
a broken man.
Yeah, back broken
from too much sex.
You are on
the road to disaster.
No, I am on shag highway,
heading west.
Farewell, failure.
America, watch out!
Here comes Colin Frissell.
And he's got a big knob.
Take me to a bar.
What kind of bar?
Just any bar. Just
your average American bar.
Can I help you?
Yes. I'd like a Budweiser,
please.
King of beers.
One Bud coming up.
Oh, my God.
Are you from England?
Yes.
That is so cute.
Hi, I'm Stacey.
Jeannie?
Yeah?
This is...
Colin.
Frissell.
Cute name.
Jeannie.
He's from England.
Yep. Basildon.
Wait till
Carol-Anne gets here.
She's crazy
about English guys.
Hey, girls.
Carol-Anne, come meet Colin.
He's from England.
Well, step aside, ladies.
This one's on me.
Hey, gorgeous.
That is so funny!
What do you call that?
Bottle.
What about this?
Straw.
Table.
Table. The same.
It's the same.
Where are you staying?
I don't actually know.
I guess I'll just check into a
motel like they do in the movies.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, that is so cute.
No, no, no, listen. This may be a
bit pushy 'cause we just met you,
but why don't you come
back and sleep at our place?
Yeah.
Well, I mean, you know, if it's
not too much of an inconvenience.
Hell no!
But there's one problem.
What?
Well, we're not the
richest of girls, you know.
So we just have
a little bed and no couch.
So you'd have to
share with all three of us.
And on this cold, cold night it's
gonna be crowded and sweaty and stuff.
And we can't even
afford pajamas.
No?
Which means we
would be naked.
No, no, I think it'd be fine.
Great.
Cool.
The thing that's gonna
make it more crowded...
Harriet.
You haven't met Harriet.
There's a fourth one?
Yeah.
Don't worry, you're totally gonna
like her 'cause she is the sexy one.
Really? Wow.
Yeah.
Praise the Lord!
And he's a Christian.
- Cheers.
One present only each
tonight. Who's got one for Dad?
I have.
Let Mommy go first.
I'll get it. I'll get it.
No, no, no. I want to choose
mine. I want to choose mine.
I think I want
this one.
I have, of course, bought you
the traditional scarf as well,
but this is my other,
slightly special, personal one.
Thank you.
That's a real first.
Rip it!
What is it?
I'm going to...
All right, I'll rip it.
God, that's a surprise.
What is it?
It's a CD.
Joni Mitchell. Wow.
To continue your
emotional education.
Yes. Goodness.
That's great.
My brilliant wife.
Yes.
Actually, do you mind if I just
absent myself for a second?
All that ice cream.
Darling, could you just make
sure the kids are ready to go?
I'll be back in a minute.
All right, all right,
let's take it easy.
Mine first. Mine.
Oh, my God.
It's a miracle.
You're all dressed.
Come on, come on,
come on, we're horribly late.
Right, then. Come on.
In the car. In the car.
Come on.
Has she noticed you yet?
No.
You know the thing
about romance is
people only get together
right at the very end.
Of course.
By the way, I feel bad. I never
ask you how your love life is going.
Uh-huh.
No.
As you know, that was
a done deal long ago.
Unless, of course,
Claudia Schiffer calls,
in which case I want you
out of the house straightaway,
you wee motherless mongrel.
No, no. We'll want to have sex
in every room, including yours.
It's a rainy
Christmas Eve all over the UK
and the big question
is who is number one
on the Radio One
chart show tonight?
Is it Blue or the unexpected
Christmas sensation from Billy Mack?
You might have guessed it,
although you may not believe it.
It's Billy Mack.
You are the champion!
Hi, Billy.
Hello.
We're live across the nation,
and you're number one.
How will you
be celebrating?
I don't know.
Either I could behave like
a real rock and roll loser
and get drunk
with my fat manager,
or, when I hang up,
I'll be flooded by invitations to a
large number of glamorous parties.
Let's hope it's the latter. And here
it is. Number one, from Billy Mack,
it's Christmas Is All Around.
Jesus, not that crap again.
Bill, it's for you, babe.
Hello. Elton.
Of course. Of course.
Send an embarrassingly
big car, and I'll be there.
It's gonna be
a very good Christmas.
Right.
I'd better be getting inside,
actually. My mom and, you know...
Of course, yeah.
It's getting a bit cold.
Well, good night.
Night.
Okay.
All I want for Christmas
is you.
Right.
Thank you. Good.
Good night.
Look, everyone,
it's Uncle Jamie.
Hi, Uncle Jamie!
Yes, splendid. It's
lovely to see you all.
And...
I'm off, actually.
But, Jamie, darling...
Sorry.
Man's gotta do
what a man's gotta do.
I hate Uncle Jamie!
I hate Uncle Jamie.
Gatwick Airport, please.
Fast as you can.
Night, Sarah.
Night, Karl.
I...
Merry Christmas.
Hi, babe.
How's it going? Yeah.
Is it all party, party,
party down there?
Sam, time for dinner.
I'm not hungry.
Sam, I've done
chicken kebabs.
Look at the sign
on the door.
Right.
It's a little long.
I'll get it.
Hi.
Who is it?
It's carol singers.
Give them a quid and
tell them to bugger off.
Merry Christmas.
Enough.
Enough now.
What the hell
are you doing here?
You're supposed to
be at Elton John's.
Well, I was there for a minute or
two, and then I had an epiphany.
Really?
Yeah.
Come on. Just come up.
So what was this epiphany?
It was about Christmas.
You realized
it was all around.
No. I realized that
Christmas is the time
to be with
the people you love.
Right.
And I realized that,
as dire chance
and fateful cock-up
would have it,
here I am, mid-50s,
and without knowing it, I've gone
and spent most of my adult life
with a chubby employee.
And, much as it
grieves me to say it,
it might be that the
people I love is, in fact,
you.
Well, this is a surprise.
Yeah.
Ten minutes at Elton John's,
you're as gay as a Maypole.
No, look.
I'm serious here.
I left Elton's
where there were
a hefty number of
half-naked chicks
with their mouths open in order
to hang out with you at Christmas.
Well, Bill...
It's a terrible,
terrible mistake, chubs,
but you turn out to be
the fucking love of my life.
And to be honest,
despite all my complaining,
we have had
a wonderful life.
Well,
thank you.
I mean, come on,
it's been an honor.
I feel very proud.
Look, don't be a moron.
Come on, let's get
pissed and watch porn.
Dear sir...
Dear David,
Merry Christmas and I hope
you have a very happy New Year.
I'm very sorry about
the thing that happened.
It was a very odd moment
and I feel like a prize idiot.
Particularly because,
if you can't say it at
Christmas when can you, eh,
I'm actually yours.
With love, your Natalie.
Jack, yeah, I need a car.
Right now. Thank you.
Don't wait up.
I'd like to go to Wandsworth,
the dodgy end.
Very good, sir.
Harris Street.
What number, sir?
God, it's the
longest street in the world,
and I have
absolutely no idea.
Hello.
Does Natalie live here?
No.
Right, fine.
Thank you. Sorry to disturb.
Hey, aren't...
Aren't you
the prime minister?
Yes. In fact, I am.
Merry Christmas.
Part of the service now.
Trying to get around to
everyone by New Year's Eve.
Hello.
Does Natalie live here?
No, she doesn't.
Oh, dear. Okay.
Are you singing carols?
No. No, I'm not.
Please, sir, please.
Please.
Well, I suppose I could.
All right.
Good King Wenceslas
looked out
On the feast of Stephen
When the snow
lay round about
Deep and crisp and even
Brightly shone
the moon that night
Hello. Sorry to disturb.
Does Natalie live here?
No. She lives next door.
Ah!
Brilliant.
You're not who I think
you are, are you?
Yes, I'm afraid I am, and I'm
sorry about all the cock-ups.
Not my fault. My
cabinet are absolute crap.
We hope to do better next
year. Merry Christmas to you.
Ah!
Hello. Is Natalie in?
Where the fuck
is my fucking coat?
Oh!
Hello.
This is my mom and my dad and
my Uncle Tony and my Auntie Glynne.
Hello.
Very nice to meet you.
And this is
the prime minister.
Yes, we can see that,
darling.
And, unfortunately,
we're very late.
It's the school Christmas
concert, you see, David.
It's the first time
all the local schools
have joined together,
even St. Basil's...
Too much detail, Mom.
Anyway,
how can we help, sir?
Well, I just needed Natalie
on some state business.
Right, yes.
Of course. Right.
Well, perhaps you should
come on later, Plumpy.
Natalie.
Well, listen, I don't want to
make you late for the concert.
No, it's nothing, really.
Keith will be
very disappointed.
No, really,
it doesn't matter.
The octopus costume's
taken me months.
Eight is a lot
of legs, David.
Hmm.
Well, listen,
why don't I give you a lift,
and then we can talk about this
state business business in the car?
Okay.
Lovely, yes.
Lovely.
Thank you.
Hold tight, everybody.
How far is this place?
Just round the corner.
Right. Well...
I just wanted to say
thank you for
the Christmas card.
You're welcome.
Look, I'm so sorry
about that day.
I mean, I came into the room
and he slinked towards me
and there was a fire
and he's the President
of the United States
and nothing happened,
I promise.
And I just felt like
such a fool because
I think about you
all the time, actually.
And I think you're
the man I really...
We're here.
...love.
Oh, wow.
That really was
just round the corner.
Well, look, I...
I think I'd better
not come in, you know?
Last thing anyone wants is some sleazy
politician stealing the kids' thunder.
No, please come. It'll be great.
No, I'd...
I'd better not.
But I will be very sorry
to drive away from you.
Just give me one second.
John's been very mysterious.
Where did you two meet?
No!
Come on in. We can
watch from backstage.
Okay. Terry,
I won't be long.
Look, this has to be a
very secret visit, okay?
Don't worry.
This was my school.
I know my way around.
Come on.
Look, the sheep are ready
already and you're not even...
David.
How are you?
Hi, guys. Hey, hey, hey.
You all right?
What the hell
are you doing here?
Well, you know...
Well, I always tell your
secretary's secretary's secretary
that these things are going
on, but it never occurred to me
you'd actually turn up.
I thought it was
about time I did.
I just didn't
want anyone to see,
so I'm gonna hide myself
somewhere and watch the show.
Good luck, good luck, Daisy.
Good luck, Bernie.
I have to tell you, I've never been
gladder to see my stupid big brother.
Thank you.
All right.
Now, we haven't
been introduced.
Right. Well, this is Gavin.
Hello, Gavin.
My copper.
And this is Natalie,
who's my...
Who's my
catering manager.
Hi.
Catering manager.
Watch out he keeps
his hands off you.
Twenty years ago, you'd
have been just his type.
I'll be very careful. Don't try something,
sir, just because it's Christmas.
No, seriously.
Come on. Showtime. Quickly.
Look, see you after, yeah?
Yeah, probably. Yeah.
Thank you, Prime Minister.
It's all right.
Come on.
Right.
Catch a falling
star and put it in your pocket
Save it for a rainy day
Catch a falling star
and put it in your pocket
Never let it fade away
Hillier School would
now like to present
their chosen
Christmas number.
Lead vocals by 10-year-old
Joanna Anderson,
backing vocals coordinated by her
mother, the great Mrs. Jean Anderson.
Some of the staff have
decided to help out,
and for this,
we ask you to forgive us.
Thank you.
I don't want
a lot for Christmas
There's just one thing I need
I don't care
about the presents
Underneath
the Christmas tree
I just want you for my own
More than you
could ever know
Make my wish come true
All I want for Christmas
Is you
I don't want
a lot for Christmas
There's just
one thing I need
I don't care
about the presents
Underneath
the Christmas tree
I just want you for my own
More than you
could ever know
Make my wish come true
All I want for Christmas
is you
You, baby
All the lights are shining
So brightly everywhere
And the sound of
children's laughter fills the air
Laughter fills the air
Everyone is singing
Oh, yeah
I hear those
sleigh bells ringing
Santa,
won't you bring me my honey?
Won't you please
bring my baby to me?
I don't want
a lot for Christmas
This is all I'm asking for
All I'm asking for
I just wanna see my baby
Standing right
outside my door
'Cause I just
want you for my own
More than you
could ever know
You will ever know
Make my wish come true
All I want for Christmas
Is you
And you and you
All I want for Christmas
Right.
So, not quite as secret
as we'd hoped.
What do we do now?
Smile.
Little bow.
And a wave.
Absolutely no idea.
I mean, can you imagine?
I'll see you later,
all right?
I'll speak to you. Bye.
Tell me, if you were in my
position, what would you do?
What position is that?
Imagine your husband
bought a gold necklace
and, come Christmas,
gave it to somebody else.
Karen...
Would you wait around
to find out...
Good night.
Night, darling.
Happy Christmas.
Would you wait around to
find out if it's just a necklace
or if it's sex
and a necklace
or if, worst of all, it's
a necklace and love?
Would you stay?
Knowing life would
always be a little bit worse?
Or would you cut and run?
Oh, God.
I am so in the wrong.
A classic fool.
Yes, but you've also
made a fool out of me.
You've made the
life I lead foolish, too.
Darling. Darlings!
You were wonderful.
My little lobster,
you were so...
What is that word?
Orange.
Come on, I've got treats
at home. Dad's coming.
Sammy! Fantastic show!
Classic drumming, Son.
Thanks.
Plan didn't work, though.
Tell her, then.
Tell her what?
Tell her that you love her.
No way.
Anyway, they fly tonight.
Even better. Sam,
you've got nothing to lose,
and you'll always
regret it if you don't.
I never told
your mom enough.
I should have
told her every day,
because she was perfect
every day.
You've seen the films, kiddo.
It ain't over till it's over.
Okay, Dad. Let's do it.
Let's go get the shit
kicked out of us by love.
Yes.
Just give me one sec.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
That's okay.
My fault.
No, no, really, it wasn't.
You're Sam's dad, aren't you?
Yeah. Stepdad, actually.
Daniel.
I'm Carol.
Carol.
Okay, I'm back. Let's go.
Yeah. Well...
I hope we'll meet again,
Karen.
Carol.
I'll make sure we do.
Yeah? Good.
Tell her.
What?
You know...
Don't be such an arse.
Look, there she is.
Where?
Over there.
Oh, no.
It's okay, we'll go to the
airport. I know a shortcut.
Good evening.
Mr. Barros?
Yes.
I am here to ask your daughter...
...for her hands in marriage.
You want to marry my daughter?
Yes.
Come here. There is a man at the door.
He wants to marry you.
But I've never seen him before.
Who cares?
You're going to sell me
to a complete stranger?
Sell? Who said sell?
I'll pay him.
Pardon me. I'm meaning
your other daughter - Aurelia.
She's not here - she's at work.
I'll take you.
You ! Stay here.
As if I would. Stupid!
Father is about to sell Aurelia
as a slave to this Englishman.
Wait. Wait.
Oh, no.
You better not say "yes" Father.
Shut up, Miss Dunkin' Donut 2003.
Look,
we're not actually flying.
You can't come through
without a boarding pass.
Not even to let the boy say
goodbye to the love of his life?
No.
I'm sorry, Sam.
Boarding pass, sir?
Just a moment, I know
I've got it here somewhere.
Sorry. Would you
mind hanging on to that?
Unless...
What?
Do you want to
make a run for it?
Hold on to that, as well.
You think I should?
Yeah.
Thank you. Hold those.
Okay.
Yes!
No, I must have left them where
I was having a cup of coffee.
I'm sorry.
Apparently he is going to kill Aurelia.
Cool!
Joanna.
Sam?
I thought you
didn't know my name.
Course I do.
Oh, Jesus.
Here, I've gotta run.
Where is Aurelia?
Why should I tell you?
This man wants to marry her.
He can't do that -
she's our best waitress.
Good evening, Aurelia.
Good evening, Jamie.
Beautiful Aurelia -
I've come here with a view to asking you
to marriage me.
I know I seems an insane person
because I hardly knows you
but sometimes things are so transparency
they don't need evidential proof.
And I will inhabit here,
or you can inhabit with me in England.
Definitely go for England, girl.
You'll meet Prince William -
then you can marry him instead.
Of course I don't expecting you
to be as foolish as me...
and of course I prediction you say "no"
but it's Christmas
and I just wanted to check.
Oh, God - say yes, you skinny moron.
Thank you.
That will be nice.
Yes is being my answer.
Easy question.
What did you say?
Yes, of course.
Bravo!
You learned English?
Just in cases.
Hello, Daisy.
This one's Greta.
Hello, Greta.
Here she is. This is Aurelia.
This is Juliet. This is Peter.
Mark, hi,
didn't see you there.
Yeah, just thought
I'd tag along.
Jamie's friends
are so good-looking.
He never tells me this.
I think maybe now I have
made the wrong choice,
picked wrong Englishman.
She can't speak
English properly.
She doesn't know
what she's saying.
Dad! Dad!
Oh, God.
Did you get us any presents?
As a matter of fact, I did.
Thanks, Dad.
How are you?
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Good to have you back.
Come on. Home.
There she is.
Hi.
Hello.
He should have kissed her.
No, that's cool.
Hey. What are
you two doing here?
I might get a shag at last.
Naughty.
Got to go.
Bye.
Now, this is Harriet.
Hi.
Really pleased to meet you.
Hello, Harriet.
I hope you don't mind, I sort
of brought my sister to stay.
This is Carla.
She's real friendly.
Hello, you must be Tony.
I heard you were gorgeous.
God, you weigh a lot.
Shut your face.