Our American republic
is not all that different
from old Rome.
Can we preserve our past
and all its wondrous heritage?
Or will we too fall victim,
like old Rome,
to the insatiable appetite
for power of a few men.
Time, stop!
I sing of Colossus,
and the history of Man.
Let us go whither
the omens of the Gods
and the iniquity
of our enemies calls us.
The die is now cast.
whether or not
their president is a crook.
- Watch it!
- Julia!
- Come on. Hey.
- Please.
We're gonna go out again.
- Call me. Call me later.
- Like, for breakfast.
Whoops!
I hate and I love, why do I so,
perhaps you ask?
- All right, let's go.
- You think so?
Julia, get in the car.
All right. Bye, Clodio.
Goodbye, my love.
You're not mad at me?
You're going to tell my dad?
Let's go.
Mayor Cicero's
financial problems are so huge
that only a federal bailout
can solve them.
Julia...
Attention, attention!
Detonation imminent.
Clear the area!
Repeat, clear the area!
Explosion imminent.
Wait.
Go.
This time,
you've gone too far, Catilina.
This site is under
Design Authority jurisdiction.
And what happens
if you've overstepped your mandate?
We'll apologise.
Apologise?
After the building's down?
Mayor Cicero will be pissed!
Yes!
Recently elected
New Rome Mayor Cicero's
poll numbers continue to drop.
Cesar Catilina,
of the blue-blood Crassus family,
wins a Nobel Prize
for invention of the Megalon,
a miracle building material.
When does an empire die?
Does it collapse
in one terrible moment?
No.
No, but there comes a time
when its people
no longer believe in it.
Then does an empire begin to die.
Our new mayor Franklyn Cicero
has inherited
a nasty fiscal situation,
so now he is blamed for the
firing of teachers, police...
Design Authority office.
- Put Cesar on the phone.
- Hold, please.
budget.
In hot financial news today,
Crassus National
is down seven points...
I'm sorry, Miss Wow,
Mr Cesar is unavailable just now.
I know he's there.
I'll let him know. Goodbye.
Wow Platinum,
your very own Money Bunny,
giving you the score
from the trading room floor.
Cesar gained to his side
history's richest man,
his uncle, Crassus,
who was here to support
Cesar's vision of New Rome,
which was displeasing to Mayor Cicero,
Cesar's bitter rival.
Hello, gentlemen.
Welcome. Good to see you.
Good to see you all.
Here we are, waiting above
this model of the city,
over the Design Authority's
newly demolished site,
which everyone
is now claiming as their own.
Hey, Mr Crassus, over here!
Hey, Mr Crassus! Over here.
Let me ask you a real question, okay?
Turn the cameras off.
Let's have some fun.
Fuck the cards.
What is it like being rich?
- What's it like?
- Yeah.
Well, you can scare people.
You like to scare people?
Sleighboy, Strayboy, Playboy...
Gay boy?
No, sir,
that's my sisters you're thinking of.
Word has it, you're doing a little
hanky-panky with your sisters.
If it's true, stop it.
Rumours, Grandpa, rumours. Rumour.
You could be the next male heir...
Could be.
Clodio Crassus Pulcher the Third.
But you never know.
- Running a bank is no joke!
- Is no joke!
Claude, protect our family name!
Whoo!
Hi.
Hello. Hello.
Welcome. Welcome.
Welcome, thank you. Thank you.
The heartbeat
of our golden city on a hill.
Envision what could be...
A fun casino,
the latest in electronic gaming.
And no construction delays
of any kind,
or trouble from the unions
or the waterfront,
thanks to the Mayor.
It's really neat,
when you run concrete.
Aw, come on.
- Come on! No?
- Whoo!
Let's go.
"To be or not to be,
that is the question.
"Whether 'tis nobler
in the mind to suffer
"the slings and arrows
of outrageous fortune
"or to take arms against
a sea of troubles
"and by opposing end them.
"To die, to sleep no more...
"and by a sleep
to say we end the heartache,
"and the thousand natural shocks
that flesh is heir to,
"'tis a consummation
devoutly to be wish'd.
"To die, to sleep...
"To sleep,
"perchance to dream,
"ay, there's the rub:
"For in that sleep of death
what dreams may come,
"when we have shuffled off
this mortal coil,
"must give us pause."
"There's the respect
"that makes calamity
of so long life..."
Nush,
what do you think we do here?
Wait it out.
"Who would bear the whips
and scorns of time,
"th'oppressor's wrong,
the proud man's contumely,
"the pangs of dispriz'd love,
the law's delay.
"The insolence of office,
"and the spurns that patient
merit of th'unworthy takes,
"when he himself might in his quietus
"make with a bare bodkin?"
Where's my bodkin?
As Chairman of the Design Authority,
my jurisdiction
covers parks and fairs...
Please don't take a picture of that.
Thank you.
Come out with me.
- I can't. I'm sorry.
- Why?
My jurisdiction
covers parks and fairs,
and we've already issued
the necessary bonds
to develop this site.
The Mayor's show for the honchos
has become a battle
for their attention,
especially with Cesar Catilina,
whom I am acquainted,
denying my requests for a comment.
I cleared this site
to create something to inspire people.
People? Wha...
When have you ever even cared
about people, Catilina?
A city that people can dream about.
People don't need dreams.
They need teachers, sanitation, jobs.
The "need" is to create something
that lives on
after a City Fair, Mayor.
Which is why Megalopolis will be built
entirely out of the Megalon,
which is imperishable.
The Megalon is unsafe!
Concrete, concrete, concrete,
and steel, steel, steel is safe!
Imagine today's society
a branch of civilisation
about to reach a dead-end...
Humanity as an old tree
with one misguided branch
called "civilisation..."
going nowhere.
I like trees as much as the next guy,
but we're not here to discuss trees.
People need help,
and they need it now!
No. Don't let the now
destroy the forever.
We are talking about people.
People, Catilina,
and how they live now.
No time to talk of
people's future?
Yet there's always time
to convince them
to use money they don't have,
to buy things they don't need,
to imitate people they don't like.
Which makes you the chief slumlord
and the Mayor of the city of nothing.
You call me that again,
and I will smash your face.
Easy, gentlemen.
Were you so cool and collected
when you poisoned your wife
and her body disappeared?
Is Megalon, your miracle method,
made from her body?
Is your poor Sunny Hope
a plastic girder somewhere?
A wall panel?
What really happened?
Well, you were the prosecuting DA,
so you know I was acquitted.
- And you're still a slumlord.
- I am not a slumlord!
You will not stand here
- and call me a slumlord.
- No, no, no.
No. No, no,
I am not a slumlord!
- Stop. I'm...
- You will never call me that!
Easy. Easy, Frank, calm down!
- No! No!
- Hold him.
I'm so sorry.
Is that what we're playing?
Three-year-old games.
Thank you.
Hit it, Jerry!
I'm Wow Platinum,
and that is the score
Come for me on the trading room floor
Every weekday at 9:00 am.
Mwah!
The great ladies of Rome
obsessed over fashion
while having intimate dealings
with the scum
of the gladiatorial shows,
poisoners, and blackmailers.
I really want to take him down
for being so nasty to my father.
Yeah, right?
Okay, we're gonna write him
a poison-pen letter.
I'm very, very good at those.
Let's kick his ass.
- A devil?
- Yeah.
Give him a little moustache.
He's still kind of hot though.
- Who?
- It's your cousin.
My cousin? Really?
You're bad.
You should wear that.
Fucking clown.
- I think I hate your brother.
- I do too.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
My God. My fucking God.
Yeah, I will, I fucking will.
Yes, we do.
When you were 22,
your buildings created the future.
But now your nephew, this genius,
he says they are obsolete.
I still have
some powder in my pistol, I must say.
Is that right?
Have you no concept of time?
For God's sake, turn yourself off.
Like most geniuses, he can be...
You were in that car
and you didn't take my call.
I waited till I had
good news to share.
Fuck your stupid Megalopolis!
Wow, it's the beginning
of the discussions.
It means more to you than I do.
Conversation, it isn't enough.
It's the questions
that lead it to the next step,
but initially you have
to have a conversation.
The city itself is immaterial,
but they're talking about it,
for the first time.
And it's not just about us
talking about it,
it's the need to talk about it.
It's as urgent to us as air,
and water, and...
Is it getting messier in here?
Mess? What mess?
Come on,
you're an obsessive-compulsive
wacko, Cesar.
You're anal as hell.
I, on the other hand,
am oral as hell.
What about your bad habits?
I'm trying to improve.
Well, I'm bored being your mistress.
I need to be half of a power couple.
Which half?
Whichever half you want
to put your giant foot on.
My career is beginning to slump,
my ratings are down,
and now
I need more.
Cesar. Cesar.
I love you.
I love you with all my heart.
Really, I do.
Never marry for love.
Cesar...
Why would you say such a thing?
Are you trying to deflect
from my amorous behaviour?
No, I'm just trying to do
a goddamn interview, come on.
Is there anything that you don't have?
There certainly is, young lady.
There certainly is.
I'd like to see Dr Catilina.
About what?
The future of the world.
That.
Boss,
some sixth grader is here...
And did she say I was tall?
She remembers you talked to her class
because it got them out of gym.
I know the one.
Okay, go ahead and send her up.
What if what connects power
also stores it?
Good idea.
Thank you.
I like that idea myself.
She's on her way up, Chief.
She ain't what you expected.
- My great expectations?
- No.
Holy Jesus Christ.
Aren't you a bit big
for a sixth grader?
I sent a letter to you last night.
A, childish letter,
and I want it back before you read it.
Childish...
No.
That one.
May I have it, please?
Unfortunately, I have already read it.
And yes, it was childish.
I had help,
and we weren't in our right minds.
But witty, I'd say,
in a cruel and insulting way.
Well, I think the way
you treat the mayor
is cruel and insulting.
Defending your father
is admirable, Julia Cicero,
as delinquent as usual.
I'm turning over a new leaf,
don't mess with me.
I'm not messing,
you're the one who came in disguise.
I finished a year of medical school.
One year of medical school.
Were you kicked out?
I was not. I dropped out.
I wonder why.
I guess you could say
my love of science
bumped up against a brick wall of...
intellectual vigour
on the subject of jellyfish.
Their mesoglea material
is a flexible skeleton, unique...
until encountering something higher,
almost spiritual...
like the Megalon.
Look, a real Nobel Prize.
Expired?
Nobel Prizes don't expire.
I meant your medication.
What I'm curious about
is the Mayor's take
on your absurd behaviour.
You ask my father
about people living as I do,
and he's shocked.
What's shocking about you?
I want to be the Statue of Liberty!
I see.
The gossip columns say that you...
Ooh, you read gossip columns.
Whatever for?
To waste time.
You have so much of it
you can waste it?
Sometime.
Dear.
Lots of empty bottles.
You know, I was reading
about you last night, where you said,
"In order to understand time,
consciousness, courage,
"you must identify it in yourself".
You really must have been
a rude and spoiled child.
As you are now?
So, do you still have
your med school microscope?
No, I sold it when I dropped out,
to buy drugs.
Psilocybin, of course.
And who supports your lifestyle now,
Daddy?
I hope I didn't ruin your breakfast.
- Come back.
- What for?
Well, for laughs, of course.
What else did you come here for?
I was trying to be a go-between.
You want to help me.
Yeah. And, well, I...
Well, I want to learn.
And you think one year
of medical school
entitles you to plough
through the riches
of my Emersonian mind?
- Entitles me?
- Yes.
You have no idea about me.
You think I'm nothing,
just a socialite...
No, not nothing,
but I reserve my time
for people who can think.
About science and literature
and architecture and art.
You find me cruel,
selfish and unfeeling? I am.
I work without caring
what happens to either of us.
So go back to the club, "bare it all",
and stalk the kind of people
that you enjoy.
Fine. I will!
Come back
when you have more time.
Yes.
I saw you change the laws of physics.
Could it be the great Cesar Catilina
doesn't obey anything,
not even T-symmetry?
What did you see?
I was hoping you'd tell me.
Interesting.
Follow me.
It is the daughter
of his rival Cicero standing here,
the offspring of Cesar's opposition.
And yet...
I like her.
This is it?
Walk into the future.
With your eyes closed.
And tell me what you see.
Um...
I see everyone,
in their neighbourhood.
Creating together,
learning together...
perfecting body and mind...
And they're celebrating.
They're...
They created shelter.
Because of the rain.
Just came right above me.
It's a perfect school-city
for its people,
able to grow along with them,
just like great cities
have always done.
What about those standing in your way,
who like it the way it is?
Like your father?
What, him? You're working for him?
My daughter, a traitor?
Daddy, please!
You taught me to be true to myself.
You can't keep living
in the Middle Ages.
That man is a megalomaniac!
He lures young beautiful girls
like you with his bullshit genius.
He destroys innocence,
loveliness, and asks of them
what Pygmalion asked of marble!
Daddy, he's not as evil as you think.
But there's... there's something.
Something almost magical.
Hey, ladies!
Hi.
- Hold up, sir.
- What?
You're going to stop
the Mayor's parade?
You gotta be fucking kidding me.
This man is the bane of my existence.
- I want him out of my life.
- Yes.
He actually made sure
I was here on time.
He dropped you off?
Smile. Smile. Smile.
"Soviet satellite
falling out of orbit in space..."
"...and its nuclear fuel
"will scatter harmlessly
over Labrador..."
- Hi!
- Hi.
- "an earth-orbiting..."
- And you!
"nuclear-powered Soviet satellite
"will plunge through earth's dense..."
- Hi.
- Hello.
- What's your name?
- How do you do?
- Huey.
- Great to meet you.
- Claudine. Claudette.
"combust...
"in the residual atmosphere,
of the satellite's
nuclear fuel cells..."
Yeah,
welcome to the magic carpet ride.
"emergency management discerned."
Which way did Huey go?
That way.
Well, let's all go this way, then.
Cesar...
Cesar, my darling.
May 12th.
Reviewing District Attorney
Cicero's files
regarding Catilina murder case.
Any place in particular, Chief?
Uptown, downtown, heaven, or hell?
Purgatory.
Copy that.
You like ruins...
You like going to Atlantic City?
We got time.
Well, we've always got time,
even if I don't understand it.
Time's a funny thing to understand.
Passing the time,
finding time, losing time.
Time that flies.
I don't get it.
How is spying being ethical?
It's not spying, it's research.
His wife's body completely vanished.
How? Why?
To where?
Julia.
I love you, Julia.
You can't cheat time
and you can't beat time.
You can't touch it,
taste it, see it, smell it.
Time stops for nobody.
And I mean nobody.
Cesar.
You piece of shit.
Pull, pull, pull, pull,
pull, pull around!
Hey, honey.
Surrounded by injustice...
so much suffering.
Stop, stop.
This doesn't make sense.
Cesar buys flowers.
But for who?
Okay, stop, stop.
My heart breaks for you, Chief.
Evening, Mr Catilina.
All right, wait for me, okay?
He still loves her.
He still loves...
We should go.
Such are the mysteries
of the human heart,
making it difficult
for this historian...
to understand.
- What goes there?
- A small stadium.
With a roof like gold tissue.
Tell me,
of all the institutions
your utopia will preserve,
which is the most important to you?
Marriage.
The wind blows
across the Aegean,
bringing what the ancients
learned from their ancients,
the poetry of Sappho.
"Some say cavalry
"and others claim infantry
and a fleet of long oars
"is the supreme sight
on the black earth.
"I say...
"it is the one you love."
They're so happy to see you.
Where stands the Colosseum,
so stands Rome.
When the Colosseum falls,
then Rome falls too.
And when Rome falls,
the world falls with it.
- Yes.
- My wedding gift to you.
Wow!
This is it?
God damn it, Jerry!
"Greed is but a word...
"jealous men inflict
upon the ambitious."
Now you have
everything you always wanted.
Wow!
Here, folks,
are the richest grandkids,
the notorious Claudettes:
Clodia, Claudine, and Claudette,
along with their tagalong brother,
Claude Crassus Pulcher.
Banker Hamilton Crassus's
snotty trust fund grandkids
show up everywhere in the city.
The richest kids in the world.
And rumour has it,
they're sleeping with each other too.
Thank you, Jake.
- Cesar!
Cesar!
Right here!
Okay.
Julia!
Hold on, hold this.
There's more here.
- You see this?
- Cesar!
We understand Megalon is not safe,
do you have any comment on that?
No, it is not safe,
it is incredibly dangerous.
What's your plan
for Megalopolis?
We all should run! No, it's very safe.
Best question anyone's ever asked.
What kind of pizza places?
Just a couple questions.
Just a quick statement.
How do you feel about your
father bankrupting the city, Julia?
I am not here representing the Mayor.
Cesar, do you plan
on staying out all night partying?
- Always. Always.
- Thank you for your question.
Julia,
do you still prefer girls?
- Questions?
- Do you want to dispel any rumours
- about your lifestyle?
- Who doesn't prefer girls?
Who doesn't prefer girls?
Everyone prefers girls.
Thank you for your questions,
have a great night.
Okay, we just head this way.
There's one more here,
you need to talk about the dress.
Tell us more about Megalon.
Hired help.
- Vesta, over here!
- Hi!
I can never get used to this. Hi!
Vesta!
Ladies and gentlemen,
ladies and gentlemen,
Vesta Sweetwater.
Is it true, Vesta,
is your dress made of Megalon?
Yes, the first one ever.
Designed by Cesar Catilina
just for little ol' me!
- Vesta, over here!
- Vesta!
Looking absolutely gorgeous tonight!
Millions of tiny cell cameras transmit
what they see
through to the other side.
I'm invisible!
Hello, would you like to buy
a military college cadet uniform?
Patches, golden buttons, everything...
What a disgrace.
He used to be an Academy cadet,
now he's selling the fucking thing.
Ladies and gentlemen,
and children of all ages.
Welcome to this wonderful gathering
in celebration of the marriage
of our brother Crassus
and his Wow of a bride.
Crassus Bank is saving our city
from debt.
Did you get
a prenuptial agreement?
It's you.
What are you up to with this...
Fraternity prank.
Did you get a prenup?
Well, I may be old
but I'm not stupid, you know.
Well, then
why are you marrying her?
She's my gift to myself.
She cures my headaches,
and she keeps me young.
I might even live forever.
Excuse me.
Whoop-de-do for the heir!
There he is!
- Hello, genius cousin.
- My congratulations, Uncle,
- you've chosen well.
- Well, you would know.
I'd like to propose a toast.
To Wow Platinum
and my dear Uncle Hamilton.
Together they represent the big three:
economics, journalism...
And sex appeal.
- That's a good one, I like it.
- To the future of our family.
To the future of our family!
Future of our family.
Future...
They say the only thing bigger
than Hamilton Crassus's bank account
is his prick.
Good evening, Mother.
Don't drink too much.
I think maybe alligators
have the right idea.
What's that?
They eat their young.
- It's what I'm gonna do.
- Crassie.
- This is my wedding.
- It's your wedding.
- That's why...
- My wedding...
- It's your wedding too.
- It's our...
How did you get the name Wow Platinum?
Is it Greek?
I picked it up at Penn Station
on my way to an employment agency.
- Holy... See, that's a lie.
- Wow!
She told me
it was from a Cracker Jack box.
Jesus, you can't trust what she says.
And let's give
a round of applause
for our reigning champion,
Gaius Metalus!
Hyah! Hyah!
These are his.
Byfavo remimazolam. Yummy!
Reporting for duty.
Listen, you're an aide-de-camp,
not a minder.
But once I cut loose,
don't worry, you're off the clock.
You're absolved. Have a punch.
Why do you pretend you're so bad?
Well, if you pretend to be good,
the world won't take you seriously.
But if you pretend to be bad...
they kill you.
Are the wrestlers coming?
There's Gargantua!
Gargantua's here!
Hi, I'm Leah Arpelles,
from my school's newspaper,
it's called the Dingbat News.
Is it better to look good,
or is it better to smell good?
I think both.
Amazonia!
Big-time hunks!
Is Cesar Catilina sexy?
That... is a big question.
I'm so jealous.
We call them C-notes,
I've got my cell phone number on them.
Okay, don't grab.
When did you smoke your first joint?
Never.
Your father hates Cesar.
Why work for him?
Is he your boss,
or is he your boyfriend?
Thank you very much,
Your Majesty, Your Highness, King.
Here we are in Sweden.
Thank you very much for having me.
From what I understand,
there's a buffet after this.
So, the faster I can say my speech,
the faster we can all eat.
What I like are those little hot dogs
wrapped in the pastry.
I think they're...
I can't remember the name
of them right now...
Pigs in a blanket,
that's what they're called.
Really, the Nobel Prize should be
for the person who invented those.
Cesar! Cesar! Cesar!
Make no mistake,
this discovery will change the world.
Nice jacket, Cesar.
Is that Baratha from Savile Row?
May I touch it?
10:17 pm. Drunk and stoned,
Cesar doesn't know
who he is for a few hours.
A moment of grace, perhaps?
- Are they together?
- No.
And with that womaniser?
"Womaniser",
that's an awful word.
As if the woman
had nothing to do with it.
Look at that.
When you leap into the unknown,
you prove that you are free.
When we leap into the unknown,
we prove we are free.
We prove that we are free.
When we leap into the unknown,
we prove that we are free.
Follow me, I'll show you.
But if it's our mind
that can invent gods,
and if from them flows such power,
why can't we apply
that power directly?
From this moment forward,
we perform without a net.
My God!
Look at that!
But if it's our mind
that can invent gods...
His pleasantness,
his beautiful skin,
middle-aged women scream for him
as girls scream for rock stars.
But if it's our mind
that can invent gods,
and if from them flows such power...
Cesar...
prove that we are free.
You fooled me!
When we leap into the unknown,
we prove we are free.
But if it's our mind
that can invent gods,
and if from them flows such power,
why can't we apply
that power directly?
But if it's our mind
that can invent gods,
and if from them flows such power,
why can't we apply
that power directly?
But if it's our mind
that can invent gods,
and if from them flows such power,
why can't we apply
that power directly?
Cesar.
But if it's our mind
that can invent gods,
and if from them flows such power...
Mr Crassus?
- Who's in charge?
- Right here, Mr Crassus.
Well, hello,
Mr Boss Man.
Play this for my grand finale.
Listen, do what he says.
- The bank is his.
- Absolutely free.
So everyone can see!
For your time, putz.
Widen out, camera 3.
Camera 4, punch in.
We did it!
Whoo!
Hey, get outta here, bozo!
Enjoy the show.
The vestal virgins
assured the success
and sanctity of ancient Rome.
Dedicated to Vesta,
goddess of the hearth,
whom Ovid calls "custos flammai",
or "keeper of the flame".
Ladies and gentlemen,
a vision of virginal veracity...
She took the "Pure Love Pledge".
I present to you
our own virgin sweetheart,
Vesta Sweetwater!
Okay, girls, come here.
Grab that and go in front.
You go in the front.
I always thought
that it wasn't true
That in the darkness,
the light came through
And then I found it, the missing key
Right there inside me, God's purity
I'm reachin' out
See through the clouds
Stand with me now, and lose all doubt
- I'm reachin' out
- 'Cause I'm here now
See through the clouds
- You have my vow
- Stand with me now
- Serenity is fine with me
- CLODIA: Foreplay...
I'll stand under the sun
Hear my song and hear my prayer
I'll pledge my purity
- It's my promise, it's my swear...
- I want each of you
to look into your heart
and give generously
to support her virgin pledge.
Which of you will pledge
a hundred thousand?
One hundred thousand.
Two hundred thousand?
'Cause I'm here now
You have my vow...
Five hundred thousand!
I know you, I feel you,
I see you, I hear you...
Remember,
her pledge to marry as a virgin,
that is money to the city!
And your pledge, joined with hers,
is helping our city 10, 12, 20 fold!
Been down the roads you've been down
'Cause I am you I know...
$1 million!
Just reach into your pockets and give!
We can make the difference!
That's it, that's it,
you see that?
There's some big money up here!
We can make
the numbers board go up, up, up!
$10 million!
We are going to do it!
We can do it!
Do I hear $100 million?
$100 million!
Thank you, Nush Berman,
for your generous pledge!
Under the sun, hear my song
And hear my prayer
I'll pledge my purity
It's my promise, it's my swear
You can see right through me!
That's good, stay with that.
Stay with that, camera 3.
It's Cesar!
Liar, liar!
Rather than just design the form
or shape of an object,
you can actually design
at the cellular level.
You can actually design
Ladies and gentlemen, stay calm!
Ladies and gentlemen...
Wait, ladies and...
Ladies and gentlemen!
Hey! Can you bring me down?
Bring me down!
Ladies and gentlemen!
Wait, ladies and gent...
Testing, testing. One, two, three.
Testing, testing.
In heaven's name,
Catilina,
how long will you try our patience?
How long will this madness
of yours mock us?
Hey, buddy,
don't look at your nose in the mirror
'cause it's not where it used to be.
To what depths of devastation
will your unbridled audacity
hurl this city?
Your sordid life
is marked
with every sort of scandalous blot,
every dishonour
and wicked stain
our human imagination can conceive.
What times!
Within this city...
there is nothing that can
give you satisfaction any more.
Apart from your own
degraded band of hangers-on,
does not the alarm of the people
have any effect upon you?
No man exists
who does not hold you in detestation.
I hold you in detestation,
whatever the hell that man means.
Resign in disgrace, Catilina.
It is your only choice, step down now!
Huey, anyone can own this city.
There's a big sign nailed to it,
"City for Sale".
Catilina stumbles
into the night, broken and dazed,
but there is no softness
in his degeneration.
This breakout
was long overdue, Miss Julia.
Lord.
Wait, what's happening?
- Hands where I can see them!
- Hands where you can see them.
Cesar Catilina, open the door.
He's asleep.
Hey, Cesar.
I don't care if he's asleep,
get him up!
- He's sleeping!
- Get him up right now.
He's sleeping! Excuse... Hey! Hey!
- Hey, no!
- Let go!
- This is not...
- Stop resisting!
- Stop it!
- Commissioner.
- Fundi, take it easy. Take it easy.
- What's going on?
- Mr Catilina is under arrest.
- What are the charges?
Unlawful intercourse with a minor,
statutory rape, and more coming.
- What are you talking about?
- No. No. No. It was a setup, okay?
- Get your hands off him!
- Give me your hand!
- Fuck you!
- Julia. Julia,
please get back in the car.
- No, he's not... No.
- Julia.
Okay, no.
- This is not right.
- Please, Julia.
- Wait! It's not...
- Julia!
Fuck you!
- This is not right!
- Julia, don't make it any worse.
This is wrong. No!
- Would you get back in the car?
- You're wrong.
Until he can
understand his rights,
we'll call it "protective custody".
Come on, Miss Julia,
let's get you home.
Revenge tastes best
while wearing a dress.
Time,
stop.
Vesta,
not a single thing on her.
Yeah.
I don't trust her.
Wait, what's this over here?
- Got it?
- Yeah...
Here it is.
Bingo. Vesta.
My God.
- Got it.
- She wasn't even born here.
She was born in Indonesia.
She came here when she was six.
Lying little slut.
Good job. Nailed it.
Okay, let's go.
Quick, quick, quick.
You can sit down.
It makes me very happy
that you came to me ahead of Cesar.
A father matters, yes?
Always father.
Always your faithful daughter.
Exactly
who else knows about this?
Come on, Daddy. She's 23 years old.
Clodio faked that video.
Catilina is
the guiltiest man unhanged.
But that's Vesta's birth certificate.
It exonerates him.
Legally, yes.
But not morally.
I can get another one.
Don't.
Julia.
I'm going to Hamilton Crassus.
Julia?
All the money in Rome
couldn't get me to change my mind.
- Julia.
- Hi.
Come in, come in, come in.
I had hoped to speak
with Mr Crassus.
I love that sound.
Listen, bitch.
You and I ought to have
an understanding.
You're on my territory now,
and you're going to play by my rules!
Okay?
One, Crassus is mine.
Two, the bank is mine.
And three, and this may come
as a little surprise to you...
Right.
Cesar's mine.
And he has been, for a long time.
Romans ruled the world,
but their wives ruled at home.
I'll be Robin Hood for Saturnalia.
Tra la la! Beautiful.
It's all great, and the shoes?
I can't trust you.
Why not?
You've been attacking your cousin
since you were six years old,
and I only hope you had
nothing to do with that shit.
Of course not. How...
How could you say that?
So what happens now?
Am I off the list?
What list?
Your list of heirs.
You're going to have
to prove yourself to me, son.
And cut your hair!
Teen singing sensation
Vesta Sweetwater,
who had marketed herself
as being a 16-year-old,
and the city's "Virgin Sweetheart",
is actually 23 years old,
the New Rome district attorney
announced today.
Forensic examination
of the photos of sexual acts
revealed that they were doctored
and not authentic.
There goes the dream
that you had for me
I guess I'm burning it down
It's all fucked
And there's no turning around
Hello!
How do you feel today?
What great new ideas do you have?
I bet there's at least 50 of them!
Addiction, Disgrace, Scandal,
and Murder.
The charges against you were dropped!
I've lost my power.
I can't control time any more.
Artists can never lose
their control of time.
You taught me that,
how painters stop time,
how architecture is frozen music,
how dancers combine time and space,
musicians rhythmatise it,
poets sing it.
I didn't murder my wife...
but my moods...
my mania...
they drove her to...
I'm sure she was proud
to be your wife.
Now, time,
stop!
Do it for me.
Try.
Stop time, for me.
Try it.
Hear me, time.
For Julia...
Just try.
Hear me, time, stop now.
We seem to have done it.
Dream?
The omens are bad, my love.
I was looking at the full moon,
when a cloud
that looked like a hand grabbed it.
Only those in a nightmare
are capable of praising the moonlight.
Poor Chippy
broke his leg in the door.
First Megalon splint, by Julia!
Chippy! Aw, what happened?
Her leg tissue will be fused
with the Megalon in just a few weeks.
Make an interesting shape,
but try not to break the structure.
Within five minutes,
we should be able to get to
a hospital, to a theatre.
All within five minutes.
This is what I'm talking about,
we need to be interconnected.
Let's take things from nature.
These are legs, faces, heads...
The fastest way is through
a straight line to a point.
Okay, next.
Look at that model again
and explain it to me one more time.
What's this?
Look just below the top.
That's gotta go.
Try to maintain the shape.
I remember,
they rushed me to the hospital
because I had a terrible stomachache.
Instead... what I had was you.
A genius son.
Mom, this is... this is Julia.
I wish I could have had a girl.
We could have gone shopping,
we could have had lunch...
Mom, Julia's a girl.
Instead, you were my great surprise...
And you go on and on and on and on
surprising everyone.
I don't...
Despite what you think, I'm not crazy.
My voices say I'm sane.
Well.
Without that girl's love,
you're going to be
a has-been and a fake,
like your father.
Do you know
that there is string theory?
Do you know what that means?
That there are 11, 11 dimensions.
It hasn't been proven yet,
but that's what they think.
It's all just strings, you know...
that interesting?
You know,
when you got that Nobel Prize,
why didn't you mention my name?
You could have gotten up,
and you could have said,
"To my mother".
- I was very sick.
- You could have said...
I forgot.
I'm sorry.
I don't think so.
They don't know I'm your mother.
When you're with her...
you're finally able to forget me.
- No, no.
- No?
No.
That hurt.
He hurt me.
You hurt me.
I was kissing you, Mother.
What a diff'rence a day made
Twenty-four little hours
Brought the sun and the flowers
Where there used to be rain
That's it. Faster.
No, you were doing it.
- You were doing it.
- I'm just doing a solo.
You've taken my life and turned it
into something really beautiful,
and I can't create anything
without you next to me.
No, I mean it.
You're the driving force
behind everything.
My inspiration comes from you,
my clarity comes from you,
my patience comes from you.
If I can imitate just 10%
of how you are in the world,
it would be a success.
I've never loved anybody like you.
Love you. I love you. I love you.
Go to hell, Cesar!
Excuse me.
What is this about?
Catilina levelled
their fucking neighbourhood
for his stupid Megalopolis.
He's an unelected monster!
He tore down our house,
ripped off the roof,
now we got no food, we got nothing!
- Fucking disgusting.
- Give them some money.
- Here. Here, take it.
- Hey, you guys okay?
Just look at them... I'm not sure...
See, this...
this is power,
this is where you find it.
You want power, you go public,
that's where the real power is.
Then you'd be giving the city
to a bunch of mongrels.
- I mean, look at them, look at them.
- Not mongrels, immigrants.
They're citizens these people,
they believe in voting, understand?
They hate Cesar, okay?
This is my chance to tear down
this bullshit Megalopolis.
I'm a citizen, you're a citizen.
These people are just human garbage.
Okay, okay, give me my money,
and get me to the front of them,
that's what you're doing. Yes?
Make way for Clodio!
All hail, Clodio!
Hail, Clodio! Make way!
Power to the people.
Yeah?
Get that for me. Buy that.
- Hey, here, give him the mic.
- I'll give it back to you.
Power to the people.
I care.
Hand this out. Hand this out.
- I care. I see you.
- Fuck Catilina.
- Where the hell is Cesar?
- I see you.
- Power to the people!
- I care.
- I care about you
and I'm here and I see you!
- Hands off our homes!
- Sorry.
- What is it?
Mr Nush Berman is here,
he'd like a minute of your time.
I'll... I...
Not in the residence.
I'll see him in the banquet hall.
Excuse me just one moment,
I'll return soon.
Come back soon, Frankie.
So we're going to go slow,
quick quick slow, quick quick slow...
Slow, quick quick slow...
I'm aware that this kid Clodio
is a close friend of your,
your daughter Julia?
He's no friend of Julia's,
he's an acquaintance,
and a bad influence.
He faked that video
of Catilina somehow.
He's picking up
a large popular constituency.
He's some kind of genius,
he can talk everything.
You handle this, Nush.
Okay. I'll fix it.
Just wanted to check with you first
because, you know...
Julia?
I don't mind the lightning,
but the thunder scares
the shit out of me.
- And...
- Your Honour,
- you're never going to believe this.
- What?
You know that satellite
that's coming down over Labrador?
- Yes?
- Well,
it's not coming down over Labrador.
How... How do they know?
Well, that's just it, sir,
they don't know, not exactly.
Well, when will we know, when it hits?
- Yes, Your Honour.
- That's too late.
I'm aware of that.
What do we do?
Mr Catilina, you've said that,
as we jump into the future,
we should do so unafraid.
But what if
when we do jump into the future,
there is something to be afraid of?
Well, there's nothing to be afraid of
if you love.
Or have loved.
It's an unstoppable force.
It's unbreakable.
It has no limits,
it's within us, it's around us,
and it's stretched throughout time.
It's nothing you can touch,
yet it guides every decision
that we make.
But we do have
the obligation to each other
to ask questions of one another.
What can we do?
Is this society,
is this way we're living,
the only one that's available to us?
And when we ask these questions,
when there's a dialogue about them,
that basically is a utopia.
Ralph Waldo Emerson said,
"The end of the human race will be
"that it will eventually die
of civilisation".
But trend is not destiny.
Time,
show me the future.
Together, we'll discover new paths,
which lead to the unknown
world ahead of us.
- You found me.
- I have good news.
What's that,
what's your good news?
Those cigarettes, Cesar...
Why is there lipstick
on the cigarettes?
Are you really asking me
- why there's lipstick...
- Who's been in our home again?
I was at home
and not on a jury stand...
- Why do you do this?
- Where the judge is asking...
- You use that great brain of yours.
- Why do I do what?
You manipulate. You blame.
Why do I use my brain
to find logical things...
And try to make me
feel like I'm the crazy one.
As opposed to
hypothetical situations?
But I'm not the crazy one here.
I'm not trying to
tell you you're crazy,
- but you're trying...
- You are, you are.
How are you
not trying to tell me I'm crazy?
You make me feel
that I'm imagining.
- It's not my imagination!
- It's so convenient...
I'm so prepared, all I do...
Save your dreaded heart,
our family together.
How long
will this madness of yours mock us?
A man of the future
so possessed by the past...
Which is important now,
more than ever before.
Why now?
Can't you even guess?
No.
Can't you see it in my eyes?
The result of all our drunken
messing around?
A baby?
- Yeah.
- A baby?
A baby.
Let's get married.
Married? What is that?
We can't get married.
Why not? Of course we can. A baby!
No, Cesar, you're in a moral pickle
of your own conscience.
You're already married.
Why didn't you and Sunny
have children?
We were trying.
Sorry.
Anywhere in Megalopolis,
you'll be able to ride
one of these to a park
in less than five minutes.
- Would you like to try?
- I would love to try.
Would you... Thank you.
All this is just
an exhibit, of course.
Frankie, come on.
Stick in the mud.
I mean, he comes up with magic
whenever he needs to sell something
to the people.
Frankie, come on, I'm floating.
Don't get it.
You will.
Plus, every adult,
every single adult will have
a private beautiful garden.
And I'll put this in, the kitchen.
Welcome to our home.
Cards, what fun.
What should it be, poker?
Nickel-dime.
I've put beans on the table.
Utopias offer no ready-made solutions.
Well, they're not meant to
offer solutions,
they're meant to
ask the right questions.
Yes, but...
utopias turn into dystopias.
So, we should just accept this
endless conflict that we live in now?
Wasn't it human friendliness
that stimulated our brains
by "learning",
and enabled us to out-compete
all the other species on earth?
Dear. Blah blah blah.
It's a nice picture,
but how do we know?
Well, there's no other way.
How else could such
a slow-maturing species
make it through the Ice Age?
- Now, boys...
- How could such few,
weak, bipedal apes
evolve more costly brains,
smarter brains than other apes,
and do it without reproducing
so slowly they'd go extinct?
We were fierce, aggressive, war-like
as our closest ancestors, chimpanzees.
Yes, yes, but there were so few of us,
and scattered across a vast continent,
so... no.
In or out,
are we playing cards
or reinventing history?
Where were we?
This is an enormous pot.
Cesar is winning.
"Civilisation itself remains
the great enemy of mankind."
Rousseau.
You're quoting Petrarch,
to be accurate, misquoting him.
Julia can quote anyone.
- I...
- Humour me, please.
Daddy.
You remember. - I do, I remember.
Poise...
"It is the responsibility
of leadership
"to work intelligently
with what is given,
"and not waste time
fantasising about a world
"of flawless people
and perfect choices."
- Marcus Aurelius.
- Hear, hear.
Excellent.
Don't say your philosophy, Daddy,
embody it.
"The object of life is not to be
on the side of the majority,
"but to escape finding yourself
"in the ranks of the insane."
Marcus Aurelius.
"The universe is change,
"our life is what
our thoughts make it."
Marcus Aurelius.
Julia,
there is no one like you,
having such beautiful things
in your home.
And I understand
it can expand as needed?
Well, yes.
Now that we're going to have a baby.
- What?
- Darling!
If it's a girl,
she'll be given the name "Sunny Hope".
And if it's a boy,
he'll be named Francis.
Julia.
Daddy. Daddy, please.
Daddy, look at me.
In my eyes. It's me.
Could I love someone evil?
Frankie...
Amor?
Daddy?
Daddy.
We fight for what we love.
But we don't always win.
Julia.
Cesar, I...
I just...
I'm breaking his heart.
So what do you want to do,
do you want to leave?
No.
It was a time
of excess and greed.
No one was satisfied with the senate
and practically everyone contemplated
the idea of change with pleasure.
Hi, Channel 4!
What do you say?
Hi, Crosstalk.
Hi, TV, New Rome.
Hi, all news.
He has no boundaries.
And that's how you get into...
that makes a political leader.
A little crazy, no boundaries,
- and he's an entertainer.
- Say, "Hi, all news".
That old fool Nush tried to muscle you
out of politics.
Yeah, well, he dropped dead,
and I won.
Don't you see what we built?
This is the dream, the unwanted,
the unneeded, the uneducated,
we're all together now.
Power to the people.
- Power to the people!
Pulcher for the culture!
- Cesar's not a pleaser!
Pulcher for Alderman,
it's only me, no one else!
You can't name anyone else!
- It's just...
- Cesar Catilina!
Who said that?
Cesar Catilina!
You shut the fuck up!
Will no one rid me
of this fucking cousin?
Stop. Go film them.
Fuck Cesar!
Catilina.
This is an unexpected visit, Cicero.
Call me Frank.
It's not Franklyn, but really Frank.
You know, like Sinatra, Francis.
Francis. Is this
Design Authority business?
There's something I need to say.
It's difficult.
May I?
Sure. Go on.
Please. I know I've attacked you,
prosecuted you,
but you can't begin to know
what Julia means to me.
I'll give up everything.
Please, pass her by.
We both know what's best
for her and the child.
Let Julia go. Think of her.
If you could make her feel
you no longer love her...
I would put this in your hands.
It's my signed confession.
Evidence about your wife's body.
Now that Nush Berman is dead,
I can say it.
I was dishonest
in my prosecution of you.
Now, I can survive anything,
just not her
to know my complicity.
This is your insurance policy.
Although I don't understand
what you're doing,
I will support you.
Privately
and publicly.
If you can do this for my family,
we will always be grateful.
I'll wait three days to hear from you.
Cicero.
There are only two things
impossible to stare at very long,
the sun
and your own soul.
Wow, where's your coat?
I waited with no coat
because I knew you'd give me yours.
And it would be warm.
It smells of you.
Sandalwood... citrus...
sweet male memories.
It can still all be yours, Cesar,
me and Crassus's bank,
which I'll steal
so I can give it to you.
Wow.
I should really learn
more about banking, dear.
I'm so bored all day.
That's no good.
And you want me to, right, darling?
You want me to take over?
- Yes.
I'll start with Cesar's accounts.
Tonight on Crosstalk.
Is Megalon
the path to a better life
for you and your family?
Or is it the dream of an eccentric
mad scientist that could kill us all?
On Crosstalk.
Megalon is from outer space.
Open your window, man,
look at what's happening
in the streets.
The new revolution, man!
Sex, drugs, and Megalon!
"Megalopolis Doesn't Fit Together!"
"Megalon Deemed Unsafe by Experts."
- What are you doing?
- What bullshit.
What are you doing?
You can't park here.
This is a construction site.
You can't park here. Look!
You don't...
You don't understand. Okay.
- Okay. Okay.
- You got it.
I have to get home soon
to make dinner.
You have to move.
I'm just going to go say hi.
I'll deal with this guy.
You, get in your car,
you don't understand me?
Move! I said, get in your car
and move it. Let's go.
Let's go. Let's go!
Get in. Let's go!
- The mayor's waiting.
- Let's go. Let's go!
- Can I have your autograph?
- Of course you can.
- What's your name?
- Sam.
Sam. I love that name Sam,
it's to the point.
Cesar will never say no to a child.
"To Sam..." How old are you, Sam?
- I'm 12.
- Twelve.
I used to be 12,
you believe it or not.
- Do I look 12 now?
- No.
Thank you, Sam.
All right, there you are, Sam.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too.
No!
Boss!
Hey! Hey, stop!
Help him! Help him!
Come on.
I will not let time
have dominion over my thoughts.
Have dominion over my thoughts.
I will not let time
have dominion over my thoughts!
have dominion over my thoughts.
I will not let time have...
I will not let time have dominion...
my thoughts.
Let time... I will not let time
have dominion over my thoughts.
My thoughts...
I will not let time
have dominion over my thoughts.
Time, stop!
I'm here, my love.
Megalon has no delineation,
knows no boundaries...
Megalon will activate
some of the signals
that will express genes,
sub-atomic particles, atoms,
molecules, human connection...
Cesar.
Megalon fuses all forces...
will activate some of the signals
that will express genes...
enabling Cesar to grow his face
like a second skin.
Do you have the cells?
It is a language.
Sunny's hair.
We found
a sample of Sunny's hair.
The first of its kind
bio-hybrid.
A living material
combining man-made
and nature-grown tissues.
The Megalon is the connection,
the signal.
You think this is a joke?
You've made him a martyr,
you fucking idiot.
It's bad enough he won the Nobel,
now you've made him a martyr.
You're an ignoramus.
Sic semper tyrannis!
Sunny...
I'm here, honey.
I was desperate.
It's okay.
I discovered the principle of Megalon
trying to save her life.
The red envelope...
Cicero.
Something never disclosed.
The embodiment
of all my desires and regrets
were named Jane Doe.
My mania,
my obsessions,
my greatest loss,
Jane Doe.
Condemned with the truth.
Truths, found in the coldest,
darkest morgue of our heart.
Be with her.
She came home with good news,
but saw something
that enraged her jealousy.
I followed, but I saw her
drive over the bridge,
and into the icy water.
And in that madness, it came to me.
I discovered the principle of Megalon
trying to save her life.
She said she had good news...
her secret.
And then all was lost to me forever.
This is my heart.
No, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no! No, no!
We're here to see Crassus.
Someone froze our accounts.
- Someone's messing with the...
- No, no, no, no, no!
I'll be in the car
if you need me, okay?
What...
You know, when I heard you were shot,
I was pissed...
that I didn't get to do it myself.
It's a joke.
But you never had a sense of humour.
I have a sense of humour.
And I have everything else
that you have.
Brains, family,
name, talent.
It's injected the wrong way,
but I share your passions.
Creation...
destruction.
You know, your way,
it's meticulous and it's hygienic,
but it's fucking soulless.
And my way is real, and I want it.
I want it all. I want the moon.
And I'm going to have it.
Clodio.
Creation...
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Darling, what is it?
Our accounts are frozen.
I'm in a position where I can do
all kinds of things on my own, Cesar.
My God...
It can all be yours, Cesar,
everything.
These diamonds mean nothing to me.
Take me.
Take my love.
Cesar!
Come in. Come in, Cesar.
You got to be careful?
Yeah. Okay.
You just sit right here.
Here. Here.
Let me just see...
I came to ask why...
our accounts are frozen.
Frozen?
Must be a mistake, son.
- Wow, do you know anything about this?
- "Moxie".
- Uncle...
- Yes.
Be remembered...
for your generosity.
Remembered?
I'm not going anywhere.
What's a seven-letter word
for "God's revenge on mankind"?
Pandora.
Bingo.
Huey.
- Pick up my hat.
Pick up my hat.
Going up.
Yes, we are.
We are going up,
and they are going down.
We just have to get
our affairs in order,
tell all the little boys what to do.
One, two, three, yippee yay.
Hello.
Do you like my outfit?
Yes, it's beautiful, Wow.
Yes, Auntie Wow.
Yes, it's beautiful, Auntie Wow.
Does it make my ass look good?
I can't see it.
Yes, it's beautiful, Auntie Wow.
Kiss it.
Grandpa Crassus is beginning to doubt
that you're giving up on politics.
You are a very bad, bad boy.
But you're lucky,
because Auntie Wow
has come here to help you.
- Are you lucky?
- Yes.
- Yes what?
- Yes, Auntie Wow.
- What's that?
- That's your pussy.
I said, what is that?
That's Cesar's Megalopolis
using up the city's power.
Think it's all over the city?
- It's all over the city.
- Do you want to fuck me?
I want to fuck you so bad, Auntie Wow.
Then take your pants off
and get on the table.
Yes, Auntie Wow.
Now,
your grandfather insisted
on a prenuptial agreement
so that I can't inherit his bank.
Therefore...
you and I are going to do a takeover.
You and your Auntie Wow,
and she knows how.
Yes, Auntie Wow.
- One, you will suggest to Crassus...
- Yes.
That you become interim CEO
of his bank,
that they draft up a memo
of his support
- and that you two work...
- Fuck!
On a "term sheet" together.
- We're gonna work on a term sheet...
- Yeah.
- Auntie Wow.
- You understand?
- Now, he'll think...
- Yes.
That he's going to remain
Chairman and CEO...
But he won't.
And keep you as interim CEO.
- Two, when he does that...
- Two.
Yes.
You're going to refuse, okay?
I'll say, "No, no!"
And then all the friendly talks
are going to fall apart.
Okay.
- You like obeying me, don't you?
- Yes.
I've come to ask
if you'd consider saying
you support my becoming interim CEO.
- You cut your hair.
- I did.
You're making an effort, good!
Well, what I would need is,
I would need a memo
from the board, Grandpa,
saying you support
my becoming interim CEO.
You're a banker now.
I'm proud of you.
Yeah, I'll give you a title,
teach you the game.
Wait,
this term sheet says
that you would be
interim CEO and Chairman.
Well, yeah. I mean, I don't know.
Interim CEO...
And I would retire.
It's not friendly.
This is hostile. This is treacherous!
- I didn't mean...
- Villainous!
I didn't mean it to be hostile!
Whose name is this?
I thought it was inevitable.
- Who signed this?
- Just stay still, please.
I did what you asked.
- Yes, indeed. Grandpa, please.
- No! No!
- Get away from me! No!
- Please, you have to lie down!
I can't...
Mr Crassus!
God, it was you
who gave me my fortune.
And It will be the will of Chronos
to seek our revenge.
"Let us fall in love again
"and scatter gold dust
all over the world.
"Let us become a new spring
"and feel the breeze
drift in heaven's scent.
"Let us dress the earth in green
and like the sap of a young tree,
"let the grace from within sustain us.
"Let us carve gems
out of our stony hearts
"and let them light our path to Love.
"The glance of Love is crystal clear
"and we are blessed by it."
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
Happy Saturnalia to you!
Happy Saturnalia to everyone!
Okay, gentlemen,
deliver.
This is an inside takeover.
Begin.
O beautiful for spacious skies
For amber waves of grain
For purple mountain...
Doesn't that feel good?
Cause for celebration.
Now get the fuck out of my car.
America! America!
The move is final
as of 11:00 pm, Eastern Standard Time.
And crown thy good with brotherhood
From sea to shining sea!
Now that
the new board is installed,
and has voted...
Speak louder, I'm hard of hearing!
The board has voted
to remove Hamilton Crassus
from the office of CEO
of Crassus National Bank.
Arigato.
Thank you very much.
We got the bank,
now unleash the mob.
Nam si violandum est jus,
aliis rebus pietatem colas.
Be just,
unless a kingdom tempts
to break the laws,
for sovereign power alone
can justify the cause.
Where is Cesar now?
Where is his Megalopolis?
We've waited long enough, no?
If you don't fight like hell,
we're gonna lose the city.
Keep what's ours.
Cesar has failed,
Cicero has failed.
The city is ours!
Attention, attention.
Murder and violence
stalk our streets...
We are here,
we are powerful,
and we are taking our country back!
Pulcher for the culture!
We are threatened by evil men.
New Rome, the greatest country
the world has ever known,
is threatened
by those men
who propose to take charge
of the affairs of the government.
Fuck Cesar!
Fuck the Mayor, and fuck City Hall!
Back away
from the gate of City Hall.
Commissioner?
Over here, the train's coming.
This is an illegal gathering.
What have you done
with Megalopolis?
Where's Megalopolis?
Hold the line!
Mayor Cicero?
There's another car coming, guys.
The mayor's extraction
is underway. Over.
Hi...
Hi.
May... May I hold her?
Yeah. It's your grandpa.
Hi...
- Who's that?
- Hi...
I used to hold you like this.
- Look at you.
- Look, she likes you.
Yeah.
You're holding the future
in your hands.
Don't you want a better world for her?
Cesar is a reckless dreamer
who will destroy the world
sooner than he can build a better one.
Can't you and I
be like we were before?
Could we?
Can't we, Julia?
My little girl, my angel?
Trust us.
Trust me, Daddy.
There's been some news.
The rioters have been pushed back,
and the road's cleared.
Thank God.
Earlier today has devolved
- into a scene of violence.
- America,
master of the known world,
is now kaput.
Be quiet for once
and follow my lead.
Our poor Robin Hood.
He doesn't have much time left,
but he wanted to see you.
Well, he's not one
to give up on things.
He can barely speak.
We came to pay our respects, Grandpa.
What do you think of this boner I got?
One look at her and I'm up...
If it wasn't for this,
I would have been
able to out-spend you
in the end.
But I will
outlive you.
Wow,
you Wall Street slut,
this is your closing bell.
What?
No.
No, Auntie Wow.
No, no, no.
Fuck!
The gods have decreed
that history teach us,
all that is needed is a slight push
to send our republic toppling.
For it is in the power
of any daring man
to overturn a sickly commonwealth.
You are here illegally.
Go home or you will be arrested.
Put down your weapons
and go back to your homes, please.
Cesar is alive!
We need you to stop!
Man.
What is that?
What do we know of him?
His gods?
Liberty...
love...
kindness,
mind,
death,
destiny.
Destiny.
I'm not concerned
with my place in history.
What I am concerned about is time,
consciousness, and courage.
But what is time,
except a curve
of past and future around us?
What is consciousness,
except a burst of the soul
from inside?
And what is courage,
but the beginning
of a vital conversation?
We're in need of a great debate
about the future!
We want every person in the world
to take part in that debate.
This city is threatened by unusual
- and dire circumstances...
- Wait, Your Honour.
- We have...
- Your Honour, listen.
He's incriminating himself.
Tear down debt!
Tear down the world
of ready-made slums
that those families that run the world
shove you into.
You were born with the option
to be what you want to be,
and must!
Cesar! Cesar Catilina!
Let it not be said that
we reduced ourselves to be brutes
and mindless beasts of burden.
The human being shall rightly
be called a great miracle,
and a living creature
for all to admire!
We are such stuff
as dreams are made of.
- Yes!
Catilina!
Hail, New Rome!
Hail, Megalopolis!
Our Mother Earth
gave us the genius
to see a future so beautiful
that we can't let it be denied.
The gates of Megalopolis are open!
Go now, and know
our world is changed forever!
Evoke the contingency clause.
I'm going to leave
the patents to Megalon,
the bank, my entire fortune,
to Cesar's Garden of Eden,
to Megalopolis!
I'll be known as
"Crassus the Generous",
loved for eternity!
Yeah, go, go.
- One more.
- Wait!
All right.
- One more.
- Okay.
- Ready, and pull!
- Yeah, go, go, go.
You threw us under the bus,
you piece of shit.
- Yeah?
- Where'd all the money go?
- The team!
- You double-crossed us.
"Don't tread on me!"
- You double-crossed us!
- You own the bank?
You used us.
So much for your loyal base, asshole,
what'd I tell you!
"No crutches, no crosses!"
Tie him up!
Wait, wait, wait! Wait!
Help!
Help me, Grandpa!
Thank you.
Come on.
Please.
Come on, Frankie.
Teri...
Darling.
Happy New Year!
Good to see you! Good to see you!
Happy New Year, everybody!
Happy New Year!
We've got a new year...
- Happy New Year!
- Mwah!
Happy New Year!
- Happy New Year!
Mother.
While I'm here, can I just have one?
There's still so much to accomplish...
but is there time?
Promise me, you will build nobly.
Yes, Dad. We promise.
Yes,
be assured.
Build a future for her.
- Julia...
- Ten, nine...
- stop time.
- Eight, seven, six,
- five, four...
- Now, time, stop!
I pledge allegiance
to our human family,
and to all the species
that we protect.
One earth, indivisible,
with long life,
education and justice for all.
Education and justice for all.
One, two, three, four.
Planet Earth is slowing down
Overseas, underground
Wherever you look around
Lord, take me by the hand
Lead me through these desert sands
To the shores of a promised land
You make me cry
When you look into my eyes
And see me for who I really am
If you can't change the world
Change yourself
And if you can't change yourself
Then change your world
The world's too big
And life's too short
To be alone