Well, Dmitri.
Every search for a hero
must begin with something
that every hero requires,
a villain.
Therefore in a search for
our hero, Bellerophon
we created a monster.
Chimera.
I beg you, Dmitri,
come to Sydney
and accompany me to
Atlanta immediately.
However we travel,
I must arrive at my destination
within 20 hours of departure.
Ring around the rosie.
A pocket full of posies.
Ashes, ashes.
We all fall down.
Folks, we're two and a
half hours from Atlanta.
Look out your window now. We have a
great view of the Rocky Mountains.
You keep staring at that watch as if
your life depended on it, Doctor.
Well, yes.
I suppose I'm a bit anxious.
You'll soon be with old friends.
I'm with an old
friend now, Dmitri.
I'm sorry it couldn't be
under happier circumstances.
I'm sorry too.
You are sorry, and I am sorry.
You don't know Gradski
thought the world of you.
Did he
know
before the end that you
two had succeeded?
Yes, he knew. Just.
Not in time to save him?
No.
After you've been infected
with Chimera for 20 hours
nothing can save you
not even Bellerophon.
You can carry them together
safely?
Yes.
And you'll get us to safe place
with them in Atlanta, thank God.
This is your Captain again.
We've experienced a slight but
abrupt drop in cabin pressure.
As a precaution, I've
released the oxygen masks.
Please put them on,
sit back, relax.
There's nothing to worry about.
Are you concerned?
Not so far.
Just put on your oxygen mask.
- I'll see what's going on.
- Okay.
Denver Centre, this is
Transpac 2207, 747 heavy.
We're unable to maintain
cabin pressurisation.
We've initiated a
descent to 1-6000.
Captain...
God.
It seems we have a
problem, Dmitri.
You keep calling me Dmitri.
You really shouldn't.
You are not Dmitri?
No.
Wallis,
hold on to this.
Ulrich, remember to pull the...
Remember to pull the
NO2 tank and dump it.
All done, chief.
Terrain. Terrain.
Pull up. Pull up. Terrain.
Seven nine nine!
Checkpoint Charlie,
three, two, one!
Go!
Terrain. Terrain.
Pull up. Pull up.
Good morning, Mr Hunt.
Your mission, should you
choose to accept it
involves the recovery
of a stolen item
designated Chimera.
You may select any two team
members but it is essential
that the third team member
be Nyah Nordoff-Hall.
She is a civilian
and a highly capable
professional thief.
You have 48 hours to
recruit Miss Nordoff-Hall
and meet me in Seville to
receive your assignment.
As always, should you or any member
of your IMF team be caught or killed
the Secretary will disavow all
knowledge of your actions.
And, Mr Hunt, the next
time you go on holiday
please let us know
where you're going.
This message will self-destruct
in five seconds.
If I let you know
where I'm going
then I won't be on holiday.
I see you found it.
What are you doing here?
Think you're the only one
who can pick a lock?
Not just a pretty
face after all.
Do you mind if I'm on top?
Either way works for me.
- You'll never find it there.
- Damn it.
- Find what?
- His ex's Bulgari necklace.
It goes up for
auction on Tuesday.
And are you going to
tell me where it is?
Far left.
This is very disconcerting.
Hey, you put me here. I
just do as I'm told.
Right.
Now
who are you and what's
it gonna cost me?
I wouldn't do that.
What?
That.
Mr Keys, it is you.
It is Mr Keys, our security engineer.
Apologise!
No, no need to apologise.
Miss Hall, my associate, has your
necklace in a very safe place
but obviously we do feel the alarm
should have gone off a little sooner.
Isn't that right, Miss Hall?
Oh, absolutely. Much,
much too long, I'd say.
We'd recommend resetting the sensors
to respond to a lighter load.
How do you feel about
40 kilos, Miss Hall?
Perfect.
Shall we?
Miss Hall,
haven't you forgotten something?
What are you trying to
do, senorita, rob me?
The thought had crossed my mind.
I'm missing something here, aside
from my half million pound necklace.
Even after I screwed up the job, I
could have walked out with the thing.
At least you walked.
If you weren't going to let me get away
with it, why did you watch me do it?
I wanted to see how
good you were.
I was hoping we might
work together.
Sounds terrific.
Now be serious. Whatever
you're talking about,
you couldn't want me
after that performance.
- You didn't do that badly.
- You apologising for me?
Quite the gentleman.
Not really.
I triggered the alarm.
Sorry.
I don't do laundry, cook
or put up with cheeky bastards
who set me up on their territory
so they can poach on mine.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Would you mind slowing down?
Where did you get this number?
I don't even have it.
Would you like it?
Pull over and listen to me, will you?
Just listen.
- Listen to what?
- I need your help.
- I think you could use mine.
- Your help?
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about
Scotland Yard, interpol
every Dutch authority.
I can make them all go away.
Oh, bloody hell.
You're a spy!
Well, if you want me,
you've gotta catch me.
You having fun?
Sorry.
Watch the road.
What's your name?
Ethan Hunt.
Well, Ethan Hunt
what is it you want
to talk to me about?
A lot more than I thought.
Awfully short notice.
Care to wait a decent interval?
Who wants to be decent?
So what have you
got against spies?
When they've got your
recruiting technique
nothing.
- This wasn't exactly by the book.
- They've got a book for this?
They've got a book
for everything.
So this thing these
blokes pinched...
I don't know that
they pinched it.
I don't even know
that they're blokes.
What am I doing here?
I thought I was supposed to be some
kind of thief to catch a thief.
So did I.
Sort of.
Damn, you're beautiful.
Espresso? Cappuccino?
No, thanks.
Sit down.
Festival's a pain in the ass.
Honouring their saints
by setting them on fire.
Lets you know what they think
of saints, doesn't it?
Damn near set me on fire
on my way over here.
Sorry, I barged in
on your vacation.
- Sorry I didn't tell you where I was.
- Wouldn't be a vacation if you did.
Well, you're sorry,
and I'm sorry.
- Why did you phrase it like that?
- Like what?
"You're sorry. I'm sorry."
You gotta be kidding.
Well, Dmitri
once again I need your help
just as in the old days, huh?
When you saved our lives,
saved our very sanity.
We have this little problem.
Every search for a hero
must begin with something
that every hero requires,
a villain.
Therefore in a search for
our hero, Bellerophon
we created a monster.
Chimera.
I beg you, Dmitri,
come to Sydney
and accompany me to
Atlanta immediately.
However we travel,
I must arrive at my destination
within 20 hours of departure.
I fear I can entrust
this to no one but you.
As we say, I'm sorry,
and you are sorry.
Do you have any idea what the
hell he's talking about?
An idea? Yeah.
- Like?
- It's a good idea to get him now.
A bad idea to fly him on a commercial
carrier. Is he still in Sydney?
Dr Vladimir Nekhorvich is dead.
So is his colleague Gradski,
but that happened earlier.
We had Nekhorvich on
a flight from Sydney
that crashed in the Rockies.
Dead.
Are you listening to me?
If he didn't want to
go anywhere without me
how did you get him
on that flight?
You were there.
When I couldn't find you,
I had to replace you.
Sean Ambrose was the
obvious choice.
He doubled you two
or three times.
- Twice.
- What did you think of him?
We had reservations about each other.
It's a bit late to be asking me that.
No, not necessarily.
Airline records
list a Captain Harold Macintosh
as the pilot of flight 2207.
As far as the media and all the
governmental agencies are concerned.
Captain Macintosh
died in the flight.
But, in fact, he missed it.
He did, however,
make the next flight
in cargo
stuffed into a rather small
suitcase, considering his size.
Someone on that flight
planned an operation
designed to bring the plane down
and make it look like an accident.
Someone skillful enough to
bring it off without a hitch.
There's one thing we know
that Ambrose doesn't.
Then you do think it was Ambrose?
You're not surprised?
Sean feels he
hasn't done the job
unless he leaves a lot
of hats on the ground.
The question is why.
What was this Chimera
Nekhorvich was carrying?
Only Ambrose knows that.
In any case, you must
recover this Chimera
and bring it to us.
In order to do that, I've got to figure
out how he plans to make money on it.
That is where Miss
Hall comes in.
Excuse me?
Miss Hall and Ambrose
had a relationship
which he took very seriously.
She walked away, and he's been
wanting her back ever since.
We believe she's our surest and
quickest way of locating him.
And then what?
Well, make sure she
continues to see him
gets him to confide in
her, and report to you.
You made it sound as if
I was recruiting her
for her skills as a thief.
Well, then I misled you or you
made the wrong assumption.
Either way, we are asking her
to resume a prior relationship
not do anything she
hasn't already done.
Voluntarily, I might add.
No, she's got no training
for this kind of thing.
To go to bed with a
man and lie to him?
She's a woman. She's got all
the training she needs.
I don't think I can
get her to do it.
- You mean it'll be difficult.
- Very.
Well, this is not Mission: Difficult,
Mr Hunt. It's Mission: Impossible.
Difficult should be a
walk in the park for you.
I'm open to suggestion.
If you can think of a quicker
way to get to Ambrose
you're welcome to try.
You might want to
take a look at these
if you have any further qualms
about getting her to do the job.
How many people are capable
of something like that?
Sean Ambrose
for one.
Right.
This wasn't what I
had in mind, Nyah.
But it is what you'd
like me to do.
What?
Oh, let my conscience be my guide.
Is that it?
Something like that.
I don't have a conscience.
I'm a bloody thief.
You're gonna try and
force me to do this?
Generally, I don't
favour coercing someone
not when there's a chance my life
could end up in their hands.
Is that the only reason?
- Can you think of a better one?
- Me? No.
I was hoping you might, thinking that
somewhere in the course of business
this got personal as
well as physical!
Okay. Would it make you feel any better
if I didn't want you to do this?
- Yeah, much.
- Then feel better!
Sean will never be anything
but suspicious if I pitch up
saying, "Hey, honey, I'm home."
What wouldn't make
him suspicious?
That I needed him
in some urgent way.
Destitute,
in serious trouble,
the kind I couldn't
possibly sort out myself.
Serious trouble, Nyah
is something I can
always arrange.
This transponder chip is
completely untraceable.
It transmits your
location to a satellite
which can be read by
only this computer.
We can then track you
to within three feet
anywhere.
Since your arrest, I've
been sending news bulletins
to every law enforcement
agency in the world.
I know Sean Ambrose
and I guarantee that
after that airline crash
he's monitoring
every one of them.
He knows you're there.
And he has the means
to get you out.
I'm not gonna lose you.
Agent Hunt?
Good day, mate. I'm William
Baird, but Billy's okay.
Anything you need me to get,
move or watch, I'm your man.
I'll have a look around.
Shit.
Yes, it is.
This ain't funny.
I just bought these
$800 Gucci shoes
and you got me in a
helicopter with this man?
Computer's up. We got her.
Let's put in the coordinates
and get a visual.
- Visuals aren't coming up.
- Satellite doesn't work as fast as I do.
Yeah, I heard about you, Luther.
I wanna say it's an honour and a
pleasure to be working with you blokes.
Isn't there any way
we can speed this up?
With what? This is the only
computer that will do this.
Ethan, here we go.
Now there's a bloke who knows
how to give a proper welcome.
Don't get me wrong, mate. You
were very friendly also.
Is it him then?
- It's him, Billy.
- So we got him.
We don't know what we've got.
'Cause we don't
know what he's got
where he's got it or what
he's doing in Sydney with it.
Not much luggage.
I left in a bit of a hurry.
I'm incredibly grateful, Sean.
How in the world
did you find me?
How I usually find you.
Magic.
No flies on her.
No bugs either. No transmissions.
She's clean.
All cats are.
Your room?
And my room?
She did it.
She's in the compound.
Yeah?
We've just rolled up a snowball
and tossed it into hell.
Now we'll see what
chance it has.
Try it on.
Go ahead.
I'm dying to see if I
remembered your size.
You're not interested
in seeing how it looks?
Oh, I am.
Later.
Every search for a hero
must begin with something
that every hero requires,
a villain.
Therefore in a search for
our hero, Bellerophon
we created a monster.
Chimera.
Nekhorvich was a
molecular biologist.
Why is he going on about
an old Greek myth?
Nekhorvich specialised in
recombining DNA molecules.
In the myth.
Bellerophon was a prince
who killed the Chimera,
a monster with the
head of a lion
and the tail of a serpent
who plagued the ancient world.
I think Nekhorvich created
a monster virus in Chimera
and the antivirus to kill it
in Bellerophon.
That simple, huh?
Why not?
Thirty-seven million pounds.
Well, that's a promising
bid for Nekhorvich's work.
Don't look so worried, Hugh.
We're halfway there.
We'll need this at the track
if we're going to
get the other half.
Well, then...
Sorted.
Not everything.
Why do you think
she's really here?
From her point of view or mine?
She wasn't exactly
gagging for it
when she left you
six months ago.
The question is, "Do
you trust her?"
One considers her
timing, of course.
Getting nicked within a week
of the plane going down.
Suggestive
even borderline suspicious
but hardly conclusive.
You've thought about
it at any rate.
Tell me, Hugh.
You don't exactly hang on Nyah's
every word and gesture, do you?
That's a fairly ratty nail.
Don't, please.
Suppose she is some sort of
Trojan horse sent in by IMF
to spy on us?
Why should I deny myself the
pleasure of a ride or two?
Or don't you think I can learn more
from her than she can from me?
I do! I do! I do!
Now, Hugh, you must realise
that some of us have the
burden of sex to deal with.
And I may or may not know
why she thinks she's here
but I'm willing to take the risk
because, Hugh
I am gagging for it.
Come on! Come on!
Darling, you won!
I suppose I did.
What made you pick that nag?
She's never won a bloody thing.
"Thief in the Night."
Say no more.
I'm off to grab a drink.
You still favour the Bellinis?
Naturally Vain.
Pardon me?
Naturally Vain?
In the fourth. Check her out.
She's due.
You can speak as if I'm
right by your side.
Where are you?
Mounting enclosure, just
off the track, 2:00.
How's it going?
Just like old times.
Just like old times?
Just about.
Tell me who you've run
into at Ambrose's.
Near as I can tell, there's about a
half dozen blokes about the place.
Maybe more.
Hugh Stamp. Old
friend of Sean's.
He's the only one I recognise.
A creep and then some.
We know him. He's over your left
shoulder looking at you right now.
Ambrose has photos of newspapers
with money piled on them.
Thirty-seven million
on the London Times.
What's that about?
Bids from possible
Chimera buyers.
Ambrose is meeting
some bloke in the bar.
Big bloke. Ginger hair.
They're into something.
- Who is this guy?
- Checking now, Ethan.
John McCloy, CEO Biocyte
Pharmaceuticals,
1989, acquired Biocyte
in a hostile takeover.
- He was Nekhorvich's boss.
- Right.
He worked for him as the
research scientist at Biocyte.
Ambrose is showing something
to McCloy on a digital camera.
Whatever McCloy's looking at,
he's not happy about it.
Ambrose just pulled the
camera's memory card
and put it into an envelope.
Put it in his inner
left jacket pocket.
Confirm left jacket pocket.
Roger that.
Nyah,
Ambrose is on his
way back to you.
- There's an envelope inside...
- His left jacket pocket.
That's right.
Where do I meet you?
Betting table 12,
off the paddock.
- Are you sure you're up to this?
- I'll muddle through.
- There you are.
- See anything you like?
Well, yeah.
Naturally Vain.
But they're about to
close the betting
- and I haven't a bean.
- Nyah!
- Would you mind terribly?
- Not at all.
But you are gonna pay for it
and with interest.
I have no doubt.
Hold on.
Put down a thousand for me.
- To win?
- What else?
Billy, make sure
Nyah's not followed.
No worries, mate.
Luther, digital camera,
ready to transmit.
Betting table 12.
- There you go.
- Thanks.
Sorry about that, mate.
That must have...
Say again?
Whatever you're about, in
future watch your step.
Never know who you
might run into.
Where's the loo?
Thanks, mate.
How'd you do?
Don't turn around.
I managed.
You turned around.
What are you gonna do, spank me?
I'm booted up. Go, Ethan.
Are you getting this?
"Sergei Gradski"
"20 hours after exposure."
God.
Stamp's out of the loo.
He's coming out of the tunnel
heading your way, mate.
- I want you out of Ambrose's place.
- What are you talking about?
What's happened?
What did you see?
Okay, he's coming up
behind you, Ethan.
You've done your job. I
want you out of Australia.
- Thirty steps.
- How do you suggest I go about it?
- Twenty, nineteen...
- He's touched your heart,
you're overwhelmed and
need to think it over.
Fifteen, fourteen.
- Twelve, eleven.
- I want you out of there now.
Give me the earpiece.
Nine, Ethan. Eight.
If you don't get out of there, I'm
coming in and getting you out.
Get out of there.
You place your bet, ma'am?
Just.
Horses are ready to race.
Come on!
Come on! Your nag's making a
run for it on the outside.
Come on!
You picked another winner!
I thought you were
going to dinner.
Hugh, take care of the
Nekhorvich memory card.
Where is it?
In the envelope in
my jacket pocket.
My right jacket pocket.
We at our state-of-the-art,
solar-powered Biocyte building
recognise that eternal vigilance
is the price of health
whether it's funding
the teaching centre
at the Royal Prince
Edward Hospital,
removing aerosol
products from the market
or braving the influenza quarantine
at Bruny Island late last month.
At Biocyte,
your life is our life's work.
We've got an opportunity here.
I'm not going to miss it.
George, take me home.
George.
What the hell?
George!
George. George!
Sean?
Sean.
Shh. Shh. Shh.
Easy.
Oh, Ethan.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I am now.
What is this?
A visit from an old friend.
You crashed on the plane.
You're dead.
Tired, certainly.
But dead is a little extreme.
On the other hand
when my colleague Gradski had your
pulse and your blood pressure
he had less than a day to live.
You're infected with
Chimera, my friend.
No use, my friend.
The medical staff
wants no part of this.
Doctors don't fancy the idea of
dying any more than anybody else.
How could I possibly
be infected?
That's exactly what Gradski
said 27 hours before he died.
You've got the antidote,
you miserable bastard!
- You stole Bellerophon. All of it!
- My, my, my.
I need it.
I need it now, you
whacked-out Russian gypsy!
And what about Gradski, who you
deliberately infected with Chimera?
How was I to know he needed treatment
with Bellerophon within 20 hours?
By asking me.
You still don't get it, do you?
I needed to know just how bad the
disease was in the real world
not just the lab.
You were genetically splicing
together strains of influenza
to create a cure for
all influenzas.
But you were also creating a
disease so terrible in Chimera
the cure would be priceless.
I needed Chimera in order
to peddle Bellerophon.
It's not that difficult
to understand, is it?
Look, I've got the virus,
you've got the cure.
I need them both.
Time was, a shot of penicillin would
knock off every bug in the zoo.
Not any more.
If I couldn't make money killing the
microscopic little shits out there
you'd help me put one out there
that I could make money on.
Well, there it is.
I've confessed.
L, John C. McCloy
am in business to make money.
Now forget any deal you may have
made with that thug Ambrose
get me treated, and
let's go back to work.
You know
I think it's a little
late for that.
Do give my regards to Gradski
if you see him.
Well?
I've heard
all I need to hear.
Nyah.
It's imperative that we do
nothing to alarm Ambrose.
What?
You told me to leave
as soon as I could.
I thought you were
here to collect me!
Listen to me. There's
no time to talk.
It is critical,
absolutely critical
that you do whatever
Ambrose asks.
Do you understand me?
Don't worry.
It will all be over
very soon.
That's a promise.
Come on.
Off you go.
Luther, we know this much.
Nekhorvich gets on a plane to go to the
Centre for Disease Control in Atlanta.
He's carrying a virus
he created, Chimera,
and the cure for that
virus, Bellerophon.
Ambrose doesn't have the virus.
That's why Ambrose needs McCloy.
So we go into Biocyte,
kill Chimera.
Ambrose has a cure without a
disease and we're home free.
You were right.
Hunt stung McCloy tonight.
So he knows.
He'll be going into Biocyte.
Good.
Then we know where
he'll be, don't we?
Well done, Hugh.
Well done.
You're home, mate. Home.
Where's George, my regular driver?
Where is he?
He's gone home sick.
Touch of the flu.
The building up and running yet?
- That's not exactly it.
- Sorry, but this is a Biocyte facility.
Their storage structure.
I'll have it up in a minute.
Okay, take a look at this.
Let's start from the inside out.
All storage and production
of Chimera is done here
in this lab on the 42nd floor.
Hunt's target will
be the Chimera
stored and manufactured at
Biocyte on the 42nd floor.
If you look at Hunt's operational
history, and I have,
he invariably favours
misdirection over confrontation.
He'll never break into
Biocyte from the bottom,
where security is heaviest.
No garage entrances.
Lobby's protected by five
guards on rotating patrol.
Not going in from the ground.
Show me the atrium.
The atrium? One of a kind.
Runs down through the
centre of the building.
Provides 24-hour natural light via
mirrors and daylight storage cells,
optimum growing
conditions for the virus.
Ends in a glass floor which doubles
as part of the lab ceiling.
Uh-uh.
The atrium roof
closes at sundown.
And if the louvers are up for
more than 40 seconds at night,
the civil emergency alarms are tripped.
Those even I can't stop.
We have a total of 40 seconds to
get you in and the cables out.
Hunt will prefer to enter Biocyte from
the top, where security is minimal.
He'll undoubtedly engage
in some aerobatic insanity
before he'll risk harming a hair
on a security guard's head.
- Check, check. Copy?
- You're five-by-five.
Luther, how we doing?
Not there yet, Ethan.
I'll give you the word.
Billy, ready to go?
- Package away in five.
- Not yet. The louvers aren't moving.
Luther, we gotta go.
Wait. There's a glitch
in the access code.
Luther, we're out of time.
On the count.
Please, baby, open up. Open up.
Five, four...
- Come on!
- ...three, two, one!
- I'm going now!
- Ethan, wait!
25, 24, 23,
22, 21, 20.
You've got 19 seconds
to clear the cable.
Okay, retracting cable.
Come on.
Nine, eight, seven, six, five,
four, three, two...
Cable's clear!
Transponder activated.
Reading package and cable clear.
He'll breach the lab at
the only possible time.
Whether you break in from
the ground or the roof,
it's 23:00 hours, one minute
when the air filtration generators will
cover the sound of Hunt's break-in
and rotating guards make the building
vulnerable to our break-in from below.
Ethan, the generators
are about to go active.
Just a friendly reminder, we'll be
out of contact for eight minutes.
I'm betting Hunt
will destroy Chimera
rather than attempt to
preserve any part of it.
He'll have to do
it in two places.
First,
the incubation room where
the growth vials are kept.
And finally, in the
inoculation chamber
holding the last remaining Chimera
virus and three injection guns.
He won't be allowed to destroy
the virus in those guns.
What's this? You're
on time for once?
Not exactly, sport.
John C. McCloy.
Billy, we've got a problem.
Nyah's on the wing up early.
Billy, do you copy?
Yeah, I got you, Luther.
Exactly where is she?
- In the building.
- Say again, mate.
Sounds like you said
she's in the building.
I am. She is.
Well, then, she's not
likely to be alone, is she?
She's in the elevator
headed towards Ethan.
The question is,
how many of them?
I can't get through to Ethan
till the generators go off.
When's that?
Not for another
five-and-a-half minutes.
Chimera in vitro pH
and temperature level
outside optimal range.
Chimera in vitro pH
and temperature level
outside optimal range.
Chimera working seed stock
pH at critical level.
Alert. Chimera stock
life threatened.
life terminated.
Come on, Ethan. Come on.
Subject is contaminant-free.
Zero contaminant factor.
Come on, come on.
Luther, what the hell can we do?
What can we do?
Hope he kills all the bugs before
the yellow dot gets to the red one.
However we travel,
I must arrive at my destination
within 20 hours of departure.
How was I to know he needed treatment
with Bellerophon within 20 hours?
Get him.
How much longer before
you can reach him?
We got 29 seconds before
the generators turn off.
Then Ethan'll be back on line.
Luther!
Hold your fire!
Hold your fire, damn it!
Well, Hunt,
how you been?
Fighting a bit of a cold.
That was the hardest part
of having to portray you,
grinning like an idiot
every 15 minutes.
I always thought the hardest part was
kerbing that pressing need of yours
to get your gun off.
You were in such a hurry
to knock off that 747,
you never figured out
where Chimera really was.
- I knew where it was.
- Oh.
Then you knew the only way Nekhorvich
could smuggle the live virus
was by injecting himself,
and using his own bloodstream
as a petri dish.
You knew that
while you were knocking him off,
destroying the very thing you came for.
Stop!
Put a sock in it!
Hit that bloody gun, and you'll
spread that virus all over the place!
There it is, guys.
The last of it.
What was the top bid?
Why? You gonna make
me a better offer?
Than 37 million pounds?
Not really.
Oh.
Somebody has been
slipping you our mail.
Come on out here, you bad girl.
She doesn't belong here.
Let her go.
She wouldn't be here if
it wasn't for you, Hunt.
From this moment, you are responsible
for what happens to her.
And if you're looking
out for her well-being,
I suggest you advise her to pick up
the injection gun and bring it to me.
The ball's in your court, Hunt.
Nyah's in the building.
Do you copy?
Thank you.
How do you know he won't shoot
you the minute he's got it?
One can't hold Nyah
responsible for her actions.
You know women, mate.
Like monkeys they are.
Won't let go of one branch till
they get a grip on the next.
Get it, Nyah. I'll cover you.
I am waiting.
Things haven't exactly worked out the
way you thought they would, Ethan.
Sorry.
You bitch!
You're not gonna shoot me, Sean.
Not this bitch.
'Cause she's worth
37 million pounds.
- What did you think you were doing?
- I wasn't thinking!
Just trying to stop you from
getting hurt, that's all.
You who don't have a conscience.
I guess I lied.
You can't get us both
out of here, can you?
I'm infected with Chimera.
You know you don't have a choice.
Just do it.
Do it. Now!
We've got 19 hours
and 58 minutes.
I'll get Bellerophon into
your system before then.
Just stay alive! I'm
not going to lose you!
Feel like pleading
for your life?
Well, then how about dying so
you can make me a lot of money.
In just a few hours time
you can be assured of going down in
history as the Typhoid Mary of Oz.
Good day.
There's not a chance of locating Nyah
until I can access the satellite.
I can't do that till I
get this computer fixed,
and that's taking a while.
- How much time does she have left?
- Not long.
- But Nyah will take care of Nyah.
- What do you mean?
Unless we dose her with Bellerophon,
Nyah will kill herself.
So first things first.
Ambrose and his team have
arrived over the bridge,
and Nyah's not with him.
Copy that.
You all right, mate? Looks
like heavy security from here.
What's it look like from there?
Risky.
Simon.
Stay here.
Breached the structure
at the 10:00 grating.
It's a DNA match. The blood's
loaded with Chimera.
And they certainly
have Bellerophon.
You've got the virus and the antivirus,
which means I've got 30 million for you.
Not exactly. We don't
want just your cash.
- What do you want?
- Stock, Mr McCloy.
Stock options to be a
little more precise.
Cut her loose right in
the centre of town.
The more crowded, the better.
Just picked up an Ambrose call.
Nyah's been dropped off.
- I think she's still alive.
- Where is she?
Somewhere in Sydney.
Somewhere in Sydney? Care
to harden the target?
I can't until I can get the GPS up
on our computer. It's still down.
The clock is ticking.
How quickly can you manufacture
more of the antivirus?
- No time at all, once I've got it.
- Good.
Biocyte stock is just a few weeks
away from going through the roof.
- What are you talking about?
- An outbreak of Chimera.
- Where?
- Downtown Sydney, for a start.
You create the supply, Mr McCloy.
We've just created the demand.
Three million people in Sydney and
17 million people in Australia
are going to need Bellerophon
within the next few days.
Not to mention the
rest of the world.
Now, this is how
it's going to work.
- The shares outstanding are?
- 93.4 million.
Which means, Mr McCloy,
we need to get our hands
on 480,000 options.
We'll borrow your 30 million
to buy those options.
Your stock has never
sold above $31 a share.
When your stock goes north
of 200, which it will,
those options will
be worth billions,
and I will own 51
percent of Biocyte.
This is outrageous.
I will not let you take
control of my company.
Sit down.
You'll be a billionaire. That's
better than being broke.
I have terrorists and other
pharmaceutical companies
standing in line.
The ball's in your
court, Mr McCloy.
Run that bastard down.
We're running short
on time, Mr McCloy.
We have got to
conclude our business.
Yes.
Start the transfer.
Follow it and let me know.
Raise your hands very slowly.
Sure you want me to do this?
Ethan. Ethan, do you copy?
Keep it going.
Sean, this rat's reached
the end of the maze.
Is he alive?
Yeah, more or less.
Bring him to me.
Go.
Sean, transfer completed.
Well done, Stamp. Well done.
Stop mumbling!
I'm afraid he's got no choice.
I believe I broke his jaw.
Stamp, I'm impressed.
We don't have a lot
of time, Hunt.
Whatever you've got
to say, say it now.
How about giving us a big smile?
No?
What are you doing?
Get down on your knees.
Now, this is what's known
as getting your gun off.
There he is!
Ethan!
Just back off and
pinpoint their positions!
Luther, clear the bridge for me.
Hunt's heading for the bridge,
coming in at 12:00 high.
Oh, I'm mad now.
- You all right, mate?
- That punk put a hole in my Versace.
Ethan, the computer's up.
I've got Nyah.
She's moved out of the city.
She's on the north bluff
approaching the cliffs,
but I can't get a visual.
Copy! She's only got
a little time left!
Track ahead and pick her up!
I can't get a good shot!
Ethan, we won't be
able to cover you.
My earpiece is failing.
You've got me on GPS.
Bring her to me.
Billy, north head bluff.
Haul ass.
- Get out there and keep firing!
- I can't see anything!
Slow down, mate, slow down!
Range is 2 "K."
Go ahead. Use it, Hunt.
It's not a bad way to go.
It's a lot better than the
way that bitch is gonna die.
There she is!
Hunt!
You should've killed me.
Miss Hall's blood has absolutely
no elements of the Chimera virus,
not even antibodies.
Yes, I gathered as much.
But you were under specific instructions
to retrieve a live sample of the virus.
I'd be very interested to know how,
after you'd managed this recovery,
it subsequently got destroyed.
By fire.
- It's the best way, really.
- Oh.
Well, as for Miss Hall,
in light of her efforts
her criminal record will
certainly be expunged.
Wiped out.
I'm assuming you approve.
I do.
Where is she now? Any idea?
I don't know. Not exactly.
- So what are your plans?
- I don't know.
Some sort of vacation. I'll
let you know where I'm going.
Don't have to do that.
It wouldn't be a
vacation if you did.
Let's get lost.