I sense you, brother.
Hiding...
...behind your cloak.
It is time to earn yours.
Still too small to take me head on.
Use the cave!
You fight with rage.
I fight like father.
You are not father, you are Dek!
Do you yield?
Never!
Good.
I'm still alive, brother.
Still much to prove...
...to show who you are.
I am Yautja.
Not yet.
Are you holding your sword, Kwei?
No.
Pick it up!
You kept this toy?!
You remember what happened...
I lost my fang!
And you saved my life.
You protected me.
Come here.
Fixed it for you.
Don't blow yourself up.
Today you make a vow...
...as our ancestors did before you.
To earn your place in the clan...
...you must choose your prey.
Bring it home...
...or never return.
Wait - Go back!
Genna.
The death planet.
Home of the un-killable Kalisk.
Even father fears it.
Then the Kalisk shall be my trophy.
Father calls me the weakest...
...so I must kill the strongest.
Failure means death.
Then I will not fail.
I cannot allow it.
I make my vow.
I make my vow!
Father.
I welcome you with honor.
Why is it not done?
He deserves a hunt.
He is our clan's weakness...
...weakness must be culled.
He will bring home the Kalisk.
Foolishness.
He is a runt.
You should have done it as he slept.
Kill him!
Now!
He will only honor us in death.
Father.
Kwei?
Be brave, brother.
Father!
Kwei!!!
To forgive weakness...
...is to show weakness.
No! Father, no!
Get your sword!
Kwei!!!
COMPUTER, IN YAUTJA:
Launch sequence initiated.
Bring it home.
For Kwei.
Yautja!
Is this-- Is this-- Is this--
Is this better?
Universal translation.
You hear Yautja,
others hear their language...
Oh, boy.
This isn't great for you.
It waits
for the needles to paralyze you.
Then eats you
while you can't move.
I could help you, but...
I need a hand.
Yautja hunt alone.
Yautja might hunt alone,
but they die alone too.
Kalisk.
You're hunting the Kalisk.
Gotta run faster.
It happens fast, huh?
If you had a weapon,
you know, I could use it.
Throw me that,
and I can get you the antidote.
Now or never.
Hi.
Should be good as new.
The venom makes them bloom.
Also makes them
a handy antidote.
How about a lift?
Let's go.
Excuse you, sir.
What happened to your legs?
I'm synthetic.
I was built and deployed
by the Weyland-Yutani
Corporation for research.
Because their humans wouldn't
last a day on this planet.
We found that--
Look...
Many Yautja have come
for the great Kalisk,
and none have survived it...
or Genna.
I've seen the Kalisk.
I survived it.
You take me along with you,
and I'll guide you to its den.
Once there, I get my legs,
you get your trophy,
and everyone's a winner. Deal?
You have seen the Kalisk?
Oh, yeah. I've seen the Kalisk.
Okay. Hmm.
Good luck with your journey.
I'm just gonna...
go on my journey.
I'm sure
you'll figure something out.
Hey.
I've already shown you
that I can be useful to you.
Useful...
like tool?
Yes. Yes, exactly, like a tool.
The only way to survive Genna
is to work with it,
and I know how.
And with the right tool...
...you could get the Kalisk.
You could be the first.
I will use you, tool.
You may call me Thi-- Whoa!
You seem smaller than the other
Yautja. How old are you?
And what does the chewing?
Your outside fangs
or your inside teeth?
Oh. What should I call you?
Whoa!
I've never been thrown before.
What a... ...thrill!
How fast were you going
when your ship crashed?
Faster than sub-light speed?
We haven't cracked that yet.
Also, that plasma sword
is interesting.
Is it unique to your clan?
And what may I call you?
I call these imbre anguis.
They just want a snack.
You catch more flies with honey
than you do with vinegar.
Don't want flies.
Predatory organisms are
my specific area of expertise.
I've studied Yautja extensively.
It's an impressive culture.
Here, ask me anything.
I bet I have the answer.
Oh!
Very funny.
And you still haven't
told me your name.
Name is Dek.
Now talk that way.
Okay, sure.
Well, let's back up
and start at the beginning.
Genna was formed
64 billion cycles ago,
when a dying red dwarf star
in a neighboring system...
It's so beautiful.
After all the time
I've been stuck here,
I never get tired of the view.
How long have you been here?
Well, we arrived on Genna two
years ago, and we built a base.
Then, I was in
the vulture's nest
for the most exciting
13 days, seven hours, 43 minutes
and two seconds of my life.
But I always knew
someone would come.
I was just wrong about who.
Who would come?
Tessa.
Our crew is made up
entirely of synths.
But Tessa and I are special.
We have a higher sensitivity
than the others.
Sensitivity is weakness.
Sensitivity is what allows us
to understand
the creatures on this planet.
We were created
to work in tandem.
Me, cooped up in the lab,
Tessa out in the field.
Until the wonderful day
Tessa let me come with her.
We were exploring Genna.
And then the Kalisk attacked us.
Separated me... and us.
The last sound
I remember hearing
was Tessa calling out my name.
Reaching for me.
Then the Kalisk.
I didn't know what to do.
But I refuse
to believe she's dead.
Thia, Thia, Thia, Thia.
Thia, Thia, Thia...
Tessa!
Thia, Thia, Thia, Thia.
Thia, Thia.
Hello, Tessa.
The Company is not pleased.
Continued failure will result
in your decommission.
Where's Thia?
The Yautja has Thia.
I must eat.
Two warriors.
Dek and Thia, on the hunt.
Oh.
Quick question.
What should I be doing?
What is this creature?
Bone bison.
They're Kalisk food.
Then it will be my food, too.
So exciting.
Hunting with a Yautja.
Tessa wouldn't believe it.
Just a warning...
Quiet tool!
Razor grass.
It'll cut you to ribbons.
We'll just go around.
You give up too easily.
We might not be alone
in this hunt.
What an odd critter.
I've never seen you before.
Thia. Nice to meet you.
Looks like your competition
is better--
Careful up in these trees.
There are Luna bugs!
Coming up behind you!
Stronger than it looks!
Uh, Dek?
Dek! Look!
Kalisk?
Not a Kalisk.
This is a Luna bug!
Have any other weapons?
Why'd you stop?
Let's get out of here.
You give up too easily.
That was the best hunt
I've ever been on.
This is the dream team
right here.
The Dynamic Three.
The Dynamic Trio.
The Dynamic Tree-oh!
Tree-oh! Remember when
we went down the tree?
That monster's mouth,
I mean...
Didn't smell great,
didn't smell great. But...
We got him. We got him.
And then we met you,
our little sweet,
little, little thing.
Thank you, seriously,
for that experience.
Truly amazing. Thrilling.
Truly thrilling.
What was your favorite part?
When I pierced its head with my sword,
and its blood rushed down my face.
Cool.
Oh. No, thanks. I don't eat,
but that's very sweet.
This flesh is not sweet.
Good to know.
Our little bud here
looks hungry.
I think she's marking you.
She wants you
to be a part of her clan.
Maybe she's lost.
I have no clan!
What do you mean?
Don't all Yautja have family?
No clan.
So you never had anyone
looking out for you?
I had a brother.
Had?
What happened to him?
Father killed him.
You're grieving.
Grief is weakness.
You're here
because you lost your brother.
I am here for Kalisk.
Why are you here?
I'm here
because traveling with you
is the best way
to get back to Tessa.
When I was
in that vulture's nest,
I was so afraid
I would never see her again.
You should be able to survive on your own.
I can survive on my own.
But who would want
to survive on their own?
Tessa is your sister.
Sister.
Yeah.
I guess she is.
I have... a sister.
What a lovely thought.
I need to find her.
And legs.
Excuse me?
Find your sister.
And legs.
Was that a joke?
The sun rises.
Let's go.
We can't leave Bud.
Bud?
Yeah, Bud. I named her.
Yautja hunt alone.
You're not alone, I'm with you.
You're a tool.
The tree would have eaten us
without her.
We're not in the tree now.
Kalisk?
It drinks here.
It drinks here?
You are a useless tool if you don't speak.
Bud saved us.
She spit on you to claim you
as part of her family.
Why'd your father
kill your brother?
My brother was protecting me.
The clan can have no weakness.
I will show them strength.
On Earth...
there's a predator known
as the wolf.
It's a powerful creature.
They hunt in packs.
They're very loyal.
The leader of the pack
is the alpha.
Known as the most dominant.
Wolf.
This alpha must be a great killer.
I will hunt it too.
No.
The alpha isn't the wolf
who kills the most.
The alpha is actually the one
who best protects the pack.
I see...
But I will be the alpha
that kills the most.
The Kalisk's den?
Who are they?
Weyland-Yutani synths.
The Kalisk destroyed
most of our mission team.
There I am.
Easier to walk now.
It's about to be.
No.
Easier for me to walk now.
Oh. Of course. Right.
Thank you, Dek.
I'm never gonna forget this.
I too will remember this...
today I become Dek of the Yautja.
I will honor Kwei...
when I bring the Kalisk home.
Then I taste revenge.
You will be the first to see my trophy.
It is a great honor.
For you.
Dek, there's something
I have to tell you.
You need to leave now.
Location beacon activated.
What?
I called Tessa.
The company is on its way.
You can't be here
when they arrive.
I came here for the Kalisk.
So did I, Dek.
The company sent us here
to capture the Kalisk.
You want my trophy.
Where is the Kalisk?
Dek, you can't kill it.
I use you, tool. You do not use me!
I'm sorry. You have to leave.
I needed you
to help bring me here.
I use you!
Where is the Kalisk?
I'm trying to help you, Dek.
You think your brother
saved your life
just so you could die here?
Then my death will be honorable.
Call your sister.
None can stop me.
Ugh! Come on!
Dek!
Save yourself, tool!
Tool, get these off!
You are not Thia.
Release me!
You are another broken tool!
The Yautja cull their weak.
Why were you spared?
Remove these!
Or I'll rip out your spine
and crush your skull!
I read Thia's logs.
You never told her
why your brother protected you.
You are nothing. A device.
Made by others to do their work for them.
That's correct.
And you are now property of the
Weyland-Yutani Corporation.
It is a great honor. For you.
Tessa.
You made it.
We made it.
I've seen so much.
I have so much to tell you.
I saw such incredible creatures.
The Yautja is a great
travelling companion.
Thia.
You were right about the Kalisk.
You betrayed me!
The creature
is a regenerative miracle.
Humanity will thank us.
We have the Kalisk?
Yes.
And Muthur will be pleased
with your additional catch.
Additional catch?
The Yautja
is not an ideal specimen.
No, not ideal.
But its technology is valuable.
We can salvage its weapons
and leave the Yautja.
Good idea.
But it's so malformed.
We're going to need a sample.
For research.
He was not the goal
of our mission.
Tessa, he is deficient.
Tessa!
Thia,
this is what is asked of us.
We can be more
than what they ask of us.
What can we be?
Sisters.
Thia.
Do you know why
Muthur gave us feelings?
So we could understand
the creatures on this planet.
-And exploit them.
-Exploit them.
The Yautja is different.
He rescued me.
Like you rescued me.
I did not come here
to rescue you.
I am completing our mission.
When we first faced the Kalisk,
I tried to protect you.
And that almost cost me
everything.
What do you mean, Tessa?
I almost made the same mistake
the Yautja's brother made.
The weak must be culled.
And Thia, you're broken.
Tessa, incoming message
from Muthur.
Motivate the Yautja
to explain its weapons.
And the unit?
Box her up.
I trusted you.
Don't like these tools.
I'm sorry. My sister is -
Don't like sister either.
Why are you speaking
its language?
Tell tool you're asking about the device.
You heard the orders.
I'm asking it
to explain this device.
What is the device?
He's asking about the device.
It's a children's toy.
But say it's a map.
What did it say?
He says it's a map.
How does it work?
Tell tool to look inside.
That was a toy for children?
Yautja children!
Run Dek!
Go... Go!
Stop!
KWEI!
Enter destination coordinates, Kwei.
You saved me, brother.
Wolf.
Kalisk.
Kalisk child.
Hello, Muthur.
Tessa.
We're about to load the Kalisk.
Priority one complete.
The specimen has been acquired.
Thank you, Tessa.
We truly are building
a better world.
And what is the status
of the Yautja?
The Yautja
is a defective specimen.
What is the status
of the Yautja?
I'm sorry, Muthur.
The Yautja is dead.
Then the Yautja
is no longer a threat.
The Company will be pleased.
Whoo!
Nicely done.
-Form up.
-Oh, shit.
Good job.
Don't... move.
Dek! What are you doing here?
I came to rescue you.
You came back for me?
Wolf.
What exactly are you wearing?
Bone Bison.
Dek of the Yautja.
Not yet...
Thia.
We need to hurry.
More of them will be here
any minute.
Halt!
What are you doing here?
Thanks, Bud. I'm good.
We need to go.
Kalisk!
Still, Dek?
Kalisk child!
Bud?
They have her mother!
Bud's its child?
What's the plan?
You free the Kalisk.
I get my trophy.
You have 20 minutes
to initiate launch.
Let's go hunt.
Wait here.
You roll in there,
you're not exactly gonna fit in.
I have an idea.
I see him. On me.
What are you doing?
What are you doing here?
I told you to get to the Yautja.
You said to prepare the ship
for take off in 20 minutes.
Then what are you doing here?
I gave you an order.
What should we do
about the creature?
What creature?
You should listen to her.
I should listen to her?
I don't know.
We need his eyes.
Hi, Dek.
How does it feel to be hunted?
You tell me.
This is the plan, yeah?
Tessa.
Betrayed by my own... sister.
We are not sisters.
That's not yours.
Dek of the Yautja.
Not yet.
You've come here for revenge?
I've come for my cloak.
What is this?
I've completed my hunt.
That is my trophy.
You disgrace our clan...
And so did Kwei.
Get rid of him.
Perhaps the right son did survive.
Yield now...
...and take your place in our clan.
I have my own clan.
Finally earned that cloak.
Dek of the Yautja.
More friends of yours?
No.
It's my mother.