(ENGINE REVVING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(HORN BLARING)
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(CHATTERING OVER RADIO)
(GROANS)
It's time to get out.
(ANOTHER WAY TO DIE PLAYING)
Another ringer with
the slick trigger finger
for Her Majesty
Another one
with the golden tongue
Poisoning your fantasy
Another bill from a killer
Turned a thriller to a tragedy
A door left open
A woman walking by
A drop in the water
A look in the eye
A phone on the table
A man on your side
Oh, someone that you think
that you can trust
is just
Another way to die
Another tricky little gun
Giving silence to the one
That will never
see the sunshine
Another inch of your life
sacrificed for your brother
In the nick of time
Another dirty money
heaven-sent honey
Turning on a dime
Well, a door left open
A woman walking by
A drop in the water
A look in the eye
A phone on the table
A man on your side
Oh, someone that you think
that you can trust
is just
Another way to die
Hey!
You know you're gonna die
Shoot 'em, bang, bang!
A door left open
A woman walking by
A drop in the water
A look in the eye
A phone on the table
A man on your side
Oh, someone that you think
that you can trust
is just
Another way to die
Another
It's just another way
Shoot 'em up, bang, bang!
You know you're gonna
Die!
Just another
It's just another way
Bang, bang, bang, bang
(MAN CHATTERING OVER P.A.)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
Don't bleed
to death.
Hello, Mitchell.
Bond.
The Americans are gonna be
none too pleased about this.
I promised them Le Chiffre,
and they got Le Chiffre.
They got his body.
If they'd wanted his soul,
they should have made
a deal with a priest.
M: Has he said
anything?
No.
I'm going to check
the perimeter, ma'am.
You look like hell.
When's the last
time you slept?
Vesper's boyfriend,
Yusef Kabira, the one who was
abducted in Morocco,
the one she was
trying to save.
His body was washed up
on a beach in lbiza.
We're meant to believe
the fish did that to his face.
His wallet and ID
were in his pocket.
BOND: Well,
that's convenient.
Quite.
Which is why I did
a DNA check
on a lock of his hair
found in Vesper's
apartment.
It's not him.
A lock of his hair?
I wouldn't have thought
Vesper the sentimental type.
Well, we never really
know anyone, do we?
But I do need
to know, Bond.
I need to know
that I can trust you.
And you don't?
Well, it'd be
a pretty cold bastard
who didn't want revenge
for the death of
someone he loved.
You don't have
to worry about me.
I'm not gonna
go chasing him.
He's not important.
And neither was she.
It's clear, ma'am.
Thanks, Mitchell.
Shall we?
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(MAN ANNOUNCING ON P.A.)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
Are you gonna tell us
who you work for?
I was always
very interested
to meet you.
I'd heard
so much about you
from Vesper.
The real shame is that
if she hadn't killed herself,
we would have had you, too.
I think you would have
done anything for her.
Well, you know you're not
in Britain, and God knows
where you'll be tomorrow.
Which should tell
you that eventually
you will tell us about
the people you work with,
and the longer it takes,
the more painful
we'll make it.
(LAUGHING)
You really don't
know anything about us.
It's so amusing
because we are on
the other side,
thinking, "The Ml6,
the CIA, they're looking
over our shoulders.
"They're listening
to our conversations."
And the truth is
you don't even
know we exist.
Well, we do now, Mr. White,
and we're quick learners.
(CHUCKLING) Oh, really?
Well, then, the first thing
you should know about us
is that we have
people everywhere.
Am I right?
(GROANS)
(PEOPLE PROTESTING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(GROANS)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(BELL TOLLING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(SIREN WARBLES)
(HORN HONKING)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
Anything?
Craig Mitchell
worked for me
for eight years.
He passed a full
security check and lie
detector test every year.
Didn't leave so much
as a scrap of paper
to explain any of it.
Eight years! Five as
my personal bodyguard.
I found this
and three other bloody
Christmas presents
I bought him
about the house.
I don't think he smoked.
And you had
to kill him.
Couldn't bring him in for
questioning so that we might
actually learn something.
When someone says
we got people everywhere,
you expect it to be hyperbole.
Lots of people say that.
Florists use that expression.
Doesn't mean that they've
got somebody working for them
inside the bloody room.
What the hell is
this organization, Bond?
How can they be everywhere
and we know nothing
about them?
I assume we found
no trace of White.
No.
The agent guarding
the door in the garage
was dead
before you passed him
on the stairs.
I passed him
on the stairs?
Christ!
Mitchell must have killed
him when he went out to
check the perimeter.
You're lucky to be here.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Do you think
White's still alive?
Yes, I do.
What is it?
TANNER: Craig Mitchell,
45 years old.
No living family.
Gave generously
to charity.
Tell me you know
more than that.
Our moneymen went through
every bill in Mitchell's
wallet and house.
How much did he have?
Less than 100 pounds,
and about the same
in euros and dollars.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, ma'am.
We've done a complete
forensic analysis
of every note and
its traceable history.
Not in the mood.
After you.
TANNER: This particular note
from Mitchell's wallet
may be of interest.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Scanning.
We introduced tagged bills
into Le Chiffre's
money-laundering operation
by intercepting
illegal payoffs.
We traced money through
several of his bank accounts
around the world.
That's pretty thin.
At the rate money
changes hands,
you could probably
find a tenner in my
wallet with a tag.
That's true, ma'am.
A single bill could be
a coincidence,
but what about
a whole stack?
These bills,
from the same series
as Mitchell's,
were just scanned at a bank
in Port-au-Prince, Haiti,
deposited in the account
of a Mr. Slate.
Impress me.
We have a Mr. Edmund Slate
returning to Port-au-Prince
from Heathrow this morning.
His entry documents
have him staying at
the Hotel Dessalines.
He's in room 325.
Thank you.
DRIVER: You're welcome.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
Do you have any
messages for 325?
No, sir.
The only message was
about the briefcase
that was delivered
earlier.
Did you want us
to continue holding it?
No. No,
I'll take that now.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Get in!
What?
Get in.
All right.
You're late.
I got pulled
into a meeting.
Who with?
A friend of Mr. White's.
Don't think
I know him.
It's funny.
You don't look at all
like I expected.
Really? What were
you expecting?
I didn't think
geologists looked so...
So?
A friend of yours?
I don't have any friends.
(HORNS BLARING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Get out of
the way! Move!
We didn't settle
on a price.
Make me an offer.
We can
work it out later,
over drinks.
Dominic didn't give you
any trouble, did he?
No.
What the hell is this?
I think someone
wants to kill you.
That wasn't very nice.
You were supposed
to shoot her.
Well, I missed.
Get Bond.
Where is he now?
Approaching the docks,
Kings Quay.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Connecting.
TANNER: Tanner.
I've got Bond.
Ask him about Slate.
She wants to know
about Slate.
Tell her Slate
was a dead end.
Slate was a dead end.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Connection terminated.
Damn him.
He killed him.
(SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Touch me and I'll
break your wrist.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Camille.
How nice to see you.
Alive, you mean?
I knew we shouldn't
have slept together.
I think I'm starting
to like you.
So you did just try
and have me killed.
(EXHALES)
And that made me
very sad
thinking I would never
see you again.
But here you are.
Damn it, Dominic!
I was trying to help you.
I was trying to
uncover a leak.
And you, you sent
someone to kill me?
Please don't talk to me
like I'm stupid!
It's unattractive.
Come. I wanna
show you something.
Come.
There's nothing
that makes me
more uncomfortable
than friends talking
behind my back.
It feels like
ants under my skin.
It's been
that way forever.
I remember
when I was 15,
I had a crush on one of
my mother's piano students.
Somehow I overheard her
saying very nasty things
about me.
I got so angry.
I took an iron.
Is that him?
I...
We only spoke
on the phone.
It's such a shame
because he's one of
my best geologists.
He said you asked
to buy information.
No. He called me
and offered to
sell me information.
Why would I come back here
if I was lying?
(CHUCKLING) Because
you love me.
I was doing it
for you.
To stop him
from betraying you.
You know what burns more
than all your bullshit?
Is that I always got
the feeling that you were
only sleeping with me
to get to General Medrano.
Is that him?
You know how these
deposed dictators are,
jealous of their safety.
Stick around.
I'll introduce you.
Do you see the girl
that just walked in here?
Could you give her that?
Tell her to call me.
(IN FRENCH)
(RINGING)
WOMAN ON MACHINE:
You've reached
Universal Exports.
Our offices are
currently closed.
(IN FRENCH)
(LAUGHING)
And you can do
all this for me?
Well, look
at what we did
to this country.
The Haitians elect a priest
who decides to raise
the minimum wage from
38 cents to $1 a day.
Whoa!
It's not a lot,
but it's enough to
upset the corporations
who were here
making T-shirts
and running shoes.
So they called us,
and we facilitated
a change.
The difference is,
my country's not some
flyspeck in the middle
of the Caribbean.
But we've already begun
destabilizing the government.
We'll supply
the private security.
We'll pay off
the right officials,
and we have 26 countries
ready to officially recognize
your new
Bolivian government.
You want your
country back.
My organization
can give it to you
within the week.
You've been busy.
And in return
you want what?
A desert.
(THANKS IN FRENCH)
This part.
This land is worthless.
Oh.
So you're getting
a great deal.
You won't find
oil there.
Everyone has tried.
Maybe, maybe not.
But we own
whatever we find.
Did you know
Ernesto Montes?
A very powerful man
in his day.
He had a beautiful
Russian wife.
A dancer.
Well, his daughter
works for me.
Or did.
She's lovely,
but I don't see
the resemblance.
Why don't you
consider her
as something to
sweeten the deal?
Just promise me to
drop her over the side
when you're done.
Camille,
General Medrano.
(GREETS IN SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Be careful
what you wish for,
my dear.
Have fun, you two.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING EXCITEDLY)
(ACCELERATING)
(CLAMORING IN SPANISH)
(CAMILLE GROANS)
(YELLING IN SPANISH)
What the hell
are you doing?
You're welcome!
You idiot! Take me back!
You know, maybe
I'll do that later.
You're not one
of Greene's.
Dominic Greene?
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
Get down!
Give me the wheel!
Navigate!
Left!
What are you doing?
Hold on!
(EXCLAIMS)
Get down!
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
Excuse me.
Thank you. She's seasick.
(BEEPING)
It's Bond.
Connect Bond.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Connecting 007.
Yes?
Name check,
Dominic Greene.
G-R-E-E-N-E.
I might need
a little more
than that.
There are a lot of
Dominic Greenes.
Do you have
a social security
or passport number?
No.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Scanning DGSE databases.
BOND: Anything?
Scanning KGB databases.
Do you have anything?
Will you put her on, please?
I am on, Bond.
What happened to Slate?
I'm not dwelling
on the past.
I don't think
you should, either.
You killed him.
Largest hit, Dominic Greene,
CEO of Greene Planet.
It's a utility company,
but Greene's been doing
a lot of philanthropic work,
buying up large tracts of land
for ecological preserves.
You should be getting
his picture now.
Yep, that's him.
I'm afraid there's
a firewall around his
other corporate holdings,
so we have no
other information.
Get me the Americans.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Connecting.
AMERICAN WOMAN:
Go ahead.
Interest in Dominic Greene,
Greene Planet.
Transferring you now.
MAN: Hold for
Gregory Beam, please.
Thank you.
Hi, this is
Gregory Beam, ma'am.
Hello, Mr. Beam.
I'm so sorry to
keep you waiting. We have
no interest in Mr. Greene.
Thank you, Mr. Beam.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Connection terminated.
He's a person of
extreme interest.
But he just said
that he wasn't...
Tanner, I asked about the man
and she transferred me
to the section chief
of South America.
How would she know to do that
if they weren't tracking him?
TANNER: Bond,
we have your location
as approaching an airfield.
Is Greene on the move?
Yeah.
I've got a tail number,
Golf-Zero-Charlie-
Sierra-Charlie.
Get me a destination.
It's a private charter
going to Bregenz, Austria,
leaving immediately.
Tanner, authorize
a charter for 007.
And, Bond,
if you could avoid killing
every possible lead,
it would be
deeply appreciated.
Yes, ma'am.
I'll do my best.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Connection terminated.
I've heard that before.
WOMAN: Hello.
Hi.
Ah. Welcome aboard.
(EXCHANGING GREETINGS
IN FRENCH)
Come. Have a seat.
Charlie-Sierra-Charlie.
Jeez.
Sorry.
How much longer?
So do we have
an understanding?
Uh, yeah.
We do nothing to stop
a coup in Bolivia,
and in exchange,
the new government
gives America the lease
to any oil found.
If it's oil
you want.
Well, you didn't find
diamonds, did you?
(LAUGHING)
Drilling underground,
you kept off everybody's
radar for a very long time,
but you can't buy
that much piping
without somebody
getting curious.
We'll have to
verify the find.
I'm not even admitting
there is one. You are
getting this for free.
Venezuela, Brazil,
now Bolivia.
With you tied up
in the Middle East,
South America is falling
like dominoes.
You don't need another Marxist
giving national resources
to the people, do you?
Well, we can
hardly be expected
to do something
about a coup
we know nothing about.
And I have
a pest.
This.
You have any idea
who that is?
Sorry.
It's James Bond,
British Secret Service.
I don't know how
I could have missed that.
I will need you
to get rid of him
for me.
Yeah. That's not
gonna be a problem.
(ENGINE STARTS)
You know who Greene is
and you wanna put us
in bed with him.
You are kidding,
right?
Yeah. You're right.
We should just deal
with nice people.
I need to know
you're on the team, Felix.
you value your career.
(BEEPING)
Dominic Greene.
Good to see you.
How are you?
Good. Thank you.
WOMAN ON P. A:
Ladies and gentlemen,
tonight's performance ofTosca
will begin shortly.
Please take your seats.
(CLATTERING)
(SINGING OPERA)
(DRAMATIC ORGAN MUSIC PLAYING)
(ARTIFICIAL THUNDER CRASHING)
(MAN CONTINUES SINGING)
WOMAN OVER EARPHONES:
What else does
General Medrano require?
WOMAN: (INTERMITTENTLY)
Anything further from
Canadian intelligence?
MR. WHITE: (INTERMITTENTLY)
We'll discuss that later.
(CONNECTION CRACKLING)
MAN 2: How much more
pipeline do we need?
Ideally,
2,000 kilometers.
Are there
any objections?
WOMAN: No.
MAN 1: Not here.
MAN 3: No objections.
Transfer the funds
from our Siberian holdings.
MR. WHITE: Done.
Where do the
Americans stand?
Well, the CIA doesn't care
about another dictator
as long as they get their end.
But when they find out
that they've been duped?
I'm working on that.
MAN 4: I'm still not sure that
the Tierra Project is the
best use of Quantum's time.
MAN 5: Perhaps
we should shift our focus
to the Canadian.
DOMINIC: This is the world's
most precious resource.
We need to control
as much of it as we can.
Bolivia must be
top priority.
Can I offer
an opinion?
I really think
you people should find
a better place to meet.
Where do you think
you're going?
(CAMERA CLICKS)
Thank you.
(FOOTSTEPS CLATTERING)
(GROANING)
Well, Tosca isn't
for everyone.
(INAUDIBLE)
(MAN SHOUTING)
(GASPING)
Drop it.
(GUN CLATTERING)
So who are you
working for?
Piss off.
DOMINIC: Get rid of
anything we brought with us.
We've been compromised.
I asked you who
you were working for.
Is he
one of ours?
No.
Then he shouldn't
be looking at me.
Get me M.
(PHONE RINGING)
MAN: It's your line.
Thanks.
Connect call.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Connecting Tanner.
TANNER: We've ID'd
the pictures.
Show me.
Gregor Karakov,
former minister,
now owns
most of the mines
in Siberia,
Moishe Soref,
former Mossad,
now telecom giant,
and Guy Haines,
special envoy
to the Prime Minister.
Get Bond.
There's something else.
It appears Bond
shot Haines' bodyguard
and threw him off a roof.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
M: Where are you?
Did you get
my pictures?
Was this a conversation?
Can you link these people?
Is that stress
in your voice?
I need you to
come in and debrief.
I don't have time.
Bond,
(OVER SPEAKER)
You killed a man in Bregenz.
I did my best not to.
You shot him at point blank
and threw him off a roof.
I'd hardly call that
showing restraint,
especially since he was
a member of Special Branch.
So who was he guarding?
Bond, are you missing the fact
that you killed a member
of Special Branch?
I need you to come in.
And I would, but right now
I need to find the man
who tried to kill you.
Go back to sleep.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Connection terminated.
Restrict Bond's movements.
Cancel his cards.
Put an alert
on his passports.
All of them.
And I want to know
everything we don't know
about Haines.
TANNER: Yes, ma'am.
And, Tanner, be careful
who you trust with this.
Hopefully, you're
a better judge of
character than I am.
You want to follow
your friends to
La Paz, Bolivia?
Please.
(BEEPS)
Oh.
I'm sorry, sir,
but this doesn't work.
Do you have
another card?
No.
Could you do me
a favor?
You're gonna get
a phone call in a minute.
Would you mind telling them
I'm headed for Cairo?
I'd be happy to.
Thank you.
(PHONE RINGING)
(GREETING IN GERMAN)
Mathis.
What do you want?
Come to apologize?
You know, Mathis,
I think retirement
suits you.
None for him.
Sorry. He's in
a bad mood today.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(AGREES)
I need a passport
and matching credit cards.
And Ml6 ran out
of plastic?
Well, oddly, right now,
you're the only person
I think I can trust.
That is odd.
But I guess
when one's young,
it seems very easy
to distinguish between
right and wrong.
But as one gets older,
it becomes more difficult.
The villains and the heroes
get all mixed up.
I was sorry to hear
about Vesper.
I think she loved you.
Mmm.
Right up until the moment
she betrayed me.
She died for you.
Why did you really
want to see me?
I need some information.
Ah.
You have some hard friends.
This man is some
kind of facilitator.
Fingers in many pies,
and they don't
leave any prints.
These men
were together?
They're buying up
oil pipeline.
Something called
the Tierra Project.
Do you know it?
Destroy these.
That's Guy Haines.
You don't know him?
Should I?
(CHUCKLES) I suppose not.
You haven't been keeping
secrets as long as I have.
He keeps
a very low profile,
but he's one
of the Prime Minister's
closest advisors.
Well, they say you're
judged by the strength
of your enemies.
Do you know anything
about Bolivia?
I was stationed
in South America
for seven years.
Well, do you have
some contacts there?
A few.
What do you want
to know?
Come with me.
(SCOFFS)
(IN ITALIAN)
You can't sleep?
MAN: May I fix you
a drink, sir?
What are you
drinking?
I don't know.
What am I drinking?
Three measures
of Gordon's gin,
one of vodka, half of...
Kina Lillet.
Kina Lillet,
which is not Vermouth,
shaken well
until it is ice-cold,
then served with a large
thin slice of lemon peel.
Six of them.
That's impressive.
They're good.
You should have one.
No, it'll just
keep me awake.
(SNIFFLES)
So what's
keeping you awake?
I was wondering
why you came with me.
It takes something
to admit you were wrong.
You want
a sleeping pill?
No.
Pain pill?
I have pills
for everything.
Some make you taller.
(SNORTS)
Some make you forget.
I'm going to try
and get some sleep.
Good idea.
Thank you.
Mr. Bond, my name is Fields.
I'm from the consulate.
Well, of course
you are.
And what do you do
at the consulate,
Fields?
That's not
important.
My orders are
to turn you around
and put you
on the first plane
back to London.
Do those orders
include my friend
Mathis?
I'm sorry,
I don't know
who you are.
You see that?
Gone such a short time
and already forgotten.
(SIGHING) You're just
saying that to hurt me.
Mr. Bond, these orders
come from the highest
possible authority.
Taxi. Fields, when is
the next flight to London?
Tomorrow morning.
Well then,
we have all night.
If you attempt to flee,
I will arrest you,
drop you off in jail
and take you to
the plane in chains.
Understand?
Perfectly. After you.
(QUIETLY) I think
she has handcuffs.
I do hope so.
(DRIVER CHATTERING
IN SPANISH)
He blames
the water shortage
on global warming.
Hello, Carlos?
Carlos.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(DRIVER CONTINUES
CHATTERING)
The Colonel who heads
the National Police.
(SHUSHING IN SPANISH)
(DRIVER CONTINUES CHATTERING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
We have a reservation.
(EXCHANGING GREETINGS
IN SPANISH)
MAN: Cómo está?
Very well, thank you.
Your name?
Miss Fields.
You're going nowhere.
So shoot me.
I'd rather
stay in a morgue.
We are teachers on sabbatical.
This fits our cover.
No, it doesn't.
Get in.
(ENUNCIATING)
Get in!
(DRIVER CONTINUES
CHATTERING)
(MATHIS SHUSHING
FRUSTRATEDLY)
(CHATTERING CONTINUES)
(MATHIS SHUSHING
DRIVER SHARPLY)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Follow me, please.
May I show you
your room, senor?
No, it's fine.
Thank you.
(THANKS
IN SPANISH)
I can't find the, um...
The stationery.
Will you come
and help me look?
(SCOFFS)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
You've been invited
to a party.
I didn't know we had
any friends here.
Greene Planet.
You're not coming?
I'm having a drink
with my friend
the Colonel.
I'll see you
there later.
Do you know how angry
I am at myself?
I can't imagine.
(EXHALES TREMULOUSLY)
You must be furious.
Do you want to go
to a party?
A party?
But I have
nothing to wear.
We'll fix that.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(SOFTLY) It might be useful
to know your real name.
Fields.
Just Fields.
Fields it is, then.
DOMINIC: We are in a spiral
of environmental decline.
Since 1945, 17%
of the planet's
vegetated surface
has been
irreversibly degraded.
The Tierra Project is just
one small part of a global
network of Eco Parks
that Greene Planet
has created
to rejuvenate a world
on the verge of collapse.
I hope that tonight
you make the decision
to be part of that.
Thank you.
(PEOPLE APPLAUDING)
And have fun.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Excellent speech
and congratulations.
Wonderful speech,
Dominic.
We need you here.
Thank you.
Miss Fields, Mr. Bond,
my friend Carlos.
Pleased to meet you.
Ma'am.
Mr. Bond,
Mathis has spoken
a great deal about you.
I want you to know
my entire police force
is at your disposal.
Well, that could
be very useful.
You know, there are people
in this country spending
half their paycheck
just to get
clean water.
What do you
think of that?
The Bolivian government
is the problem.
They cut down the trees,
then act surprised
when the water and the soil
wash out to sea.
I couldn't agree more.
I hope this figure
is to your liking.
Chéri, you
shouldn't tease.
Why don't you tell them
about all the land you
bought up outside Potosí?
It's been a pleasure.
Will you excuse me?
Of course.
CAMILLE: Somehow
the logging rights
went to a multinational
corporation that
cut down the forests,
but only after our last
government sold the land
to Greene Planet.
(CHUCKLING)
Or have I got
my facts crossed?
(CHUCKING) Yes,
I think you did.
You'll excuse us?
What a wonderful night.
You just cost me
quite a bit of money,
darling.
You can't
put a price
on integrity.
I can try.
Oh!
Thank you.
Tell me
you didn't drop by tonight
just to piss on my parade.
Or are you still after
this General's head
for your mantel?
A little of both.
Tell me where Medrano is
and maybe you won't lose
any more investors.
(CHUCKLES)
You are really
breaking my heart,
choosing an insect
like that over me.
(CHUCKLING)
Are you going
to throw me over?
No. You've
been drinking,
so maybe you slipped.
(POUTS) Oh. Just think
how much you'd miss me.
(GASPS)
BOND: Good evening.
There you are.
Would you
excuse me?
Mr. Bond.
What a pleasure.
Well, careful with this one.
She won't go to bed with you
unless you
give her something
she really wants.
It's a shame because
she's really quite stunning
once you get her
on her back.
(SNIDELY) I wish I could say
the feeling was mutual.
I'm sorry, Mr. Greene,
but we have to go.
Please. My friends
call me Dominic.
I'm sure they do.
How much do you know
about Bond, Camille?
Because he's rather
a tragic case.
As Ml6 says, he's
difficult to control.
Nice way of saying
that everything he touches
seems to wither and die.
Shall we?
Doesn't bode well
for you, I'm afraid.
You two do make
a charming couple, though.
You're both...
What's the expression?
Damaged goods.
(EXCLAIMS)
(GROANING)
Oh, my gosh!
I'm so sorry.
Come on, lighten up.
You're cramping my style.
So it's British
intelligence now.
What the hell do
you want from me?
You're gonna show me
Dominic Greene's
Tierra Project.
Are you up to it?
Do I have a choice?
Do you want one?
There's something horribly
efficient about you.
Is that a compliment?
(SIREN WAILING)
Well, what's the bet that
Dominic Greene has friends
in the police force?
Stay here.
(GREETS IN SPANISH)
(IN SPANISH)
(TO HIMSELF) Now, why
would you want me
to do that?
(GUNSHOT)
Mathis?
(GROANS IN PAIN)
There's a hospital
on the other side of town.
Please.
Stay with me.
Stay here, please.
Please.
(WHISPERING)
Come here.
(GASPS)
It's okay.
That's better.
That doesn't hurt.
Is Mathis
your cover name?
Yes.
Not a very
good one, is it?
(SCOFFS)
Do we forgive
each other?
I shouldn't have
left you alone.
Vesper.
She gave everything
for you.
Forgive her.
Forgive yourself.
Is that
how you treat
your friends?
He wouldn't care.
Let's go.
The Foreign Secretary's
asking to see you.
What don't I know?
Rene Mathis has been
shot dead in Bolivia.
The police claim
it was Bond.
(GREETS IN SPANISH)
CAMILLE: How much
did you pay him?
Well, he wanted you,
but I left him the car
as collateral.
He'll make much more
when he sells us out.
Right.
Let's see if
this thing'll fly.
Here.
All the information
I found said there was
nothing of value there,
but Greene's geologist
had proof that there was.
My sources tell me you're
Bolivian Secret Service,
or used to be,
and that you infiltrated
Greene's organization
by having sex with him.
(SNORTS)
That offends you?
No, not in the slightest.
So what's your
interest in Greene?
Amongst other things,
he tried to kill
a friend of mine.
A woman?
Yes.
But it's not
what you think.
Your mother?
She likes to think so.
What's that down there?
That's a sinkhole.
There are a few
around here.
Just for the record,
I wasn't with Greene for my...
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
(IN SPANISH)
Damn it!
(ENGINE REVVING)
CAMILLE: I think we lost him!
(IN SPANISH)
He's coming fast!
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
He's right behind you!
(PROXIMITY ALARM BEEPING)
(ALARM BUZZING)
Here. Put that on!
(PANTING)
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
(SCREAMS)
Come on!
Camille!
(GROANING)
According to the Bolivians,
it was a routine stop,
and when they discovered
Mathis' body, Bond disarmed
and shot them.
Of course,
there are no witnesses
to prove otherwise.
I need something.
I can't go in there
unarmed.
I'm sorry.
There's nothing.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Come in.
What's today's excuse?
That Bond is legally blind?
No, Minister.
I don't think
I need to tell you
how upset the PM is.
With respect, the PM
has my direct line.
And he'd have used it if
he'd wanted to speak to you.
I'm sorry, M.
Things have changed.
We've had long discussions
with our cousins.
Mr. Greene's interests
and ours now align.
Minister, this man
is a major player
in one of the most
dangerous organizations...
We've never
even heard of.
Foreign policy cannot be
conducted on the basis of
hunches and innuendo.
Then give us time
to gather enough evidence
so you can make
informed decisions.
Fine.
Say you're right.
Say Greene is a villain.
If we refused
to do business
with villains,
we'd have almost
no one to trade with.
The world's running
out of oil, M.
The Russians
aren't playing ball.
The Americans and Chinese
are dividing up what's left.
Right or wrong
doesn't come into it.
We're acting
out of necessity.
Bond is running wild.
Who's to say
he hasn't been
turned?
Pull him in
or the Americans
will put him down.
I think I found
a way out.
You're freezing.
I'm fine.
So what is it
that Greene has
that you want?
It's not Greene.
It's Medrano, the man
he met in Haiti.
My father worked
for the military junta.
He was a very
cruel man,
but he was my father.
When I was a small child
the opposition sent
general Medrano
to our house.
He shot my father.
He did things
to my mother
and my sister
and then strangled them
while I watched.
I was too young
to be any trouble,
so he just smiled at me
and set the house
on fire.
He left his mark.
So when I pulled you
off the boat...
I waited years
for that chance.
I apologize.
It seems
we're both using Greene
to get to somebody.
You lost somebody?
I did, yes.
You catch
whoever did it?
No.
Not yet.
Tell me when you do.
I'd like to know
how it feels.
We should go.
You ready?
They used dynamite.
(CLATTERING)
This used to be
a riverbed.
Greene isn't
after the oil.
He wants
the water.
We can't leave it
like this.
It's one dam.
He's creating a drought.
He'll have built others.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Excuse me, sir.
Your wife left
a message.
The English woman,
she left it for you
this morning.
Thank you.
My pleasure.
What is it?
Would you mind
waiting down here?
I'll be outside.
So that's
what she meant.
I hope you can
trust these men.
Just a moment.
It's Tanner.
Yes?
We've got the
girl downstairs.
She says to tell you
she's sorry but this
is not her fight.
It isn't. Let her go.
She isn't our concern.
Well, I'm
disappointed.
You are?
How much oil
did the Americans
promise you?
This isn't
about oil.
Well, that's good,
because there isn't any.
It's about trust.
You said you weren't
motivated by revenge.
I'm motivated
by my duty.
No.
I think you are so blinded
by inconsolable rage
that you don't care
who you hurt.
When you can't tell
your friends from your
enemies, it's time to go.
You might like
to tell her your theory
about there being no oil.
Her lungs are
full of it.
It was Greene.
No doubt. But why?
It's just misdirection.
I mean, why her, Bond?
She was just supposed
to send you home.
She worked in an office,
collecting reports.
Look how well your
charm works, James.
They'll do anything
for you, won't they?
How many is
that now?
You're removed from duty
and suspended pending
further investigation.
You'll give whatever weapons
you have to these men
and leave with them now.
(MEN GROANING)
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Miss Fields
showed true bravery.
I want that mentioned
in your report.
Now you and I need
to see this through.
There's nowhere to go.
There's
a capture or kill
order out on you.
(CHATTERING)
Who would have done that?
Ma'am?
Find out
where he's going.
He's on to something.
Ma'am, the CIA is insisting...
I could give a shit
about the CIA or their
trumped-up evidence.
He's my agent,
and I trust him.
Go on.
Get in.
Are you gonna try
and shoot me?
I said, get in.
BEAM: You're gonna get
botulism if you keep
drinking that.
It's bottled water.
It probably came from
some stream just around
the corner from here.
Bunch of little kids
peeing in it.
That's why I eat
the peppers.
Well, all
I'm saying is
(FLY BUZZING)
You can't trust
a damn thing around here.
(PHONE RINGING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
You know,
you should just
answer, "CIA," Felix.
A taxi driver told me
where the office was.
Well, if we're so easy
to find, James,
you really should
come visit.
Or maybe you should come out
and see some more of the city.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING IN SPANISH)
I heard a rumor
you'd gone native.
Felix.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
You know, I was just
wondering what South
America would look like
if nobody gave a damn
about coke or communism.
It's always impressed me
the way you boys have
carved this place up.
I'll take that
as a compliment
coming from a Brit.
Are you sure
you're playing
with the right side?
Regimes change
once a week down here.
Medrano'll be no dirtier
than the next guy.
Oh, you see,
that's what I like
about U.S. Intelligence.
You'll lie down
with anybody.
Including you, brother.
Including you.
Do you know
you're being played?
Dominic Greene's gonna
suck this place dry,
and then he's gonna move on,
and you're gonna be left
picking up the
broken crockery.
What can I tell you?
There's no such thing
as a free lunch.
Well, you see, Felix,
I don't think you're
half as cynical
as you make out to be.
You don't know me.
Why? Just because
you didn't come alone?
How long
have I got?
Thirty seconds.
Well, that doesn't give us
a lot of time, does it?
Medrano can't move
until he pays off the army
and the police chief.
Greene's bringing him
his money now.
A hotel called
La Perla de las Dunas
in the desert.
Thank you, Felix.
James, move your ass.
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
MAN: Get down!
Get down, now!
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
Move it! Move it!
What the hell happened?
What did you tell him?
Just what we agreed.
(IN SPANISH)
(DISTANT EXPLOSION)
(MEDRANO SPEAKING)
(CHUCKLING)
What are you doing?
The slide's caught.
Maybe you should
check your own.
I will.
Have you ever
killed someone?
Your training
will tell you that when
the adrenaline kicks in
you should
compensate.
But part of you
is not gonna believe
the training
because this kill
is personal.
Take a deep breath.
You only need one shot.
Make it count.
Pendejo.
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
In euros,
as requested.
The dollar isn't
what it once was.
The cost of war.
I am afraid
that the corruption in
this current government
can no longer
be tolerated.
And mine?
Right after you
sign over my land.
(IN SPANISH)
My first official act.
And this, if you would.
What is this?
As of this moment,
my organization owns
more than 60% of
Bolivia's water supply.
So this contract states
that your new government
will use us as
utilities provider.
This is double
what we are paying now.
Well, then
don't sign it.
But you should know
something about me and
the people I work with.
We deal
with the left
or the right,
with dictators
or liberators.
If the current president
had been more agreeable,
I wouldn't be
talking to you.
So, if you decide
not to sign,
you will wake up
with your balls
in your mouth
and your
willing replacement
standing over you.
If you doubt that,
then shoot me,
take that money and have
a good night's sleep.
(EXHALES)
(SCREAMING)
You and I had
a mutual friend.
(MEN CLAMORING)
(SCREAMS)
(SOBBING)
(YELLING)
(SCREAMING)
(GUN FIRES)
Sounds like you
just lost another one.
(LAUGHING)
(GASPING)
Not this way.
I can't. I can't.
Come here.
Like you said,
"Take a deep breath.
"Make it count."
(COCKS GUN)
(WHISPERING)
Close your eyes.
(CLATTERING)
BOND: Come on!
BOND: Wait here.
(PANTING)
(COCKS GUN)
You promised
that you'd...
Let you go?
I answered
your questions.
I told you what you wanted
to know about Quantum.
Yes, you did,
and your friends'd
know that
so they're probably
looking for you.
But the good news is,
you're in the middle
of a desert.
Here.
I bet you make it
20 miles before you
consider drinking that.
Goodbye, Mr. Greene.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Thank you.
It's my pleasure.
Are you all right?
Fine.
But I keep thinking,
"He's dead.
"Now what?"
Well, the dam we saw
will have to come down,
and there'll
be others, too.
Someone
who worked for Greene
might be of help.
Not a bad idea.
Do you think
they'll be able
to sleep now?
I don't think the dead
care about vengeance.
I wish I could
set you free.
But your prison
is in there.
(LAUGHING)
YUSEF: Fine.
Anything for
an easy life.
BOND: (QUIETLY) Sit down.
Sit down!
It's okay, baby.
You're Canadian?
You work in
Canadian intelligence?
It's all right.
I know you do.
And knowing this man,
I'd guess you have
access to some very
sensitive material
which you're gonna
be forced to give up.
His life will
be threatened,
and because you love him,
you won't hesitate.
It's a beautiful
necklace.
Did he give it to you?
I have one
just like it.
He gave it to
a friend of mine,
someone very
close to me.
Your name is?
Corrine.
Corrine, I suggest
you leave now.
You contact your people,
and you tell them
to check their seals.
They have a leak.
Do it now, please.
This man and I have
some unfinished business.
(CLEARS THROAT NERVOUSLY)
Thank you.
Please.
Make it quick.
Is he still alive?
He is.
I'm surprised.
Did you find
what you were
looking for?
Yes.
Good.
I assume you have
no regrets.
I don't.
What about you?
Of course not.
That would be
unprofessional.
They found Greene dead
in the middle of
the Bolivian desert,
of all places.
Two bullets in the
back of his skull.
They found motor oil
in his stomach.
Does that mean
anything to you?
Wish I could help.
You'll be glad to know,
I straightened things out
with the Americans.
Your friend Leiter's
been promoted.
He replaced Beam.
Well, then
the right people
kept their jobs.
Something like that.
Congratulations.
You were right.
About what?
About Vesper.
Ma'am.
Bond,
I need you back.
I never left.
(NECKLACE JINGLING)
(BOND THEME PLAYING)