A sharp left hand...
Come on! Come on!
Again! Again!
He's getting killed!
Oh, no, no, he's not getting killed, he's getting mad!
Come on, the whole world's watching!
Come on, knock me out!
Risin' up
Back on the street
No!
Did my time, took my chances
Went the distance, now I'm back on my feet
Again! Come on, champ, you ain't so bad!
Rocky!
So many times
It happens too fast
You trade your passion for glory
Come on! Come on!
Don't lose your grip on the dreams of the past
It's the eye of the tiger, it's the thrill of the fight
Risin' up to the challenge of our rival
...five, six, seven,
eight, nine, ten.
You're out!
I can't believe we're doing this.
Come on, come on, we made a deal.
I know, but this is extremely crazy.
Yeah, it's mentally irregular, right?
Yeah.
But it makes all the sense in the world.
You owe me a favor.
I know, but when did you think of this?
About three years ago.
Oh, this is very crazy, Apollo.
Look, Stallion. Look, when you won that last fight,
you won by one second, you beat me by one second.
One second, that's very hard for a man of my intelligence to handle.
Oh, is it? But didn't you say after I beat you,
you learned how to live with it?
I lied.
Oh, you lied!
Oh, so now you've just got to prove it to yourself, right?
Just to myself. No TV, no newspapers, just you and me.
Nothing, just you and me. Age before beauty.
Anything you say, Stallion.
I do all the work. Okay.
I'll tell you, Apollo, we'd better go slow,
'cause you ain't as young as springtime no more.
I'm still young enough to whip your butt, Stallion.
Oh, yeah? How you gonna do that?
You taught me everything you know.
Almost everything. You've got to remember now,
you fight great, but I'm a great fighter.
You ready?
Oh, absolutely.
All right. You know, Stallion,
it's too bad we've gotta get old, huh?
Just keep punching, Apollo.
Wanna ring the bell?
All right.
Ding, ding.
Come on, Stallion.
Come on, come on.
Boy, you really move good for an older guy.
Looking fly.
Look out, now.
No, no, you don't want any of this.
Come on. Come on.
Maybe I'm in here with the wrong guy.
Dad, you're late! Mom's gonna yell at you!
So how ya doin'?
Fine.
Don't you think that's a little bright, don't you think?
A little bit?
Where'd you get that hat?
A friend gave it to me. Like it?
Who punched you in the eye?
Same friend.
That's weird. Better hurry, Dad.
You know, you're developing a very, very loud personality.
Don't go too fast or you're gonna get out of focus.
Oh, really?
Yo! Yo, it's about time.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Listen, why don't you go over there and get ready to eat, okay?
Great, you're here. Now you can stop calling him names.
Oh, you been callin' me names, huh?
Well, we wait any longer, then I'll be ready for the next birthday.
Where have you been?
Oh, out gettin' punched.
Look, why don't you bring the cake in here?
We can get the celebration underway.
Boy, am I hungry.
Hey, babe, why don't you get the cake? I think he'll love it.
We got a great surprise for you.
You're gonna love this cake, okay?
You're gonna love your present, Uncle Paulie.
Where is it? Let me set the mood here.
I've got to turn the lights down and everything.
Watch this.
Is it parked outside in the driveway?
Just be patient, would ya?
I'm so excited, in fact, I'm starting to sweat.
I feel like I'm getting ready to go
into a big fight or something.
Watch this.
Happy birthday, Paulie.
What the hell is this?
Your present.
Yo, I wanted a sports car for my birthday,
not no walking trashcan.
Oh, come on, he looks great here.
This is extremely psycho, Rocko.
Since you don't have any friends, we thought you'd like it.
Yeah, pretend you're happy, will ya?
It'll keep you company when you're all alone.
That's a great-looking guy.
Please make a wish.
It's creepy! That talks, that thing!
Creepy? This thing's the greatest.
I wish I had one of these when I was growing up.
Go on, make a wish, like he says.
I wish I wasn't in this nightmare.
Hey, very classy wish. Very nice. What do you think there?
Very good, huh?
You wanna help me put out this forest fire?
Sure.
On the count of three. One, two, three!
Well, they're out!
You drowneded me!
Oh, don't worry.
I'll clean it up for you, Paulie.
Ta-da.
Rocky.
You noticed.
What are you doing with that cake?
Well, the party ain't over yet, you know?
Still gotta celebrate some more. It's a special night.
Yeah, it's Wednesday.
It's definitely Wednesday, but in case you forgot,
it's almost been nine years since you been married to me,
so here's your prize.
Oh, but our anniversary's a week away.
That's true, but why wait?
Has it been that rough?
Oh, no.
I'll tell you, it's been excellent, really.
Open your prize. Go on.
Go on, open your prize.
Okay.
You like it?
It's beautiful.
All right!
I was so nervous. I didn't know. I hope you like it.
The guy I bought it from says,
"Even if it looks like a snake, don't worry, 'cause it won't bite you. "
Oh, it's beautiful.
You know what's amazing?
That after all these years, everything still seems kind of new.
You remember a long time ago, I told you that...
I said that you ain't never gettin' rid of me?
Remember that?
Well, you're not.
You're never gettin' rid of me.
Happy almost anniversary.
Could you answer a few questions, please?
How long are you here for?
We talk later, please.
When are you gonna fight, Drago?
We talk later. Let's go.
Is it definite the Soviet Union will enter professional boxing?
Please, no more talk now. We will talk at press conference.
Do you know where it's gonna be held?
We talk later, please.
Today may have proved to be a landmark in sports history.
After unraveling years of red tape,
Russia will now throw its hat into the ring.
The prize ring, that is.
The introductions were made by his wife, Ludmilla Vobet Drago.
She was she double gold medalist in swimming.
Today, the Soviet Union has officially entered professional boxing.
My husband and great undefeated heavyweight world amateur champion,
Captain Ivan Drago,
has come here with his trainers to America
to compete as an international sportsman
and ambassador of goodwill.
Has Drago ever boxed against a real professional?
From having been trained in Russia
by great boxing coach Manuel Vega,
and now by Sergei Rimsky,
we hope he's qualified to do so.
Hope?
Well, I know he is, but I don't want to sound too confident.
If possible, we would like to have an exhibition bout
with your famous champion Rocky Balboa.
What makes you think he can stand the pressure
of fighting someone as seasoned as Balboa?
There is no one who can match his strength, his endurance,
or his aggressiveness.
You make it sound like he's indestructible.
Yes, he is.
Well, can this mammoth Russian,
who's already been nicknamed the Siberian Express,
wreak havoc among the professional heavyweight ranks?
Whoever he fights first, it'll be one hot ticket.
We'll be right back with a check on
today's pro football sports scoreboard.
Dad, when can I learn to fight?
I can't hear you. What?
I want to learn to fight!
Yo, could you turn your robot down?
You see, I fight so you don't have to fight,
'cause I want you to use your head for something
instead of a punching bag, like I do.
Your head doesn't look like a punching bag.
No? That's nice. Thanks a lot.
It looks like a catcher's mitt.
Oh!
Oh, a wise guy, huh?
Mr. Balboa, Mr. Creed's on the phone.
Yeah? I'll be right there.
You can get it right here.
Hope it's not another rematch.
Oh, don't worry about it. Okay. Hello?
Yeah, Apollo! Hey, turn that down.
Yeah, Apollo, how you doin'?
Yeah? You comin' out?
That's great.
What am I doin'? I'm just gettin' dizzy.
My husband and I thank you
for coming to our training quarter today.
As you can see, it is highly advanced,
and we wish to show the American press
a small portion of the advances our country's made
in the technology of human performance.
Coach Rimsky, what does all this do to enhance performance?
Well... If I may answer.
It makes a man a better man,
a great athlete, a super athlete
by harnessing all his strength.
Though most of the world is ignorant in body chemistry,
we wish to educate your country.
There have been rumors of blood doping
and widespread distribution of anabolic steroids in the Soviet Union.
Has Drago partaken in any such experiments?
No, no. Ivan is naturally trained.
Then how do you explain his freakish strength?
Like your Popeye, he ate his spinach every day.
Shall we have a demonstration?
Please do. Thank you.
A normal heavyweight
averages 700 pounds of pressure per square inch.
As you can see, Drago averages 1,850 pounds,
so the result's quite obvious.
And what results are those?
Whatever he hits, he destroys.
I've seen this Drago fight when he was an amateur.
He's big and he's strong, but he's clumsy.
I know I can beat him.
Why do you want to fight again?
Let's just say it's something I believe in.
You can do your homework.
Okay. Later, Dad.
Later, Uncle Paulie. Later, Apollo.
Later, big guy.
See you later, kiddo.
Yo, don't you think people are expecting to see Rocky whack this bum out first?
Yeah, yeah, and he will, when it's for real.
This is just an exhibition bout. It's kids' stuff.
What's the purpose?
I mean, what at this point in your life is worth getting hurt for?
What the hell is that?
That's my girl.
Thanks, honey.
You're welcome.
That's a nice song.
It's my favorite. You're the greatest.
See you, sport.
See you.
Yo, Paulie, who taught it to talk like that?
She loves me.
Oh!
Like I was saying,
I don't want this chump to come over here with all that hype, you know,
trying to make us look bad.
They try every other way.
With Rock's help, we can get great media coverage.
We can make them look bad for a change.
I think it's wrong.
No, it's never been more right.
You're a great fighter,
but you've been retired for nearly five years.
Don't you think it's time to start thinking about something else?
I mean, how much can you take? Either of you?
I'll get the coffee.
Look, I'm sorry. I didn't mean to...
I just care about you both. I...
You ever try these comics?
No, no.
Keeps your fertility.
Hey, Paulie.
The ring now. Rocky's holding that right hand up.
He's fighting right-handed! I don't believe it!
Now, this was a great fight.
Yeah, great. I'm gettin' punchy just watching it. Look at this!
Mamma mia! What you using for a chin there, Stallion?
I should have slipped that one.
Yeah, you definitely should have slipped that one.
Ain't it something, Stallion?
It's crazy how people, they just care about you when you're in that ring
and they care about you when you're bleeding,
but once you step out of that ring, Stallion,
it's like you're ancient history.
Oh, go on. It ain't ancient history, you know.
I don't see anybody asking for autographs, do you? Huh?
Hey, Apollo, can I ask you something?
What?
Well, you know, this fight you're having against the Russian...
Do you think maybe it ain't against him?
If it's not him, Stallion, then who's it against?
Well, do you think maybe it's, like, you against you?
What do you think?
You know, I think you really are getting brain damaged,
that's what I think, Stallion.
Maybe. But, really, I'm speaking the truth here, Apollo.
Are you? Yeah.
I don't think I want to hear this, Stallion.
Oh, come on. Hey, Apollo, look,
you were a great fighter, no doubt about that,
but, look, we gotta face the facts, too.
You don't want to believe it, but maybe the show is over.
Man, that's easy for you to say. You're still on top.
But what happens when you're not on top? Then what, huh?
Where do we go, Stallion?
'Cause we sure as hell can't be born again.
No, I know, we can't be born again,
but, you know, let's face it, we gotta change sometime.
I don't want to change, man. I like who I am.
I like who you are, too, but look at that, you know?
You don't want to believe this,
but that ain't us up there no more, Apollo.
We can't do that the way we did it before.
We're changing. We're, like, turning into regular people.
No, Stallion, maybe you think you're changing,
but you can't change what you really are.
And you can forget all this money and stuff you got all around you, man,
'cause it don't change a thing.
You and me, we don't even have a choice.
See, we're born with a killer instinct
that you can't just turn off and on like some radio.
We have to be right in the middle of the action
'cause we're the warriors.
And without some challenge,
without some damn war to fight,
then the warrior may as well be dead, Stallion.
So I'm asking you,
as a friend,
stand by my side this one last time.
You're a great talker, Apollo.
All right, but when this is over...
You know me, Stallion.
I always think of something else.
That's what I'm afraid of.
All right, you've got a deal there.
I feel sorry for that guy, you know?
Apollo, what made you decide to put on an exhibition fight with Drago?
Oh, let's call it a sense of responsibility.
Responsibility how?
I had to teach this young fellow to box, American style.
Apollo, isn't Drago a little inexperienced to be in the same ring?
Well, you know, some folks got to learn the hard way!
So, no quick knockout prediction?
No, no, no. I'm not angry with him.
See, I just want to show the whole world
that Russia doesn't have all the best athletes.
Rocky, how do you think Apollo should fight Drago?
Well, personally,
I think the first thing you'd better get Apollo is a ladder.
Drago, how does it feel to spar with the great former champion?
The man's tongue didn't come through customs.
My husband is very happy to have this opportunity.
It's his dream.
Dream? How do you mean?
In our country, Apollo Creed
is well known and very respected.
It could be a good victory.
Hey, wait a minute, now. Wait a minute. Hold it.
Win?
You don't really think you gonna whip me, do you?
Well, he didn't come here to lose.
You hold on, little lady, you hold on,
'cause lose, and lose royally, he's gonna do.
How can you be so sure?
Well, I been with the best, and I've beat the best.
I've retired more men than Social Security!
Excuse, please.
You are not very realistic, are you, Mr. Creed?
Where did you come from? What are you talking about?
You can box, yes, but you are far too old
to think that you can win over Drago.
Is that a fact?
Yes! And it could be a painful one.
You put that heavy bag with eyeballs in the ring with me,
and you're gonna see the meaning of pain.
Why do you insult us?
Now, you just hold on here. Don't make me out to be the bad guy.
I came here to talk about a friendly exhibition bout
till Comrade Big Mouth started up.
It is you who are the aggressor. This is obvious.
I wish to say to the press, in all fairness,
Drago should not even fight this man,
because he is a has-been.
You get that big chump in the ring right now,
and I'm gonna show you what I have.
Break something! Bring it on!
I don't want to hear anything about hurt. Just let that chump go.
All right, all right, all right.
All right, I said what I feel.
We're gonna finish this in the ring.
You understand? We're gonna finish this in the ring.
Look, you just shut up, and all these puppets that you brought with you.
You history, chump! You history!
How did I do? Little loud for my taste.
But good?
Oh, yeah, very good.
Welcome, one and all, to the city of lights, Las Vegas,
and to one of the most unusual events in years,
East meets West,
age versus youth in a goodwill exhibition match
as the former champion Apollo Creed takes on
a mountain of muscle from the Soviet Union,
Ivan Drago.
Come on, man. Patience is a virtue, you know?
I'm ready to rock 'n' roll, and you want to talk patience!
I understand, but you gotta get your equipment here.
There you go. Now you look like a mummy.
I feel like a mummy, too. How does it feel? Okay?
Feels great. I feel like I could eat nails, Stallion.
You know, I never tried them things.
What are you talking about?
Snails. I never had 'em, you know.
I've seen 'em in the garden, but I never wanted to eat 'em.
I didn't say anything about snails.
I said nails. Nails, Stallion.
Okay. Nails, yeah.
Well, you look pretty good, but, you know, just do me a favor.
When you go up there, Apollo, try not to wear yourself out, okay?
Yeah. Wear myself out. Sure.
Well, it's just that you ain't been in the ring for, like, five years,
so I just want you to maintain a little bit.
What are you talking about? You sound like I'm an old man.
I'm in the best shape of my life. I'm stronger, I'm quicker.
Well, hey, hey, I'm not saying you're not ready or anything,
but personally, if it were me,
I wouldn't mind postponing a couple of weeks.
Postpone?
Yeah. I mean, come on, Apollo,
we don't know anything about this guy you're fighting, really.
Look, okay, okay, let's say I postpone, right?
I pull out, somebody else steps in and whips this chump,
then where does that leave me?
What do you mean "leave" you, Apollo?
It's just some kind of exhibition fight. This thing don't mean nothing.
No, no, no, man. That's where you're wrong.
This is not just an exhibition fight that doesn't mean anything.
Look, this is us against them. What are you talking about? Come on.
Stallion,
maybe you don't know what I'm talking about now,
but you will when it's over.
Believe me, you will when it's over.
Ivan!
Good luck. I hope after we can be friends.
I hope so.
Of course, they're sportsmen, not soldiers.
Enjoy the fight.
Ow!
Knock me out, hit it
Hit it
Whoo
Super highways
Coast to coast
Easy to get anywhere
On the transcontinental
Overload
Just slide behind the wheel
How does it feel?
When there's no destination
That's too far
And somewhere on the way
You might find out who you are
Living in America
Eye to eye
Station to station
Living in America
Hand to hand
Across the nation
Living in America
Got to have a celebration
You may not be lookin' for the promised land
But you might find it anyway
Under one of those old familiar names
Like New Orleans
New Orleans
Detroit City
Dallas Dallas
Pittsburgh, PA Pittsburgh, PA
New York City New York City
Kansas City Kansas City
Atlanta Atlanta
Chicago and LA
I live in America
Head to head
Toe to toe
Sing, I live in America
Say it loud It'll make you proud
I live in America
Hey
I know what it means
Living in America
Got it made
I said now eye to eye Tooth to tooth
This is the undisputed truth
Living in America
Yeah
All the way with your bad self
Living in America
Yeah
I feel good!
Good evening, everyone.
Along with Warner Wolf, I'm Stu Nahan,
and we welcome you to a most unusual event.
For the first time ever, West against East in professional sports.
Thanks for getting me here, Stallion.
I owe you one, okay?
Oh, no, no. We're even.
God, I feel born again.
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome.
I would like to announce the presence of a true fighting champion
that defines the word courage.
The Italian Stallion, Rocky Balboa.
Excuse me, would you?
Oh, certainly.
Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
Rocky!
Tonight's special event features two great athletes.
In the blue corner, weighing 221 pounds,
a former heavyweight champion of the world,
the Dancing Destroyer,
the King of Sting,
the Count of Monte Fisto...
Yo, you think you got enough names?
Patience, Stallion. Almost done.
...the Master of Disaster, the one and only Apollo Creed!
The crowd anticipating a great fight now as Apollo is in the ring.
He's playing to the crowd.
In the red corner, weighing an even 261 pounds,
gold medalist and undefeated world amateur champion
from the Soviet Union,
the Siberian Bull,
Ivan Drago.
I want you! I want you! I want you!
Now the two fighters come to the center of the ring
for the instructions from referee Lou Filippo.
You boys know the rules.
Watch your low blows, kidney punches, rabbit punches.
In case of a knockdown, you go to the corner I tell you to
and you stay there until I tell you to come out.
Shake hands. Let's have a good fight.
All right, it's time to go to school, son.
Come on, get your hands up, man!
You need an interpreter? It's time to go to school!
You will lose.
Why don't you land him on his head?
All right.
The bad blood between these two can be felt all over this arena.
I can't get over the size of this Russian.
Apollo! Apollo! Apollo!
Get ready, 'cause it's show time!
It's show time! It's show time!
Excuse me, didn't you forget something?
Huh. Come on.
And Apollo seems to be in great spirits tonight.
He's really putting on a show for this capacity crowd.
Be back in a minute, all right?
Round one.
Creed dancing around.
Creed backpedaling now. He's been away five years...
Don't wait on him. Get on first.
Come on! He may be big enough, but you are mean!
Come on. Come on, chump. Come on.
Neither fighter ready to throw a punch.
A left jab there. A left jab once again by Creed.
And a slip! A slip by Creed.
This is bizarre.
Creed is over the hill,
and the Russian hasn't fought anybody.
Keep him bottled! Keep your chin down!
Keep moving, Apollo! Stick him!
Drago moving in again.
A left hand by Creed, another left hand by Creed,
and Drago moves away.
All right, come on!
Get your hands up! Get your hands up!
Another left hand by Creed!
Drago waiting, waiting, cocking that right hand.
Ooh! A crushing right by the Russian!
Get out of there! Stay away from him!
Get out of there!
And a left hand. He's taking some punishment now!
Drago moves him against the ropes.
Tie him up now!
Left hand ties him up.
And now the Russian throws Creed across the ring.
Move!
He comes in with more punishment.
It is Drago with the upper hand now,
Drago with the left to the midsection.
Get out of that corner!
...with the right hand. Another right. Another right.
Another right hand thrown by Drago.
Can Creed stay up?
Creed... Creed is against the ropes.
What's the matter with you guys?
What are you guys doing? This is supposed to be an exhibition!
You understand? An exhibition!
A tremendous end to the first round by the Russian,
and a very bloody Apollo Creed.
The Soviet's strength is incredible!
Champ, look, I gotta stop it.
This fight's finished. I gotta call it.
Look, champ, you can't do no more out there.
I'm here to fight him.
He's killin' ya. I gotta stop this thing.
I'm here to fight. Promise me you're not gonna stop this fight.
Boy, I'll you something, that was a pulverizing round for the ex-champion.
Hey, folks, Ivan Drago is definitely for real.
Apollo! Apollo!
You don't stop this fight, no matter what.
Apollo! Apollo! Apollo!
No matter what.
Apollo! Apollo! Apollo! Apollo!
Creed now comes out for round two, dancing around.
The legs appear to be still a little rubbery.
Get your hands up. Get your hands up.
And now it is the Russian just standing there,
the Russian trying to intimidate Creed.
And the Russian throws a right hand and staggers Creed!
Another right to the jaw! Another right to the head!
Get out of that corner!
Get out of the corner!
Creed is being pounded without mercy.
Stop the fight!
The referee tries to step in,
and he's thrown across the ring.
Throw the towel! Throw the towel!
No!
I've never seen Apollo take so much punishment!
Throw the damn towel!
No!
My God!
Creed is down!
Apollo is down, and he could be badly hurt.
Let him breathe!
Move back! Get these guys out of here.
The winner, Ivan Drago.
Let me through! Apollo!
I cannot be defeated.
Is he okay?
Somebody get a doctor in here!
There is no movement by Creed.
Get that light off him!
I defeat all man.
Is he dead? Get out of here.
It's absolute pandemonium.
Stand back.
Let him breathe! Come on, Apollo, you can do it.
Soon I defeat real champion.
Where's the stretcher?
Somebody send for a doctor. Is he dead?
Let him breathe, for God's sake!
What started out as a joke has turned out to be a disaster.
Creed appears to be in very serious condition.
Is the man alive?
You can make it. You can make it, Apollo.
If he dies, he dies.
There's a lot I could say about this man.
I don't know if it matters now.
I guess what matters is what he stood for,
what he lived for,
and what he died for.
You always did everything
the way you wanted it.
I know I didn't understand that, but...
Now I understand.
I'll never forget you, Apollo.
You're the best.
Rocky, is the decision final?
Yes.
Rocky, over here, please.
Is this the first time the champion has given up his crown?
I don't know about that.
Doesn't the title mean anything to you anymore?
Not until this is over.
Coach Rimsky, considering Rocky's known punching power,
do you still think this is gonna be an easy fight?
Yes, of course. It is a matter of science.
Evolution. Isn't it, gentlemen?
Drago is the most perfectly trained athlete ever.
This other man has not the size
or the endurance or the genetics to win.
It's physically impossible for this little man to win.
Drago is a look at the future.
Champ, there's been no mention of it yet,
but how much are you making for this fight?
No money. It's not about money.
Has the fight date been set yet?
December 25th.
Why Christmas?
That's what I was told.
Where?
It's in Russia.
Are you nuts?
Rocky, what's going on?
Why did you agree to this?
We fight in Soviet Union, or we fight nowhere.
Why don't you ask Drago's wife why she is afraid?
Tell them, please.
I'm afraid for my husband's life.
We have threats of violence everywhere.
We are not in politics.
All I want is for my husband to be safe, to be treated fairly.
You call him a killer.
He's a professional fighter, not a killer.
You have this belief that you are better than us.
You have this belief that this country is so very good
and we are so very bad.
You have this belief that you are so fair
and we are so very cruel.
It is all lies and false propaganda
to support this antagonistic and violent government!
Oh, violent?
Hey, we don't keep our people behind a wall with machine guns!
Who are you?
Who am I?
I'm the unsilent majority, big mouth!
Good! Yes, good! Insult us!
Is more typical rude behavior toward visiting foreigners.
But perhaps this simple defeat
of this little so-called champion
will be a perfect example of how pathetically weak
your society has become!
We go!
Rocky, over here.
Rocky, can you tell us about a...
Mrs. Balboa! Mrs. Balboa!
How do you feel about going to Russia?
Is your husband going to Moscow?
Mrs. Balboa, how does it feel to be part of such a controversial decision?
Mrs. Balboa!
Adrian! Adrian!
Mrs. Balboa, did Creed's death make up your husband's mind?
I don't know what you're talking about!
One more question! Why is he going at Christmas?
Was it his decision?
When will you be going to Russia?
Look, I'm not going to Russia. I don't know what you're talking about.
I don't know why you're here. I don't know what you people are doing here!
Mrs. Balboa! Was it his decision?
Rocky?
Yeah?
You all right?
Yeah. Fine.
Why'd you do it?
I just gotta do what I gotta do.
You don't have to do anything.
No, Adrian, I do, and...
I gotta leave this place, too.
So where are you going?
They said they're going to let me train in Russia, and...
I just want to go someplace where
I ain't gonna think about nothing except him.
Rocky, give it some time.
Don't do this. A lot of people live with hurt.
Adrian, a lot of people don't have a choice. I do.
And for that, you're willing to lose everything?
Adrian, this ain't everything.
This house, the cars, and all the stuff we got,
it ain't everything.
There's a lot more than this, Adrian.
Before, there were reasons to fight I could understand,
but I don't understand this.
Even if you win, what have you won? Apollo's still gone.
Why can't you change your thinking? Everybody else does!
'Cause I'm a fighter.
That's the way I'm made, Adrian.
That's what you married.
We can't change what we are.
Yes, you can.
You can't change anything, Adrian.
All we can do is just go with what we are.
You can't go with what you are.
Have you read the papers?
Do you know what everybody says?
It's suicide!
You've seen him. You know how strong he is.
You can't win!
Oh, Adrian.
Adrian always tells the truth.
No, maybe I can't win.
Maybe the only thing I can do
is just take everything he's got.
But to beat me,
he's going to have to kill me.
And to kill me,
he's gonna have to have the heart to stand in front of me.
And to do that, he's got to be willing to die himself.
I don't know if he's ready to do that.
I don't know.
We're not indestructible
Baby, better get that straight
I think it's unbelievable
How you give in to the hands of fate
Some things are worth fighting for
Some feelings never die
I'm not asking for another chance
I just wanna know why
There's no easy way out
There's no shortcut home
Giving in can't be wrong
I don't wanna pacify you
I don't wanna drag you down
But I'm feeling like a prisoner
Like a stranger in a no-name town
I see all the angry faces
Afraid that could be you and me
Talking about what might have been
I'm thinking about what it used to be
There's no easy way out
There's no shortcut home
Giving in can't be wrong
Baby, baby, we can shed this skin
We can know how we feel inside
Instead of going down an endless road
Not knowing if we're dead or alive
Some things are worth fighting for
Some feelings never die
I'm not asking for another chance
I just wanna know why
There's no easy way out
There's no shortcut home
Giving in, giving in can't be wrong
No, there's no easy way out
There's no easy way out
There's no shortcut home
There's no easy, no easy
No easy way out
There's no easy way out
There's no shortcut home
There's no easy, no easy
No easy way out
Be careful with those plaid ones. They belong to the boss.
Paulie, did you pack your toothbrush?
You know how tobacco stains your teeth.
If I've told you once, I've told you 1,000 times.
Hey, stop busting my chops.
Paulie.
I'm gonna have her wires tied when I get back.
When will you be back?
Oh, pretty soon.
Are you scared?
No.
Yes, you are. A little, maybe?
Well, wouldn't you be?
If a big, giant man wanted to beat me up,
I'd be real scared.
Well, the truth is, you know, sometimes
I do get a little scared, you know.
When I'm in that ring and I'm really getting hit on,
and my arms hurt so much I can't even lift 'em,
and I'm thinking, "God, I wish this guy would hit me on the chin
"so I don't feel nothing anymore. "
Then there's another side that comes out
that isn't so scared.
There's another side that, like,
wants to take more,
wants to go that one more round
because by going that one more round
when you don't think you can,
that's what makes all the difference in your life.
You know what I mean?
And will you remember one more thing?
Remember that Daddy thinks you're the best boy in the world.
And that Daddy loves you, no matter what?
I gotta go now.
You gonna take care of everything?
Okay.
And don't forget to feed your robot.
Bye, baby.
Good luck.
Thanks.
Come on! The meter's running!
Two worlds collide Rival nations
It's a primitive clash
Venting years of frustration
Bravely we hope against all hope
There is so much at stake
Seems our freedom's up against the ropes
Does the crowd understand?
Is it East versus West
Or man against man
Can any nation stand alone
In the burning heart
Just about to burst
There's a quest for answers An unquenchable thirst
What a horrendous flight.
This is Russia?
Don't look so tough, Rock.
Mr. Balboa.
We take you to quarters now.
Hey, when does the sun come up?
This is detrimental to my sinuses.
Weather changes hour to hour. Get used to it.
Get in the car now. We have very long trip.
Sounds like Dracula's cousin.
Come on, Paulie.
In the warrior's code there's no surrender
Though his body says stop
His spirit cries "Never!"
Deep in our soul a quiet ember
Knows it's you against you
It's the paradox that drives us all
It's a battle of wills
In the heat of attack
It's the passion that kills
The victory is yours alone
In the burning heart
Just about to burst
There's a quest for answers
An unquenchable thirst
In the darkest night
Rising like a spire
In the burning heart
The unmistakable fire
Like you request, yes?
You requested this dumb location?
Yeah.
Why? You planning to grow reindeer or something?
I just wanted to get away from things, you know?
The equipment you requested is in barn.
Who are they?
They?
They are assigned to you.
Official chaperones, yes?
Where you go, they go.
Oh, I have a bad dream here.
Paul, it's okay.
It's okay?
This is below human standards.
There's no antennas. You gotta complain!
We'll crack out here!
You have everything I have been instructed to provide.
We are finished, yes?
No sparring?
I don't think I need it anymore, Paulie.
No sparring, no TV, nothing?
How the heck is he supposed to train around here?
No TV. What about the Rose Bowl game?
No room service, I bet.
I hope they got my comics here.
What a depressing vacation.
God damn.
All right, you chipmunks,
are you ready to sing your song?
I'll say we are.
Christmas, Christmas time is here
Time for toys and time for cheer
We've been good, but we can't last
Checkmate, friend.
Yeah?
Hey, champ, can I come up?
Yeah, sure.
How you doing?
Pretty good.
Some kind of weather we're having up here, huh?
Yeah, it's pretty rough.
But for what you gotta do, it's good.
Toughen you up.
I guess so.
I know you're gonna have to do almost everything alone up here,
but you know I'll be with you.
Yeah, I know.
Apollo was like my son.
I raised him.
And when he died, part of me died.
But now you're the one.
You're the one that's gonna keep his spirit alive.
You're the one that's gonna make sure
that he didn't die for nothing.
Now, you're gonna have to go through hell,
worse than any nightmare that you ever dreamed.
But in the end, I know you'll be the one standing.
I'll try.
You know what you gotta do.
Do it.
Thanks, Duke.
I couldn't stay away anymore.
I missed you.
I'm with you, no matter what.
No matter what?
No matter what.
Silent darkness creeps into your soul
And removes the light of self-control
The cave that holds you captive has no doors
Burnin' with determination
To even up the score
Hearts on fire
Strong desire
Rages deep within
Hearts on fire
Fever's rising high
The moment of truth is here
No pain.
No pain. No pain.
Oh, yeah
Hearts on fire
Strong desire
Go on, pick it up.
Pick it up, come on.
Come on, push!
Come on! Come on! Push it up!
Drago!
Hearts on fire
Strong desire
Rages deep within
Drago!
Hello, everybody, and Merry Christmas from a very unusual place.
We're in Moscow, in the Soviet Union.
I'm Barry Tompkins, along with Al Bandiero,
and this promises to be the most-watched event in boxing history.
The Iron Horse, from America, Rocky Balboa.
Ivan Drago,
since that tragedy in Las Vegas and the death of Apollo Creed,
he's been re-nicknamed "Death from Above. "
Drago! Drago! Drago!
Drago! Drago!
And high above us, the general secretary of the Soviet
and other members of the Politburo
have now made their way to their seats
high above the ring here in Moscow.
Rocky, I know you're kinda busy just now,
but I want to tell you some things I never told you.
I know sometimes I act stupid and I say stupid things,
but you kept me around
when other people would have said, "Drop that bum. "
You give me respect.
You know, it's hard for me to say these kind of things,
because that ain't my way,
but if I could just unzip myself and step out and be someone else,
I'd want to be you.
You're all heart, Rock.
Thanks, Paulie.
Now, blast this guy's teeth out.
I'll try.
Right now, one of the fighters
is starting to make his way through this crowd and toward the ring.
Listen to this crowd!
We knew he wouldn't be popular,
but this borders on pure hatred!
Rocky's face, absolutely like stone.
He is the picture of concentration,
and the booing crowd here does not seem to bother him one bit.
The champ has a look tonight that can burn through lead.
It seems that the booing crowd has absolutely no effect on the man.
His concentration seems to be like stone.
That's my dad!
We know.
What do you think we are, nerds?
Listen to this crowd. It sounds insane.
And now the entrance of the Russian national champion,
Ivan Drago, a man with an entire country in his corner.
Look at the expression on the face of Ivan Drago.
He seems impervious to this madness of the crowd.
He's like a volcano just waiting to erupt.
The Russian champion
is amazingly cool, ladies and gentlemen,
as he acknowledges his premier.
As I say, I would like to point out again,
this is a non-sanctioned fight.
This is not for the title.
The American Boxing Commission have not sanctioned this bout.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...Rocky Balboa!
It's unbelievable.
I have never, in all my years of reporting,
seen such a hostile crowd.
...Ivan Drago!
They are screaming and roaring for their champion.
The two men are walking toward the center of the ring.
It's an unbelievable sight to see.
They're toe to toe.
The Russian towers above the American.
It's a true case of David and Goliath here.
It's unbelievable, the condition of both men,
but the Russian champion...
I must break you.
Remember what I said back there about wanting to be you?
Yeah.
Forget it.
Thanks, Paul.
Drago! Drago!
Take it straight to him, now.
Take it straight to him and be a rock for me, you understand?
Be a rock for me! Be strong!
All right? Now take it to him! No pain!
No pain. No pain.
All right, run to him!
There's the bell for the opening round,
and Rocky Balboa comes out to the center of the ring.
But the Russian, right back into Balboa's corner now.
Just grab him! Grab him! Grab him!
Come on! Get out of there!
Come on, spit him out! Let's go, Rock!
Get out of there!
Balboa gets out of the corner now,
and now once more it is Drago backing Rocky Balboa up with a jab,
and Balboa is not staying on balance because of the long jab of the Russian.
Brace yourself! Brace yourself!
Come on, get up! Hands up!
Charge him! Now!
He can't seem to touch the Russian.
Rocky pounding away at the midsection of the Russian,
and he's just hitting with everything he's got.
And Drago just smiled at him.
There you go! Keep jabbing away!
Chop him down! Chop him down!
Stick it to him! Now, Rocky!
Come on, Rock!
Rocky Balboa is in serious trouble.
They might have to stop this one before somebody gets killed.
Reach and grab him! Reach and grab him!
He's pounding away at the American.
Rocky's hurt.
He woke the sleeping giant, and now he's paying the price.
A right hand from Drago sends Rocky Balboa 15 feet across the ring!
And the champ is down!
Get up!
Come on, get up!
Back up! Back up!
Drago continuing to punish Rocky Balboa.
He just will not let him out of that corner,
and Rocky Balboa is just trying to get through this first round.
The Russian just threw Rocky Balboa into his own corner like a rag doll.
What a tough first three minutes for Rocky Balboa.
He's not only fighting what appears to be an invincible opponent,
he's also fighting a very hostile crowd
and the Russian premier and most of the Politburo looking on.
All right, what's happening out there?
He's winning.
I see three of him out there.
Hit the one in the middle.
Right! Hit the one in the middle.
Yeah. Okay.
Take his heart. You hurt him, you'll take his heart.
No pain. No pain.
No pain. Take his heart.
Keep working! Keep working!
There's the bell for round two.
It's been a one-sided fight so far.
It'll take more than luck for Rocky to survive this round.
Rocky's been hit with bombs.
Slip him a hook, Rock! Slip him a hook!
Rocky Balboa trying to stay in the middle of the ring
against the big Russian.
Move down! That a baby!
Do what you gotta do!
Stay with him!
Go for it! Go for it!
For all intents, Rocky Balboa should be all finished tonight,
but he's fighting back ferociously.
Rocky!
Up, Rock! Get up!
And Balboa goes down again from a right hand,
bounces right back up.
He's gettin' killed out there.
Rocky Balboa has taken Ivan Drago's best punches so far.
He's cut and he's bleeding, but he's on his feet and he's on the run.
Hold on! Hold on!
Drago! Drago!
He's cut! He's cut!
The Russian's cut, and it's a bad cut,
and now it's Rocky Balboa coming after Ivan Drago!
You got him! You got him! Yes!
Incredible! Go get him!
Go! Go!
And now the Russian wants to go on!
He grabs Rocky Balboa by the throat.
Balboa picking up the Russian
and throws him to the ground like a wrestler.
It's a gutter war, no holds barred in Moscow.
Rocky may be on the receiving end so far, but he's here to fight.
This is shaping up to be a personal war,
and right now it's anybody's boxing match.
You're doing good, Rocky. Couldn't do better myself.
Thanks.
You got him hurt bad. Yeah?
Now he's worried.
You cut him! You hurt him!
You see? You see? He's not a machine! He's a man!
You want it more than he does. No pain.
No pain. No pain.
Okay, take it to him! Take it to him! Take it to him!
Get up!
Balboa's down!
It's all right.
And a good right hand by Rocky Balboa!
Come on, come on!
Rocky's got him now!
You're doing fine. You're doing great.
You've come a mighty long way, baby.
Crush him! Now!
That's it! Keep going!
Go, go!
Punch him! Punch him!
Come on!
A few cheers now for Rocky Balboa!
Suddenly, Moscow is pro-Rocky!
No pain. No pain.
Keep taking it to him, you understand?
Take his heart. No pain.
I'll tell you, Al, this place is ready to explode.
Lethal punch after punch! Amazing willpower!
Neither man backing off,
and Rocky Balboa's determination
is actually beginning to win over what was once a hostile crowd.
This is incredible!
What round is it?
Fifteen. One more round.
There's no stopping us now. This is our round.
Rocky! Rocky!
Don't stop it now! We start, and we don't stop!
All your strength, all your power, all your love,
everything you've got!
Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
Rocky! Rocky!
To win, you've got to knock him out.
You've got to punch and punch till you can't punch no more.
This is your whole life here.
All right, knock him out, Rocky.
Do it now! Now!
There's the bell. The war is on.
This is the last round...
To the end.
Which one of these magnificent fighters
will be standing at the end of this round?
Drago snaps out a stiff jab, and another.
Come on.
Another!
Rocky taking punishment, trying to get inside.
He's completely exhausted.
Come on, Rock!
What are you waiting for?
Fight!
Rocky! Rocky!
Hit him! Hit him!
Come on! Come on, fight!
Rocky! Rocky!
Come on, fight!
Come on!
Balboa is chopping the Russian down!
Don't stop, Rock! Don't stop!
Combinations of punches on the Russian,
and Drago throws a hard right hand,
which stuns Rocky Balboa.
Don't go down! Don't go down!
You can forget technique, forget strategy,
this is just a street fight.
It's a question of who wants it most.
What is he doing? He's winning.
To the body! To the body!
Come on!
Rocko! Rocko, break his head!
Rocko, knock his head off!
Come on! Finish him!
Don't stop, Rock!
Yeah! Don't stop! This is incredible!
You're gonna do it!
Four!
Six!
Rocky Balboa has done the impossible,
and these people love it!
It is absolute pandemonium.
More than ever, Rocky has proven himself a true champion!
Rocky! Rocky!
...Rocky Balboa!
Thank you.
I came here tonight,
and I didn't know what to expect.
I seen a lot of people hatin' me,
and I didn't know what to feel about that,
so I guess I didn't like you much none either.
During this fight,
I seen a lot of changing.
The way you felt about me,
and the way I felt about you.
In here, there were two guys killing each other,
but I guess that's better than 20 million.
So, what I'm trying to say is
that if I can change
And you can change,
everybody can change!
I just want to say one thing to my kid,
who should be home sleeping.
Merry Christmas, kid!
I love you!
Silent darkness creeps into your soul
And removes the light of self-control
The cave that holds you captive has no doors
Burnin' with determination
To even up the score
Hearts on fire
Strong desire
Rages deep within
Hearts on fire
Fever's risin' high
The moment of truth draws near
Time will not allow you to stand still, no
Silence breaks the heart and bends the will
And things that give deep passions are your sword
Rules and regulations have no meaning anymore
Hearts on fire
Strong desire
Rages deep within
Hearts on fire
Fever's risin' high
The moment of truth is here
Oh
Is here
Oh, yeah
Hearts on fire
Strong desire
Rages deep within