Savree maranun verabonun verobotay.
Barooch ata adony elohaynou melech aholam.
Borah pree hagafan.
Asher kideshano bemitzvotaiv...
verazha banou veshabat kodsho...
behava hencheel lanoe.
Zecaron lemase berashit ke hoe yome...
techelah lemekray kodesh...
zecher letziat mizraim.
Kee banoe bacharta veotano kedashta mekol hameem.
Veshabat kodsho behavat razone.
Henchaltanoe.
Barooch ata adony mekadesh hasabat.
- Name? - Horowitz, Salomon.
[ Indistinct Talking, Various Languages ]
Schneider, Sarah. Birnbaum, Olga?
[ Children Crying, Indistinct Talking ]
Over there. Over there! Kommen Sie Doch.
- Isak Hudes. - Hudes, Isak.
Zucker, Helena.
Hirsch, Salomon? Mandel, Maria. Hirsch, Salomon.
- Hauptman, Chaim! - Weisman! Weisman, Marcus!
- Feber, Ludwig! - Feber, Ludwig.
Elsa Bauman.
-Josef Klein. - Klein.
- Davidowich, Ignacy. - Paula Biffer. - Nadel, Rachela.
Steiner, Gertruda. Steiner, Hilda.
##
####
Jerzy, you know who that man is? I don't know.
Let's get together, please.
Smile. Good.
Yes, sir.
Bring them over a round of drinks.
Very good, sir. And who shall I say th-they are from?
You can say they are from me.
From the gentleman. Where?
Do you know him?
Find out who he is.
Yes, sir.
Agnieszka, I would give anything...
to hear you sing tonight.
But I know you won't.
You embarrass me.
What's he doing?
Stay here.
How are you doing?
You'd leave a woman alone at the table in a place like this?
Sweetheart, you're the picture of loneliness.
Oh.
Mmm, what a lovely fragrance. You are breaking my heart.
An extra chair, please. Vodka for my friend.
And for the lady? Pernod.
# Im Grunewald, im Grunewald ist Holzauktion #
[ Men Laughing, Whistling ] # Ist Holzauktion #
Come to the table, girls! Drink with us! # Ist Holzauktion #
# Links um die Ecke 'rum, rechts um die Ecke 'rum #
# Ueberall ist heute Holzauktion #
Come to us! Marry us!
# Der ganze Klafter Suessholz kostet 'nen Taler #
# 'Nen Taler, 'nen Taler #
# 'Nen Taler-- ##
Thank you. I'll tell you what I mean by cooperative.
Two days after the law is passed that allJews have to wear the star,
the Jewish tailors are turning them out by the gross...
in a variety of fabrics at three zloty each.
Tell me about your cellar wines.
I have an excellent German Riesling. 1937. Mmm, French.
A Bordeaux. Chateau Latour, '28, '29? No, I'm sorry.
It's as if they have no idea what kind of law it is.
As if it's the emblem of a riding club.
A Margaux, '29? No, no, we don't have that.
Burgundy then? A Romanee-Conti, '37? Yes.
It's human nature. ''We'll do this to avoid that.''
That's what they have done since thousands of years.
It's what they do. They weather the storm.
But this storm is different. This is not the Romans. This storm is the SS.
## Wem Gott will rechte Gunst erweisen ##
##Den schickt er in die weite Welt ##
##Faleri, Falera ##
##Faleri Falera-ha ha ha ##
##Den schickt er in die weite Welt ##
Martin?
Yes, sir.
Who is that man?
That-- That's Oskar Schindler!
##Faleri Falera-ha ha ha ##
##Den schickt er in die weite Welt ##
##Faleri, Falera ##
##Den schickt er in die weite Welt ####
To Krakow!
##
####
An alleJuden!
Ab sofort ist es allen Juden untersagt...
Fleisch aufkoscher Art zuzubereiten.
Meldung an alleJuden. Ab sofort--
Rabbi-- Private property cannot be confiscated.
How long are the schools going to be closed? I do not know.
Article 47: Pillage is formally prohibited. You don't know anything!
I am familiar with the Hague Convention. Religious--
They come into our house and tell us we don't live there anymore.
It now belongs to a certain SS officer.
Please. I only know what they tell me.
And what they tell me changes from day to day.
Aren't you supposed to be able to help?
I mean, what if I just took this thing off?
What are they going to do about it? They will shoot you.
Why don't you stop this silly talk? Itzhak Stern!
I'm looking for Itzhak Stern.
Are you Itzhak Stern or not?
I am. Where can we talk?
There's a company you did the books for on Lipowa Street.
Made what? Pots and pans?
By law, I have to tell you, sir, I'm a Jew.
Well, I'm a German. So there we are.
A good company, you think? Modestly successful.
I know nothing about enamelware. Do you?
I was just the accountant.
Simple engineering though, wouldn't you think?
Change the machines around, whatever you do,
you could make other things, couldn't you?
Field kits, mess kits. Army contracts.
Once the war ends, forget it, but for now it's great.
You can make a fortune, don't you think?
I think most people right now have other priorities.
Like what?
I'm sure you'll do just fine once you get the contracts.
In fact, the worse things get, the better you'll do.
Oh, well, I can get the signatures I need. That's the easy part.
Finding the money to buy the company, that's hard.
You don't have any money?
Not that kind of money. You know anybody?
Jews, yeah.
Investors. You must have contacts...
in the Jewish business community working here.
What community? Jews can no longer own businesses.
That's why this one's in receivership. But they wouldn't own it.
I'd own it. I'd pay them back in product-- pots and pans.
Pots and pans. Something they can use.
Something they can feel in their hands.
They can trade it on the black market, do whatever they want.
Everybody's happy.
If you want, you could run the company for me.
Let me understand.
They'd put up all the money, I'd do all the work.
What, if you don't mind my asking, would you do?
I'd make sure it's known the company's in business.
I'd see that it had a certain panache.
That's what I'm good at, not the work. Not the work.
The presentation.
I'm sure I don't know anybody who'll be interested in this.
Well, they should be, Itzhak Stern.
Tell them they should be.
Achtung! Achtung!
An alleJuden... Ab sofort ist es verboten--
Vere dignum et justum est, aequum et salutare,
nos tibi semper et ubique gratias agere,
Domine Sancte, Pater Omnipotens, Aeterne Deus.
I've got a client who'll sell marks for zloty at 2.45 to 1.
Wool, mink collar. It's a nice coat.
She'll trade it for ration coupons.
Wicks, for lamps. You have a truckload of wicks?
What am I going to do with a truckload of wicks? Nine by 12, nine by 14.
I don't know. Big, beautiful, Persian.
Lumen aeternum mundo effudit--
Psst. What?
You don't recognize this? It's shoe polish.
In metal containers? You asked for shoe polish.
In metal containers. This is glass. In metal containers.
It's not what I asked for. What's the difference?
What's the difference? What's the difference?
Shh! My client sold it to his client,
who sold it to the German Army.
Only by the time it got there, because of the freezing cold, it broke. All 10,000 units.
Mmm, ooh, ooh, ooh. This is not my problem.
This is not his problem. This is not your problem?
This is not my problem. All right.
The German Army wants to find out where it came from.
I am going to make sure they find out. Now it's your problem.
You be quiet!
Metal containers.
Hello.
Pardon me for interfering, but that's a nice shirt.
Nice shirt.
Do you know where I can find a nice shirt like that?
...laudare, benedicere et predicare.
Like this?
It's illegal to buy or sell anything on the street.
We don't do that. We're here to pray.
Jesum Christum Dominum Nostrum--
Do you have any idea how much a shirt like this costs? Nice things cost money.
...adorant Dominationes, tremunt Potestates.
Coeli coelorumque virtutes ac Beata Seraphim...
socia exultatione concelebrant--
How many?
I'm going to need some other things, too, as things come up.
This won't be a problem. From time to time.
Achtung! Achtung!
- Name? Adresse? - Formular ausfuellen!
Weiter, weiter! Nicht draengeln!
Kommen Sie hierher! Stellen Sie sich doch an!
Achtung, achtung! AlleJuden sind verpflichtet...
im abgesonderten juedischen Bezirk zu wohnen.
Nichteinhaltung der Meldepflicht bei der Einwohnerbehoerde...
verstoesst gegen das Edikt 44l91 und fuehrt zur Anzeige...
beim Militaergericht.
This is obviously the right place. How are you doing? Herr Schindler.
Good-bye,Jews! Good-bye,Jews!
Good-bye,Jews!
This iz the vechteka, Moyshe. Ojciec.
Nyne, this kan neash zyane.
[ Baby Crying, Woman Singing Polish Lullaby ] Oh, my God.
Oy, God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
It could not be better.
It could be worse. How? Tell me.
How on earth could it possibly be worse?
Dzien dobry.
Dzien dobry. Dzien dobry.
Hey, Goldberg. Poldek.
What's this? Uh, the Judenrat has its own police now.
You don't say. Ordnungsdienst.
I'm a policeman now, could you believe it? It's hard to believe.
Oh, no, it's not hard to believe.
It's a good racket, Poldek. The only racket here.
Look, maybe I could put in a good word for you with my superiors.
Your superiors? Come on, they are not as bad as everyone says.
Well, they're worse than everyone says, but it's a lot of money.
A lot of money.
Give me my housing assignment.
Come on. You look funny in that hat, Goldberg.
You look like a clown, you know?
He's a very important man.
Just give him two minutes of your time.
Since when did time cost money? Just sit down and listen.
Please. Sir?
For each thousand you invest, I will repay you with...
Two hundred. 200 kilos of enamelware a month,
to begin in July and to continue for one year.
After which time, we're even. That's it. It's very simple.
Not good enough. It's not good enough.
Not good enough?
Look where you're living. Look where you've been put. ''Not good enough.''
A couple of months ago you'd be right, not anymore.
Money's still money.
No, it is not.
That's why we're here.
Trade goods-- that's the only currency...
that'll be worth anything in the ghetto.
Things have changed, my friend.
Did I call this meeting?
You told Mr. Stern you wanted to speak to me.
I'm here. I've made you a fair offer.
Fair would be a percentage in the company.
Forget the whole thing.
Get out.
How do we know that you will do what you say?
Because I said I would.
You want a contract? To be upheld by what court?
I said what I'll do. That's our contract.
...mielismy racje.
Piec, szesc, siedem...
osiem, dziewiec.
The standard SS rate for Jewish skilled labor is seven marks a day,
five for unskilled and women.
This is what you pay the Reich Economic Office.
the Jews themselves receive nothing.
Poles you pay wages. Generally, they get a little more.
Are you listening? What was that about the SS?
The rate? The what?
the Jewish worker's salary-- you pay it directly to the SS, not to the worker.
He gets nothing. But it's less.
It's less than what I would pay a Pole. It's less.
That's the point I'm trying to make.
Poles cost more.
Why should I hire Poles?
An enamelware factory over at, uh, Lipowa Street.
It, uh, it, um-- It's owned by a German.
But it's outside the ghetto, so you can barter for extra goods--
for eggs, I don't know what you need--
with the Polish workers. You can't get it here.
Also, he's asking for ten healthy women for the-- I am healthy.
Bring your sister, okay?
[ Shouting Orders In German And Polish ]
Chodz.
You need to convince them you have a trade, something valuable to the war effort.
Like what? What if you don't? I'm a musician.
Your name goes on a list. And they put you on trucks--
No, no, no, that's not true. You're a musician?
Yeah. I'd find a good hiding place if I were you.
I'm not going to hide like some animal. There are places to hide.
Der Naechste!
I'm a graduate of the University of Lwow.
I used to work at the hydroelectric station in Roznow--
Blauschein.
I'm gonna get the necessary papers because this card is no good anymore.
You can stay in this line all day, you'll still get one of these.
They are no good. You'll have to leave the line now,
then you'll get a blue card, a Blauschein, to say that you are an essential worker.
I'll get these papers for you at Pankiewicz.
Pharmacist. Just there, look.
Guess who is here?
Poldek! Enjoying the weather, Poldek?
Enjoying the lines? Need some shoe polish?
In a metal container maybe?
Not essential? I think you misunderstand the meaning of the word.
No Blauschein, sir. Stand over there.
Move. Next!
What do you mean, ''Not essential''?
I teach history and literature. Since when is not essential?
He's a metal polisher.
It was not right? It's very good. He's 53 years old.
It's too new. Mmm. Thank you.
You're crazy. You left it in your drawer.
How many times have I told you?
Your work certificate you keep in your pocket at all times.
And you leave everything in your drawer.
How many times I've told you?
I'm a metal polisher.
Take the round sheet of tin,
dip it in soap emulsion.
Then place it centrally in the press.
We obtain the soup pot. The soup pot.
Soup pot.
Grosz, Mrs. Grosz, stay together.
Sir, I have ten work permits here for the Deutsche Emailwarenfabrik,
cosigned by Mr. Bankier and myself.
If it's carbonized, clean it with a file.
But don't touch both the electrodes at the same time.
You'll get electrocuted. Here, have a try.
Roll the metal under the press,
but be very careful unless you want your fingers...
to become part of the teapot.
Occupation? I'm a writer. I play the flute.
But Moses is a skilled metalworker.
He can make tin pots. He can make tanks.
He can make whatever Mr. Schindler asks.
He's highly skilled. Give him your card.
Moses, give him your card.
Now, dip the basin with the tongs...
into the enamel solution.
And after swiveling it around, carefully place it aside to drip dry.
And whatever he asks you, allow me just to represent you and speak for you.
Don't say a word.
Filing, billing, keeping track of my appointments, shorthand.
Typing, obviously. How is your typing? Uh, all right.
Please.
[ Typing Slowly, Bell Rings ]
[ Typing Extremely Slow ]
You need a secretary. Pick one.
I don't know how. They're all so... qualified.
You have to choose.
Prosze sie ladnie usmiechac. Big smile. Big smile.
Uwaga.
####
If you would, look after my guest.
Um, boxed teas are good. Coffiee, pate, um...
kielbasa sausage, cheeses, Beluga caviar. Yes.
And, of course, who could live without German cigarettes?
Get me as many as you can find.
And some more fresh fruit.
The real rarities-- oranges, lemons, pineapples.
I need several boxes of Cuban cigars. The best. Yes.
And dark, unsweetened chocolate. Not in the shape ofladyfigers, the chunk chocolate.
Yes. Big as my hand, you sample at wine tastings.
We're going to need lots of cognac. The best, Hennessy.
Dom Perignon champagne. Um, get L 'espadon sardines...
and, oh, try to find nylon stockings.
It is my distinct pleasure to announce...
the fully operational status of Deutsche Email Fabrik...
Patrzjakies szmaty!
manufacturers of superior enamelware crockery...
expressly designed and crafted for military use.
Utilizing only the most modern equipment,
D.E.F. 's staffi of highly-skilled and experienced artisans and journeymen...
deliver a product of unparalleled quality,
enabling me to proffier, with absolute con ence and pride,
a full line of field and kitchenware...
unsurpassable in all respects by my competitors.
See attached list and available colors.
Anticipating the enclosed bids will meet with your approval.
Made in Havana, Cuba. Looking forward to a long and mutually prosperous association.
Look at this. I extend to you in advance my sincerest gratitude...
and very best regards. Oskar Schindler.
Yeah, I need 700 gross from here for next Thursday.
Nine hundred-- No, make it ten for Wednesday.
All this stuff here goes to Madritsch's factory on Tuesday of next week.
My father was fond of saying, ''You need three things in life
''a good doctor, a forgiving priest...
and a clever accountant. ''
The first two... I've never had much use for.
But the third--
Just pretend, for Christ's sake.
Is that all?
I'm trying to thank you.
I'm saying I couldn't have done this without you.
The usual thing would be to acknowledge my gratitude.
It would also, by the way, be the courteous thing.
You're welcome.
Get out of here.
Klonowska, who is it?
She's so embarrassed. Look at her.
You know something? You would like her.
Oskar, please. What?
I don't have to like her... just because you do. You would, though.
It doesn't work that way.
You've done well here.
You look wonderful.
Be careful of the step, miss. Mrs. Schindler, Marek.
##
It's not a charade, all this? How could it be a charade?
The clothes, the car, the apartment. Wait a minute.
Take a guess how many people are on my payroll. Oskar.
My father, at the height of his success, had 50. I've got 3 50.
3 50 workers on the factory floor, with one purpose.
To make pots and pans?
To make money. For me.
Does anyone ask about me?
Back home? Everybody.
All the time.
Hmm.
They won't soon forget the name Schindler here, I can tell you that.
''Oskar Schindler,'' they'll say.
''Everybody remembers him.
''He did something extraordinary.
''He did something no one else did.
''He came here with nothing--
''a suitcase--
''and built a bankrupt company into a major manufactory.
''And left with a steamer trunk--
''Two steamer trunks full of money,
all the riches of the world.''
Hmm.
It's comforting to see that nothing's changed.
You're wrong, Emilie.
There's no way I could have known this before,
but there was always something missing.
In every business I tried, I can see now, it wasn't me that failed.
Something was missing.
Even if I'd known what it was, there's nothing I could have done about it...
because you can't create this thing.
And it makes all the difference in the world between success and failure.
Luck?
War.
Should I stay?
It's a beautiful city.
I asked you if I should stay.
It's up to you.
Promise me, Oskar, no doorman or maitre d' will ever presume...
I'm anyone other than Mrs. Schindler, and I'll stay.
Good-bye, darling.
I could try to read this or I could eat my lunch while it's still hot.
We're doing well?
Yes. Better this month than last?
Yes. Any reason to think next month will be worse?
The war could end.
What? There is a machinist outside...
who'd like to thank you personally for giving him a job.
Every day he comes. He's very grateful. It'll just take a minute.
Mr. Lowenstein?
I want to thank you, sir,
for giving me the opportunity to work.
You're welcome. I'm sure you're doing a great job.
The SS beat me up. They would have killed me,
but I am essential to the war effort, thanks to you.
That's great.
I work hard for you.
I'm sure you do. I'll continue to work hard for you.
That's great. Thanks.
God bless you, sir. All right.
You are a good man.
He saved my life. Yes, he did.
God bless him. Yeah. Come on.
God bless you.
I'm sorry, Herr Direktor, but you're running very late.
This is for the Obersturmbannfuehrer, sir.
And this is for his niece, Greta. It's her birthday.
Greta as in Garbo. By the way, don't ever do that to me again.
Go. Go, go, drive! Don't bow.
Did you happen to notice that that man had one arm? What? Did he?
What's his use? Very useful.
How? Very useful! Success!
##Achrar kach loe nedah ##
Besen und Schaufeln werden ausgeladen...
jeder nimmt sich eine und dann wird die Strasse gereinigt.
We'll be late for work.
You shouldn't think of them as yours, Oskar.
You need to understand that some of the officers here...
don't give a damn about production.
To them, it's a matter of, um, national priority...
that Jews be made to shovel snow.
It's got nothing to do with reality, Oskar.
You know it and I know it.
Jews shoveling snow--
It's got a, um, ritual significance.
Come with me. I am an essential worker.
Essential worker? Yes.
I work for Oskar Schindler. Essential worker for Oskar Schindler.
A one-armed Jew? Twice as useless! Yes, yes.
I lost a day of production, Rolf.
I work for Oskar Schindler.
Danka, look at the snow. Look at the snow. Look at the snow!
I lost a worker. I expect to be compensated.
File a grievance with the Economic Office. It's your right.
Would it do any good? Of course not.
A big shot from the SS Budget and Construction Office came to lunch...
and he told us that to believe the Jewish skilled worker had a place...
in Reich economics was a treasonable idea.
A one-armed machinist, Oskar?
He was a metal press operator.
Quite skilled.
Herr Direktor?
Shit. I don't believe it.
Stern, is that you?
No, it's Poldek. It's about Stern.
Leave your luggage on the platform.
Clearly label it.
Given name first, then your surname.
Do not bring your baggage with you.
It will follow you later.
Leave your luggage on the platform.
Clearly label it.
Lassen Sie Ihr Gepaeck am Bahnsteig.
Stern?
He's on the list. He is?
Well, let's find him. I'm sorry. You can't have him.
He's on the list. If he were an essential worker, he would not be on the list.
I'm talking to a clerk. What is your name?
Sir, the list is correct. I didn't ask you about the list.
I asked you your name. Klaus Tauber.
Tauber.
Hauptscharfuehrer, this gentleman thinks a mistake's been made.
My plant manager is somewhere on this train.
If it leaves with him on it, it'll disrupt production...
and the Armaments Board will want to know why.
Achtung, dieser Zug faehrt jetzt ab.
Is he on the list? Yes, sir. Itzhak Stern.
Well, the list is correct, sir. There is nothing I can do.
What is your name? Close and secure all doors.
My name? My name is Kunder. This train is now leaving.
Kunder. Hauptscharfuehrer Kunder.
K-U-N-D-E-R. And what's yours?
Schindler. S-C-H-I-N-D-L-E-R.
Gentlemen, thank you very much.
I think I can guarantee you you'll both be in...
Southern Russia before the end of the month. Good day.
Zamykac dokladnie drzwi. Dokladnie zamykac drzwi.
Stern!
Stern! Stern!
Itzhak Stern!
Stern! Itzhak Stern!
Stern! Stern! Itzhak Stern!
Stern!
Sir?
Stern! Herr Direktor.
My apologies.
Stop the train! He's here! I apologize.
- Stop the train! - Stop the train! Stop it!
Sign here. Initial there.
Makes no difference to us, you understand. This one, that one.
It's the inconvenience to the list.
It's the paperwork. I somehow left my work card at home.
I tried to explain them it was a mistake, but--
I'm sorry, it was stupid! What if I got here five minutes later?
Then where would I be?
Shechel.
Sacrean, sacrean end tzukeer.
Tzukeer end sacrean.
I woke up from a dream this morning.
I was broke and sharing a room with 12 people I didn't know,
only to discover I was broke and sharing a room with 12 people I didn't know.
You laugh about it? I have to laugh.
You are living behind walls.
The walls I can deal with. It's the restrictions to my life I'm tired of.
Those walls keep them out. That's all I care about.
I like it here. There's a kind of, I don't know,
ancestral squalor to it all.
You are a slave to these people. No one envies us anymore.
I'm smart. Oh, yes, you're smart.
You're a real genius. You had your chance.
Today, today I actually found time to organize a thought.
I can't remember the last time I did that.
When's the last time we did this?
When's the last time we stood around and talked?
No one ordered me onto a truck today.
No one took my business away from me.
You don't really have a business to take.
There's nowhere down from here.
This is it. This is the bottom.
The ghetto is... liberty.
This street divides the ghetto just about in half.
Right side, Ghetto A: civil employees,
industrial workers and so on.
Left side, Ghetto B: surplus labor,
the elderly and infirm mostly.
Which is where you'll want to start, huh?
Do you have any questions, sir?
Ja, why is the top down? I'm fucking freezing.
We expect a labor force of 25,000 to 30,000.
Segregated, of course. The men in the barracks near the quarry.
The women on the other side of the wire.
My place is where? There, sir.
There? You call that a villa? Yes, the villa.
Their synagogue, can you see it? That's not a villa.
We're planning to turn it into the camp stables. It's a house.
What's that over there?
Kindergarten. Fifty-one.
And we have a dentist, shoemaker, practical physicians.
There they are, sir.
Hmm.
One of you is, uh, a very lucky girl.
There is an opening for a job,
away from all this... backbreaking work,
at my new villa.
Uh, which of you has...
domestic experience?
Ja, on second thought, I don't really want someone else's maid.
All those annoying habits I have to undo.
I don't want to give you my cold.
Uh, what's your name?
Helen Hirsch. What?
Helen Hirsch.
What? I can't hear. Helen Hirsch.
Ja. Take it all down!
To work!
Take it down! It is not safe!
She says the foundation was poured wrong. She's got to take it down.
I told her it's the barracks, not the fucking Hotel Europa.
Fucking Jew bitch engineer. You fucking bitch!
Herr Kommandant. The entire foundation...
has to be torn down and repoured.
If not, there will be at least a subsidence...
at the southern end of the barracks.
Subsidence, and then collapse.
And you are an engineer? Yes.
My name is Diana Reiter. I'm a graduate...
of Civil Engineering from the University of Milan.
Ah, an educated Jew, like Karl Marx himself.
Unterscharfuehrer! Jawohl?
Shoot her. What?
Herr Kommandant, I'm only trying to do my job.
Ja, I'm doing mine.
But, sir, she's foreman of construction.
We are not going to have arguments with these people.
Okay.
No. Shoot her here, on my authority.
It will take more than that.
I'm sure you're right.
Take it down, repour it, rebuild it. Like she said.
We have more to see, but we have only one more hour of light.
##
Today is history.
Today will be remembered.
Years from now, the young will ask with wonder...
about this day.
Today is history, and you are part of it.
Six hundred years ago...
## [ Singing Morning Prayer]
when elsewhere they were footing the blame for the Black Death, Kazimierz the Great, so-called,
##Ke laolam chasedo ## told the Jews they could come to Krakow.
Chaja, bread. They came.
Not that fat. No, less. They trundled their belongings into the city.
Yes, a bit less. They settled.
They took hold. They prospered...
in business, science, education, the arts.
They came here with nothing.
#### Nothing.
And they flourished.
For six centuries there has been a Jewish Krakow.
Think about that.
By this evening,
those six centuries are a rumor.
They never happened.
Today is history.
Absitzen und in Zweierreihen antreten!
Kameraden! Schneller!
[ Whistle Blowing, Indistinct Shouting ]
I think we will start... with Ghetto B.
Hopp, hopp, hopp, hopp!
All right? Start from both sides?
I would like you to start there. The right side?
The right side, yeah. And then move around. Okay.
Beschriften Sie es deutlich. Es wird Ihnen nachgeschickt.
Lassen Sie Ihr Gepaeck stehen.
Beschriften Sie es deutlich.
Es wird Ihnen nachgeschickt.
Aufmachen! Lakoom.
Loe ani loe yodahat olay kaday lehachnese at hayladeem mitachat la shoolchan.
Mitacht la meeta. Bohow.
Hopp, hopp, hopp, hopp!
[ Soldiers Shouting In German ]
'Runterkommen!
[ Soldiers Shouting, Banging On Doors ]
'Rauskommen,Juden!
Ziehen Sie sich warm an! Kommen Sie 'raus!
Na Platz!
Gold, Chaim! Platz Chodi.
Gold, Chaim! Yes, Chaim Gold.
Shoot him.
Nie zabijaj! Nie zabijaj!
Ziehen Sie warme Kleidung an und begeben Sie sich zum Platz--
Keine Koffier! Keine Koffier!
Gehen Sie durch! Keine Koffier! Keine Koffier!
Hey, little boy. Wie alt bist du, huh?
Na, wie hiesst du? Wie heisst du, huh?
Keine Koffier, hab'ich gesagt!
Packt keine Koffier! Keine Koffier!
'Rueber zum Platz Chodi! Koffier hierlassen!
Blauschein. Platz Chodi!
Was soll der Koffier hier?
Alles 'rueber zum Platz Chodi!
We're getting out through the sewers.
I have to check if they're clear.
Mila, pack some things. Nothing bigger than this. I can't go in the sewers.
I told you I won't go in the sewers.
You can go. Yes, you can.
I won't go in the sewers.
Move! Over there! Over there! Move!
Your card,Jew!
Deine Papiere, Jude!
Deine Papiere,Jude!
That line.
Deine Karte!
Ich geh'nicht 'rauf wegen Deiner verdammten Karte!
Deine Scheisskarte!
[ Woman Wailing In German ]
Was soll denn die Scheisse? Bist du denn verrueckt geworden?
Mit diesem Scheissgewehr haettest du mich erschiessen koennen!
Du hast so nah an mir vorbeigeschossen!
Was heisst hier Entschuldigung. Du bist wohl verrueckt geworden!
Zurueckbleiben! Zurueckbleiben!
Nicht sprechen, nicht sprechen! Einfach zu den Lastwagen gehen!
Weiterlaufen! Weiterlaufen! Nicht sprechen!
Komm her, du Judensau!
Bleib stehen, hab'ich gesagt. Bleib stehen!
[ Whispering In Polish ]
Chodzcie tu szybko!
[ Chattering, Baby Crying ]
[ Whistle Blowing, Soldiers Shouting ]
She's good as dead. Leave her.
Give me a moment. Just let me bring her inside.
[ Man Speaking German Over Loudspeaker ]
You can join her... or join the line.
[ Soldiers Shouting, Whistles Blowing ]
Women to the left! Wilhelm! Rose!
Men to right. Women to the left.
Women to the left. Let me go! I won't leave my husband!
Women to the left, and men to the right. Promise me, be safe.
Your government is in the wrong country!
[ Shouting, Wailing Continue ]
Mama! Mama!
[ Dogs Barking, Soldiers Shouting ]
Mila!
Oh, God, Danka!
You have a Blauschein. Blauschein doesn't matter anymore.
They are cleaning out the ghetto. There's not enough room for you.
What are you talking about? We tried it before. There's more than enough room.
- I changed my mind! - Mama!
Look at the space in there. Now look at me. You are just scared.
I can fit the girl, but not you.
- Mama, I'm coming out! - Stay where you are.
I'd rather you be here than who knows where.
Mama!
[ Soldiers Shouting In German ]
Herr Kommandant!
Very good saluting.
I respectfully report I've been given orders to clear the bundles from the road...
so there will be no obstructions to the thoroughfare.
Finish and join the lines, little Polish clicking soldier.
[ Laughing, Muttering Continue ]
Mrs. Dresner?
Yes.
Oh, you are a friend of my son's.
Don't worry, I'll go quietly. I'll be no trouble.
No, get under the stairs. They'll be done searching soon. You'll be safe there.
Please hide! Please! ...warmed by the sun.
Hide under the stairs.
I've searched the building. There's no one here.
Also, gehen wir zum naechsten Block. Einverstanden.
Danka! Ah! Mama!
Hello, Adam.
H-Hello, Danka.
[ Soldiers Shouting In Distance ]
Come with me. I will put you in the good line.
Do you know the saying, ''An hour of life is still life''?
You are not a boy anymore. I'm saying a blessing for you.
[ People Shouting, Machine Guns Firing ]
####[ Children's Choir Singing ''Oyfin Pripetshok'']
## Ofyn pripetshok brent a fayerl ##
## Un in shtub iz heys ##
## Un der rebe lerent kleyne kinderlech ##
##Dem alefbeys ##
[ Gunshot, People Screaming ]
##Zetzhe kinderlech gedenktzhe tayere ##
## Vos ir lerent do ##
##Zogtzhe noch amol un take noch amol ##
##Komets alefo ##
## Ofyn pripetshok brent a fayerl ##
## Un in shtub iz heys ##
## Un der rebe lerent kleyne kinderlech Dem alefbeys ##
[ Shouting, Gunshot ]
Oh, please, let's go. Let's go, please.
Come on.
##Zetzhe kinderlech gedenktzhe tayere ##
## Vos ir lerent do ##
##Zogtzhe noch amol un take noch amol ##
##Komets alefo ##
##Komets alefo ####
[ Whistle Blows, Dogs Barking ]
Markieren.
Nie! Prosze pana, niech pan--
##
...nie znajdziemy!
####
Was ist das? Ist das Bach? Nein, nein. Mozart.
Mozart? Ja.
####
[ Machine Gun Fire, Piano Continue ]
Das wollen wir heute noch schaffien? Nee, schaffien wir nie.
Jemu niedobrze sie robi.
Nee, das schaffien wir nie.
I wish this fucking night were over.
####
[ Machine Gun Fire Continues ]
- -Appell! Fuenferreihen!
Antreten!
Halt, alle anstellen!
Fuenferreihen!
Muetzen ab!
Namen verlesen! Wer aufgerufen wird, hebt seine Hand und ein deutliches Jawhol!
Jawohl.
Keller, Fanni! Jawohl.
Adalbert, Hermann! Jawohl.
Faber, Dorothea! Jawohl.
Goldstein, Pola! Jawohl.
Warmberger, Markus!
Jawohl.
Edelstein, Max!
[ Soldiers Continue Shouting Names ]
Appell abtreten!
Do pracy! Do pracy!
The worst is over. We are workers now.
[ Man Speaking German Over Loudspeaker ]
[ Officer Shouting In German ]
Keine Muedigkeit vorschuetzen!
[ Woman Shrieks, People Shouting ]
Oh, God, Amon.
[ Officer Shouting In German ]
Sofort in der Baracke zurueckmelden!
[ Man Shouting In German ]
[ Officer Shouting In German ]
Komm du mal schoen her! Komm du schoen!
Na komm! Na komm!
Amon, you're such a damned fuckin' child!
Wakey, wakey.
Make coffiee. Make it yourself.
The SS will manage...
certain industries itself inside Plaszow--
a metalworks, brush factory,
another for reprocessing Jewish clothing...
from the ghettos for use by bombed-out families back home.
But it's private industry like yours that stands to benefit most...
by moving inside the wire of Commandant Amon Goeth's camp--
No, no, no. Sit, sit. Julian, how are you?
How are you? Good to see you, my friend.
Oskar Schindler. LeoJohn.
Franz, good to see you. Hello, Oskar. Glad you could join us.
My pleasure. Julius. How are you? You lost weight.
Only in the shoulders. Please, everybody, sit down.
How are you doing? Oskar Schindler.
We started without you. Fine. I miss anything good?
I was explaining to Herr Bosch and Herr Madritsch...
some of the benefits of moving their factories into Plaszow.
I meant the food.
Since your labor is housed on-site, it's available to you at all times.
You can work them all night if you want.
Your factory policies, whatever they've been in the past, they'll continue to be.
They'll be respected.
I have to know, where do you get a suit like that? What is that? Is that silk?
Of course.
Ja. It's-- It has a nice sheen about it.
Thank you. Very nice.
I'd say I'd get you one, but the man who made it is probably dead.
I don't know.
I go to work the other day.
Nobody's there.
Nobody tells me about this. I have to find out. I have to go in.
Everybody's gone.
No.
They're not gone. They're here.
They're mine! Every day that goes by, I'm losing money.
Every worker that is shot costs me money. I have to find somebody else.
We are going to be making so much money that none of this is going to matter.
It's bad business.
Thank you.
Leave the bottle.
Take that.
Lena... thank you.
Scherner told me something else about you.
Yeah? What's that?
That you know the meaning of the word ''gratitude.''
That it's not some vague thing with you...
like it is with others.
You want to stay where you are.
You've got things going on the side.
Things are good.
You don't want anybody telling you what to do.
I can understand all that, you know. I-- I know you.
What you want... is your own sub-camp.
Do you have any idea what is involved? The paperwork alone?
You've got to build the thing. Getting those fucking permits is enough to drive you crazy.
Then the engineers show up, they stand around, they argue about drainage, foundations,
codes, exact specifications, fences four kilometers long, 1,200 kilograms of barbed wire,
6,000 kilograms of electrified fences, ceramic insulators,
three cubic meters of air space per prisoner.
I'm telling you, you want to shoot somebody. I've been through it. I know.
Well, you know. You've been through it.
You could make things easier for me.
I'd be grateful.
Aus dem Weg da!
Weitergehen! Weitergehen!
Wlewo zwrot! Trzymac szereg!
Weitergehen. Nach links.
Where's Stern?
Goldberg and Chilowicz... make sure I see my cut...
from the, uh, factory owners in this camp,
leaving you to take care of my main account--
the Schindler account.
He wants his independence. I gave it to him.
But independence costs money.
This you understand?
Look at me.
Don't forget who you are working for now.
####
Jawohl! Make sure he kisses each and every one!
Ja. Now, girls, everyone.
We need more wine. More wine!
Stand in my place. Don't let him leave.
[ Chattering, Shouting Continue ]
## Was passiert denn in einem Leben ## Prost! Prost!
Thank you, Herr Direktor.
Prost, Herr Direktor!
What are you doing? What? Scratching my head.
Makes them think we have lice. Helps them keep their distance.
Do you have lice? Do you have your notebook?
The calendar on my desk has the birthdays of our SS friends' wives and children.
Don't forget to send something.
Record payoffs to the Main Administration and Economics Office, the Arm--
Slower, Stern, slower. The Armaments Board, Governor General's Division...
of the Interior and Chief of Police as ''fees,''
and make them on the first of each month,
as opposed to individual payoffs to our SS contacts.
The list is in the lower drawer of my desk, which you-- ''First of month--''
SS contacts: list, lower drawer of my desk, which you handle...
as cash contributions to legitimate charities sent to each official's office.
Dealings with our black market contacts, listed as suppliers...
in the legitimate ledger, are more complicated. Forget it.
What do you mean, forget it? You can't forget it! It gives me a headache!
I couldn't get you out of here. I'll be all right.
Anyway, I'm here almost every week. Wednesdays, usually.
I'll look in on you, see how you're doing.
Here, put these in your pocket.
Come on.
Herr Direktor, don't let things fall apart.
I've worked too hard.
Thanks for-- Good luck.
## [ Music, Shouting Continue ]
Achtung, Muetzen ab!
- Work! - An die Arbeit!
What are you making?
Hinges, sir.
Ja, I've got some workers coming in tomorrow. Where are they from again?
Yugoslavia, Herr Kommandant.
I've got to make room.
Make me a hinge. Yes, sir.
Keep going, you're doing well.
Says he's doing well.
Oh, that's very good.
But I'm a bit confused, and perhaps you can help me.
What I don't understand is that you've been working...
since I think, what, about six this morning?
Yet such a small pile of hinges.
Oh, Christ. May I try that, sir?
Check the angle-lever. Maybe it's bent.
No, no. You wouldn't hear a click if it was the angle-lever.
Maybe it's the pin. Maybe the pin shaft is greasy. Ja, come on.
What did I just say? Here.
Herr Kommandant,
I beg to report that my heap ofhinges was so unsatisfactory...
because the machines were being recalibrated this morning.
I w-was put on to shoveling coal.
Strange, huh?
Yeah.
Thank you, Muek.
Ah, Lisiek. Don't touch the leather, it's just been oiled.
Rottenfuehrer. Oh, for me?
Oh, thank you very much, Herr Direktor. Thank you. Herr Direktor!
Herr Direktor!
He was making hinges slowly.
So the man can turn out a hinge in less than a minute. Why the long story? Hmm?
Thank you, sir. You're welcome.
Nobody knows who stole the chicken, hmm? Tell him about the chicken.
A man walks around with a chicken and nobody notices this.
Save yourselves.
Tell him about the chicken.
Still nobody knows.
It was you. You committed this crime.
No, sir. But you know who, though.
Yes. Who?
Him!
He's very gifted. Yeah, sure. Bring him over.
Yes, sir. Thank you.
Thank you again, Herr Direktor. You're welcome again.
It's an honor to work for such a great company. It's great to have you.
I promise to learn everything about enamelware production. That's great.
Hello? Miss Elsa Krause is here. I only need five minutes.
She wants to speak to the Herr Direktor.
Yes.
He won't see you.
Please, sit down.
Pernod? Cognac? Uh, no. No, thank you.
So, what can I do for you?
They say that no one dies here.
They say your factory is a haven.
They say you are good.
Who says that?
Everyone.
My name is Regina Perlman, not Elsa Krause.
I've been living in Krakow on false papers since the ghetto massacre.
My parents are in Plaszow.
Their names are Chana and Jakob Perlman.
They are older people. They are killing older people now in Plaszow.
They bury them up in the forest. Look...
I don't have any money.
I, I borrowed these clothes.
I'm begging you.
Please, please bring them here.
I don't do that.
You've been misled. I ask one thing:
whether or not a worker has certain skills.
My father is an importer, not a metalworker.
Such activities are illegal. You will not entrap me!
Cry, and I will have you arrested. I swear to God!
People die. It's a fact of life.
He wants to kill everybody? Great! What am I supposed to do about it?
Bring everybody over? Is that what you think?
Send them over to Schindler. Send them all!
His place is a haven, didn't you know? It's not a factory.
It's not an enterprise of any kind.
It's a haven for rabbis and orphans...
and people with no skills whatsoever!
You think I don't know what you're doing?
You're so quiet all the time. I know, I know!
Are you losing money? That's not the point!
What other point is-- It's dangerous! It's dangerous to me!
You have to understand. Goeth is under enormous pressure.
You have to think of it in his situation.
He's got this whole place to run.
He's responsible for everything here, all these people.
He's got a lot of things to worry about.
And he's got the war which brings out the worst in people.
Never the good, always the bad. Always the bad.
But in normal circumstances he wouldn't be like this. He'd be all right.
There'd just be the good aspects of him which--
He's a wonderful crook.
A man who loves good food, good wine, the ladies, making money--
Killing.
He can't enjoy it.
Bejski told me the other day, somebody escaped...
from a work detail outside the wire.
Goeth lined up everybody from the missing man's barracks.
He shot the man to the left of Bejski, the man to the right ofhim.
He walked down the line shooting every other man with the pistol.
Twenty-five.
What do you want me to do about it? Nothing, nothing.
We're just talking.
''Perlman.''
Perlman!
Husband and wife.
Jakob and Chana Perlman!
Have Goldberg bring them over.
Muetzen ab!
Appell abtreten!
## [ Drunken Singing In German ]
I'm sure this will be better than those rags, Lisiek.