Thad?
I said no toys at Grandfather's.
But it's Christmas.
Stop it!
Hey.
Hey! Dad!
Hey!
Thad, you can't go crying,
to other people all the time.
A man needs to know when
to stand up for himself.
Dear Magic isn't real Ball,
will Thad ever be a man.
Outlook not so good.
You broke it.
Dad?
Sid?
Someone help me!
Help!
Hello?
Thaddeus.
Thaddeus Sivana.
Who are you?
How do you know my name?
I am the last of the consul of wizards.
Sworn to protect realms
from the Seven Deadly Sins.
For years have passed,
and I grow weak.
That is why I seek a champion,
to inherit my magic.
You want me, to do magic?
With this...
all of my powers will become yours.
But first...
you must demonstrate
that you're pure of heart,
and strong in spirit.
He lies.
Don't be his champion.
We can give you power.
Take the eye.
Take it.
Your father thinks you're weak.
Show him your power.
No!
What? What happened?
Only the purest of hearts,
can resist their temptations.
But you...
you will never be worthy.
Wait.
I'm good enough, I swear!
What?
Let me back in!
Calm down, Thad!
Calm down.
Stop it!
Calm down. Thad!
Stop!
Stop it!
Hey, I'm gonna kill you.
Stop!
Thad...
I was just there.
This man.
This wizard.
He took me to a castle...
Thad?
And...
Stop!
Stop it!
You miserable, whiny, little shit!
You coulda killed us!
Do you understand that?
Dad?
Dad!
You're ok.
You're gonna be ok.
You did this.
You did this!
No.
Dad...
FIND US
Your magic grows weak.
Soon you won't be able to contain us.
Seeking spells!
Find me one soul who is worthy!
No matter how long it takes.
Holy moly!
The boys in blue!
Sheriff, glad to see you.
I called as soon as I saw.
They're in there.
You stay here.
Police!
I saw them hide back in there.
Police, coming in!
Police!
There's nobody here.
What do you mean?
It's a closet.
You really bought that?
Hey, no, no, no!
Stop, stop, stop, stop!
Open this up right now, kid!
That's a federal offense, kid!
You can't do that!
Don't go in that car.
Come on, open the door, please.
Please, come on!
Please!
Open this door, right now!
Come on!
Very good, very funny.
Very funny. That's great.
That's hilarious, yeah.
Hey dispatch, we need backup at
the Laurelwood shopping center, please.
Dispatch, cancel that request.
Some kid stole our walkie-talkies.
Walkie-talkies?
How old are you?
No, no, no, no.
That's my lunch, kid!
Miss Batson, I've...
I've been looking for you.
No. Gosh.
It's me, it's Billy.
Ok.
I want the tiger.
I know honey, I know.
But Mom's not exactly going pro here.
We got one!
But I wanted a tiger!
Oh, but this is the real prize, baby.
See?
You can use that your whole life.
You'll always find your way.
I can't let the ball get away.
Mom?
Mom!
Hey.
Who are you with, bud?
Yeah, he says it's Billy Batson.
Don't worry, kid.
I'm sure she'll come looking
before too long, ok?
They always do.
Mom.
I'm home.
Yes?
Yeah...
Is... Is Rachel Batson?
Who's asking?
Yeah, see the thing is...
I think you're my mom.
You sure about that?
Sorry to bother you.
You just had to take my lunch?
You save me any fries?
Foster home in Pittsburgh reported
you missing two weeks ago.
You sending me back?
No.
They don't want you.
Harsh.
You laugh,
but you've run from foster homes
in six counties, Mr. Batson.
From...
good people...
who want you, all in pursuit of
someone who arguably does not.
It's time someone looked you in
the eye and told it to you straight.
I don't need parents
to play make believe with.
I got a mom.
Yes.
You're some detective.
73 Batsons,
between the ages of 28 to 40,
and you've crossed out every one.
She's still out there.
I know it.
There's a couple outside, Mr. Batson.
They run a group home.
I can take care of myself.
When you're 18.
Until then,
I won't have you living on the streets
looking for someone
who never looked for you.
Give these people a chance.
Because that's what they're giving you.
You're out of options.
Alright, let's get the spiel.
Just know that me and Rosa, we get it.
We were foster kids back in the day.
Back in the dark ages.
Girl!
I'm young at heart.
I got my finger on the pulse.
Yeah, that's a reference to his
blood pressure because he's old.
Billy, do you have any food allergies?
Gonna wish you did.
Darla's cooking.
Oy, guerito!
What?
We know how overwhelming
it can all be.
New house, new faces.
All up in your face.
Just...
take it at your own speed.
Hello?
We're home!
That's what happens when you suck!
So much for the welcome party.
Yeah, that thing growing out
of the couch would be Eugene.
Is that him?
Oh, my gosh! Billy!
Slow down, slow down!
Welcome home!
And that's Darla.
I'm Darla.
Big hugger.
I noticed.
Die! Die! Die!
He doesn't mean that.
It's the game.
Hey.
No sodas after dark, remember?
When did it get dark?
Oh, the poster. I made you one.
Come look!
Oh, no!
Sorry, Pedro must've been working out.
His goal is to get swole.
Here.
Yes.
Exactly why your Math Department
is so uniquely suited for me.
I can't, I can't, even with
Eugene right now.
Sorry. Mary, hi.
College interview.
I'm Billy.
What am I most excited about?
What a great question.
I was hoping you'd ask.
Mention you're a foster kid.
Colleges eat that up.
What I'm most excited about?
Is the campus experience.
As a foster child, I'm a big believer,
in finding family and friends in the most...
unlikely of places.
I'm gonna miss that girl so much!
It's Caltech, it's a very prestigious school.
And also all the way in California.
But we don't have to talk
about that right now.
It's a tough subject for me.
Do you like vegan food?
Because, see I love animals.
Oh, no! The Tofurkey!
Oh, no, we may have
to eat a real turkey!
Is that?
It's ok.
Come, I'll show you your room.
It's a bit of a madhouse, I know but...
it's fun!
Watch the bumps step.
Pedro, mi amor, hola.
Say hi to Billy.
Don't take it personally.
He's like that with everyone.
Freddy.
This is Billy Batson.
Make sure you make him
feel at home, ok?
Maybe don't say anything too weird?
Oh, one weird thing is,
did you know the Romans used
to brush their teeth with their urine?
And apparently, it works.
Oh, it's...
it's a long way down.
Trust me, I speak from experience.
Victor pushed me.
They seem nice,
but don't buy it.
It gets real Game of Thrones
around here.
What?
Dude, I'm...
just, messing around.
It's...
it's terminal cancer I...
I only have three months.
Kidding, again!
You look at me and you're like,
why so dark?
You're a disabled foster kid,
you've got it all. Right?
Oh, yeah, that's the...
the old batarang.
I mean it's a replica but...
Feel how sharp.
I could kill you in your sleep
with that thing.
You ever a supes guy?
Yeah, me too.
Behold, the holy grail.
One nine millimeter round
shot at Superman himself.
It's legit.
Probably worth, I don't know,
five, six hundred, maybe more.
What's in the bag?
Hey.
Hey, it's all good.
It's good to maintain boundaries.
You don't gotta talk so much,
you know.
I mean, this place is great.
You're gonna love it.
Dinner!
All hands on deck!
Sweet.
Thank you for this family.
Thank you for this day.
Thank you for this food.
Even if it's not steak fillet.
Big school. 2,000 students,
you might think,
so many strangers.
But not if you think of them as,
possible for each friend, then it's...
So many friends.
The principal, her name's Shirley.
She's the best.
Next.
This is our security scanner.
Like in an airport.
It's totally safe.
I know what it is.
Does she always do this?
Silence makes me uncomfortable.
She's almost never uncomfortable.
Have a good first day, big brother.
Look, you don't have
to hug me all the time.
We're not actually brother
and sister so...
I'm sorry.
Hey.
I. I didn't mean to make her...
I was overwhelmed, honestly.
He said, I must be pure of heart.
He called himself a wizard.
He is just like a...
a wizard from Harry Potter, some...
But you're saying that other
people have experienced this?
In a sense, yes.
Do you remember what he said to you?
He tested me.
There were these statues.
Their eyes, it's like
they were looking at me,
making me think things.
Horrible things.
And do these approximate
what you saw?
Yes. That's exactly how I remember it.
I don't understand.
How do you know?
Recurring imagery has proven very
common in cases of mass hysteria.
Mass hysteria?
I know.
The term's a bit theatrical.
But take UFO sightings, for example.
Lights in the sky, flying saucers.
Isolated incidents of people
who do not know each other...
The symbols.
Ask her about the symbols.
Sorry, Ms. Kwan.
But as an example of recurring imagery,
maybe you recall seeing
these symbols before
the alleged abduction?
I don't remember any symbols, no.
I think I got it on video.
There was something...
I remember the numbers on
my alarm clock, they kept
shifting.
Video?
Show me the video.
Ms. Kwan, this is Dr. Sivana.
One moment, I can send it.
Hello?
Oh, my God!
Who's there?
Hello?
What's going on?
What's happening?
I'm. I'm going to call the police.
Then this blinding light all around me.
And I felt like I was getting
pulled down into something.
I felt like a temple carved
inside a mountain...
He looked exactly what you'd expect
from a guy who calls himself a wizard,
and how you were brought
there to save the world.
Wearing a cape.
And there is no ceiling.
We ran the numbers again...
Dr. Sivana!
I appreciate your enthusiasm.
But you're funding my project.
And when I'm interviewing,
I don't wanna be interrupted.
56 reported abductions.
I never saw it.
Saw what?
Doctor, what is all this?
All these years...
I was convinced...
I had the incorrect sequence.
Or perhaps...
the wrong symbols to open the door.
But on that woman's alarm clock,
the seven symbols.
The sequence...
repeated itself...
seven times.
That's the difference.
Is this some sort of joke?
It may seem that way to you.
Because we're not in actuality,
studying mass hysteria.
What all these people have seen,
every single one of them,
is absolutely real.
An alarm clock malfunctions,
and your first thought is
it's proof of a wizard?
Come on, Dr. Sivana.
You can't believe any of this is real.
Why yes.
Yes, I do.
I've been waiting for this moment,
for so long.
And now here we are.
You don't remember me, do you?
I remember you.
You were a boy.
And now you dare intrude
in my kingdom.
Do you know what it's like
for a child to be told,
you'll never be good enough?
No you don't.
What you said to me all those years ago,
made me realize who I really was.
And you know something?
I am not pure of heart.
The wizard is too weak to stop us.
No.
No!
You never found your champion.
But we found ours.
You are the true champion.
They're using you.
You're nothing to them
but a means of escape.
Through you, they'll spread their
poison to everything they touch!
Make mankind turn on each other!
You seek a pure soul old man.
But no one's worthy.
Flight or invisibility?
If you could have one superpower,
flight or invisibility,
what would you pick?
I mean, everybody chooses flight.
You know why?
So they can fly away
from this conversation?
No. Because heroes fly.
And who doesn't want people
to think they're a hero, right?
But. But invisibility, no way I mean,
that's pervy.
Spying around on people who
don't even know you're there.
Sneaking around everywhere.
It's a total villain power, right?
Then they did this study,
and this is a real thing.
They asked people the same question.
You know, what power do you want?
But this time,
they made it, so the answers
were anonymous.
And. And most people,
since they knew that it was secret,
said invisibility.
And I think that's because most people
don't feel like heroes
on the inside, deep down.
You're gonna run away.
I mean, you stole my Superman bullet.
Dude, I get it. I get it.
You've been screwed over
way too many times.
You don't trust anyone.
But that's the thing about invisibility.
You end up all by yourself.
I didn't steal your dumb bullet.
Hey, how was it today?
That good?
Oh, my God! Freddy!
Are you ok?
Freddy.
What the hell?
What is wrong with you two?
No way that's gonna buff out.
You gonna pay for that, Freeman?
For the dent you made almost hitting me?
Yeah, sure...
You guys take these?
Brett, stop!
Don't touch my brother!
What, you need your fake
family to stand up for you?
Stand up for yourself, Freeman.
Yeah?
Hey Freeman. Here, stand up.
Stand up for yourself.
What are you gonna do?
Go home and cry to mommy?
Oh, yeah, you don't have a mommy.
Stop hurting him!
Hey!
Man, sorry about that.
That wasn't fair but,
then again you don't fight fair, so...
Back off assbags!
I know how to use these things!
Hey!
He's getting away!
Where you going?
Freddy, are you ok?
Hey, let's go through the back.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Nowhere to run!
Hey!
Go, go, go!
Grab him!
Move! Get out of the way!
Move!
Move, woman!
No, no, no, no!
You're dead, kid!
Yeah, you think you're funny?
We know where you go to school, buddy!
Next stop, 30th Street Station.
Change for the Regional Rail Line.
Hello?
What's going on?
Help!
Ok.
Holy moly.
Hello?
What the hell?
Who's doing this?
Hi...
I was supposed to get off at 30th.
Billy Batson.
How'd you know my name?
I am the last of the Council of wizards.
Keeper of the Rock of Eternity.
You're...
that guy.
Hey listen, I don't have any money.
Do not patronize me, boy!
You are standing
in the source of all magic.
The Rock of Eternity.
Seven thrones of seven wizards.
But long ago, we chose a champion.
And we chose recklessly.
He used his power for revenge.
Releasing the Seven Deadly
Sins into your world.
Millions of lives were lost.
Entire civilizations,
erased from existence.
That is why I vowed
never to pass on my magic,
until I find one truly good person.
Strong in spirit.
Pure in heart.
Look, man,
maybe this is magic.
I. I don't know but...
the people you're looking for,
good, pure people...
I'm not one of them.
I. I don't know if anyone is, really.
You, Billy Batson,
are all I have.
All the world has.
Lay your hands on this staff.
Gross.
And say my name so my
powers may flow through you.
I open my heart to you, Billy Batson.
And in so doing,
choose you as champion.
Thanks.
Real sweet of you mister, but I...
really gotta get going.
My brothers and sisters
were slain by the Sins.
Their thrones lie empty!
My magic must be passed on.
Now.
Speak my name!
I. I don't know your name, sir.
We just met.
My name is...
Shazam.
Wait, for real?
Say it!
Ok.
Jeez.
So just say it?
Like...
Shazam?
Yes!
Carry my name and with it,
you carry all my powers.
The wisdom of Solomon!
The strength of Hercules!
The stamina of Atlas!
The power of Zeus!
The courage of Achilles!
And speed of Mercury!
What happened to me?
Why am I...
Wha.. Wha.. What did you do to me?
What did you do to my voice?
You have been transformed
to your full potential, Billy Batson.
With your heart, unlock your
greatest power.
The thrones of our brothers
and sisters await!
Get me outta here!
Dope!
My brother, I applaud your choices today.
Gold shoes, gold belt, white cape!
It shouldn't work but,
hot damn, it does!
Hey!
Hey, babe!
Yes, officer, I'm aware
he's run away in the past, I...
23 times?
Guy's got no social media presence.
At all.
The guy is a ghost.
You know guys,
I'm happy to look for Billy.
More than happy.
But now you gotta wash the dishes,
that's what's more important.
What are you gonna do, Freddy?
Run after him?
Very funny!
No wait, don't scream.
Victor! Victor! Victor!
No, no!
It's me! It's Billy!
It's Billy!
You asked me,
flight or invisibility?
I thought that was stupid, but now
I look like this and I need your help!
Meet me back here after lights out?
What's up, bud? You alright?
Yeah. Yeah.
I'm just...
I'm really sad.
Because Billy's gone.
And you know,
maybe it's my fault.
Maybe I did it.
You know, maybe I. I snore...
Hey, hey, hey.
Not your fault son, alright.
We'll find him, ok?
You don't snore that bad.
But you kinda smell.
Oh, my God!
Hey, stop right there.
How do I know you're not a
supervillain using telepathic abilities
to make me believe that you're Billy?
All I have to do is press dial on this thing.
No, no, I have proof, I have proof.
Here.
Look, I lied, ok?
I took your bullet.
No, no, no! No!
No! No!
Stupid adult hands!
But you saw it.
You saw it, right?
Look, Freddy, I swear it's me, ok?
Look, I know we're not really
close friends or anything,
but you're the only person that I know
that knows anything about
this Caped Crusader stuff.
That's Batman.
What?
Forget it.
Can I...
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Oh, my God!
It's crazy, right?
What are your superpowers?
Superpowers? Dude, I don't even
know how to pee in this thing!
Ok, can... Can you fly?
Ok, let's do this.
How do we do this?
Just...
Just like Superman it.
Oh, my God.
Obviously, you have to jump.
Come on.
How is any of this obvious?
Ok.
Try, to believe that you can fly.
Ok, I read this deep dive in the peer
reviewed studies about superpowers
and in 6 out of 10, belief is the key.
Belief, belief, belief.
Ok, ok.
I believe I can fly.
I believe I...
I...
Did you believe?
Yeah.
You wanna try invisibility?
How do I do?
You. Forget it. You know.
Ok, ok, ok.
Oh, my God! It worked!
Where'd you go?
I'm right here.
You can't see me?
Where?
I'm invisible!
I'm right here.
Over here.
I'm invisible!
Hey! Nice outfit, dipshit!
I. I might have...
been testing invisibility and super
intelligence at the same time.
Freeman, I'm gonna come
over there and beat you.
Oh, my God!
The lightning emblem! It was staring us
right in the face the whole time!
Literally!
Ok, ok.
Clearly, we gotta give you a lightning
themed superhero name.
Yeah.
Oh, right.
Hey, you! Back...
off.
Hyperspeed, check!
I... I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
I thought you were the one
who was screaming.
I doused him with pepper spray.
Smart move. Yeah.
Hey, get up, mister mugger guy!
Give the old lady her purse back.
I'm... I'm your age.
And he didn't get a chance to take
it because I didn't let him take it.
Good, yeah, good.
You're really on top of this stuff.
And that should teach you
that old ladies,
regular aged ladies like yourself,
don't need your protecting.
Right? So get woke, bro.
I'm sorry, who are you?
His name is Thundercrack!
Hero to the people.
With the power and speed
of lightning all in one.
Dude, that sounds like a butt thing.
Mr. Philadelphia!
That's a cream cheese thing, dude!
Powerboy, because he's got
all the powers.
Because sometimes pepper spray
can't protect against evil.
Powerboy, do you know this child?
Like, like a teeny little bit.
I don't really know...
Yeah, he's, like, my manager.
He's like a miniature manager.
I'm his manager.
The... and you know.
Powerboy's not gonna work either, ok?
So work on something else...
Hey, hey, hey.
Bud. What could...
Electricity manipulation,
hyper-speed, super-strength!
Dude, you're stacked!
You're just cool as Superman,
almost.
I didn't see you,
or what just happened here.
I don't wanna know.
Just don't hurt me.
Oh, no, no, I'm not gonna hurt you.
Thank you for your kind donation.
No, no, no, no.
But if you need any more help,
just look for the superhero
that still can't fly.
Forget flying man,
we just made 73 bucks!
73 bucks?
See.
Come on!
Hey, wait a minute.
I just got an idea.
I'd like to purchase some
of your finest beer, please.
I don't know about this.
I mean, we don't have a fake ID even.
Freddy, Freddy, would you relax?
Look at me, I am the fake ID.
Everything from the register!
Go! Go!
Now! Come on!
We don't have much time!
Let's go! Move!
I want it all! Hurry!
This is your chance.
I. Oh. See.
Come on, come on,
come on, let's do this!
Gentlemen!
Why use guns when we can
handle this like real men?
Billy, look out!
Bullet immunity.
You have bullet immunity!
I'm bulletproof.
Today is December 8th,
and this is video proof of authenticity.
Shoot him again.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Here, here.
Go, both of you, come on.
Go to town.
Wai... Wait. Wai.. Wait!
We still don't know if the suit
is bulletproof or if you are.
Shoot him in the face.
Shoot me in the face...
in the face?
It kinda tickles.
You're dead.
Sorry about your window.
Have a good night.
But you're welcome
for not getting robbed!
Come on!
Let's get outta here!
Hey.
To fighting bad guys.
Yup.
That tastes like actual vomit.
Hey, you know,
habanero jerky, if you eat enough of it,
it could burn a hole in your stomach.
Worth it.
Yeah.
Probably not you though. You've
probably got stomach superpowers.
Probably.
Oh, hey, what's up?
I'm a superhero.
Yeah, his name is...
Captain Sparklefingers.
No it's not. No it's not!
It's not. It's not my name!
Hey, we should hang out.
We're like, the same age.
Ho! po-po. I'm out.
Hey, wait up!
I mean, it's a pretty sick view.
I totally get why Rocky was
training so hard to get up here.
You know, I like you like this.
This is so cool.
I mean, no offense, but like...
Like at first, you were kinda
like the opposite of how...
of how Darla is.
A dick?
Your words, not mine.
But yeah.
Alright, well, I feel like every criminal
is was either on drugs
or asleep by now.
Wanna head home?
Looking like this?
Yeah. I mean...
usually we'd have a lair
to go back to, but...
that's long term.
Right now you have a bunk bed.
Just scares me thinking of
him out there all alone.
This is what he does, Rosa.
Difference is when they find him,
we'll be the first to take him back.
With open arms.
Didn't even make it two days.
Not even two days.
Baby, we did our fair share
of running off back when.
At least I did.
Yeah.
Even Mary did it.
Twice.
That second time she ran off,
you said something to me
that I'll never forget.
You said.
It's not a home till you call it a home.
It's something you choose.
All we can do is
give him a place full of love.
Whether he chooses to call it a home,
that's up to him.
Yeah.
You gonna help me with this tree?
This tree's so sad.
Hello?
Got lost finding the bathroom.
Oh, ok, Freddy, sweetie, goodnight!
Good night.
Freddy, who's that?
It's Billy, he's just... he's really
tired and he has laryngitis.
What? What laryngitis?
I'm just kidding! I'm just kidding.
He's really, really tired and
he wants to go beddy-bye.
Beddy-bye? Who says beddy-bye?
Just hide, hide.
Billy, you're back.
Let us see you!
We're so worried about you.
I told you this was a bad idea!
Freddy?
Hey, what happened to the stairs?
Hey, covering her mouth
like you're gonna kidnap her
is not gonna make her less scared, ok?
Darla it's me, it's Billy.
I know I don't look like me.
A wizard made me look like this.
Maybe don't start with wizard,
it's just gonna make her more confused.
Some old guy brought me to a temple,
and he made me say Shazam...
Rosa!
Verbally triggered body
manipulation properties!
You can switch by saying Shazam!
Baby, was that you?
Are you ok?
I was screwing in a bulb.
Listen to me. Darla you cannot
tell anybody about this, alright?
But it's Billy, he's a hero.
Yeah, but if a supervillain
finds out that he's a hero,
that endangers us, ok?
A hero's loved ones, are like
a perfect bad guy target.
I mean, is she even good
at keeping secrets?
Moderate.
No.
Oh, God.
Ok, listen D.
You cannot tell a single soul
about this alright? Please.
Why? What if it's people we trust?
Because good sisters don't tell secrets.
I'm a good sister.
Yeah, you are.
You know what would make
you an even better sister?
Is when you fix the doorknob for us, ok.
Yeah.
Sweet dreams.
Sweet dreams, goodnight.
See you in the morning.
Good night.
Hello sir, how may I help you?
Hi, sir.
Sir, you can't go in there.
Excuse me!
You. You cannot go in there!
Sorry I'm late.
Thad, this is for board members only.
I'm aware of that, Father.
Now...
That night...
in the car...
I swore to you I saw something,
but you never believed me.
So much easier to blame me, wasn't it?
And say that if I hadn't screamed
that night,
you'd still have your legs.
But now I have proof.
That's enough, Thad.
Dear Sid.
You think?
You know, even before the accident,
you belittled me.
Don't make me throw you
out of here, Thad.
You don't need to make a scene.
Oh brother...
The scene,
has only just begun.
Ask that if you can throw me out.
What?
Ask the ball if you're man enough
to throw me out of this room.
Let me spoil it for you.
Outlook...
not so good.
I've come here during the season of giving...
to give you...
what you deserve.
Run!
Oh, my God! No!
No! No!
Help!
Somebody!
Help me!
You can't go crying to other people
all the time.
What sin best befits you, Father?
I'll give you anything.
Money.
The company.
You want the company?
There it is.
Greed.
Do you honestly think...
all this material you've accumulated,
amounts to actual power?
This is power.
More than you ever had.
More than anyone has.
There is one more powerful.
The wizard found his champion.
Kill the champion
before he learns his true potential,
or he will defeat you.
Show me where to find him.
Oh, Greed,
you can have him.
No.
No. Oh, no!
No! No! No!
Family is more than just a word.
At Sivana Industries,
our focus is family.
Burke.
Where's the truck?
I can hear it.
Oh, my God!
My truck!
Are you kidding?
You know, guys,
I don't think that's gonna buff out.
Hey.
Making the crippled kid
do the dirty work.
I'm a better lookout.
I can play innocent.
And I can't?
Your face gives off a very strong vibe
of someone who's hatching schemes.
My face? This face?
Yeah.
Ok.
You boys got a hall pass?
Oh, us? Yeah. Always.
You!
You look like you're up to something.
Me? Up to something?
No. Never.
Am I up to something.
Our dad's picking us up. He...
He got held up at the...
The business... office.
The business office?
Sure, kid.
Look, parents or guardians
must appear physically
to check out students.
Gotcha.
Ok well, you hear that, Dad?
Hey!
Shazam!
Hey there, son,
and hey there, other son
that I also have
that's related to that son
I just passed in the hallway.
I'm so sorry I'm late.
I got held up at the business office,
doing all the work stuff.
This is the... the security guard
all the kids admire so much.
Actually, that's the other one.
This one sucks.
This is. That's not funny.
I'm gonna talk to him about that.
I apologize.
Anyway, this is me appearing physically
to check my sons out of school.
So, thank you so much
for keeping them safe, Detective Moron.
It's Moran.
You ready?
Algebra!
Science!
English!
Health!
Are you ok?
I'm sorry!
More powerful than a locomotive.
Locomotive.
What are you? An old prospector?
Can leap tall buildings
in a single bound.
Single bound.
I'm so sorry!
Sorry, sorry people. Hi.
Your phone's charged.
You know, you really need like a,
like a mic drop catchphrase after
you do something cool.
I've been thinking about that.
I was thinking, what about,
what about this.
That's why you don't mess
with electricity.
Catchphrases obviously
aren't one of your superpowers.
And your phone's charged.
Well, you think you can do better?
What the hell?
Let there be light.
Come on.
Yeah, yeah, baby. Yeah, baby, ok.
How do I... Never mind.
Shazam!
What'd you see?
Were there boobies?
You see nipples?
Why aren't you talking?
We're gonna need more money.
Why? You were in there for,
like, five minutes.
Dude, they were very convincing!
Oh, get it!
That's money.
Go, go, go!
No!
Stop! No!
I'm not even looking!
Stop. Stop.
Oh, and done!
What?
Finished him.
A lair.
Yes.
And obviously, we're gonna have to
be making this purchase anonymously.
Obviously.
And... if you have a location like on
a cliff, like a castle-esque type thing.
Overlooking some water.
Overlooking some water,
seas, below it. Rough, you know...
Like a waterfall,
so you can drive into...
Waterfall, yeah. If you... Yeah.
Look, maximum voltage is it?
You can call me Max.
Look Max,
why don't you just start with how
many bedrooms you're looking for?
One!
Seven.
One?
Seven?
What, am I running a foster home now?
Have you seen the one
where he throws the football into space?
So dope.
Hey, you guys gotta wonder
who's filming those, right?
I mean, that's bravery in
and of itself.
I mean, is it, though?
Yeah. I'd actually argue
maybe even more brave.
Holding a camera?
Staring in the face of danger.
Like some weirdo fanboy.
Hey, Freeman.
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
What, is your bestie gonna hit us
with a wheelchair this time?
No, maybe not him,
but I have another best friend,
who might hunt you down
and destroy both of you.
Ok, Freddy.
You may have heard of him.
The Human Power Storm.
Frequency Flinger. Sir Zaps-A-Lot.
Yeah. He's a man of many names.
You know the Red Cyclone?
You?
My ass you do.
We're a lot closer than you think.
Maybe even at this very moment.
Prove it.
I will tomorrow.
Tomorrow he's gonna come
to lunch, and...
Rig... Right, Billy?
Oh, yeah, and then Superman's
gonna be bringing us dessert, right?
Tomorrow at lunch. You'll see.
And when he doesn't show,
then, we'll kick your ass.
So wait, my identity's a secret
so no one I know can get hurt.
Except when it makes you look cool,
then, then it's all good.
Billy, it's not like they're supervillains.
They're just super douchebags.
So, you're breaking your own rule?
Got it.
This thing is as much as mine
as it is yours.
Sorry, I'm starting to think you
think it's all your thing.
Billy, you're still gonna do it,
though, right?
I mean, what would a good brother do?
All hands on deck.
Thank you for this family.
Thank you for this day.
Thank you for this food.
Sorry Billy's hand's on vacay.
Big news in Philly.
They found a costumed hero.
He's doing good.
Yeah, but is he, though?
Controversy. Into it.
Share with us your,
perspective Eugene.
Just saying, he's what?
Charging people's phones?
So what?
I can charge a phone, with a plug.
Preach.
Pedro, any thoughts?
Costume's stupid.
Yeah.
Ok.
Big white cape like
he's getting married or something.
What if he didn't get to pick his costume?
Ever think about that?
You're a specialist, Freddy.
What do you think?
Yeah Freddy let's...
manage to see the positive.
Ok, well I think it looks like...
he doesn't have gratitude
for what he's been given.
Very specific. Alright.
Maybe to the superhero,
gratitude doesn't mean
having to be clingy.
Clingy? Interesting take.
Maybe sometimes a superhero just...
wants a little me time.
You know me time, could also
be construed as pushing away his family.
Family, is that what they are now?
It's a classic symptom of
Superhero Syndrome.
Coined by German psychologist
Heinrich Von...
German something where,
superpowers become
an all-consuming narcotic.
Son, we're still eating dinner.
What he needs is a sidekick.
Name one cool sidekick.
Darla, why are you
so quiet over there, baby?
You're never at a loss for words.
I'm eating.
Why am I still doing this?
Billy, you can't skip every day.
Not at your age.
But I'm not your age anymore.
But, I can go with you.
We just gotta...
trick the guard out, you know, and then...
Billy, where are you going?
Billy...
You're still gonna have
lunch with me, right?
Billy!
Sir Zaps-A-Lot's still gonna eat
in the cafeteria, right?
Alright.
Did you check it to...
People typically like give me
a little money, you know...
to...
You're a sweet couple.
You guys have a good day.
Oh, my God.
Mary?
Mary, are you ok? Are you...
How do you know my name?
How do I know your name?
One of my superpowers
is name guessing.
Which is really weird, I bet.
It's not as cool as
super-strength or super-speed but,
it's really helpful when
I meet new people.
Are you hurt?
No, I'm...
I'm ok. Thank you.
I...
I just need a second to think.
This has been such a weird day.
Using my powers of super-observation,
I see that you're holding a letter
from a college,
in your hand. Are you upset
because you didn't get in?
I got in.
Well, now my superpowers
are failing me and I am very confused.
Yeah. Me, too.
I don't know. I know I should be excited
because this is my dream and
I've worked really, really hard for this,
but it's like...
I don't know. Leaving my family
does not feel fun, you know?
Can I. Can I. Can I give you
a little piece of advice?
Don't be worried about everybody else.
Always look out for number one.
Gandhi said that.
I don't think he said that.
Yeah, he did.
Gandhi did not say that.
Somebody like Gandhi said that.
Take care of number one.
It was a really wise...
It might have been Yoda.
Listen.
I'm sorry, no.
Agree to disagree. The point is...
you do you. You know,
you gotta look out for you.
And get as far away from
this place as you can.
I don't know if I want to.
Of course you do.
What're you gonna do?
You gonna live in a group home
for the rest of your life?
Look, families are for people who
can't take care of themselves, ok?
So...
You know, you can take care of yourself.
All you know...
Also, look both ways
when you cross the street.
I'll just call him. I'll just make sure.
It's ringing.
Red Cyclone! Hey!
Hey, what's going on?
Oh, that's crazy.
Yeah, it's Freddy, by the way.
Yeah, it's crazy.
That is...
Great story.
He's not talking.
I was! I was!
We're friends.
I know him. I do.
I know him! I know him!
Yeah.
Shit.
Come on, now.
Hands. Lightning with my hands.
Lightning with my hands.
Hey! Hey!
Hey, young man.
What are you doing?
I'm in the middle of a show right now.
How can I help you?
I just wanted to say thank you
for showing up to lunch today.
Yeah, I got a little something
called a suitcase wedgie, right?
I don't know if you've ever
heard of it, but it's when...
someone grabs your
underwear like that
and hold you like a suitcase,
walks you down the hallway.
And this...
was my underwear.
Gross.
You said you'd come.
You said I will come,
I never said I was...
I'm a superhero, dude.
Well, you're acting real heroic.
How much people paying you today?
Listen, I have serious
responsibilities now, ok?
But that's cool, because I can
carry that burden with my...
hands. Lightning with my hands.
Oh man!
Holy moly.
Don't move!
Nobody move!
Oh, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
Stay, stay.
Stay. Stay. Stay.
That looked like it hurts.
It's him!
It's that superhero guy!
Help us! Save us!
Come on.
Come...
What's he doing?
What's going on?
What? No way.
Oh, no. Oh, no, no.
Please don't make me do this.
God, That is the worst idea ever!
I did it!
I got the bus!
I got the bus.
Nobody move in there!
I gotta put this thing down,
I gotta put this thing down.
No, no, no, doggie, doggie,
you have to move. Move!
Move! Shoo!
Shoo!
Please be a good dog.
Good dog!
You're being a bad dog.
Go! Go!
Please go. Please move.
Yes, thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Yeah, no, no, no, my f...
I was in the neighborhood,
you know, so I thought...
Thank you.
We both...
Oh yeah you know,
it's kinda my fault, anyway.
So, it seems Philadelphia has
gotten an early Christmas present
in the form of its very own superhero.
And we're out.
Hey, thank you very much.
Of course, yeah.
Dude! Dude, dude!
Dude, did you see that?
Yeah, you electrocuted a bus
and almost killed these people.
And then I caught it!
Freddy! I caught a bus
with my bare hands, man!
I caught a bus like people
catch fly balls, like...
Who does that? I do that.
Billy, you do nothing, you...
you take selfies
and make people pay you.
You know forget it. I can't really
talk to you when you look like this.
You just wish it was you.
No shit.
You think?
I would kill to have what you have.
Because everything I do,
is like some, some desperate attempt
to get people to notice me.
To not feel sorry for me.
I mean, look at me.
Look at me.
Do you even see me?
Because most people don't.
Because they don't want to.
And you don't either.
I mean, you think this is who you are?
I mean Billy you're 14.
And now you're no better
than the Breyers.
All this power,
and all you did was turn
into a show-off and a bully.
Whatever, kid.
I do what I want!
And I'm like mid-20s, probably.
Maybe even like 30.
Chosen one.
The so-called perfect man.
Pure of heart.
Flawless in every way.
What made you so worthy?
I'm sorry, can I help?
Can I help?
Do you want a autograph or something?
Give me your power.
Or die.
Oh, snap.
You're like a bad guy, right?
Ok, ok, ok, ok.
Look, before this gets really
stupid for you,
you should know that
I'm basically invincible.
So wou kno...
The weapons of man draw
no blood from our kind.
This is the...
The only thing that extinguishes
is magic,
is magic.
Time to transfer your power to me.
You did not see that one coming,
did you grandpa?
Them's street rules!
Ok, ok, ok, ok, ok!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I never should've punched
you in the nuts like that.
That was totally my bad.
We can talk about this.
You grovel like a child.
That's because I am one.
I'm a kid.
You don't want to hurt a kid, do you?
I believe I can fly!
I can fly!
Freddy said if I believe, I can fly!
Then I can fly, so I believe!
I believe, I believe!
Ok! Superman!
Superman!
What arm is it?
Why am I not flying?
Please, I don't wanna die!
I'm floating!
What the hell was that?
I can fly!
Billy?
Freddy! I need your help!
You can fly?
Who's the other guy?
Santa!
So, like, what do you and Mrs. Claus
do in the summertime?
Well, in some ways,
Santa's always here for you.
Help! Help!
Help Santa!
Help Santa! Needs help!
Help!
Give us a shout if you need us.
I'm just gonna chill in here for
a little while, if that's ok.
This is crazy!
This is crazy.
You don't have to fight this guy.
This isn't your job.
You can run, right?
Yes! You can run. Awesome.
You!
Get back!
Just get... Get away!
I'm Batman.
Get him, Batman!
Oh, sorry.
Come on!
Sh... Shazam!
Billy!
Billy, where are you?
Where are you, Billy?
Billy, come on!
Billy.
Where is he?
Supervillain.
Supervillain! Supervillain!
Worse.
Much worse.
Radioactive anthromorph.
Psychic energy manipulator.
I won't let you read my mind.
My mind is blank.
You can't get in.
I don't need to read your mind.
Because you are going to tell me.
Where is he?
Oh, my God, are you ok?
You ok?
Yeah.
What happened?
Are you hurt?
Come inside.
We need to have a talk.
Just don't be too hard on him, ok?
Running out on us.
Lying.
Then I get a call from the school
telling me you've been cutting class.
Getting in fights.
Bill, the man saved nine people.
Is that?
I'm questioning his motive.
What's Freddy doing with a superhero?
What's this superhero doing with Freddy?
You remember dinner?
When Billy and Freddy were arguing,
like an old married couple like this?
When he rescued me,
he knew I lived in a group home.
He knew my name.
He called me Mary.
Wait.
Are you saying Billy's
the Human Power Storm?
Yes! You guys figured it out!
All on your own.
I didn't help.
I didn't break any promises.
You knew?
I'm a good sister!
I mean, what were you thinking?
And then you bring Freddy into it.
Give him some space, guys.
He's a little upset. Ok?
Billy?
You're him.
You're the hero.
Yeah, well not anymore so...
Why do you have my notebook?
Eugene finished you search.
Look, I'm not a hacker, ok?
But I have played Watchdogs and Uplink.
And maybe I did pick up a few skills,
which maybe did get me
into federal databases
most people can't get into, but...
Good for you, but I'm gonna go.
Your parents' names
are Marilyn and C.C. Batson.
What?
You were born in Zumbrota, Minnesota.
They divorced when you were three.
Your mom moved here that year.
20 months later, you got lost.
You never found them because
your dad's been in prison,
in Florida for 10 years.
And your mom's...
What?
Is she dead?
She's two subway stops away.
What?
You know, you didn't find her
because she reverted
to her maiden name.
Hey, Billy!
Billy!
Victor, get the keys.
I got it.
Kids, stay here in case Billy comes back.
Come on. Inside, let's go.
Wait.
I thought we were running after Billy?
No, we're gonna wait here for now.
Billy?
Freddy?
How quaint.
Actually, I take that back.
What a shithole.
Just a second.
Hey, look, I'm late for work
already, alright?
We don't need any
magazines or whatever.
Oh, I'm not.
Thanks, though.
You probably don't recognize me but...
I found my way home.
Mom.
It's me.
Oh, God.
Is it?
Hang on.
Who's at the door?
It's...
It's no one, Travis.
That wasn't Dad, was it?
No, I...
Listen...
it's...
It's really you?
I didn't mean to run away.
You know that, right?
I let go but it was by accident, I...
Yeah, I know, I know, I know.
I saw you.
What?
I saw you after.
So, it was never your fault.
I was 17.
And my dad, he kicked me out.
And your dad just...
decided not to be a part of anything.
You know it was hurting,
and I was screwed up.
I wanted the tiger.
I know, I know, honey but...
Mom's not exactly going pro here, ok?
Billy?
Billy!
Jesus Christ, Billy, this isn't funny!
Here you go, buddy.
That should warm you up.
Is that better?
Look, it's just once
I saw you with the police,
I realized that...
they could do a better job taking
care of you than I ever will.
But you're good, right?
I mean you landed on your feet.
Because I mean you look real good.
It's just...
Now is not a really good time
for me, Billy.
All I wanted to do is...
let you know I'm doing good but...
I have to get back
to my real family, so.
Here.
What's this?
Marilyn! What's going on out there?
You might need it more than me.
Freddy, you were right.
Sorry I yelled at you.
Come home, Billy.
Come home.
Billy! Supervillain!
Supervillain!
Shazam!
Who are you?
What do you want?
What do I want?
I want...
That.
Kick his ass, Billy!
Oh, God.
Yes, Billy.
Try it, by all means.
Let them go and I'll come inside.
No, first you come inside,
then maybe I'll let them go.
Good boy.
Because that's all you are, isn't it?
How old are you?
Basically, 15.
When I was a child,
the old man told me
I wasn't good enough.
And here you are,
a coward.
Run from me,
and that wizard chooses you?
You're not a hero.
But I'm gonna give you
the opportunity to be one.
Give me the power of a champion.
No, don't do it, Billy!
Give me the power,
and I'll let them go.
Darla, no.
Don't, don't go, Billy!
Don't go! Don't go, Billy!
No, no, I have to, I have to, it's...
It's what a good brother would do...
Right?
Billy.
I dedicated my life to getting here.
I scoured the earth.
No one believed me.
No one helped.
Not the wizard.
Not my family.
I only had myself.
I get it.
I get what that's like.
Feeling like you're all alone in the world.
Stand.
Feeling like there is that one thing,
if you could just find it.
Then you'd finally be good enough.
Stand.
The champion's name.
Say it.
Look no offense mister,
but I don't think these things
have your best interest at heart.
Don't listen to this child.
Take the staff.
Hold it and say the champion's name.
They're using you.
You have to see that.
That they are using you.
Say your name.
His name...
is Captain Sparklefingers.
And we're gonna keep throwing things,
at your big fat ugly ass head,
until you let our brother go.
Boy, am I glad I didn't sell that batarang.
Pedro, is that a lamp?
It's an ugly one.
Come on, come on, come on.
Guys, I appreciate the thought,
I really do.
But I don't think your
weapons are gonna help.
You can put them down now.
The door was right here.
Billy, how do we get out of here?
What, you think I know?
I don't know.
This way!
Go, go, go, go, go follow Darla.
Good job, Darla!
Go, go, go, go!
Kids?
Why is this open?
Freddy?
Mary?
Pedro, Pedro, come on.
Freddy, Freddy, keep up.
Darla, stay in front.
We gotta hurry.
So many doors.
One of these has to be a way out, right?
Yeah, I would hope so.
Not this one.
Ok, no more doors.
Nobody open any more doors.
Come on, Billy,
what are we gonna do?
Darla, I don't know.
Billy, yes, you do, just. just think.
How'd you get out last time?
Last, last time I thought about the
subway and I was on the subway.
Then Billy, look,
think about the subway.
Think about any place
except for here, ok?
Come on, come on, come on.
Why are you covering my eyes?
Really?
This is the first place you think of?
You're welcome.
Why can't I see what's inside?
You are not old enough.
Old enough to know
that was great music.
Not my thing.
Where's Freddy?
Yeah, you too, Sriracha, hey,
have a holly, jolly Christmas.
Freddy, what are you doing?
It's nice people.
Nice pe... Come on.
Is that glitter?
They have glitter.
Can I get glitter?
No, not from them.
Please?
No..
Darla.
Go, go, go, go!
Everybody go!
Freddy, Freddy, Freddy.
One, two, three. Up we go.
Carnival. Go, go, go, go.
Mary, go.
Go. Come on, Pedro.
Come on.
Don't run, but don't walk.
Just be cool.
Walk, just be cool,
act naturally, like kids naturally
act in a carnival.
He's not gonna look for you...
Is that him?
Oh, my God, guys.
Dude, it's Zap-tain America!
Hey, Powerboy.
He's an impersonator, ok?
Yeah, I'm an impersonator.
I'm a fake version of myself.
Don't take pictures...
Shazam!
Hey, where'd he go?
What, is he invisible now?
Oh, man, oh, man, I just spit on a baby!
Yo, what is that?
Who is that guy?
Champion!
You don't deserve that name.
See that? Look at that up there!
Hiding behind innocent people
who will now die.
Because deep down, you're
still just a scared, little boy.
Oh, no.
Run!
What do we do? What do we do?
Just hold on!
To what?
The bar, you idiot!
Well, you wanted me to be a hero.
Are you kidding?
Ok, no. Old guy's up there
harboring multiple spiritual entities,
plus, I mean, he has the same
powers as you, plus,
you know, he knows what he's doing,
plus, you're my best friend,
I don't want you to die.
If a superhero can't save his family,
he's not much of a hero.
That was a decent catchphrase.
Shazam!
Now let's try this again.
Or try that again.
Billy, look out!
Laser eyes?
Guys, he's got laser eyes!
Too bad your aim sucks balls!
That's his power matrix.
His what what?
When the demon guys leave his eye,
he loses his powers.
That's why the batarang hurt him.
Hey, over here!
Wait. What are you doing?
Trust me. Divide and conquer.
We separate the sins from the eye,
and he's just an old man.
Gather the mutts.
Run!
Darla, no!
Here, take it.
Take it, it's for you.
Hold it tight.
Close your eyes.
Everything's gonna be ok.
Ok?
Ok.
Get up!
Shazam!
Playtime's over, boy.
Your friends can't help you anymore.
Shazam!
Hey!
Nice trick.
Catchy.
One simple word.
I have a better trick.
Four words.
Kill the little girl.
No, No! No!
Stop!
Billy, there is one more
demon guy in his eye!
You gotta just rip it out of his face...
It's where he gets his power.
Reach for it.
I dare you.
Wise decision.
Hands on the staff.
Billy, don't do this. Billy!
Billy!
Don't do it, Billy! Don't!
Say my name,
so my power may flow through you.
I open my heart to you, Billy Batson.
And in so doing,
choose you as champion.
With your heart,
unlock your greatest power.
The thrones of our
brothers and sisters await!
All hands on deck.
Say my name.
Billy!
No, not my name. No.
Say the name that I say
to turn into this guy.
Shazam!
Guys.
What's happening?
I can fly!
Guys.
Check out these guns.
No.
It's not possible!
Gee whiz, mister.
Sorry I took your game.
Do you want it back?
Guys, I don't believe in violence,
but I think we should kick
this guy's butt, like,
really hard.
Guys, I think I can move really,
fast.
Hyperspeed!
Check!
Billy!
The eye.
Look out!
What?
What!
Dude!
You almost exploded me!
Dude, I've studied the fighting techniques
of every single superhero.
What do you got?
Well, that's terrifying.
Enough games, boy.
You think a pack of children can...
Wait, what?
You will beg for mercy,
as I feast on your heart.
Slow...
Are you making some big, evil guy
speech right now or something?
You're like, a mile
away from me right now.
There's cars and trucks...
I will have the world eating
out of the palm of my hand...
All I see is mouth moving.
I don't hear any...
Only I...
have the power to unleash...
Oh, whatever, screw it.
Oh, my gosh, those people!
Hi!
I caught you!
I got it!
Oh, my God, I do got it.
You're not gonna believe this,
but you're actually the first villain
I've ever fought.
It's, like, kind of a huge deal for me.
Somebody help!
Hadouken!
Hi!
It's really you.
My name is Darla
and I've been really good!
What?
Oh, crap.
No, no, no, no.
No, no!
Oh, my God!
Is he giving us suitcase wedgies?
So this is like the Seven
Deadly Sins, right?
I mean, I've never been
great at math, but...
The big angry one, that's Wrath yeah?
And then Gluttony, obvi...
Pride.
Greed and Sloth, Lust to...
I thought was gonna be way hotter,
I'm being honest.
But that's only six. Where's...
Where's lucky number seven?
Where's little man?
Where's Envy?
Is he just scared of me and my
family because we're so awesome?
Because I get that.
Like the other sins,
they get to come out and fight,
because they're big and strong and scary.
But Envy,
he's just a runt.
And that's why all the other sins
never invite him out to play, man.
Because they all know who'd win.
And it's not weak,
worthless, ugly.
Envy.
Gotcha.
Shazam!
Ready to go round up your buddies?
No.
No!
Here's the thing about power.
What good's power,
if you got nobody to share it with?
Nice.
Ta-da.
That's disgusting.
Fatality.
I got the voice.
What's that?
I can have anything I've ever wanted?
Billy, no.
No, no, no, no!
You should hear yourself.
That's not funny.
What, you think I'm gonna
put a demon ball in my head?
That's disgusting.
It's not funny. Pretty funny.
You got me going.
Guys, guys. Guys.
What?
Oh, hey.
Alright, we did it!
Yeah! Yeah!
Thank you!
We did it!
Yeah, you guys are all safe.
There's no more danger anymore.
We're fine. It's ok.
Alright, alright, alright.
We're good.
You sure this is gonna work?
Told ya.
You guys know what this place is, right?
A dark, haunted cave with demon statues.
Well, yes, but also...
Lair!
We got a lair!
Lair.
Yeah.
We got a lair.
What's a lair?
And thanks to six superheroes,
citizens are back in their homes,
safe again with their families.
And here with an eyewitness
account of the events...
It was fucking crazy, man!
Creatures from fucking hell!
Lightning coming out of
everyone's fucking everything.
And that is not fucking cool, man!
So, first day as a superhero.
I'm tired of it.
Every words...
Automatic top spot for best ever.
The man shattered
the glass noodle ceiling.
No. That's racist.
Not if I say it.
Guys.
All hands on deck.
Wait! wait, wait, wait.
Wait.
Thank you for this food.
Thank you for this day.
Thank you for this family.
I thought maybe this time I'd stay.
I mean, after all.
I'm home.
He better not sit at our table.
Nope.
Ok.
What are you doing?
Waiting for your
imaginary BFF to show up?
Yeah.
What are you guys doing here?
Well, we're having lunch with you.
But you guys have
different lunch periods.
Well, we made a very
special arrangement.
Darla, what's going on?
Why are you asking me?
Freddy Freeman!
This guy...
taught me everything I know
about being a dope superhero.
True story, you should
get some pointers,
from him. What's going on,
my best bud, in the whole world.
And also new kids that
I'm meeting for the first time,
but seem very cool?
I invited another friend,
I hope that's ok.
By LESAIGNEUR
Sync & corrections July 2019
Sun of Ra.
Ouroboros.
Solomon's...
Knot.
No! No!
Primitive symbols.
You walking talking monkeys
with your cave drawings.
You assume there is only one way
to gain magic.
No, no, no.
There are more ways
than a mind can imagine.
What in God's name?
I name the gods, Doctor.
Not the other way around.
Oh, what fun
we're going to have together.
The Seven Realms are about to be ours.
Don't beat yourself up, buddy.
You're gonna find someone.
Yeah, I'm sure.
Because there is plenty of fish
in the sea.
Of course it's not real.
I can't talk to fish.
Even if I could, I mean, honestly,
what could we do with that that's cool?
I don't know, maybe command
an army of billions in the ocean.
Oh, yeah.
Well, that's not that cool.