On October 13, 1972,
an Uruguayan plane
crashed in the Andean Mountain Range.
Forty of us passengers
and five crew members
were on board the plane.
Some say it was a tragedy.
Others call it a miracle.
What really happened?
What happens when the world abandons you?
When you have no clothes…
and you're freezing?
When you have no food, and you're dying?
The answer's in the mountain.
We have to go back to the past
to understand that the past
is what changes the most.
MONTEVIDEO, URUGUAY
OCTOBER 1972
Let's go! Get in there!
C'mon, Olds! Yeah! Come on! We got this!
That ball's ours! Push!
Go, Christians!
C'mon, Christians! Push!
Get in there! Let's go! Let's go!
Get it! Come on!
Go, Roberto!
Pass it to Nando!
Roberto, pass it!
-To Nando!
-Come on!
Pass it! Roberto, pass it!
Pass it!
Pass it.
There were four players ahead of you.
I couldn't pass.
-You could have, but you thought too much.
-You gotta think less and do more.
-You couldn't have done better.
-Couldn't have done worse.
I messed up once!
We won the last cup because of me.
Because of you?
All right, all right! Knock it off!
Hey. What's so funny, huh? Today's score?
Roberto, you trust me, right?
So, when I say,
"Pass it," you pass it. Okay?
And when I say the trip money
is due today, I expect it today!
Okay? We have half a plane to fill.
Dan, is your cousin coming?
-Yeah. It'll be the four of us.
-Our money.
No envelope? Great, Coco.
-No.
-Anybody else, then?
Gastón, are your friends in?
-Yeah. I convinced them.
-You're sure?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Well, except one.
"'You are my beloved Son,'
He said."
"And at once, the Spirit
drove Jesus out into the desert."
"And He remained in the desert
for 40 days and nights,
being tempted by Satan at all times."
"'If you are the Son of God,
tell these stones
to become bread,' the tempter said."
"But Jesus answered,
'Man shall not live on bread alone…'"
Psst!
Pancho.
Pancho!
…and gave it
to them, saying, "This is my body…"
Pancho, for Numa. Numa.
We proclaim your death,
O Lord, and profess your resurrection
until you come again, Jesus.
Come on, Alfredo.
Hey! You!
Come here. Come here. Come here.
Hand this paper to Pancho. Right there.
Thanks.
Psst, Numa.
Excuse me. Can you hand this to him?
Gastón.
COME TO CHILE, MAN!
Workers and students,
hand in hand, we stand!
No, it's the final Commercial Law test.
-I can't go.
-No! It's gonna get postponed anyway.
-For two weeks. Just look outside!
-It's not about the test.
-I don't care about rugby.
-Rugby? Rugby's the least of it!
Santiago de Chile, $45.
You'll never find a cheaper ticket.
-Never!
-In your life!
Do you know what this is?
This little list here has all the numbers
of the girls we've met there.
-Graciela…
-Flamboyant.
-Silvia…
-Fine.
-Beatriz…
-A lioness.
-Nélida…
-No, not her.
What? Nélida's amazing. Knock it off.
Nélida messed you up,
left you crying all around Montevideo.
-Whoa! What is wrong with you?
-No, no…
You keep this thing.
Don't let Gastón touch it.
Okay? Let's go grab another drink.
Come on.
-Stop. What is wrong with you?
-You gotta relax.
Don't let me travel with these two morons.
Please. I beg of you.
You're not gonna convince me,
Pancho.
-Want a good argument to talk you into it?
-Do it.
I really want you to go.
'Cause you graduate in a couple of months,
and you'll start working nonstop.
You'll be the best lawyer in all
of Montevideo, and we'll be proud of you.
But we're gonna have different lives.
This may actually be
the last trip we take together, you know?
You trying to make me cry, man?
Workers and students,
hand in hand, we stand!
Good evening.
Who's a good boy?
How's it goin', buddy?
Champ.
What do you think?
Should we go?
It's eight o'clock
this Thursday morning in Montevideo.
Jackass!
This is Berch Rupenian
from Impactos on Independencia Radio.
We're here, kicking off
this four-day long weekend
with a forecast of sunshine
and nice weather
to make your weekend even better.
Oh, Panchito.
Have a good one.
Honey, can you help me
find the boys, please?
Numa!
Hey.
Let's do it.
Canessa! Roberto Canessa!
Alexis. Alexis Hounié!
Enrique Platero.
Felipe Maquirriain.
Francisco Abal. Pancho.
Bye.
-Goodbye.
-Okay. Let's go.
Bye-bye.
-Bye.
-Mwah!
-Be good.
-Okay.
-Okay?
-Kiss Mommy.
-See you! Bye-bye. I love you.
-Love you, Mom. We'll miss you.
One. Two.
-Javier, smile.
-Three.
-Done.
-Let's go!
Bravo!
Did you hear it click?
-Yeah, I got it.
-Perfect.
Dude!
My name is Numa Turcatti.
I'm 24 years old.
It's great that all these guys get to go.
I look around,
and I barely know anyone here…
but at the same time,
it all feels familiar.
Most of them are young, like me.
Lovingly raised in houses near the sea.
Hey!
For some of them,
it's their first trip away from home.
Sit down! Carlitos, stop! Just sit down!
Come on!
Yeah, you're very talented.
Sit down.
Could be anything.
Coco, look at the camera.
Looks good.
Hey! Hey, Diego! Come on!
Hey. That's a pretty nice hand, man.
Dude, your cousin--
Opa! We just got bitten by the shark.
The mountain range, huh?
Is it true these mountains try to suck up
anyone who passes over them?
Yeah. It's true.
The warm winds
from the plains of Argentina
collide with the cold winds
of the mountains
and create a suction effect.
Nah. You're joking.
I'm not joking.
That's why there's turbulence.
But, you know, we're one step ahead.
Check it out.
This is the mountain range.
And now, we have to go from here.
But the route isn't a straight line.
Look. You can't cross it just like that.
The range is massive.
That's why we have to travel south,
looking for a lower passage through it.
We cross it, and once in Chile,
we just turn north in Curicó.
And in ten minutes,
we'll be landing in Santiago.
Attention, passengers.
Please fasten your seat belts.
-In a few minutes, we'll be in Santiago.
-Go and deal the cards, okay?
Arturo!
Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen.
This is your captain, General Carlos Páez.
Everybody, please fasten your seat belts.
Bodies are not allowed
to be scattered in the Andes.
Please recommend Casapueblo Airlines
for the forthcoming flights!
Sit down! Sit down!
Stay there.
-Bravo!
-Carlitos! Carlitos!
Stop. Fasten your seat belt, okay?
Go to the front.
I need some room to sit down.
Come on.
Sit down. I'll be right there.
Hey! What's the matter? You scared?
Careful, Javier. Grab my hand.
Nando. Nando. Your seat belt.
-No! Sit back down. Sit down.
-I gotta get there.
Nando! Nando!
-Susy!
-Don't get up!
More power! Give it power!
No, no!
-Our Father, who art in heaven…
-I don't wanna die here!
Hail Mary, full of grace…
Gastón!
Give me your hand, Roberto.
I'm down here!
Eduardo. Eduardo. Eduardo.
-Shh.
-Marcelo.
Yeah, man. Yeah. I'm right here. I'm here.
I don't want
anyone else to die!
I don't want anyone else to die!
Put him against the wall.
Okay, that's great. Lift him up.
That's it. I need you to be calm.
Relax, relax. Now, breathe.
Look into my eyes.
Look into my eyes. I study medicine.
I'm Roberto. What's your name?
-Álvaro.
-Álvaro what?
Álvaro… Álvaro--
Please wake up!
The pilot's alive! Here, help me.
The pilot is alive!
Come on, Gustavo.
On three, okay? One, two, three.
This way. Here.
DAY 1
OCTOBER 13, 1972
Right here.
Nothing's turning on. Not even the lights.
I need you to tell me how the radio works.
What? What do I press?
Hello? We crashed in the mountains.
We're Uruguayans.
We crashed in the mountains.
Is anybody there?
Does this even work?
-Huh? What?
-We passed Curicó.
What do you mean?
We're past Curicó.
What about Curicó?
Say it again. Come on.
Hey!
May… may God be with you.
The night hits like an ambush.
In the span of minutes,
temperature drops 86 degrees.
If the plane crash didn't kill us,
the cold will.
We huddle together the best we can.
Living and dead… as one.
I'm going home now.
Your passport! Give me your passport!
Your passport!
Grab my hand tighter.
That's how we spend the night.
Nobody fall asleep!
You'll freeze to death!
-The injured scream.
-Come on!
So do the rest of us.
Let go of me! Mommy!
Mommy!
Hold me.
Tighter, Pancho.
Help me. Help me.
Help.
Help!
We're still alive, Pancho.
You got another one?
Do we know where we are?
No, not yet.
Marcelo. We lost three more.
Pancho Abal and Martínez Lamas.
And the lady who was screaming.
Gastón got sucked out
when the tail broke off.
Also, my cousin Daniel
and Guido and Alexis.
Nando may not make it.
His sister's really weak.
We don't have anywhere
to take care of the injured.
Let's make room inside the plane.
Let's take out the seats
so we can all fit in there.
C'mon, guys. C'mon.
We need
to prioritize the injured.
So let's clean up this side of the plane.
That's where the sun is.
We'll take anyone who's hurt over there
and help them as much as we can.
-Platero!
-Yeah?
Anything you find that might be useful,
put in a suitcase. Okay?
See if you can find
any food in the luggage.
Anything you find,
put in a single suitcase.
Bobby. Bobby.
What do we do with the dead?
We put them over there, on that side.
Until rescue comes.
EUGENIA DOLGAY DE PARRADO - AGE 50
GRAZIELA GUMILA DE MARIANI - AGE 43
DANTE LAGURARA - AGE 41
ESTHER HORTA DE NICOLA - AGE 40
FRANCISCO NICOLA - AGE 40
JULIO FERRADÁS - AGE 39
JULIO MARTÍNEZ LAMAS - AGE 24
FELIPE MAQUIRRIAIN - AGE 22
FRANCISCO "PANCHO" ABAL - AGE 21
FERNANDO VÁZQUEZ - AGE 20
CARLOS VALETA - AGE 18
Here, take one, okay?
We gotta make it last.
Hey!
Help!
-Help!
-Hey!
Over here!
DAY 2
OCTOBER 14, 1972
-Wait. Stop.
-No. Isn't there a bigger one?
-That one there. Roy!
-No! Don't touch it.
See if you can find rags,
coats, clothes.
Here. Take it.
Come on.
-Look for fabric, clothes…
-Give me that one.
Coco! Take this. It's bigger.
How many are gonna die tonight?
No one's gonna die, Carlitos.
I promise.
Pancho! More bags!
Here, cover all those holes
so that the cold doesn't get in at night.
Marcelo.
They're coming.
Tomorrow.
Fito Strauch
isn't as optimistic as Marcelo.
He's a reasonable man.
He would never go against the captain.
But he doesn't like what he sees.
This is a place where life is impossible.
Out here, we are an anomaly.
DAY 3
OCTOBER 15, 1972
Nando. Nando.
No. No. Uh, Nando… Don't.
Shit.
-Here. Take it.
-Give me that. Thanks.
I can't hear you.
What happened?
Plane crashed.
My sister?
Susy?
Susy's over there, resting.
Where's my mom?
Your mom died, Nando.
-Bye, Dad.
-See you Monday. Take care of them.
Yeah, yeah.
I got it.
-How long have we been here?
-Three days.
They seen us?
Give me that. Okay. Thanks.
Hey!
-Over here!
-Hey! It rocked its wings! They saw us!
-They saw us!
-The wings moved!
-Over here!
-Whoo-hoo!
Do you know what I'd love to eat?
A chivito from Arocena's.
A full-stuffed Canadian chivito?
A milanesa from La Mascota.
-Oh yeah. That'd be great.
-Oh. Fries on the side.
-I love their milanesas. So good.
-They're the best.
Incredible. And the size
of the milanesas of La Mascota.
-Fries… and ham. Bacon.
-Hey.
They could've dropped
some food from the plane, right?
Well, that wouldn't make sense.
If they drop a package like that,
it'd sink in the snow.
We'd never get it.
Bring in the injured.
Easy. Easy. Okay.
Careful with his legs. Right there.
You'll be better there, Arturo. Easy.
It's getting closer.
I don't see anything.
-Yeah. Me neither.
-You see something?
I don't see it.
The Andes are massive.
They must be organizing
the search somehow.
By zone.
Yesterday, they were here.
We saw them fly over.
We heard them today,
but we couldn't see them.
They're probably searching somewhere else.
If they're looking, they didn't see us.
They're coming.
-We need to have faith.
-Faith? What faith?
Don't talk this way
in front of the younger guys.
If you tell them,
you'll destroy their morale.
You guys are the oldest ones here,
and you have a responsibility.
They will rescue us.
-We won't last like this.
-How long can we survive?
-Know the rule of three?
-No.
Three minutes without air,
three days without water,
and three weeks without food.
Three weeks without food?
I haven't eaten in three days.
I'm starving.
It's a lot worse here.
There's the altitude and the cold.
We're burning three
or four times as many calories.
Roque told us about the batteries.
They were in the tail of the plane.
In my opinion, we should go up there,
where the plane crashed,
and get the radio working.
We gotta keep going!
The snow is still firm!
-Let's take advantage of that!
-Numa! Save your energy!
I don't want to carry you back.
Fito.
What happened?
You can't see the plane.
They won't find it,
even if they fly over us.
We're going back!
It's been six days without food.
Last night,
we split what we had left.
A pack of crackers.
There's nothing else.
Carlitos came over
to tell me something.
He says that Nando's losing his mind.
Last night, he went up to him
and said he wasn't gonna starve to death.
I'm not gonna starve to death.
That he'd eat the bodies
if he had to.
If I have to, I'll eat the bodies.
I told him
that we don't have another option.
If we wanna get rescued,
we gotta stay alive.
And to stay alive, we need to eat.
Marcelo.
We're dying.
We're starving, and they're not coming.
-We're wasting ourselves away.
-Seven days and nights without food.
Nothing. If we don't eat, we're gonna die.
Eat what?
Are you crazy, Roberto?
You gonna make everyone else crazy too?
There's food outside.
There's protein outside.
Energy that we need.
Do you know what's crazy?
To go on like this!
Roberto!
Roberto's right. We're talking
about living or dying, Marcelo.
And if help arrives
in two days, then what, Fito?
Can't we wait a couple more days?
-Know what happens when you stop eating?
-Roberto!
The body dries out. Just like plants.
You can't use your brain.
Because it dries out too, Marcelo.
-My pee is black.
-Yeah, my pee is black too.
If we do it…
what will happen to us?
Will God forgive us?
God put us in this situation.
He'll understand we need to survive.
God has nothing to do with this.
I'm sorry, Marcelo.
It's luck that brought us here.
-Bad luck.
-It's meat.
-It's people we love, Arturo.
-And how do you cut up a body?
And who would even do it?
Me.
I'll do it.
-I will too.
-I'm not eating them.
That's something I refuse to do.
Is it legal to eat a dead person?
Won't we go to prison if we do it?
-It would be like organ donation.
-What's wrong with you?
For it to be organ donation,
you need to have the donor's consent.
It's a crime, Marcelo.
We can't just take, defile, and desecrate
someone's body without consent.
-We need to eat, Numa.
-We don't have the right to.
And don't I have the right
to do everything I can to survive?
Who's gonna take that from me? You?
Susy?
Susy. Susy, breathe.
No, no, no. Susana.
Susana, come on. No. No. Gustavo!
Gustavo, help me, please.
-Susana. Please help me!
-What's wrong?
She's not breathing. I don't know.
Okay. Put her legs over there.
I'll hold her head.
Roberto.
She's not breathing, Roberto.
-Help her.
-Bring her here. Right there.
Help me, Gustavo! Hurry!
-She's not breathing.
-Susy!
Coco Nicolich
wrote a letter to his parents.
"Dear Mom and Dad,
I'm writing to you
eight days after the plane crashed."
"We're in a beautiful place,
completely surrounded by mountains,
with a lake nearby,
that will unfreeze when the thaw starts."
"We're all doing fine."
"As of now, there are 27 survivors."
"Nando Parrado's sister
passed away today."
"I miss you very much."
"And I'm constantly praying to God,
that he at least
lets me see you one last time."
This is a cemetery.
And I'm not staying here.
It hurts! My stomach hurts!
I know, Moncho.
You need to calm down.
-Just breathe.
-I can't breathe.
Look at me, Moncho. Look at me. Breathe.
-I don't want to!
-Just breathe.
-I can't! I can't! Help me!
-Yes, you can.
Look at me and breathe!
I gotta get outta here!
I'm suffocating!
You can't go outside now, Moncho.
Look at me. You have to calm down.
-I don't want to die here.
-You're not going to die.
-I don't want to die here!
-You're not dying, Moncho.
DAY 9
OCTOBER 21, 1972
If I die,
I give you permission to feed on my body.
So you can keep on living.
I give you my consent as well.
And you have mine.
You also have my permission.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread.
And forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil. Amen.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread.
And forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil. Amen.
On earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread.
And forgive us our trespasses.
And lead us not into temptation.
But deliver us from evil. Amen.
I'm sorry.
Sorry, Marcelo.
Will God forgive us?
We don't have a choice.
I'm sorry, Marcelo.
Don't give me
that look, Coche.
I'm not giving you a look.
The Strauch cousins
have the most difficult job.
The one no one wants to do.
Fito chooses the bodies.
And they cut them up in secret.
Away from everyone else.
That's how they keep
the ones who eat sane.
Hey!
-What?
-I found something!
A radio!
It's all wet.
Come on, Roy. Fix it.
Those of us who don't eat
keep watching the sky.
Waiting for a sign.
Left or right?
Higher, Coco.
If you want it higher,
we'll need to get more wire
and tie it to a pole or something.
Hold it there.
A little bit to the left.
A bit more.
Less. A little to the right.
There.
Take this.
What is that?
Eat it. It's easier with snow.
No, thank you.
I'll be okay.
You have to eat, Numa.
It's not right, Pancho.
No!
Why?!
This is Spectator.
We're coming to you with new information.
The search for the Uruguayan plane
that crashed in the Andean Mountain Range
with the rugby team Old Christians,
has come to an end.
In the ten days required by the protocol,
66 search and rescue missions
were conducted,
using 17 planes from the Chilean Air Force
as well as aircrafts of the Uruguayan
and Argentinian Air Forces,
but to no avail.
Search efforts will resume
early next year,
when the thawing of the ice will provide
better conditions of visibility
to find the wreckage.
The Chilean Air Force's rescue service
has reported that, in the 34 air accidents
that have occurred in the Andes,
no survivors have ever been found.
We'll return with more news
after a commercial break.
Made with premium quality parts.
Beautiful colors and designs.
Customizable,
with three different models.
Bicicletas Victoria,
the leading bicycle brand.
I was wrong.
I begged you to wait
to be rescued for nothing.
But if I can ask you for one more thing,
I'm asking you to eat.
The only thing we have left
is our life.
And we have to fight for it.
We went up to look
for the tail of the plane.
Without telling anyone.
With no plan.
We need to find batteries for the radio.
Over there.
I'm here, Gastón.
That's Daniel Shaw, Fito's cousin.
He was behind me on the plane
and flew out.
Sun's going down.
-We should go back.
-No.
Let's look some more. Please.
If we found all these things here,
the tail shouldn't be far behind.
Who's up there?
Numa, Gustavo, and Maspons.
They left with nothing.
The temperature up there
must drop 80 or 90 degrees.
And it's gonna be night soon.
The sun had melted the snow,
and we were knee-deep in it.
No, that way!
We can barely keep going,
and the night traps us.
Everyone, get closer! Get closer.
Calm down!
Come on!
Please, Lord,
don't let us freeze to death.
Shake the ice off my back!
The more we try to get out,
the more the mountain resists.
Hey!
Gus, eat.
So, Numa.
What did you see up there?
Numa.
Tell me.
Only snow and mountains.
In every direction?
As far as I could see,
that's all there is.
And to the west?
-See anything behind that ice wall?
-No.
You can't see anything.
Chile's right behind it.
We need to go there.
But you gotta eat, Numa.
Or you won't make it to Chile.
Come on.
I don't chew
more than two or three times.
And I force myself to swallow.
For the first time,
I imagine the possibility
that feels increasingly real
of not getting back home.
But I look at Nando, and I feel hope.
He trains every day,
obsessed with one idea.
Beyond that mountain
lie the green valleys of Chile.
Climbing it is suicide.
But I'm going with him.
DAY 17
FIFTH DAY OF THE STORM
Getting worse.
Okay, Vasco. Check this out.
'Cause your rhyme was all talk
Tell me, why don't you get up
And go out for a quick walk?
You're an idiot, Bobby!
-Okay, Carlitos.
-Yeah, Carlitos.
We can barely fit 27 of us
But that's all right
While we're all cramped in here
Up in the presidential suite, they're fine
While a terrible tragedy unfolds
I want to escape
Yet I see many heroes without capes
Aww.
And although sometimes
Anger overtakes me
Standing by your side
Truly strengthens me
-Deep!
-Oh!
Even though we're now freezing to death
On this plane
I have Coco's warm feet here
And can't complain
But, Coco
Don't get used to this situation
We gotta get back to Uruguay
Our beloved nation
-That's right!
-Come on, Coco. Go.
Okay, but mine's kinda sentimental.
On October thirteenth
My mother's birthday I did miss
So I humbly ask God
To finally come home
So I can give her a big kiss
-Very sweet.
-Nice.
There are some decent people
In this space
Yet some know not the candidates
For the presidential race
They are a tremendous disgrace
-That was awful!
-That's terrible!
-All right.
-Terrible. The worst.
At least I tried, you know?
You guys didn't do anything.
Here in the mountains
The situation's intense
It makes me wanna start running
Like a puma
But I will not leave this place
Without first hearing a rhyme
From the reserved Numa
Uh…
On, uh, this extremely freezing mountain
Where… not even a spider can walk
In the… in the fridge
On the mountain of the frozen fridge
Forget it.
Of the mountain… All right.
Bravo! Good!
Come on, Numa!
Bravo!
Hey, I tried.
Roy!
-Down there! Down there!
-Here! I'm here!
Dig!
Fito!
-Tintín!
-Hey!
-Hold on!
Hold on! Hold on!
Hold on! We're getting you out!
-Coche, help.
-Get him out!
-Dig! Come on!
-Hold on!
Hold on!
Everyone, dig! Dig!
Help! Help! Help!
Hang in there, Numa!
Numa, I'll get you out!
No! Coco!
-Over here!
-Coco!
Liliana's down there!
Don't step on her!
Watch out! Liliana's down there!
For God's sake!
Please, don't step on her!
Liliana's there!
Liliana, hold on! Don't step on her!
Liliana's down there! Please!
Don't step on her! Baby, I'll get you out!
She's here!
Coco! No!
-Coco! Coco! Coco! Coco!
-Help me!
Coco!
Breathe! Breathe! Breathe!
Breathe, baby. Breathe.
Breathe! Oh God!
Breathe, baby. Please.
Breathe. Oh, baby. Just breathe.
-He's not breathing!
-Breathe.
Hold on!
Please breathe.
No, my love, don't go.
What's that noise?
What's happening?
What is that?
Come on.
-There's air.
-Oxygen's coming in.
-Yes.
Is everyone okay?
-Arturo?
-I'm alive!
Javier's alive. Liliana's gone.
-Vasco?
-Right here. I'm alive.
-I'm alive too! It's Roberto.
-Yeah, I'm alive! It's Moncho.
Pedro Algorta here.
Diego? Diego?
Diego's dead, Fito!
He's gone. And Roque. Roque too.
Maspons couldn't make it.
-It's Nando. I'm alive.
-Enrique and Juan Carlos are dead.
-Tintín, you okay?
-I'm here.
Coco?
-Coco?
-Coco's dead. This is Roy.
-And Marcelo? Marcelo?
-Marcelo!
-Marcelo?
-Captain!
Marcelo!
Marcelo was buried.
He stopped feeling cold
because he didn't feel anything.
And to stop feeling here is a relief.
For 17 days,
we've waited for a moment like that.
A moment of calm.
A second of quiet.
-How much snow could we have on top?
-It could be the entire mountain.
Everyone, pray! Right now!
"And blessed is the fruit
of thy womb, Jesus."
Today is October 30th.
Today is my birthday.
I'm turning 25.
Today it's hard
not to think of home.
If light comes in,
we shouldn't be too deep in the snow.
How long do you think we'll be here?
We can't go out until the storm's over.
DAY 18
TWO DAYS BURIED
The hunger is unbearable.
Till now, the Strauch cousins
have been able to make the meat just meat.
Meat without a name.
Without a face.
But that's impossible here.
So what?
Are we gonna do nothing?
Roberto.
To survive, we gotta eat.
Now you're letting yourselves die?
After all we've been through?
We gotta get out. I'm not staying here!
We gotta get out!
What else do you want?
Stop, Numa!
Come on!
Stop it, Numa!
Numa!
DAY 20
FOUR DAYS BURIED
I see the sky!
Come on, Moncho. Go first. You're smaller.
Go. Go, go, go.
The sun!
Help me! Come on!
We made it.
Hey! What do you see?
Margarita's out here, Álvaro.
-Your girlfriend!
-In a bikini!
Tell her I'll be right up!
-We're alive!
-We made it!
Hey! Come on!
The bottle. The bottle.
How's the leg?
It's okay.
It's just a cut. I'll be fine.
Save your energy, Numa.
'Cause I don't have any left.
Don't say that, Arturo.
Don't lose your faith.
I have more faith
than I ever had in my whole life.
What, are you an altar boy now?
Don't laugh at me.
'Cause my faith…
Sorry, Numa.
…isn't in your God.
Because that God
tells me what I'm supposed to do at home.
But he doesn't tell me
what to do on the mountain.
What's happening here
is a completely different situation.
Numa.
This is my heaven.
I believe in another god.
I believe
in the god that Roberto
keeps inside his head
when he comes to heal each of my wounds.
In the god that Nando keeps in his legs
and that lets him continue walking
no matter what.
I believe in Daniel's hands…
when he cuts the meat.
And Fito, when he gives it to us
without saying which of our friends
it belonged to.
That way, we can eat it without…
without having to remember their faces.
That's the god I believe in.
I believe in Roberto.
In Nando.
In Daniel.
In Fito.
And in our dead friends.
You're a philosopher, Arturo.
Altar boy and philosopher.
Okay.
-Come on!
-We have to go now.
-Look at the sun.
-We need to wait.
-Wait for what?
-To be prepared.
What if we get caught in a storm?
We need temperatures to rise.
We can't spend a single night
out in the open.
Tell him, Numa.
The thaw starts on November 15th.
There's a lower risk of storms
because temperatures rise.
-Two weeks… just waiting.
-No. Two weeks of preparation.
So far, we've always gone out
without a plan, and we've failed.
We don't even know
what kind of distance we're facing.
Hey!
We need help over here!
-Go grab those chairs!
-Come on. Dig
Come help.
All good? Grab those plates.
-Yeah? Let's go.
-Need help?
-How can I help?
-Dig on the other side.
I don't get it.
I thought you didn't wanna die here.
DAY 34
THE THAW BEGINS
Help me, Roberto. Give me a hand.
Watch it. Hold his head, please.
Very slowly. Lift him. There you go.
Slowly. Slowly. Slowly.
Easy, easy, Arturo. That's it.
Let's lift his shirt up slowly.
That's it.
Arturo's really sick.
He's got three days. Vasco, maybe five.
What do you think?
About what?
-The days they have left.
-What do you want, Gustavo?
Say it.
What is it?
Roberto, there's nothing more
we can do here as doctors.
We're gonna end up becoming gravediggers.
Now, I know how hard it is.
But you're the strongest player
on the team.
Now you have to walk for everyone else.
Pass it!
Roberto, pass it!
Careful. Over there.
Move him.
Let's put him here.
I'm here. I'm here. Breathe, Arturo.
Breathe with me. Come on.
Arturo Nogueira's lungs
are filled with fluid.
He can't hold on.
There you go. There you go.
-Gustavo tries to help.
-That's it. There you go. There you go.
But no one can breathe for him.
Good job. Good job.
There you go. There you go.
We have to try everything.
Four of us volunteer.
We head downhill towards Argentina.
With warmer clothes…
in the hope of surviving a night outside.
DAY 36
EXPEDITION EAST, ARGENTINA
Numa!
Ow.
Numa, you okay?
It's infected.
Let's go back.
We can't carry him.
-Roberto!
-I'm going back alone.
The plane's still close.
Okay.
Sorry.
-What happened?
-Numa?
Numa?
Where are the others?
Numa, answer me. Say something.
It's okay. We're here.
What happened?
Where is he? My dad!
-No, Vasco. We're here.
-Dad?
-Calm down. We're here.
-Where's Dad?
Look at me.
Look at me. Your dad's here.
Look at me. We're here. We're here.
-Dad! Dad, come here!
-Stop.
Calm down.
We're here.
Vasco.
-Hey, Vasco! Look at me!
-Dad!
Flight 328,
we are now boarding at gate ten.
-Thanks.
-Rafael… Rafael Echevarren.
Huh? Echavarren!
I don't understand, Javier.
From the very first moment
we crashed in this place,
I've tried to help as much as I could.
I tried…
to always do the right thing, you know?
And now, with my leg like this…
I'm useless.
What does it all mean?
What's the meaning of the death of Arturo?
The death of Vasco?
Or the death of everybody else?
Liliana gave everything. Always.
During the avalanche,
while buried under the snow,
I could feel her body underneath mine.
I remember there was only a few inches
between me and the surface.
I could actually pull my head out, and…
and shout at her
with all my strength I had.
"Liliana, hold on!"
"I'll get you out. I'm alive, love."
I saw them stepping over where she was,
and I shouted, "Oh, my God!
Don't step on her! Don't!"
"Don't step on her, please!
Liliana's trapped below."
But there was simply no way to get her out
if I didn't get out first.
But I was unable to move because my feet
were pressed against her chest.
And if I pushed against her,
it would make her sink deeper and deeper.
What is the meaning of that, Numa?
When we finally got to Liliana,
she was just a lifeless corpse.
At that moment,
as they kept digging up friends,
one dead, one alive, one dead, one alive…
then… I hugged Liliana
with all my strength.
And I felt a love
I'd never felt in my life.
And I realized that I had a purpose,
which was to take that love that
I was squeezing there against my chest…
and bring it to my kids back home.
Her death was not in vain.
That wound doesn't make you useless.
Someone ripped
all the parts off.
-Are you serious?
-Are you helping?
Nando?
They told me you've got lazy.
That you sleep all day. Why?
-You need to train, Numa.
-Why are you here?
You're not gonna believe this.
We walked for about
two, three hours, towards the east.
Until, suddenly,
behind a hill, we found the tail.
I can't believe we found it.
It… it catapulted itself forward.
To the other side.
It was amazing.
It was completely full
of scattered suitcases, clean coats.
We found bottles of rum.
Cigarettes.
And chocolate.
Stop, stop, stop, stop. Not the wrapper.
Now you're telling me
what to eat, man?
There you go.
Mm!
You were right, Numa.
We spent a night out in the open,
and we almost didn't make it.
But we found the plane's batteries.
They were in the tail.
It'll be much easier
to bring the radio here.
Did you see Roy fixed the portable radio?
And Roberto thinks he can get
that one in the plane to work too.
We're going back down there.
We need to try.
Nando, Roberto and Tintín leave
with Roy towards the tail of the plane.
I wish I could go with them.
Roy is weak and doesn't think
the radio will work.
Come on, Roy. Not a lot of time.
He's terrified.
But he's doing it for the team.
-I don't believe it.
-Nice, Roy.
-1-C-6-0-1.
-Which one is it?
B… Not this one. What was it?
Uh…
-One, seven.
-Seven…
What if it doesn't work?
Huh?
What do we do?
I guess we start walking back.
Right, Roberto?
Toward the west. To Chile.
Hello?
We're the Uruguayans
who crash-landed in the Andes.
Can you hear me? We're still here!
Hello?
Uh, I don't know. I never tried it.
With every day that passes,
we lose more of our strength.
It's okay.
The food rations aren't enough,
so we strip the bones of meat.
What was once unthinkable
became routine.
…number
of intercontinental ballistic missiles
and other strategic offensive arms.
We just stopped caring.
Come on.
Here. Eat a little.
You have to eat, Numa.
Half and half.
You can't give up now.
No, I'm not givin' up, Pancho.
You know, I'm dying.
And it hurts me to not…
not be able to do more for you.
Don't say that.
Think of yourself.
You want me to think of myself?
Look at me.
I'm 25 years old, Pancho.
I've got my enitre life ahead.
I've got everything left to do.
I want to… see my siblings again.
See my mother, my father.
I want to dance.
-Numa, you don't dance.
-I know.
But now I want to.
I wanna do it all, Pancho.
I want to laugh.
-I want to cry.
-Then cry.
-I can't.
-Cry.
Do it. Come on, cry.
Just cry with me.
What's so funny?
Cry with me. Come on. Let it go.
Do it, moron.
Come on.
Nando!
Look at this.
-What's that?
-It's waterproof.
We can use it, yeah?
It was covering some pipes.
-Is there more?
-Yeah. There's a lot.
Two, four… One, C.
No!
AS OF TODAY, NOVEMBER 29, 1972,
THERE ARE 17 MORE SURVIVORS UP ABOVE
IN THE URUGUAYAN PLANE
THAT CRASHED IN THE MOUNTAINS
What happened?
The radio didn't work.
But we found this fabric there.
-What's this?
-It's waterproof.
-We can make a vest.
-No. Not a vest, Tintín.
Let's make a sleeping bag.
With a sleeping bag, we could get
through the night. There's enough fabric.
Or we could make a big one.
When are we leaving, Roberto?
Roberto.
When?
As soon as the sleeping bag is done.
58 days after the disappearance
of the Fairchild 571 aircraft
from the Uruguayan Air Force
with 40 passengers and five crew members
chartered to transport a rugby team
from the Old Christians Club
and their companions to Chile.
The local Air Force has specially equipped
a C-47 aircraft
to resume the search
in the Andean Mountain Range.
Come on, Roberto.
We can't go back to the beginning.
They said they'll look for us.
Those morons who flew right over
and… and didn't see us?
They're looking for bodies.
-We've been lost here for two months.
-Two months, Roberto.
Do you still believe
they think we're alive?
-Well, we are alive.
-Alive?
Just look at us. Look at this.
This isn't being alive.
We won't make it
just by praying, you know.
So you want to climb the mountain
sleeping in this?
What are you doing, Roberto?
-Stop!
-Roberto.
You didn't like it?
Guys.
I'm gonna take a picture.
Tintín insists on taking pictures.
Like he's capturing memories of a trip
that he's comin' back from.
I wonder who these pictures are for.
For us?
Smile, asshole.
I'll never see them.
Come on. We can still smile.
Maybe they're for our families.
Or for other people
who are remembering us now,
looking at pictures of us
that were taken in the past.
Carlos. Look at me!
And when they look at them,
we'll live again in their imaginations.
Because they'll ask themselves
the same questions we're asking.
"What happened to them?"
What happened to us?
Who were we on the mountain?
Nando.
I want you to know that
you have my permission to use my body.
Stop fucking around. Don't say that.
I'm know I'm not coming back.
Don't say that.
It's the truth.
But it's all right.
It's fine. I'm at peace.
I'm prepared for what's coming.
We both are, my brother.
And I'm so happy
to know that you guys are gonna make it.
That makes me feel very happy, Nando.
Thank you.
My name is Numa.
I died on December 11, 1972.
In my sleep.
THERE IS NO GREATER LOVE
THAN TO GIVE ONE'S LIFE FOR FRIENDS
We're leaving tomorrow.
You got this.
-Best of luck, Roberto.
-Thank you.
-Take care.
-You too.
Keep going.
-No matter what.
-My friend.
-Give me one more.
-Take care.
Carlitos.
Yeah?
You can use the bodies
of my mom and Susy. Okay?
Let's go!
-Yeah, yeah!
-You can do it!
-You got this!
-Good luck!
Come on, guys!
Look both ways before crossing
and don't forget about us afterwards!
-We'll be waiting for you guys!
-We'll see you guys soon!
-You can do it!
-Come on, guys!
DAY 61
EXPEDITION WEST, CHILE
Nando!
We have to find a ledge
to put the sleeping bag on!
We have to climb a little more!
We're not gonna make it up there!
I'll be in the middle.
It's so beautiful.
It's too bad we're dead.
I'm not going back.
The Andes have to end at some point
The snow too.
The sea's right behind there.
-This never ends.
-Look where we are, Roberto.
After all we've climbed.
We're so close now. Look.
We just need to cross the valley.
How long can it take?
Ten, twelve days?
We only have enough food for a week.
What do you want to do?
Come and walk with me…
or wait on the plane?
You're asking me to die with you.
I'm asking you to come with me.
Look. Look over there.
See those two peaks?
In the middle, like a pair of titties.
There's no snow there.
Can you see it? That's Chile.
Can you see it?
I do.
Thanks.
Careful.
Nando and Roberto went on,
heading west.
We agreed I should come back
so the food would last longer.
From above, you can actually see
some lower ridges.
Looks like they have
a sort of brownish color.
Like there's no more snow there.
The guys are healthy. Doing really great.
They have enough food for like ten days.
Nothing's gonna stop them.
A valley.
Roberto!
Nando!
Hey! Hey!
Hey! Help us, please!
We're from a plane
that crashed in the mountains!
-Hey! Hey!
-Help us! We're starving!
AIR RESCUE SERVICE
I'M FROM A PLANE
"I'm from a plane
that crashed in the mountains."
"I'm Uruguayan."
"We've been walking
through the snow for ten days."
"There are 14 injured
and stranded people in the plane."
"We need to get out of here fast,
and we don't know how."
Call from San Fernando.
"We have no food."
"We are very weak."
-"When are you coming to get us?"
"Please. We can barely walk."
"Where are we?"
A call from San Fernando.
Mm.
-Come on.
-Camera ready?
-Get ready.
-Let's talk to these guys.
We interrupt this broadcast,
ladies and gentlemen,
to bring you more information
on the news we gave you a few minutes ago.
We now have the names
of the two young survivors
from the Uruguayan plane that crashed
in the Andes 71 days ago.
Their names are Roberto Canessa
and Fernando Parrado.
CHILEAN AIR FORCE
DAY 71
DECEMBER 22, 1972
Pass it. Pass it to me.
Lookin' good, huh?
What should we do with all this?
Okay, everyone.
I'm going to tell you
the names of the boys.
-Can you hear me?
-Loud and clear.
Just repeat each
of the names twice, please.
Each name twice.
Roberto Canessa.
Gustavo Zerbino.
Eduardo Strauch.
Álvaro Mangino.
Fernando Parrado.
Antonio Vizintín.
Pedro Algorta.
Alfredo Delgado.
Roy Harley.
José Luis Inciarte.
Ramón Sabella.
Javier Methol.
Carlitos Miguel Páez, my son.
Roberto François.
Daniel Fernández.
Adolfo Strauch.
There they are! There they are!
It's all of them!
All of them! Hey!
-Come on! Let's go!
-Whoo!
Let's go!
We're going home!
Come on, Roy! Get up, man!
-Come on, Gustavo!
-Hey! Leave it! Leave it!
-What do you mean?
-Put it down!
Stop! Stop!
-Gustavo, let's go!
-No! I'm not going without the luggage!
-No!
-Get in! Get in! What are you doing?
Fine, bring it in.
-Bring it in!
-Get in! Come on!
Come on! Let's go!
Come on!
On December 22, 1972,
16 survivors came back
from the Andean Mountain Range.
Today my voice carries their words.
How each of us played our part.
This is our story.
Mom!
This is a miracle.
-This is a miracle.
-What miracle, Ma?
What miracle?
The homecoming is overwhelming.
What is this crowd doing here?
They want to get close to my friends.
Touch them, know everything.
"What happened on the mountain?"
We made it! Thank you!
Thank you!
Journalists want to know,
with their cameras and microphones.
Doctors want to know,
with their exams and instruments.
What do they see?
They're scared of their dirty clothes.
Their skeletal bodies, baked by the sun.
The grime on their skin.
Nando!
The newspapers talk
about the heroes of the Andes.
The ones who came back from death
to reunite with their fathers…
Their mothers.
You look like an old man.
Their girlfriends.
And their children.
But they don't feel like heroes.
Because they were dead like us,
and only they got to come back home.
Now when they remember us,
they ask themselves,
"Why didn't we all get to come back?"
"What does it all mean?"
You'll need to find out yourselves.
'Cause the answer is in you.
Keep taking care of each other.
And tell everyone
what we did on the mountain.
SOCIETY OF THE SNOW
BASED ON SOCIETY OF THE SNOW
BY PABLO VIERCI