(CARNIVAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(WHISPERING)
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Where are you going?
I won't be long.
(MAN SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Welcome, Signor Sciarra.
I trust you had a pleasant journey.
(MARCO SPEAKING)
Do you have it?
Yes. It's over there.
When do we blow the stadium?
This evening at six.
And the flight out of here?
All arranged.
And then what?
(MARCO SPEAKING)
Then I visit The Pale King.
A toast, my friend.
(BOTH SPEAKING)
To Death!
Bottoms up.
(CAR ALARMS BLARING)
(RUMBLING)
(CREAKING)
(COUGHING)
(POLICE SIREN BLARING)
(SHOUTS IN ITALIAN)
(CONTINUES SHOUTING)
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Meet me in the square!
(CARNIVAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(CROWD CLAPPING RHYTHMICALLY)
(CROWD CHANTING IN SPANISH)
(CROWD SCREAMING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(BOND YELLS)
(CROWD SCREAMING)
(ALARM BLARING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
I've been here before
But always hit the floor
I've spent a lifetime running
And I always get away
But with you
I'm feeling something
That makes me want to stay
If I risk it all
Could you break my fall?
How do I live?
How do I breathe?
When you're not here
I'm suffocating
I want to feel love
run through my blood
Tell me is this
where I give it all up?
For you I have to risk it all
'Cause the writing's
on the wall
A million shards of glass
That haunt me from my past
As the stars begin to gather
And the light begins to fade
When all hope
begins to shatter
Know that I won't be afraid
If I risk it all
Could you break my fall?
How do I live?
How do I breathe?
When you're not here
I'm suffocating
I want to feel love
run through my blood
Tell me is this
where I give it all up?
For you I have to risk it all
'Cause the writing's
on the wall
The writing's on the wall
How do I live?
How do I breathe?
When you're not here
I'm suffocating
I want to feel love
run through my blood
Tell me is this
where I give it all up?
For you I have to risk it all
'Cause the writing's on
The wall
Start anywhere you like.
Take your time, 007,
but in five minutes
the head of
the Joint Security Service
is going to walk
through that door,
and I've got
to explain to him
how one of our agents decided to
potter off to Mexico, all on his own,
and cause
an international incident.
With all due respect, sir,
it could've been worse.
Worse? You blew up
half a bloody block.
Well, better half a block than
a whole stadium full of people.
You had no authority.
None.
As you know,
we're in the middle
of the biggest shakeup
in the history of
British intelligence.
The ink's barely dry
on this merger with MI5
and already they're itching
for a chance to scrap
the double-0 program forever.
And you've just
given them one.
You're right, sir.
You have got
a tricky day ahead.
This is an official question.
Mexico City.
What were you doing there?
It was just a coincidence.
I was taking some overdue holiday.
Okay. Fine.
As of this morning,
you are officially grounded.
I'm standing you down from
all operations indefinitely.
Very good, sir.
007?
Sir?
I don't know what
you're playing at,
but whatever it is,
it has to stop.
Now.
- So sorry.
- Am I interrupting?
Not remotely.
007, I'd like you
to meet Max Denbigh,
head of the Joint
Security Service.
It's a pleasure to finally meet you, 007.
I've heard a lot about you.
Most of it good.
Congratulations
on your new appointment.
Thank you.
I suppose we should
call you C now.
No, no. "Max," please.
No, I think
I'll call you C,
C.
As you wish.
Well, my door is always
open, 007, for my employees.
This merger's gonna be
a whole new chapter for us.
We're going to bring British
intelligence out of the Dark Ages
into the light.
That all sounds lovely.
That'll be all, 007.
Report to Q tomorrow
for medical, thank you.
Very good, sir.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
James?
Moneypenny.
So? How was
the meeting?
Very good,
thank you.
Here.
- Forensics finally released this.
- What is it?
It's personal effects
they recovered from Skyfall.
Perfect. You can
bring it to me later.
- What do you mean?
- My place, 9:00.
(DOORBELL BEEPS)
Evening.
Come in.
Have you just moved in?
No.
Well, I like what you've
done with the place.
Your delivery.
Thank you.
Would you like a drink?
No, thanks.
I'm not staying.
That's a shame.
What's going on, James?
(SIGHS)
There's not one person at MI6
who isn't talking about it.
Talking about what, exactly?
That what you did in Mexico
was one step too far.
That you're finished.
And what do you think?
I think you're just
getting started.
I don't know what you mean.
All right.
I think you've got a secret.
And it's something
you won't tell anyone.
Because you
don't trust anyone.
If anything happens to me, 007,
I need you to do something.
Find a man
called Marco Sciarra.
Kill him.
And don't miss the funeral.
Jesus.
Where did you get it?
In my mailbox
just after she died.
Well, she was never
short of surprises.
She wasn't gonna let death
get in the way of her job.
I've been tracking
Sciarra ever since.
And what have you found?
Nothing significant yet.
When's the funeral?
Three days. In Rome.
If you think M's signing off on
that, you're insane.
He won't let you
out of his sight.
Yes, it's a bit of
a problem.
Listen.
Could you do a little
quiet digging for me?
I heard a name in Mexico.
"The Pale King."
You want me
to be your mole.
Yes.
And what makes you think
you can trust me?
Instinct.
TANNER: Poor old girl.
Rigged for demolition in a week.
Cheaper to knock her down
than to rebuild.
Still.
Time waits for no man
and all that.
Anyway, all the money's
been spent on this,
the New Centre for
National Security.
BOND: So that's C's new digs.
You've met him, have you?
Yesterday.
What do we know about him?
Classic Whitehall mandarin.
Wrote a dossier last year
on how the double-0 program
was obsolete,
how drones could do
all our dirty work abroad.
Went to school with
the Home Secretary.
Of course, he did.
This merger's
just the start of it.
In three days, there's a security
conference in Tokyo
to decide
the New World Order.
If C gets his way,
he'll have unlimited access
to the combined intelligence
streams of nine countries.
Including us.
Quite.
Well, a lot's happened
while you were away.
A train bombing in Hamburg and an
industrial explosion in Tunisia.
It's not great timing
for us.
It's all rather
playing into C's hands.
M, well, let's say
he's feeling the pressure.
Yeah, I've noticed.
Now, this way, 007.
Be careful.
It's a trifle slippery.
Q wasn't exactly feeling
at home in Whitehall,
what with the new merger,
so he set up shop here,
away from prying eyes,
as it were.
I hear he's got something
rather special planned for you.
I can hardly wait.
Ah, 007.
- Q.
- Q: Please excuse the mess.
Everything's a little
bit up in the air,
what with the changes
and all.
Couple of things
to get through.
Shall we get started?
Just relax.
That's it. Lovely.
Now, you may feel a small...
Christ!
...prick.
What is it?
Q: Cutting-edge
nanotechnology.
Smart Blood.
Microchips in
your bloodstream.
Allows us to track
your movements in the field.
You see those readouts?
We can monitor your vital signs
from anywhere on the planet.
Well, that sounds marvelous.
Call it a post-Mexico
insurance policy.
By direct order of M.
I completely understand.
Good.
Right. Well, I've just, um,
got one last thing for you
and you can be on your way.
Magnificent, isn't she?
Zero to 60 in
three point two seconds.
Fully bulletproof.
A few little tricks up her sleeve.
It's a shame, really.
She was meant for you,
but she's been
reassigned to 009.
But you can have this.
Does it do anything?
It tells the time.
Might help with your
punctuality issues.
- M's idea?
- Precisely.
Oh, one word of warning.
The alarm is rather loud.
If you know what I mean.
I think I do.
Oh, yes. That old thing is
taking quite a bit of time.
Mind you, there wasn't
much left to work on.
Only a steering wheel.
I believe I said,
"Bring it back in one piece,"
not, "Bring back one piece."
(Q LAUGHING)
Anyway, enjoy
your downtime, 007.
- Q?
- Q: Yes?
Well, now you know exactly
where I am all of the time.
Will you do
something for me?
What do you have
in mind, exactly?
Make me disappear.
May I remind you that
I answer directly to M.
I also have a mortgage.
And two cats to feed.
Well, then I suggest
you trust me,
for the sake of the cats.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, it's lovely to
see you, 007. Lovely.
Um, now,
I meant to tell you,
the Smart Blood program is obviously
still in its developmental phase.
So we may experience the odd drop in
coverage during the first 24 hours...
48 hours after
administration,
but after that it
should work perfectly.
I'll send you a postcard.
Please, don't.
Morning.
- What's that?
- Oh, it's just something
from an admirer.
It's not your birthday,
is it?
No, sir.
That was last week.
Q: Morning.
009 has arrived to
pick up the DB10, sir.
He's waiting upstairs.
Oh, good.
Yes, fine.
Oh, shit.
(CHURCH BELL TOLLING)
(PRIEST SPEAKING ITALIAN)
BOND: I'm sorry
for your loss.
You knew my husband?
All too briefly.
What do you do?
Life insurance.
A little late for that.
For your husband, yes.
But what about you?
Me?
I hear the life expectancy of
some widows can be very short.
How can you
talk like this?
Can't you see
I'm grieving?
No.
(OPERA MUSIC PLAYING)
(SHUDDERING)
(SILENCED GUNSHOTS)
What a lovely view.
You're wasting your time.
There are 100 more
that will come after me.
All you buy me
is five minutes.
Excellent.
Time for a drink.
You killed him,
didn't you?
My husband.
He was an assassin.
Trust me, he won't
take it personally.
(GLASSES SHATTERING)
You signed my death warrant.
I was respected.
Loyal to a man you hated.
He trusted my silence.
With him gone,
I'm a dead woman.
I can trust nobody.
I know the feeling well.
Well, I can tell you
that I don't trust you.
Well, then you have
impeccable instincts.
If you don't leave now,
we'll die together.
I can think of
worse ways to go.
Then you're
obviously crazy, Mister...
Bond.
James Bond.
(BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY)
These people,
if you just knew
what they could do.
The power they have.
Did your husband ever
mention "The Pale King?"
No.
The organization,
they hardly ever meet.
But because of what
happened to my husband,
they meet tonight.
Why?
To choose a replacement.
Where?
The Palazzo Cardenza.
- Midnight.
- Sounds like fun.
I might drop by.
He was obsessed.
He spent more time
with them than with me.
Then the man was a fool.
LUCIA: Leaving your number?
BOND: I've called an American
friend of mine. Felix.
He'll contact his embassy
and get you out of here.
You'll be safe.
Don't go, James.
If you go there,
you're crossing over to a
place where there is no mercy.
I have to go.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Identify yourself, asshole.
Who are you?
I'm Mickey Mouse. Who are you?
(APOLOGIZING IN ITALIAN)
MAN:...pharmacy sites
has provided
an excellent
new sales platform.
We have adapted many of them into
clearinghouses for unapproved drugs.
In addition to which,
the latest figures show
that we presently control
70% of
antimalarial vaccines,
34% of H.I.V.,
and 40% of all oncological drugs
across Sub-Saharan Africa.
But we face challenges
from the WHO
in their campaign against our
counterfeit pharmaceuticals.
We have now identified the
key individuals to target.
We expect the same
success as we had
against the Council
on Human Trafficking.
(MAN SPEAKING FRENCH)
(WOMAN SPEAKING GERMAN)
Since the board's resignation...
..we have placed 160,000 migrated females
into the leisure sector.
The impending completion of
the Global Surveillance initiative...
...will mean our capability
is second to none...
...and now is the moment
for aggressive expansion.
The news is only good....
(FEEDBACK HUMS)
OBERHAUSER: Don't let me
interrupt you.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
The news is only good....
Our increased surveillance capability...
...means government
intelligence agencies...
...are easily counteracted.
We are winning.
MAN: Thank you, Doctor.
Now, on to
the matter at hand.
After the success of our
attacks in Hamburg and Tunisia,
the aborted attack
in Mexico City
and the death of our valued
colleague, Marco Sciarra,
leaves one of his duties
outstanding.
Signor Guerra,
The Pale King must be terminated.
Will you make
the journey to Altaussee?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Of course.
My loyalty to this organization is total.
I will protect it with my last breath.
There will be no more...
...amateurs.
No more shows of weakness.
(INAUDIBLE)
Does anyone challenge Signor
Guerra for this position?
Welcome.
State your credentials for
succeeding Signor Sciarra.
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
OBERHAUSER: It's funny.
All that excitement in Mexico
City rang a distant bell.
And now,
suddenly, this evening,
it makes perfect sense.
Welcome, James.
It's been a long time.
But, finally, here we are.
What took you so long?
Cuckoo.
Ciao, Mickey Mouse.
(YELLS)
(GUNS FIRING)
(BEEPING)
Oh, you've got
to be kidding me.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
No.
(EXCLAIMS)
- (OPERA PLAYING OVER RADIO)
- (SINGING ALONG)
(HONKING)
(CURSING)
Moneypenny.
(CELLPHONE VIBRATING)
Bond?
Listen, Moneypenny.
Hamburg, Tunisia,
Mexico City,
they're all linked.
It's one organization
coordinating multiple attacks.
So, she was right.
Of course, she was.
- I ran that check.
- MAN: Who is it?
Oh, my boss had his
credit card stolen.
It's nothing.
Why don't you go back to sleep.
Don't be long.
- Who was that?
- MONEYPENNY: No one.
BOND: No, it wasn't.
It's just a friend.
At this time of night?
It's called life, James.
You should try it sometime.
MONEYPENNY: The Pale King.
It looks like you've had
dealings with him before.
- Quantum.
- Of course.
- Mr. White!
- That's him.
Last unconfirmed sighting,
Altaussee in Austria,
four months ago.
Hold that thought.
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- (ENGINE ROARING)
- You still there?
- Yeah.
Run another name, will you?
Okay. Go.
A man called
Franz Oberhauser. He's...
(TIRES SCREECHING)
And check his files
before and after his death.
After his death?
What are you talking about?
Please, just do it.
(HORN BLARING)
Okay, Q, give me something.
That's more like it.
Here goes nothing.
Good evening.
C: Do not let them tell you
we need less surveillance.
We need more. Much more.
I say again,
the Nine Eyes committee
would have full access
to the combined intelligence
streams of all member states.
More data, more analysis,
less likelihood of
a terrorist attack.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's time for the security
services of the world to unite.
Alone, we are weak.
Together,
we're a global power.
An unelected one.
Thank you.
We will now vote
on the resolution.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please cast your vote.
The vote is eight
to one in favor.
However, as you know,
we cannot proceed
unless by unanimous vote.
The Nine Eyes motion
is therefore not passed.
Democracy.
CHAIRMAN: Thank you,
ladies and gentlemen.
- This evening's session is adjourned.
- (CELLPHONE VIBRATES)
(CELLPHONE VIBRATING)
Yes, sir.
Please, tell me 007
is in London.
Q: Oh, yes.
Um, I'll just take
a look now, sir.
Because if he isn't,
you're in deep shit.
(CHUCKLING)
You've got precisely
10 seconds.
I have him, sir.
He appears to be in Chelsea.
Well, I want eyes on him
when I get back, understood?
I completely understand,
sir.
(FAINT CLATTERING)
(CAWING)
- (CLICKS)
- (UNLOCKING)
Do me a favor.
Make it quick.
Upstairs, Mr. White.
I always knew death would
wear a familiar face,
but not yours.
To what do I owe
this pleasure, Mr. Bond?
I was at a meeting recently
and your name came up.
I'm flattered London is
still talking about me.
It wasn't MI6.
It was Rome.
Your team, not mine.
Ah.
Last month,
I found thallium in my cell phone.
It's done its job.
I have a few weeks.
Maybe less.
So, here we are, Mr. Bond,
two dead men
enjoying the evening.
What did you do?
I disobeyed him.
I followed him
as far as I could.
He changed.
Oh, I see.
You grew a conscience.
Our game is our game.
But this?
Women, children...
Well, the thallium
would suggest
that he doesn't like you
very much anymore.
And clearly
the feeling is mutual.
So why don't you tell me
how to find him again?
Oh, come on.
Tell me where he is.
He's everywhere.
Everywhere!
He's sitting
at your desk,
he's kissing your lover,
he's eating supper with your family!
(SIGHS)
You're protecting someone.
Your wife.
(LAUGHING)
She left long ago.
Your son?
Your daughter.
You won't find her.
She's clever.
She's smarter than me.
She knows how to hide.
I can protect her if
you tell me where he is.
(CHUCKLES)
I can keep her alive.
Yeah.
You have my word.
Your word?
The word of an assassin!
That's my word.
L'Américain.
You save her,
she can lead you to L'Américain.
She knows L'Américain.
Try the Hoffler Klinik.
You're a kite dancing in a
hurricane, Mr. Bond.
So long.
(GUNSHOT)
M: I can't deny I'm impressed you
got H.M.G. to cough up for all this.
C: Good God,
the government couldn't
afford this kind of facility.
No, it was benefactors mostly,
from the private sector.
When it goes online,
this building will be
the most sophisticated
data gathering system
in history.
The world's digital ghost,
available 24/7.
George Orwell's
worst nightmare.
I'm glad you like it.
My commiserations
on losing the Nine Eyes vote.
Must have been a blow.
Not really.
Only a matter of time
before the South Africans
see the light.
And you know what they say,
Rome wasn't built in a day.
Day and a half maybe.
Look, Max, I know surveillance
is a fact of life.
It's how you use the
information that concerns me,
and who is using it.
This is what we need to do
to keep the people safe.
Double-0 program
is prehistoric.
Come on, M.
You can't really tell me
that one man in the field
can compete with all of this,
running around out there
with his license to kill.
Have you ever had
to kill a man, Max?
Have you?
To pull that trigger,
you have to be sure.
Yes, you investigate,
analyze, assess, target.
And then you have
to look him in the eye.
And you make the call.
And all the drones, bugs,
cameras, transcripts,
all the surveillance
in the world
can't tell you
what to do next.
A license to kill
is also a license
not to kill.
I didn't want to
have to do this,
but it looks like you still
can't control your agents.
MONEYPENNY: (ON RECORDING)
Bond? I ran that check.
(FAST FORWARDING)
Looks like you've had
dealings with him before.
Quantum.
BOND: Of course. Mr. White!
MONEYPENNY:
Last unconfirmed sighting,
Altaussee in Austria.
BOND: Run another name,
will you?
C: So maybe there's
something to be said
for total surveillance
after all.
You watch MI6 agents?
We watch everyone.
(CAWING)
SWANN:
Please, take a seat.
I'll be with you
in just a moment.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Please excuse me,
Mr. Bond.
My name is
Dr. Madeleine Swann.
Our job today is to
analyze your needs,
both psychological
and physical.
Hmm, sounds pretty
straightforward.
I hope you don't mind.
The view can be distracting.
I hadn't noticed.
I see you filled out
most of the paperwork.
Just a few questions to complete
your evaluation, if I may.
Do you exercise?
When I have to.
Do you consider your employment
to be psychologically stressful?
Sometimes.
How much alcohol
do you consume?
Too much.
Some broader questions.
As a child, would you say you
were close to your parents?
My parents died
when I was young.
Really? How old?
Old enough to remember.
How, if I may ask?
It was a climbing accident.
So who brought you up?
Someone else.
Humor me.
How does one train at Oxford and
the Sorbonne become a consultant,
spend two years with
Médecins Sans Frontières
and end up here?
Forgive me,
but anyone might think
you were hiding
from something.
You're paying a lot of money to be
here, Mr. Bond.
Who's asking the questions,
you or me?
Of course. Carry on.
I see you left this
final question blank.
What is your occupation?
Well, that's not the sort of
thing that looks good on a form.
And why is that?
I kill people.
Small world?
Where is he?
Your father's dead.
Two days ago.
(SHUDDERING)
How do you know?
Because I was there.
Did you kill him?
I didn't have to.
He did it himself.
And you came all the way
just to tell me this?
That my father's dead?
I came to tell you that your life
is in danger and I need your help.
- Why?
- I made a deal with him
to protect you.
You're lying.
Why would he trust you?
Because he knew that I
needed something in return.
And what was that?
To find L'Américain.
This interview is over.
Dr. Swann...
You have 10 minutes to leave the building.
Then I'm calling security.
Thank you,
Dr. Swann.
(SIGHS)
Can I get you
something, sir?
Vodka martini.
Shaken, not stirred.
I'm sorry,
we don't serve alcohol.
I'm really starting
to love this place.
He'll have the prolytic
digestive enzyme shake.
Certainly.
If you've come
for the car,
I parked it
at the bottom of the Tiber.
Well, not to worry, 007.
It was only a £3,000,000 prototype.
Why are you here, Q?
Oh, I just fancied a break,
to be honest.
I've been a tad stressed
at work recently.
What with C's people
crawling all over us
and the fact that M wants my
balls for Christmas decorations.
- Get to the point.
- The point, 007,
is that Franz Oberhauser
is dead.
Dead and buried.
And unless you come back
with me right now,
my career and Moneypenny's
will go the same way.
Do you understand?
All hell is breaking
loose out there and...
- I saw him.
- You thought you saw him.
We've been through
the records.
He died in an avalanche
with his father 20 years ago.
Yes. I know that.
But I saw him.
He's not someone
I'll ever forget.
So you have a lead?
I have a name.
L'Américain.
(SCOFFS) Well,
that narrows it down.
Look, I'm sorry, 007,
but time's up.
My whole career
is on the line here.
Either you come back in and do
this through proper channels,
or I go directly to M.
Do one more thing for me.
Then you're out.
Find out what you can
from this.
I really, really
hate you right now.
Thank you, Q.
Monsieur?
Now? Please?
Where are you staying?
The Pevsner. Room 12.
One hour.
Here you are, sir.
One prolytic digestive enzyme shake.
Do me a favor,
will you?
Throw that
down the toilet.
Cut out the middleman.
- (GRUNTS)
- (WHIMPERS)
No! Stay.
What do you want?
What are you doing?
Can't any of you speak?
(EXCLAIMS)
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(EXPLOSION)
(EXCLAIMS)
Come on!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Argh, don't touch me!
Hey!
You need to take a breath and calm down.
You're in shock.
Get away from me!
Just get away!
Did it cross your mind
that you led them to me?
I haven't got
time for this.
You need to tell me everything
you know about L'Américain.
Go to hell!
I gave your father my word!
And why should I trust you?
Because my father did?
Because right now,
Dr. Swann,
I'm your best chance
of staying alive.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Dr. Swann, Q.
Q, Dr. Swann.
- Hello.
- Enchanted.
Bond, we need
to talk. Alone.
She knows.
- But, Bond...
- She knows.
What have you got?
I owe you an apology, 007.
You are onto something.
Oberhauser is still alive.
The ring proves it.
And it seems they were
all part of one organization.
Le Chiffre, Quantum, Sciarra,
your friend Mr. Silva.
And do you know
who links them all?
BOND: Him.
Exactly.
This organization,
do you know what it's called?
- No.
- SWANN: Spectre.
Its name is Spectre.
How does she know that?
Because my father
was part of it.
Then I think that
you ought to see this.
REPORTER: You're looking at
pictures from South Africa right now
of what appears to be
a huge explosion.
Q, go back to London.
M's gonna need your help.
And keep tracking me.
Q: I will.
And, Bond, you have
to find L'Américain.
He's our only link
to Oberhauser.
It's not a person.
It's a place.
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Thank you.
This is where they spent
their wedding night.
They came back every year.
Then they brought me
with them, too.
He kept coming back,
even after the divorce.
Well, then I'm sorry.
What for?
(CLATTERING)
(GRUNTS)
Ah-ha!
SWANN: What is it?
It's your inheritance.
- Want some?
- No, thank you.
You don't know
what you're missing.
(EXHALES)
This can't be it.
Well, here's to your father.
I promised myself I would never
be hurt by that man again.
I cut off all contact.
I didn't want anything to do
with him or his sick life.
And then,
with his dying breath
he sends me you.
Ironic, no?
You shouldn't be
so hard on him.
The man I just met should
have been dead weeks ago.
The only reason his heart
was still beating was you.
I'll mourn my father
in my own time, Mr. Bond.
And, now,
I'm going to bed.
- (GASPS)
- BOTH: Oh.
Don't think for one moment this
is where I fall into your arms,
seeking solace
for my dead daddy.
You sit there.
Keep watch.
That's what you're good at.
Come anywhere near me
and I'll kill you.
I don't doubt it.
(IMITATES GUNSHOT)
Look. There are two of you.
Two Jameses.
Lucky me.
(WHISPERING IN FRENCH)
What am I doing here?
(SIGHING)
To liars...
...and killers.
...and killers...
...everywhere.
(GUN COCKS)
Who sent you?
Who are you working for?
Now, where did you go?
(CHUCKLES) Of course.
What is it?
Nothing.
What's this?
It's coordinates.
Your father was scanning for
a particular satellite phone.
He was looking
for someone.
He was looking for him.
And he sent me here
to finish the job.
- I'm coming with you.
- No, you're not.
I like you alive.
I can look after myself.
That's beside the point.
I might not be coming back.
I know.
But I want to understand
what happened to my father.
So, where was he going?
Nowhere.
Thank you so much. Thanks.
All the very best.
What's going on?
The meeting was brought forward.
Did you not get the message?
No, we didn't.
Shortest meeting
I can remember.
South Africans on board,
I take it?
Yeah, well,
who can blame them?
Nine Eyes is now
officially sanctioned.
The new system goes live
in less than 72 hours.
It's a major step forward.
Global intelligence
cooperation changes everything.
As you said before.
Look.
They've asked me
to head the new committee.
Yes? And?
And I should tell you I've
spoken with the Home Secretary.
And in light of the new
information I've given him,
he's decided to close down
the double-0 program
with immediate effect.
You don't know
what you're doing.
It's not personal.
It's the future.
And...
You're not.
You're a cocky little
bastard, aren't you?
(CHUCKLES)
I'll take that
as a compliment.
I wouldn't.
This isn't over yet.
- Would you press this for me?
Thank you.
- Yes, sir.
Pick it up.
I hate guns.
I promised him
I'd protect you.
The first thing to do is to teach
you how to protect yourself.
What if I shoot you
by mistake?
Wouldn't be the first time.
Pick it up.
I said, I hate guns.
SIG 226.
Front sight.
Rear sight. Hammer.
(SIGHS)
You just point it.
You squeeze the trigger.
You try not to
close your eyes.
Please, try it.
(SIGHS)
I don't have to
teach you anything, do I?
A man once came to our house
to kill my father.
He didn't know I was upstairs
playing in my bedroom.
Or that Papa kept
a Beretta Nine-millimeter
under the sink
with the bleach.
That's why I hate guns.
I think we'll skip
hand-to-hand combat.
MONEYPENNY:
Good evening, sir.
Sorry to interrupt your
supper, but we have some news.
Q: Evening, sir.
Using the Smart Blood,
I've tracked Bond
to a point here
in North Africa.
See, every known map
registers it as empty desert.
Exactly. But if you look at the satellite
blowup, you can clearly see this.
We can't help him.
But, sir, we know
where he's heading.
C is watching
everything we do.
We're only handing them
more information.
Sir, we can't
just desert Bond.
We have to.
We only make him weaker.
But, sir,
we know exactly where he is.
Yes, I know,
but if we can track him,
so can others.
Delete all
the Smart Blood files.
Everything.
He's on his own.
You shouldn't stare.
Well, you shouldn't
look like that.
May I get you
an apéritif?
I'm not sure.
It gets me into trouble.
Makes me do crazy things.
Well, we can't
have that.
So, I'll have
a vodka martini, dirty.
Make that two.
(CHUCKLES)
I have a question.
Well, what's that?
Why, given every
other possible option,
does a man choose the
life of a paid assassin?
Well, it was that
or the priesthood.
(CHUCKLES)
I'm serious.
Is this really what you want?
Living in the shadows?
Hunting? Being hunted?
Always looking behind you?
Always alone?
But I'm not alone.
Answer the question.
I'm not sure I ever
had a choice.
Anyway, I don't stop
to think about it.
What would happen
if you did?
- Stop?
- Yes.
I don't know.
Your drinks, sir.
Could you leave
them there, please.
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
You know,
I think you're wrong.
I am?
We always have a choice.
I'll drink to that.
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(STRAINING)
(GROANS)
(GUN CLICKS)
(CHOKING)
(GRUNTS)
Shit.
(BOTH PANTING)
What do we do now?
BOND: This might be
a long wait.
Are you having
second thoughts?
Too late now.
What's that?
(COCKING GUN)
That is a 1948
Rolls-Royce Silver Wraith.
Please.
I'm scared, James.
Good afternoon,
Mr. Bond, Dr. Swann.
I want you to know just how excited
we all are to finally meet you.
Well,
it's a pleasure to be here.
Your host invites
you both to rest,
relax, and join him
for drinks at 4:00.
- Tell our host we won't be late.
- MAN: Wonderful.
Before we show you to your
rooms, just one more thing.
Oh.
You be careful
with that.
It's loaded.
Thank you.
MAN: This is
a very special place.
He has requested
you enter it alone.
Of course.
Champagne?
Maybe later.
Certainly.
(DOOR WHIRRING SOFTLY)
BOND: (SOFTLY) I think
we're meant to be impressed.
OBERHAUSER: Touch it.
You can touch it
if you want.
Do you know what it is?
It's a meteorite.
OBERHAUSER: Yes, exactly.
The Kartenhoff.
The oldest in human possession.
The very meteorite
which made this crater.
Think about it.
So many years up there,
alone, silent,
building momentum until it
chose to make its mark on Earth.
A huge, unstoppable force.
Except it did stop,
didn't it?
Right here.
I can't tell you how much I've
been looking forward to this.
All of us here, together.
A reunion.
I'm so glad you came,
too, dear Madeleine.
You were just a girl
when I saw you first.
I came to your home once
to see your father.
I don't remember that.
But I do.
(DOOR WHIRRING SOFTLY)
Shall we?
SWANN:
What is this place?
Information.
Information is all,
is it not?
For example,
you must know by now that the
double-0 program is officially dead.
(CHUCKLES) Which leads me to
speculate exactly why you came.
So, James,
why did you come?
I came here to kill you.
And I thought you
came here to die.
Well, it's all
a matter of perspective.
Speaking of perspective.
- Is this live?
- MAN: Live and direct.
16:20 GMT.
OBERHAUSER: What an
uncanny coincidence.
The French have a saying,
"It's the fate of glass to break."
Well, maybe it's the fate
of spies to just disappear.
But with any luck,
we leave something behind.
In the meantime,
I'm sure C will keep you all busy.
Thank you all.
(SCATTERED APPLAUSE)
That's touching,
don't you think?
Well, James,
it looks like
you're all alone.
Not much more than a
voyeur, are you?
Too scared to join in.
(CHUCKLING) I don't think
you quite understand.
Oh, I think I do.
You set cities on fire and
watch innocent people burn,
so you can convince
governments to join
an intelligence network
you've paid for.
Not that complicated.
I'm guessing our little friend, C,
he's one of your disciples.
You could say that.
And what does
he get out of it?
Nothing.
He's a visionary,
like me.
Visionaries.
Psychiatric wards
are full of them.
Whereas you couldn't see
what's right in front of you.
You came across me so many
times and yet you never saw me.
Le Chiffre, Greene, Silva.
All dead.
Yeah, that's right.
A nice pattern developed.
You interfered in my world,
I destroyed yours.
Or did you think
it was coincidence
that all the women in
your life ended up dead?
Vesper Lynd,
for example.
She was the big one.
Has he told you about her?
And then, of course,
your beloved M.
Gone forever.
Me.
It was all me, James.
It's always been me.
The author of all your pain.
You're a brave
woman, my dear.
Now I understand why
my father lost his mind.
He didn't lose his mind,
he was just weak.
But at least he understood
what he was up against.
You see, they failed to
comprehend the crucial fact,
that a terrible event can
lead to something wonderful.
Since you mention your father,
I'll show you.
WHITE: (OVER RECORDING) She's clever.
She's smarter than me.
She knows how to hide.
BOND: I can protect her if
you tell me where he is.
(WHITE LAUGHING)
BOND: I can keep her alive.
WHITE: Yeah.
BOND: You have my word.
No, no, no. Turn this off.
WHITE: Your word?
The word of an assassin!
Turn this off.
- This is important.
- I said turn it off!
(GRUNTING)
I want you to
understand something.
BOND: That's my word.
Madeleine?
Look at me.
Don't look at him,
Madeleine. Look at me.
WHITE: L'Américain.
You save her,
she can lead you to L'Américain.
She knows L'Américain.
Try the Hoffler Klinik.
You're a kite dancing in a
hurricane, Mr. Bond.
So long.
(GUNSHOT)
The things that
bring people together.
Out of horror, beauty.
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
OBERHAUSER: Torture is easy,
on a superficial level.
A man can watch himself
being disemboweled
and derive great horror
from the experience,
but it's still
going on at a distance.
It isn't taking
place where he is.
As you know all too well,
dear Madeleine,
a man lives inside his head.
That's where
the seat of his soul is.
Now, James and I were
both present recently
when a man was
deprived of his eyes.
And the most
astonishing thing happened.
Didn't you notice?
He wasn't there anymore.
He'd gone even though
he was still alive.
So in this brief moment
between life and death,
there was nobody
inside his skull.
Most odd.
So, James.
(CHAIR WHIRRING)
I'm going to penetrate
to where you are.
To the inside
of your head.
Now, the first probe
will play with your sight,
your hearing
and your balance,
just with the subtlest
of manipulations.
Well, get on with it then.
Nothing can be as painful
as listening to you talk.
All right.
Let's begin.
(WHIRRING)
(SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERING)
(GROANING LOUDLY)
Why are you doing this?
You probably know
that James here
lost his parents
when he was young.
But did you know
that it was my father
who helped him through
this difficult time?
Over the course
of two winters
he taught him to ski,
and climb, and hunt.
He soothed the wounds of the
poor little blue-eyed orphan.
(PANTING)
Asked me to treat
him as a brother.
My little brother.
They formed
quite an attachment.
So,
you killed him.
Yes, I did.
You know what
happens when a cuckoo
hatches inside
another bird's nest?
Yes.
It forces
the other eggs out.
OBERHAUSER: Yes.
Well, this cuckoo made me realize
my father's life had to end.
In a way, he's responsible
for the path I took.
So, thank you.
(SING-SONG) Cuckoo.
(CHUCKLING)
Do you know any other
birdcalls, Franz?
(BOND CHUCKLING)
Hello, pussy.
Franz Oberhauser died
20 years ago, James.
In an avalanche,
alongside his father.
The man you are talking to
now, the man inside your head,
is Ernst Stavro Blofeld.
Catchy name.
My mother's bloodline.
If the needle finds the correct
spot in the fusiform gyrus,
you'll recognize no one.
(CHUCKLING) Of course,
the faces of your women
are interchangeable,
aren't they, James?
You won't know
who she is.
Just another passing face
on your way to the grave.
He dies not knowing
who you are.
The daughter
of an assassin.
The only one who could
have understood him.
- Shame.
- (KEYBOARD CLACKING)
(WHIRRING)
(GRUNTING)
- (GROANING)
- (WHIRRING INTENSIFIES)
(WHIMPERING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I love you.
BLOFELD: Do those blue eyes
still recognize you?
I'd recognize
you anywhere.
The watch.
One minute.
BLOFELD: Did he say something?
Tempus fugit.
- What?
- (SOFTLY) Tempus fugit.
I can't hear you, James.
BOND: I said,
doesn't time fly?
(DRILLS WHIRRING)
(GUNFIRE)
In there!
Let's go home.
(EXPLODING)
It's not over yet.
Q: I've never even
heard of Hildebrand.
M: That is the general
idea with safe houses.
Exactly how safe
is this, sir?
We're about to find out.
It's safe.
Better wait here.
I'm M.
Madeleine Swann.
Pleased to meet you.
So, what do you
have for me, 007?
The recently deceased head of
Spectre, Ernst Stavro Blofeld,
and his chief of intelligence,
your new best friend, C.
About to take control of his very
own global surveillance system
that he built right
here under our noses.
Then we'd better move.
The system goes online at midnight.
BOND: If that happens,
Spectre will have control of everything.
So, you and I will
have a quiet word with C
while Q hacks into the system
and stops it going online.
It won't be easy.
He'll find a way.
He always does.
It's good to
have you back, 007.
Sir.
James, I can't.
I'll come back for you
when it's all over.
No, I can't.
No, you can't
stay here, or you...
I can't go back to this life.
And I'm not going to ask you to change.
This is who you are.
You're saying good-bye.
Yes.
Take care.
You're a good man, James.
Are you in yet, Q?
A few layers of impenetrable
security still to go,
but I think
I'm getting somewhere.
They've seen us! Reverse!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Go!
Get him in the building!
Move. Move!
(GUNSHOTS)
Go back and find M, now!
We need them both.
Not a good feeling
being watched, is it?
Don't tell me you're
responsible for this.
No, but my Quartermaster is.
And he's
extremely talented.
C: Well, bravo.
But in case you hadn't realized it,
you two are out of a job.
So you're trespassing.
I'm afraid you've got the
wrong end of the stick, Max.
We're going to stop this
system going online.
And then I'm going
to bring you in.
On what grounds exactly?
Poor taste in friends.
Take a look at the world.
Chaos.
Because people like you,
paper-pushers
and politicians,
are too spineless to do
what needs to be done.
So I made an alliance to put
the power where it should be.
And now you want to throw it
away for the sake of "democracy."
Whatever the hell that is.
How predictably moronic.
But then isn't that
what M stands for?
- "Moron."
- (GUN CLICKS)
And now we know
what C stands for.
"Careless."
(CLANGING)
Come on.
- (BEEPS)
- No, no, no!
You're a hard man
to kill, Blofeld.
Ouch.
I do hope that
doesn't hurt too much.
My wounds will heal.
What about yours?
Look around you,
James. Look.
This is what's
left of your world.
Everything you ever
stood for, everything
you believed in, a ruin.
Why are we here?
Did you miss me?
No.
But I know someone who does.
Where is she?
That's for you to find out.
In three minutes,
this building will be demolished.
I can get out easily.
Now, you have a choice.
Die trying to save her or
save yourself and
live with the pain.
You're bluffing.
Am I?
(LAUGHING)
(CHUCKLING)
I've really put you
through it, haven't I?
That's brothers for you.
They always know
which buttons to press.
(ALARM BLARING)
Madeleine!
- Come on.
- (KEYBOARD CLACKING)
Come on.
Yes!
Let's go.
After you.
Why can't you
just face it, M?
You don't matter anymore.
Maybe I don't.
But something has to.
(BEEPING)
Dead.
- Any word on Bond?
- MONEYPENNY: No.
But I can hazard a guess.
Madeleine!
(THUDDING)
(SWANN SCREAMING)
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
Do you trust me?
Do I have a choice?
Not anymore.
(GRUNTING)
Come on!
Good-bye, James Bond.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(BULLET RICOCHETING)
(ALARM BEEPING)
(ALARM BLARING)
Brace, brace, brace!
(BREATHING HARD)
(GRUNTS)
(ALARM CONTINUES BLARING)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
(SIREN WAILING)
(STRAINING)
Sir, this is
a terrorist alert.
Mallory, double-0 section.
Stand them down.
Echo team, hold fire.
Stand down.
(GRUNTING)
Finish it.
(RELEASING CLIP)
(COCKS GUN)
Out of bullets.
And besides,
I've got something
better to do.
Under the Special
Measures Act of 2001,
I am detaining you on behalf
of Her Majesty's Government.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
(ELEVATOR DESCENDING)
Bond?
(STAMMERING)
- What are you doing here?
- Good morning, Q.
I thought you'd gone.
I have.
There's just
one thing I need.
(ENGINE REVVING)