We come to you now with revelations
about last week's attack in London.
An anonymous source provided this video.
It shows Quentin Beck, aka Mysterio,
moments before his death.
You may find this video disturbing.
I managed to send the Elemental
back through the rift,
but I don't think
I'm gonna make it off this bridge alive.
Spider-Man attacked me.
He has an army of drones,
Stark technology.
He's saying he's the only one who's
gonna be the new Iron Man. No one else.
Are you sure you want
to commence the drone attack?
There will be significant casualties.
Do it. Execute them all.
This shocking video was released
earlier today
on the controversial news website
The Daily Bugle.net.
There you have it, folks: Conclusive proof
that Spider-Man was responsible
for the brutal murder of Mysterio,
an inter dimensional warrior
who gave his life to protect our planet
and who will, no doubt, go down in history
as the greatest superhero of all time.
But that's not all, folks.
Here's the real blockbuster.
Brace yourselves.
You might wanna sit down.
Spider-Man's real--
Spider-Man's real name is--
Spider-Man's name is Peter Parker.
What the f--?
That's right, folks. Peter Parker.
A 17-year-old high school delinquent...
- She knows him.
- Are you Spider-Man's girlfriend?
...is, in fact...
- ...the vile vigilante villain Spider-Man.
Yo, it's him.
- Please don't touch her, sir.
- You're just a kid?
You murdered Mysterio?
- You helped him?
- No, I didn't--
Come on, kid, let me see your face.
- He hit me. Spider-Man hit me.
- Come on.
He hit me.
All this time, people looked up
to this boy and called him a hero.
Well, I'll tell you what I call him,
public enemy number one.
I told you
I never wanted to do this ever again!
MJ, I'm so sorry, but I can't see anything
with your hand in my--
Sorry. Where are we gonna go?
- I don't know. Your house?
- No!
My dad will kill you.
What? You said your dad really liked me.
Yeah, well, not anymore.
- Dude.
Dude!
- Dude!
I'm so sorry. Are you okay?
- No, not really.
- Yo, Peter!
We should go. We should go. Come on.
- You said you don't want to swing.
- You should just swing me.
- Okay. We can take the subway.
- Okay.
No.
Look out!
That was so much worse. Okay. It's okay.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Come on, come on, come on.
Okay, I'm so sorry.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
I just feel so dumb.
I didn't realize you were miserable.
No, it was really fun, right?
That's why they call it a fling.
- And we flung.
- It was fun. I could've been more fun.
- We'll hang out again.
- Like, when do you think?
- I should see what that is.
- No, no, no.
- It's what I do. Peter?
- He's always coming and going.
- Peter?
- Oh, no.
- Oh, God.
- Peter? Peter?
- I don't know what to do.
- I didn't see anything.
- This isn't what it looks like.
- No, no, no, May.
- Practice safe--
Oh, hey. You must be MJ.
- Yeah. Nice to meet you.
- So nice to meet you.
- Wait, have you been crying?
- We broke up.
Hey, Spider-Man!
Thank you. I didn't know you broke up.
I thought you were in love, May.
Can we talk about this in the kitchen?
I should probably leave.
I thought you guys were
such a handsome couple.
It's really about boundaries.
- Let me answer the door.
- Let's go in here.
- Is that the door?
- Hey. Is it true?
- I was gonna go, but...
- Not now.
I didn't know you were
so awkward about sex, Peter.
This has nothing to do with sex.
If you wanna go over it again.
I mean-- What's that sound?
- Hey, Spider-Man!
- Oh, my God.
I mean, I'm happy to rehash it
if you want to.
You take care of your side,
I'll take care of mine.
What is up with this phone?
Will you get off your phones
for five minutes?
I just wanna talk to you
about your relationship, okay?
Peter?
What?
- Is that--?
- Is that here?
- Yo, Peter Parker!
- Yo, Peter!
Maybe it's not such a big deal.
Spider-Menace!
Governments around the world
launch investigations
into the murderer known as Spider-Man,
aka Peter Parker,
aka the web-headed war criminal
who, for years, has been terrorizing
the decent citizens of New York.
Well, now this city and the world see him
for what he truly is.
Murderer! Mysterio forever!
New details from last week's
devastating attack in London have emerged.
For more, we go now
to Joint Intelligence headquarters.
Authorities,
just a short while ago, confirmed
that the deadly drones used
in the London attack
were designed by Stark Industries.
Federal agents! Open up!
Federal agents? You stay here.
Department of Damage Control.
We have a warrant
for the arrest of Peter Parker.
- You know the Fourth Amendment?
- Sure.
- Unreasonable search and seizure?
- Get in here, guys. Let's go.
I didn't kill Quentin Beck.
The drones did, okay?
- The drones that are yours.
- No.
Nick Fury was there the entire time.
He can explain everything.
Nick Fury has been off-planet
for the last year.
- What?
- Peter! Hey.
MJ! They have nothing
to do with this, sir.
Don't say anything without a lawyer.
I want a lawyer.
- Ms. Jones-Watson.
- Jones. I don't go by Watson.
- Ms. Jones, why do you want a lawyer if--?
- If I have nothing to hide?
- Exactly. Unless--
- I'm actually guilty of something?
I'm very aware of your tactics
and my rights.
Just answer my questions.
I've seen your file.
You're a smart young woman
with a bright future ahead of her.
Why would you risk it all
by getting involved
with a vigilante like Peter Parker?
So sorry to keep you waiting.
- Can we get Ned a snack?
- Absolutely.
- He's been waiting.
- I got you.
Dude, I'm so sorry about that.
- I'm not supposed to say anything to you.
- Not even a thing.
I just have one question.
When MJ told you Peter was Spider-Man--
- What's up?
- I knew way before MJ did.
- I was Spider-Man's "guy in the chair."
- I know about those.
- Dude, half my guys are guys in the chair.
- Exactly.
You would know.
I literally helped him find the Vulture.
- I didn't know that.
- I helped him hack a suit once
and helped him get to space.
So in Spider-Man's illegal vigilantism,
you were his main accomplice.
I would like to have
my words stricken from the record.
With all due respect,
and I mean that very insincerely,
unless you have
some real specific charges to throw at us,
legally, you can't hold us here.
- You should definitely lawyer up.
- Excuse me?
Child endangerment's a nasty rap.
A boy was entrusted to you,
and as his legal guardian,
essentially his mother,
you not only allowed him
to endanger himself, you encouraged it.
Who does that?
I wanna see Peter right now.
Stark Industries was caught in the web
of the Spider-Man!Mysterio
controversy today,
when federal agents opened
an investigation
into missing Stark technology.
Agents wanna know
exactly what was taken...
- At least they used a good picture.
- What is happening?
That's great.
Thank you.
I have some good news, Peter.
I don't believe any of the charges
against you are gonna stick.
Wait, seriously?
- I knew it.
- Nice.
Mr. Murdock, thank you.
- Thank you.
- That's amazing.
- You're welcome.
- Perfect.
- However, Mr. Hogan...
- Yes?
...the feds are investigating
that missing technology.
I understand your loyalty
to Mr. Stark and his legacy,
but if you were involved--
- If I was?
- I advise securing a lawyer.
I need a lawyer because I'm--?
I thought he was--
You said there's no charge.
I could say under advisement of counsel,
I refuse to answer
the question respectfully
because the answer can incriminate me--
It's in Goodfellas. What's the thing
they say in Goodfellas?
I know that's what you think. Calm down.
Let's hear what he has to say. Matt?
You're gonna need a really good lawyer.
You may have dodged your legal troubles,
but things will get much worse.
There is still the court
of public opinion.
Murderer! Mysterio forever!
How did you just do that?
I'm a really good lawyer.
We'll need a safer place to live.
How do we--? How do we--?
Alarm system deactivated.
It looks nice. And this is safe.
Welcome to the spiritual oasis.
You like Donkey Kong Jr. ?
Nicky, from Jersey City,
you're on the line.
Hi. I'm not saying
I don't want to honor the Avengers,
but, you know, not doing it this way.
Putting the Captain America shield
on the Statue of Liberty?
Nah, that will look ridiculous.
Leave the Statue of Liberty alone.
Oh, Happy.
- Did you send in your applications yet?
- I finished my MIT one.
- You?
- Same.
Can you imagine
if we both got in? And Ned?
Yeah, but we'd have to get scholarships,
so we could actually go.
You got the scores and the grades.
You think I'm being too pragmatic.
No, no, no. Well...
Kind of. It's okay.
It's one of my favorite things about you.
- Really?
- Yeah.
What are your other favorite things?
- Your relentless optimism.
- I'm a glass-half-full kind of gal.
- I really like how you're a people person.
- I love people.
- I love them so much.
- You like sports.
I think the Mets are gonna go
all the way this year.
- Really?
- What's that noise?
It's-- It's Happy. Look.
Gave his room to May,
so he's sleeping down here.
I have a weird question.
Does any part of you
feel relieved about this?
Ever since I got bit by that spider...
I've only had one week
where my life has felt normal.
Or kind of normal, I guess.
And...
that was when you found out.
Because then everyone that was in my life
that I wanted to know knew.
And it was perfect.
But now everybody knows and...
I am the most famous person
in the entire world.
And I'm still broke.
I'm...
excited to see you tomorrow.
Yeah. Me too.
Wrap it up.
You both like each other.
We get it. Hang up.
There's no new ground being broken.
I need my eight hours.
- Have you been listening this whole time?
- Hi, Happy.
Not by choice.
- MJ says hi.
- Hello.
We're covering
the first day of senior year
for Midtown High's most famous student,
Peter Parker.
Go get them, tiger!
Or should I say "spider"?
The crowd has continued
to grow here all morning long
at the Midtown School of Science...
The crowd seems evenly divided
between supporters of Spider-Man
and protestors.
MJ!
MJ! MJ! We love you!
MJ, are you gonna have his spider-babies?
Back up. Back up. Back up!
MJ, you know he's a murderer, right?
Peter, do a TikTok with me.
Mysterio forever!
Do a flip!
- Hey, let's see you and MJ kiss!
- Back off.
Who are you?
- Ned Leeds. Spider-Man's best friend.
- I'm Peter Parker's best friend.
You come at my boy,
you come at Flash Thompson.
If you wanna read
about our inspiring friendship,
you can in my new book, Flashpoint.
One spider, two hearts,
a million crazy-ass memories.
Check it out.
- Go.
- No, I gotta wait--
- No. Go.
- I'll see you inside, okay?
Keep watching Midtown News all year
as we bring you up close
and personal coverage
of Peter fighting his biggest battle yet:
College admissions.
Peter,
we would love to welcome you
back to Midtown High,
where we shape heroes.
Or murderers.
Stop it.
- It's an honor to serve you, sir.
- It's not.
Mysterio was right.
- Stop. That's all.
- Mysterio was right.
Some students put this together for you.
- No, you did that.
- I helped a little bit.
And I tried to stop you so many times,
but you powered through.
- He did all of that.
- Did a great job.
I hope you have time to check it out.
Feel free to walk
or swing through the hallway.
Or crawl on the ceiling
to avoid everybody.
- We all know you can do it.
- I'm just gonna...
- I know what you did.
- Stop. You're embarrassing yourself.
He's a conspiracy theorist.
Can we just stay up here all day?
- It is so crazy down there.
- This one's good.
"Some suggest that Parker's powers
include the male spider's ability
to hypnotize females,
which he used to seduce Jones-Watson
into his cult of personality."
Stop. Stop.
Yes, my Spider-Lord.
Finally, some privacy.
It is so crazy down there.
So I was thinking...
when we get into MIT,
we should live together.
- Yeah, for sure.
- Yeah, I'd love that.
- This is gonna be us.
- Yes. Minus the Frisbee and the smiling.
MIT's obviously the dream,
but if we match up our backup schools,
then either way, we'll be in Boston.
New school, new town.
I can Spider-Man there.
- They have crime in Boston, right?
- Yes.
- Wicked crime.
- It'll be like a fresh start.
What's up?
I don't know.
I just feel like, if you don't--
If you expect disappointment,
then you can never really
get disappointed.
Come on.
Be a fresh start.
And we'll all be together.
Yeah. No, you're right. Fresh start.
Yeah.
Fresh start.
First one's here!
It's okay. It's a backup.
Peter.
No?
Last one.
MIT?
Okay.
- Ready?
- Jones,
I told you to take down
the Halloween decorations.
- Actually, that was Sasha, so--
- Enough attitude. Just do it.
On it.
Feel like I'm gonna puke.
Don't because he will
just make me clean it.
This is our only shot.
It's here or nowhere.
- Hey. Come on.
- Okay. You ready?
- Yeah.
- Okay, on three.
One, two, three.
No.
No. You?
"In light of recent controversy,
we are unable to consider
your application at this time."
This is so not fair.
I mean, this is so not fair.
I didn't do anything wrong.
You guys definitely didn't do
anything wrong.
Expect disappointment
and you will never get disappointed.
No sleep till
Boston
You didn't get in?
Yeah, because we're actually friends
with Spider-Man.
Yeah. I better get going.
There's a mixer for new admissions and--
Sorry, guys.
Jones, what are you doing?
Get back to work.
Yeah, I'm coming.
Know what?
I wouldn't change a thing I did.
Me neither.
Although I do need
to show this letter to my parents.
Subtitle
www.movieddl.me
Hi.
Hi?
I'm--
The most famous person
in the world. I know.
Wong. Try not to slip.
We don't have liability insurance.
- Is all this for a holiday party?
- No.
One of the rotunda gateways
connects to Siberia.
A blizzard blasted through.
Because someone forgot
to cast a monthly maintenance spell
to keep the seals tight.
That's right, he did, because he forgot
I now have higher duties.
Higher duties?
The Sorcerer Supreme has higher duties.
Wait, I thought
you were the Sorcerer Supreme.
No, he got it on a technicality
'cause I blipped for five years.
- Congratulations.
- If I'd been here, then--
You'd burn the place down.
You two, no one said stop shoveling.
So, Peter, to what do I owe the pleasure?
Right. I'm really sorry
to bother you, sir.
Please. We saved half
the universe together.
- Think we're beyond you calling me "sir."
- Okay, Stephen.
That feels weird, but I'll allow it.
When...
When Mysterio revealed my identity,
my entire life got screwed up
and I was wondering--
I don't know if this would actually work,
but I was wondering if...
maybe you could go back in time
and make it so he never did?
Peter, we tampered
with the stability of space-time
to resurrect countless lives.
You wanna do it again now
just 'cause yours got messy?
It's not about me.
This is really hurting a lot of people.
My Aunt May, Happy,
my best friend, my girlfriend,
their futures are ruined
just because they know me,
and they've done nothing wrong.
I am so sorry...
but even if I wanted to...
I don't have the Time Stone anymore.
That's right.
I'm really sorry if I wasted your time.
- You didn't.
- Just forget about it.
Oh, he will. He's very good
at forgetting things.
Wong, you've actually generated
a good idea.
What?
The Runes of Kof-Kol.
The Runes of Kof-Kol?
It's just a standard spell of forgetting.
Won't turn back time, but people will
forget you were ever Spider-Man.
- Seriously?
- No, not seriously.
That spell travels the dark borders
between known and unknown reality.
It's too dangerous.
We've used it for a lot less.
Do you remember
the full moon party at Kamar-Taj?
- No.
- Exactly.
Come on, Wong.
Hasn't he been through enough?
Just leave me out of this.
Fine.
So, what is this place?
The Sanctum's built at the intersection
of cosmic energy currents.
We weren't the first to seek them out.
Some of these walls
are thousands of years old.
And they shot an episode
of The Equalizer here in the '80s.
Well, I...
really appreciate you
doing this for me, sir.
Don't mention it.
And don't call me "sir."
Right. Sorry.
You ready?
I'm ready.
Nice knowing you, Spider-Man.
Wait, excuse me?
The entire world's about to forget
that Peter Parker is Spider-Man.
- Including me.
- Everyone?
- Can't some people still know?
- That's not how the spell works.
And it's very difficult and dangerous
to change it mid-casting.
So my girlfriend's gonna
forget everything?
Is she even gonna be my girlfriend?
Was she your girlfriend
just 'cause you were Spider-Man?
- I don't know. I really hope not.
- All right, fine.
Everyone's gonna forget
you're Spider-Man except your girlfriend.
Thank you so much.
Oh, my God, Ned. Ned.
What is a Ned?
He's my best friend,
so it's important to me that Ned knows.
Okay, let's not change
the parameters of this spell any more
- while I'm casting it.
- Okay, I'm done.
I swear, I'm done. I'm done.
- But my Aunt May should really know.
- Peter, stop tampering with the spell.
When she found out I was Spider-Man,
it was really messy.
I don't think
I could go through that again.
- So my Aunt May?
- Yes.
Thank you. Happy?
No, I'm annoyed.
No, it's a nickname. Harold "Happy" Hogan.
He used to work with Tony Stark,
but then he was...
Would you just stop talking?
Basically, everyone that knew
I was Spider-Man before should still know!
- Did it work?
- No.
You changed my spell six times.
- Five times.
- You changed my spell.
You don't do that.
I told you. And that is why.
That spell was out of control.
If I hadn't shut it down,
something catastrophic
could have happened.
- Stephen, listen, I am so--
- Call me "sir."
Sorry, sir.
After everything we've been through,
somehow I always forget you're just a kid.
Look, Parker, the problem is not Mysterio.
It's you trying
to live two different lives.
And the longer you do that,
the more dangerous it becomes.
Believe me.
I'm so sorry about you
and your friends not getting into college,
but if they rejected you and you tried
to convince them to reconsider,
there's nothing else you can do.
When you say "convince them,"
- you mean, I could have called them?
- Yeah.
I could do that?
You haven't called the...?
I got their letter. I assumed that was--
I'm sorry.
Are you telling me
that you didn't even think
to plead your case with them first
before you asked me
to brainwash the entire world?
When you put it like that...
Come on, pick up, pick up.
Dude, what? I'm busy.
- Flash, where's the MIT mixer?
- Why?
Because I need to talk to someone.
I'm trying to get Ned and MJ
a second chance at getting in.
What's in it for me?
I'm risking a lot just talking to you.
Okay, I will...
pick you up and swing you
to school for one week?
For a month.
- For a week.
- Two weeks.
- Flash, please. Help me.
- You know what I want.
Okay, I'll tell everyone
you're my best friend.
- Flash, please, help me.
- Cool.
There's the assistant vice chancellor.
You can plead your case with her.
- Okay, perfect. Where is she?
- She left.
- To go where?
- To the airport.
Stark network unavailable.
Facial recognition unavailable.
Hi.
Yeah, I can see you.
Oh, my God!
- That's Peter Parker.
- Mom.
- Mom, look.
- Mommy.
No, it's Peter Parker.
Hey!
Okay.
Yeah.
Hi. I'm Peter Parker.
- You do know you're in the street, right?
- Yeah, I'm sorry.
I really needed to talk to you and I know
you're on your way to the airport.
MJ Watson and Ned Leeds are
the two smartest people I've ever met,
and I'm the dumbest person
because I let them help me,
but if I didn't, millions would've died,
so please don't let MIT be dumb like me.
MIT is dumb?
No, I'm saying, don't let MIT be dumb.
I mean, like the dumber version of me
that wouldn't have let them help.
You didn't rehearse that, did you, Peter?
Basically, what I'm trying to--
Why are you running?
Oh, my God.
Ma'am, you should get out of the car.
Everybody get off the bridge!
The door's locked.
Door's-- Hey!
Hello, Peter.
Hi? Do we--? Do I know you?
What have you done with my machine?
I don't know what you're talking about.
What machine?
The power of the sun
in the palm of my hand.
It's gone.
Listen, if you stop smashing cars,
we can work together
and I can help you find your machine.
You want to play games?
Catch!
It's okay. You guys are good.
You're safe. Get out of here.
You think
your fancy new suit's gonna save you?
Should've killed your little girlfriend
when I had the chance.
What did you just say?
Looks like we got competition.
Peter!
Help!
Don't worry, ma'am! I'm coming!
Peter!
Ma'am, just stay calm.
Just take a deep breath.
- Are you okay?
- No!
I promise,
I've got this all under control.
Suit compromised.
Nanotechnology.
Ah, you've outdone yourself, Peter.
I underestimated you.
But now you die.
You're not Peter Parker.
I am so confused right now.
What's happening?
New device detected.
Pairing new device.
You don't listen to him. You listen to me.
Hey.
Hey. Hey.
Listen to me.
No, not him. Me.
Ma'am, you okay?
You can still make your flight.
Peter.
You're a hero.
No. Well, I'm--
No, I'm--
I'm gonna talk to Admissions
about your friends.
And I'm gonna talk to them about you.
But, ma'am, this isn't about me.
I am going to talk to them
about your friends and you.
- Okay?
- Really?
And if you keep your noses clean,
maybe you'll have a fair shot.
Here. Get out of the way.
Let me get that man.
Hey. You. I see you. Come here!
That was not okay.
Unbelievable.
Who are--?
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
Until you stop trying to kill me,
I'm in control, buddy,
of this whole tentacle situation
you got going on here, okay?
Now, who are you? What is going--?
No.
Osborn?
Doctor--?
Be careful what you wish for, Parker.
Let me out of here!
Can you please explain to me
what is going on?
That little spell that you botched
where you wanted everyone
to forget that Peter Parker's Spider-Man,
it started pulling in everyone
who knows Peter Parker's Spider-Man
from every universe into this one.
- From every universe?
- Who are you? And where am I?
I think it's better we don't engage
with them because, frankly,
the multiverse is a concept
about which we know frighteningly little.
The multiverse is real?
This shouldn't be possible.
- I thought you stopped the spell.
- No, I contained it.
It would appear
a few of them squeaked through.
After you left,
I detected an otherworldly presence.
I pursued it into the sewers,
where I found that...
slimy, green son of a gun.
Spell? As in magic?
What is this, a birthday party?
Who is this clown? What is this madness?
Watch this. Do you know
a Peter Parker who's Spider-Man?
- Yes.
- Is that him?
- No.
- See?
Here's what we gotta do.
I don't know how many visitors we've got--
I saw another one on the bridge.
He was like a flying green elf.
He sounds jolly. Start with him.
I need you to capture them,
bring them here while I figure out
how to get them back
before they destroy the fabric of reality,
or worse, Wong finds out.
Doctor Strange?
What?
My friends and I just got
a second chance to get into MIT,
and if the school sees me
fighting these crazy monsters--
- Hey, watch your mouth.
- I'm sorry, but--
Are you seriously
still talking about college?
- Hey, what did you just do?
- This.
Hey, you can't just--
- How did you do that?
- Lots of birthday parties.
Hey.
One shot, send them here, move on.
You're welcome.
- Get to work.
- Sir?
Now what?
This is my mess,
and I swear that I'll fix it,
but I'm gonna need help.
I can't believe
I'm in the Sanctum Sanctorum.
Neither can I.
So how did you know
you were a man of magic?
Because my Nana says
that we have it in our family,
- and I get these tinglings in my hands--
- Talk to your physician.
- Peter.
- Hey.
- Hey. Hey.
Sorry for dragging you into this.
- Help me find these guys.
- You don't have to apologize, okay?
You got us
a second shot at MIT. It's fine.
So how did the bad guys get here?
We screwed up a spell
trying to get you into college.
- You did it with magic?
- I thought it was the MIT lady you saved.
No, that was after.
Let's just focus on the good news, okay?
No, let's just focus on the bad news.
As of now, you have detected
zero multiversal trespassers,
so get on your phones,
scour the Internet, and...
Scooby-Doo this shit.
You're telling us what to do, even though
it was your spell that got screwed up,
meaning that all this is your mess.
I know a couple of magic words myself,
starting with the word "please."
Please Scooby-Doo this shit.
You can work in the undercroft.
The undercroft?
Badass.
- About this whole spell thing--
- It's totally okay.
- Really?
- Yeah. I mean, I get it.
You were just trying
to fix things, and so...
Maybe just run it by us next time,
you know?
That way, when you're thinking,
"I'm about to do something
that could break the universe,"
we could, like, help you
workshop something or...
brainstorm ideas.
Deal.
Ned?
Oh, dude, I don't care.
It's seriously not a big deal.
A torture rack.
That is a Pilates machine.
- That is--
- The crypt.
Okay, so we get the rest of the guys,
you zap them,
Doctor Magic will send them back,
and when we get into MIT,
round of stale doughnuts, my treat.
Let's catch some multiverse men.
Hey! Who the hell are these two?
- My friends. This is MJ. And this is Ned.
- Hey.
Hello.
- Sorry, what was your name again?
- Dr. Otto Octavius.
Seriously, what's your actual name?
Oh, is that a dinosaur?
If the paint won't come off,
I'll get it out.
No, no, no, May.
We gotta find these guys first.
Finish your mission and then come by.
We're having a canned food drive.
- That could work.
- I got one.
- I gotta go.
- Okay.
I mean, you can take
the guy out of the chair,
but you can't take
the chair out of the guy.
- What'd you find?
- There's a...
A disturbance near a military
research facility outside of the city,
and witnesses say that they saw
a monster flying through the air.
It's gotta be the guy I saw on the bridge.
That's impossible.
You know him, don't you?
On the bridge, you said his name.
Norman Osborn.
Brilliant scientist. Military research.
But he was greedy, misguided.
- What happened to him?
- We tire of your questions, boy!
Okay.
- I gotta go. Where am I going?
- It can't be him.
Why?
Because Norman Osborn died years ago.
So either we saw someone else...
or you're flying out
into the darkness to fight a ghost.
Keep an eye out on the trees.
We don't know where this guy is.
I genuinely don't know
how you do this without throwing up.
Did you see that?
-No.
- It is really dark.
Okay, okay, okay.
What's happening?
Peter, what is it?
Are you getting the tingle thing?
Is the tingle happening?
Is your tingle tingling?
- Are you guys seeing this?
- Yeah.
- Osborn?
- No. He was green. This guy's blue.
You wouldn't happen to be
from another universe, would you?
What's he doing?
- I don't know. Looks like he's charging.
- I don't like this. Just web him.
Go left! Left, dude, left!
Left! Go! Left! Yes!
What are you talking about? Right.
Go to the right! Right! Right!
- He means right. Don't listen to him.
- This is not helping!
Oh, no, no, no.
What happened? Peter? Peter.
Peter, it's me, Flint Marko. You remember?
- I'm Peter, but I'm not your Peter.
- What do you mean, you're not my Peter?
- What the hell is going on?
- I'll explain, but first, can you help me?
- Okay.
- You try to surround him,
and I'll pull the plug.
All right, let's go!
I can't hold him much longer.
I got it, I got it!
Different Peter. Weird.
- Thanks. Sorry.
- Don't worry about it.
I got my body back.
Hey.
This is gonna sound really crazy,
but this isn't your universe.
Another universe?
- What?
- That's what I was feeling.
The power, it's different.
I like it.
- Easy, buddy.
- It's actually my fault that you're here.
Like, the universe or the woods?
I hate the woods.
I meant, the universe, sir.
So, what, y'all just gonna stand here
and act like I ain't butt-ass naked?
- I am.
- No, no.
I...
What was that?
What did you just do to him?
- No. It's okay.
- Did you kill him?
I can explain everything. Trust me.
- Please, just trust me.
- I don't trust you. I don't know you.
What is this?
You picked the wrong side.
Connors?
Wait. You know this creature?
No, no, no. Not a creature. A man.
The same universes.
Dr. Curt Connors. He was a scientist
at Oscorp when I worked there.
A brilliant scientist.
Until he turned himself into a lizard.
Then he tried to turn
the whole city into lizards.
- It was crazy.
- It wasn't crazy, Max.
It was the next step in human evolution.
- The dinosaur can talk. Right.
- Lizard.
What happened to you?
Last I recall, you had bad teeth,
glasses and a comb-over.
Did you get a makeover?
You know I can give you a real makeover.
Let me guess, into a lizard?
- Exactly.
- Would you two just shut up?
- Where are we?
- It's complicated.
- A wizard's dungeon.
- Wizard's dungeon?
There's no real way to sugarcoat that.
It's literally the dungeon of a wizard.
You can keep your magic.
I want a taste of that energy I just felt.
- Oh, Peter, hey.
- Did those guys come through yet?
There should be an electric guy
and a sand guy.
Yeah, they're all here and locked up.
Perfect. I'm gonna just stay here
and try and fix some of this damage,
so they don't blame it on me again.
- Okay.
- But, hey, I...
I couldn't do any of this without you,
so thank you.
Of course.
Hey, ask him
if this is like a tree monster
or like a scientist
that turned into a tree.
It's just a tree, man.
Just a tree.
Coward. We have a new world to conquer.
You make me sick.
Leave me alone, please.
Hiding in the shadows.
Hiding from who you truly are.
- No.
- You can't escape yourself.
- Hey, May.
- Hey, Peter. I'm at work, and...
one of the guys
you're looking for just walked in.
May? Where's May? Thank you.
May.
Hey, here he is.
Norman, this is my nephew.
Norman Osborn? I thought that you were--
I saw Spider-Man in an ad for this place.
And I thought he could help me.
But you're not him.
Wait, so you want Spider-Man's help?
He just wandered in.
I didn't know where else to go.
Someone's living in my house.
Oscorp doesn't exist.
My son...
Sometimes I'm not myself.
I'm... someone else.
And every time he's in control,
I can't remember.
- Who's in control?
- And now I'm here--
- I don't know what's going on.
- Okay, it's okay.
- And I don't-- Doesn't make sense.
He's lost.
And I don't mean just in the cosmos.
I mean, in his mind.
Are they all like this?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
They all have their own mental
or physical issues.
Oh, well, he needs help
and maybe they all do.
Wait, you don't mean--?
No, May, this isn't my problem.
Peter, not your problem?
May, their chance of getting help is
way better back where they came from.
Sending them home, that's the best thing
that we can do for them.
For them? Or for yourself?
Look around you. This is what we do.
- We help people.
- This is what's best for them.
Trust me.
But the fact remains,
Spider-Man is a menace.
We'll be right back after a brief word
from Daily Bugle Supplements.
The only other daily fix you need.
And we're out.
What?
I got eyes on him.
- He's with his aunt and some guy.
- You sure?
- They're just leaving the shelter.
- Okay. Don't lose him.
Thanks, May. Hope to see you again.
Hey. He trusts you. So do I.
Thanks for cleaning my suit.
See you later.
- Guys, this is Mr. Osborn.
- Hey, it's "doctor."
Sorry. Dr. Osborn, these are my friends.
This is Ned and MJ.
- Mary Jane?
- It's Michelle Jones, actually.
Fascinating.
Do you think there are other Ned Leedses?
Octavius?
Osborn?
What happened to you?
What happened to--?
- You're the walking corpse.
- What do you mean?
You died, Norman.
Years ago.
You're insane.
God, I love it here.
What are you talking about?
He's standing right there.
- He's not--
- Dead.
They both died, fighting Spider-Man.
It was all over the news.
Green Goblin, impaled
by the glider you flew around on.
And a couple of years later, you, Doc Ock,
- drowned in the river with your machine.
- Nonsense.
Spider-Man was trying to stop
my fusion reactor, so I stopped him.
I had him by the throat, and then I...
And then I was here.
Please. Let me tell you something.
I was whupping Spider-Man's ass.
He'll tell you.
And then he caused an overload.
I was stuck in the grid, absorbing data.
I was about to turn
into pure energy, and then...
And then...
And then-- Oh, shit.
- I was about to die.
- Max, do you know? Do I die?
- Oh, great. You caught another one.
- No, wait, Strange.
He's not dangerous.
It's okay.
What is that?
It's an ancient relic.
The Macchina di Kadavus.
I've trapped your corrupted spell inside,
and once I finish the proper ritual,
it'll reverse the spell and send
these guys back to their universes.
And then what? We perish?
No. No, thanks. I'll pass on that.
Let me out of here. Peter!
Strange, we can't send them back. Not yet.
Why?
- Well, some of these guys are gonna die.
- Parker.
It's their fate.
Come on, have a heart.
In the grand calculus of the multiverse,
their sacrifice means infinitely more
than their lives.
I'm sorry, kid.
If they die, they die.
Peter!
Don't.
- What are you doing?
- Peter, you gotta go. Go.
- Okay.
- Get out of here.
This is why I never had kids.
- Give me the box.
- No.
Oh, my God, I'm dead.
You're not dead, you've just been
separated from your physical form.
My physical-- What?
How are you doing that?
- I have no idea.
- You should not be able to do that.
This feels amazing.
One of the coolest things
that's ever happened to me,
but don't ever do that again.
Hey! Get off of me!
What is this place?
The Mirror Dimension,
where I'm in control.
Strange, stop.
Can we just talk about this?
Parker, don't you realize
that in the multiverse,
there are an infinite number of people
who know Peter Parker is Spider-Man?
And if that spell gets loose,
they're all coming here.
I know, I get it,
but we can't just send them home to die.
It's their fate.
You can't change that any more
than you could change who they are.
What if we could?
What if we could change their fate?
What are you doing?
I'm not giving you the--
Give me that back.
Wait a minute.
Is that an Archimedean Spiral?
The dimension is just geometry?
You're great at geometry.
You can do geometry.
Square the radius. Divide by pi.
- Plot points along the curve.
- It's over, Parker.
I'll come pick you up when it's done.
Hey, Strange.
You know what's cooler than magic?
- Math.
- Don't do this.
I'm sorry, sir, but...
I have to try.
- What happened?
- I had a fight with Strange and I won.
- What?
- I stole his ring thing.
I was swinging, and then I went
through this massive mirror thing,
- and then I was back--
- Where is he?
He's trapped,
but I'm not sure for how long.
You could have left us to die.
Why didn't you?
'Cause that's not who he is.
I think I can help you guys.
If I can fix what happened to you,
then when you go back,
things will be different,
and you might not die fighting Spider-Man.
- What do you mean?
- Our technology is advanced--
I can help you. You know,
I'm something of a scientist myself.
Octavius knows what I can do.
Fix? You mean, like a dog?
I refuse.
I can't promise you guys anything,
but at least this way,
you get to go home and have a chance.
A second chance.
Isn't that worth trying?
Trust me, Peter,
when you try to fix people,
there are always consequences.
You don't have to come.
I also didn't know that you could talk.
But if you stay here...
you'll have to deal with the wizard.
So we go along or die.
Not much of a choice, is it?
I just wanna go home.
I, myself, don't wanna be killed,
especially by a guy dressed
like Dungeons & Dragons,
so, what's your plan?
I have it all under control.
What are we gonna do about this thing?
We need
to find somewhere safe for it, right?
- Yeah, sure. You gotta take it.
- Wait, what?
If something bad happens,
you just push this and then it's over.
We're not gonna leave you.
You can't. It's dangerous.
- You have done enough.
- We're in this together.
I know we're in this together, Ned,
but I can't do this if you're in danger.
Okay? So for me, MJ,
please just take this.
- Please.
- Fine.
- Thank you.
- But, Peter,
if I don't hear from you,
I'm pressing the button.
- Sure.
- Okay. And I will do it.
Yeah, we all believe you, Michelle.
No way that's his girlfriend. No way.
- She'll do it.
- Absolutely, she will.
- Okay. See you later.
- Be safe.
- You too.
- Okay.
Okay.
- Be careful, okay?
- Yeah. You too.
So...
who's coming with me?
Well, I'm in.
But if this goes sideways...
I'm gonna fry you from the inside out.
-Where's Connors?
- He wants to stay in the truck.
-Okay.
- Alarm system deactivated.
Hey, May.
- Yeah?
- I feel bad using Happy's place like this.
No, no, no. He'll get over it.
New Yorkers oppose
the Statue of Liberty renovation...
Oh, sorry.
So this is your plan, Peter?
No lab, no facilities?
Just performing miracles in a condominium?
What, you gonna cook us some cures
and some frozen burritos in a microwave?
- I could go for a burrito.
- He's gonna kill us all.
Well, let's hope not.
- You're up first, Doc.
- What?
Hey, I told you, I don't need fixing.
I don't need fixing!
Especially by a teenager using scraps
from a bachelor's junk drawer.
Nah, nah, nah.
He got something back there.
I can feel it. That weird energy.
- What the hell is that?
- It's a fabricator.
It can analyze, design,
construct basically anything.
I thought that was
the tanning bed Happy broke.
Look at that.
He's gonna kill us all.
What's going on there?
So the chip in the back of Doc's neck
was designed to protect his brain
from the Al system that's controlling
these tentacles, but if you look here...
the chip is fried.
So rather than him being
in control of the tentacles,
the tentacles are now in control of him.
Which, I guess, explains why
he is so miserable all the time.
Thirsty?
Well, yes, I am thirsty.
Fresh water or salt?
You know, because you're an octopus.
What?
Fresh water it is.
Look at this place.
- And all the possibilities.
- What, this condo?
Yeah, yeah, the condo.
I love the whole open floor plan. No.
Nah, man, I'm talking about the world.
I kind of like who I am here.
And all that power back there...
I could be so much more.
So why'd you come along?
I have a daughter, and I want to see her.
But he's not gonna send anyone home
till he's finished
his little science project back there.
You trust him?
I don't trust anyone.
How'd you end up like that, anyway?
The place where I worked at,
they were experimenting with electricity
created by living organisms, and then...
I fell into a vat of electric eels.
You're kidding.
I fell into a supercollider.
Damn.
Gotta be careful where you fall.
Remarkable.
The technology and you.
When all this is over,
if you need a job and you're willing
to commute to another universe...
It worked. That totally worked!
- I got it. I did it. Will you send him up?
- Here we go.
- Sorry.
- Hold on, Doc.
Oh, will these humiliations never cease?
You, keep your science-fair project
away from me!
It'll work. Have faith.
Says the reckless fool
who turned himself into a monster.
Please stop moving your head.
- Hold still.
- Don't you dare.
I swear, when I get out of this,
we're gonna rip you a new--
Doc?
Dr. Octav--
It's so quiet.
Those voices inside my head...
I'd almost forgotten.
Otto.
Yes. Norman.
It's me.
Would you look at that?
I'm grateful, dear boy. Truly.
Yeah, you're welcome.
How can I help?
This is Peter. Leave a message.
Yeah, Peter, this is Happy.
I accessed my doorbell camera.
Who are those guys, huh? Is that a cyborg?
You bring a cyborg
with robot legs into my house?
Was one of the guys made of mud?
What's going on? Call me.
How does it feel, Norman?
You're about to become whole again.
No more darker half.
Just you.
Just me.
Okay.
It just goes right here. This...
That should be drawing power now.
I'll come back in a second to check on it,
but keep an eye on the lights.
When they're all green,
the electricity in your body's dissipated.
Well, not all of the electricity. You need
electricity for your brain to function.
Your nervous system is...
I'm not really sure
why I'm explaining electricity to you.
- Yeah, can I ask you a question?
- Sure.
Are these your Legos?
I gotta go. I'll be back.
- Something feels off.
- What do you mean?
- I don't like this.
- Leave it alone.
The sooner you guys get through this,
the sooner we go home.
- Well, where is he?
- He's inside.
And yet here we are, outside.
Did you not hear me say, "Don't lose him"?
I want incriminating footage
of Spider-Man.
I called Damage Control.
They're on their way.
And so it begins.
Place is about to be swarming with cops.
- Peter?
What's wrong?
I don't know.
May?
What is it, Peter?
What's happening?
Why are you looking at me like that?
That's some neat trick,
that sense of yours.
- Norman?
- Norman's on sabbatical, honey.
- The hell?
- The Goblin.
"No more darker half"? Did you really
think that I'd let that happen?
That I'd let you take away my power
just because you're blind
- to what true power can bring you?
- You don't know me.
Don't I?
I saw how she trapped you,
fighting her holy moral mission.
We don't need you to save us.
We don't need to be fixed.
These are not curses.
They're gifts.
- Norman, no.
- Quiet, lapdog.
- You don't know what you're talking about.
- I've watched you
from deep behind Norman's cowardly eyes.
Struggling to have everything you want
while the world tries to make you choose.
Gods don't have to choose.
We take.
May, run.
Oh, my God.
- What have you done?
- I liked you better before.
Up here! He's up there.
It's the guy from the bridge.
Did you see that?
No, you don't!
Strong enough to have it all.
Too weak to take it!
Now I got you.
I told you, there'd be consequences!
Your weakness, Peter, is morality.
It's choking you. Can't you feel it?
It didn't work.
Norman was right.
He got it from you,
that pathetic sickness.
You tried to fix me.
May, go.
Now I'm gonna fix you.
May, run, please.
May!
Peter, Peter, Peter.
No good deed goes unpunished.
You can thank me later.
No!
- May?
- Peter.
May, May, I'm here.
May.
May, I'm here.
Are you okay? What happened?
It's okay. We're okay, right?
Yeah. Knocked on my ass.
- Yeah, me too.
- That's all.
I think I broke my ribs.
- This is all my fault, May.
- No.
I should have let Strange send them back.
You did the right thing.
They would have been killed.
It's not my responsibility, May.
What Norman said?
My moral mission? No.
- No, May--
- Peter, you listen to me.
You have a gift.
You have power.
And with great power,
there must also come great responsibility.
I know.
Let's get the...out of here.
Okay, let's go.
Let me just catch my...
- What happened? Are you okay?
- I'm okay.
Yeah, you're okay. What happened?
Just have to...
catch my breath.
Okay, well, catch your breath.
I'm right here.
We're gonna take our time.
You catch your breath
and then we'll take you to a doctor, okay?
Are you okay?
Somebody help!
I need an ambulance, please! Somebody?
- What happened?
- Nothing happened.
You're okay, you're okay.
Let me just-- Let me catch my breath.
I'm right here. I'm right here.
I'm right here.
You're okay.
It's just me and you.
May?
Will you look at me, please?
May.
What are you doing, May?
Please, will you just wake up
and talk to me? Please?
Get out of the car now! Move!
Get off, get off, get off me.
Peter!
- Run!
- It's just me and you, okay?
It's just me and you, okay?
Oh, May, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
- I'm so, so, so sorry. I love you.
- Parker, come out with your hands up!
Come out right now, or we will open fire!
Run!
All right, let's go, let's go! Move in!
Tragedy.
What else can I call it?
What more need be said?
The damage, the destruction.
You saw it with your own eyes.
When will people wake up and realize
that everywhere Spider-Man goes,
chaos and calamity ensue?
Everything Spider-Man touches
comes to ruin.
And we, the innocents,
are left to pick up the pieces.
J. Jonah Jameson reporting.
Good night, and God help us all.
We are told
that multiple people have been injured,
and we can confirm
at least one person has been killed.
Still nothing?
No.
I'm gonna press it.
- What? No, he--
- I know he told me to wait...
- but I'm gonna do it.
- I just wish--
I just wish we could see him.
- Ned?
- Yeah?
- Do that again.
- Yeah.
I just wish we could see him.
Okay.
I just wish we could see Peter.
Lola, you're right. I am magic.
Is that him?
- Yeah, yeah, it has to be.
- Peter. Peter!
- Hey, Peter! Yeah.
- Peter!
Hi. Hi.
No, no, no, it's okay.
It's okay. I'm a nice guy.
Okay.
- Who the hell are you?
- I'm Peter Parker.
- That's not possible.
- I am Spider-Man, in my world.
But then yesterday, I was--
I was just here.
String theory, multidimensional reality...
and matter displacement.
All real?
- Yeah.
I knew it.
This has to be because of the spell.
The spell? Like magic spell?
- There's no spell. No.
- No spell.
- Magic's real here too?
- I mean--
- Shut up, Ned.
- No, it's not real.
- Shut up. Stop talking.
- There's magicians, but there's no--
Stop. Stop.
- Prove it.
- Prove what?
- That you're Peter Parker.
- I don't carry an ID with me, you know?
Kind of defeats
the whole anonymous superhero thing.
- Why'd you do that?
- To see if you have the tingle thing.
I have the tingle thing,
just not for bread.
Can you not throw the bread again?
You're a deeply mistrusting person...
and I respect it.
Crawl around.
- Crawl around?
- Yes.
- No.
- Yes, crawl around.
- Why do I need to?
- This is not enough.
- This is plenty.
- No, it's not.
- Yes, it is. It is.
- No, it's not. No.
- How do I stick to the ceiling?
- Do it.
Ned.
My iota's asking if you could
just get the cobweb there.
- Since you're, like, up there.
- Yeah.
Thank you.
We--
We good?
For now.
So I opened the wrong portal
to the wrong Peter Parker.
I guess you keep doing it
until we find the real one.
No offense.
- Okay.
- Okay. You got it.
Find Peter Parker.
What's the thing on his hand?
Find Peter Parker!
Great, it's just some random guy.
Hello.
I hope it's okay,
I just came through this...
It just closed.
You're Peter?
Yeah. Peter Parker.
I've seen you two--
Hi.
Wait. He's-- He's not your friend.
Wait. So you're Spider-Man too?
Why didn't you just say that?
I generally don't go around
advertising it.
Kind of defeats
the whole anonymous superhero thing.
- I just said that.
- That's what he just said.
My iota's asking if you could clean up
the webs you just shot.
- Oh, sorry, Lola.
- Yes, of course.
I'm going to bed.
- Night, Lola.
- Good night, Ned's Lola.
This might seem kind of weird,
but I've been trying to find
your friend ever since I got here.
I just have this sense...
that he needs my help.
Our help.
He does.
We don't know where he is.
And, honestly,
right now we're all he really has left.
Well, is there someplace that he might go
that has meaning to him?
Like a place where he would go to just--?
Get away from everything?
For me, it was the top
of the Chrysler Building.
Empire State.
- It's just a-- It's a better view.
- That is a sweet view.
Yes.
Yeah. I think
I know exactly where that would be.
I'm sorry.
Peter, there's...
There's some people here.
What?
Hey, wait, wait, whoa.
What...?
Sorry...
about May.
Yeah. Sorry.
I got some understanding
of what it is you're--
No, please don't tell me
that you know what I'm going through.
- Okay.
- She's gone.
And it's all my fault.
She died for nothing.
So I'll do what I should have done
in the first place.
- Peter--
- Please don't.
You don't belong here. Either of you.
So I'm sending you home.
Those other guys are
from your worlds, right?
So you deal with it.
If they die, if you kill them...
that's on you.
It's not my problem.
I don't care anymore.
I'm done.
I'm really sorry
that I dragged you into this.
But you have to go home now.
Good luck.
My Uncle Ben was killed.
It was my fault.
I lost...
I lost Gwen, my...
She was my MJ.
I couldn't save her.
I'm never gonna be able
to forgive myself for that.
But I carried on, tried to...
Tried to keep going,
tried to keep being...
the friendly neighborhood Spider-Man
'cause I know that's
what she would've wanted.
But at some point,
I just stopped pulling my punches.
I got rageful.
I got bitter.
I just don't want you to end up like me.
The night Ben died...
I hunted down the man
who I thought did it.
I wanted him dead.
I got what I wanted.
It didn't make it better.
It took me a long time...
to learn to get through that darkness.
I wanna kill him.
I wanna tear him apart.
I can still hear her voice in my head.
Even after she was hurt,
she said to me
that we did the right thing.
She told me that with great power...
Comes great responsibility.
Wait, what? How do you know that?
Uncle Ben said it.
The day he died.
Maybe she didn't die for nothing, Peter.
Okay, so Connors, Marko, Dillon and...
I think that I can repair
the devices for Dillon and Marko,
but the others...
Oh, I got Connors.
I've cured him once, so no big deal.
- What? It's no big deal.
- Great.
Yeah, that's great.
I think I can make an antiserum
for Dr. Osborn.
Been thinking about it a long time.
Gotta cure all of them. Right?
Right.
That's what we do.
What?
Just three yous.
So... do you have a best friend too?
I did.
You did?
He died in my arms...
after he tried to kill me.
It was heartbreaking.
Dude.
- Hey.
- Will you run a diagnostic?
Yeah.
Hey, you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine. Are you okay?
You don't deserve this.
- I've ruined your life. I ruined it.
- No. No, no, no.
Look at me. I'm here.
Not going anywhere.
We'll get through this
and we'll get through it together.
Okay?
- Okay.
Thank you.
You have someone?
No.
I got no time
for Peter Parker stuff, you know?
Do you?
That's a little complicated.
I understand.
I guess it's just not
in the cards for guys like us.
Well, I wouldn't give up.
Took a while, but we made it work.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Me and... MJ.
My MJ.
It gets confusing here.
Yeah.
- Peter!
- Yeah?
- Oh, sorry, did you mean...?
- "Peter" Peter.
- We're all called Peter.
- We're all Peter.
- Peter Parker?
- Same again. We're all Peter Parker.
The computer.
- Oh, I'm ready.
- Yeah. Me too.
Okay, so now, all we gotta do is lure
these guys someplace, right?
Try to cure them
while they try to kill us,
and then send them home.
- Using a magic box.
- Well, that's the plan.
Are you gonna go into battle
dressed as a cool youth pastor,
or do you got your suit?
Good.
- Here's your web cartridges.
- Thanks, man.
What's that for?
It's my web fluid.
It's for my web shooters. Why?
- That came out of you.
- Yeah.
- You can't do that, huh?
- No.
How on earth does that even--?
We're getting sidetracked.
This is where we'll do this, okay?
It's isolated, so no one should get hurt.
We draw them there with the box.
It's the one thing they all want.
All we have to do is figure out
how to get there.
- We could portal there.
- What?
- I'm magic now.
- Yeah, he's right. He can.
- Yeah, we saw.
- Yeah, he is.
- Wait, really?
- I got Doctor Strange magic.
- No way.
- Yeah.
I promise you, I won't turn
into a supervillain and try to kill you.
Okay.
Thank you.
Here goes nothing.
What's that thing you always say?
- Expect disappointment and--
- No, no, no.
We're gonna kick some ass.
Okay.
Cure. Cure some ass.
Cure that ass.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Bugle tip line has
just received a call
from none other
than the fugitive known as Spider-Man,
fresh from his rampage in Queens.
So, Peter Parker, what pernicious
propaganda are you peddling?
-Just the truth.
- Oh, sure.
Truth is...
that this is all my fault.
I accidentally brought
those dangerous people here.
Well, he admits it.
And if those people are watching...
just know that I did try to help you.
I could have killed you...
at any given moment, but I didn't.
'Cause my Aunt May taught me
that everyone deserves a second chance.
- That's why I'm here.
- Where is "here," exactly?
A place that represents second chances.
The Statue of Liberty? Good God, folks.
He's about to destroy
another national landmark.
World, if you're watching...
Believe me, the world is watching.
...wish me luck.
Your friendly neighborhood
Spider-Man could use some.
Okay, it could be any minute now.
Yep, almost done.
You know, Max was,
like, the sweetest guy ever
before he fell into...
- a pool of electric eels.
- That'll do it.
Oh, there it goes.
You okay?
Oh, it's my back.
It's kind of stiff
from all the swinging, I guess.
- Yeah. No, I got a middle back thing too.
- Really?
Yeah. You want me to crack it?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- That'd be great.
- All right.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
Yep. That's good.
How is it?
- That's good. That's better.
- Right? Yeah.
This is so cool. I always wanted brothers.
So you, like,
make your own web fluid in your body?
I'd rather not talk about this.
- I don't mean to--
- But are you teasing me?
No, no, no. He's not teasing you.
It's just that we can't do that,
so we're curious as to how
your web situation works, that's all.
If it's personal, I don't wanna pry,
but I think it's cool.
I-- I wish I could tell you,
but it's, like, I don't do it.
Like I don't do breathing.
Like, breathing just happens.
Does it just come out of your wrists,
or does it come out of anywhere else?
Only-- Only the wrists.
Never had a web block?
I run out of webs all the time.
- I have to make my own in a lab.
- Right. That's--
- It's a hassle compared to what you got.
- Sounds like a hassle.
But I did. You said that,
I was like, "I had a web block."
- Why?
- Existential crisis stuff.
- Yeah. Don't get me started on that.
- Hey.
What are some of the craziest villains
that you guys have fought?
- Seems you've met some of them.
- That's a good question.
Yeah, I fought an alien
made out of black goo once.
Oh, no way. I fought an alien too.
On Earth and in space.
- He was purple.
- I wanna fight an alien.
I'm still, like, that you fought
an alien in space.
I'm lame compared-- I fought
a Russian guy in a rhinoceros machine.
Can we rewind it back
to the "I'm lame" part?
'Cause you are not.
Thanks. I appreciate that.
I'm not saying I am--
But it's just the self-talk.
Maybe we should...
- Listen, I--
- 'Cause you're amazing.
Just to take it in for a minute.
- Yeah, I can take it in.
- You are amazing.
- I can. Thank you.
- Will you say it?
- I needed to hear that. Thank you.
All right, guys, focus up. You feel that?
Yeah.
What's up, Peter?
How you like the new-new?
Look, you give it to me,
I'm gonna destroy it.
But I'll let you live.
Don't make me a murderer, Peter.
Okay, guys, here he comes.
Hey, Max! I missed you, man.
All right, MJ, heads up!
Got it. Close it.
- Ned, it's not closing.
- Yeah, I know.
- Why isn't it closing?
- I don't know.
- Did you close it before? No?
- I mean, I've opened some.
Max, Max, Max. Can we talk for a second?
- Just you and me, just talk?
- Look who showed up.
My old friend Spider-Man.
I'm trying to save you.
That's all I've wanted.
- You're not trying to save me.
- I am.
You ain't even the shit no more.
Don't worry about me. I'll save myself.
Burn up!
Well, I got his attention. Now what?
Okay, great.
Just FYI, lizard guy's here too.
Guys, comm check. Hello?
- I need Max's cure!
- Yeah. I'm on it.
Peter, I need the Lizard cure.
Okay, okay.
Where's the box, Peter?
- Flint, we could help everyone.
- I don't care.
Sorry!
Gross!
Sad to tell you, Sandman,
nobody's going home.
What the hell is going on out there?
I keep yelling at you, Peter 2!
- But I thought you were Peter 2.
- What? I'm not Peter 2.
Stop arguing, both of you!
Listen to Peter 1.
- We're clearly not very good at this.
- I know, I know. We suck.
- I don't know how to work as a team.
- Me neither.
I do. I've been in a team, okay?
I don't wanna brag, but I will.
I was in the Avengers.
- The Avengers?
- Yeah.
- That's great.
- Thank you.
What is that?
You don't have the Avengers?
Is that a band? Are you in a band?
No, I'm not in a band.
The Avengers is Earth's mightiest--
- How's this helping?
- It's not important.
All we gotta do is focus,
trust your tingle,
and coordinate our attacks.
Yes. Okay. Let's pick one target.
- Right.
- We take them off the board one at a time.
- You got it. Okay, Peter 1, Peter 2.
- Peter 2.
- Peter 3.
- Let's do this. Ready?
- Wait, wait, wait!
I love you guys.
- Thank you.
- All right, let's do this.
- Let's go.
Okay, Spider-Mans.
Sandman's first.
- I'm gonna lead him inside the statue.
- I'll meet you at the top.
- Come on!
- Hey!
- Hey, Dr. Connors.
- Hello, Peter.
Peter 1!
I got it!
Flint, we're trying to help you!
Guys, I'm at the top!
I need the cure!
I'm coming, I'm coming, I'm coming.
Just wait your turn, doc!
I'll be right back.
It's okay, Flint.
We're gonna get you home.
You just stay right here.
How do we stop him?
I've never seen him this powerful.
It's the arc reactor.
We gotta get it off him.
You're not gonna take this from me.
That's not gonna work.
We gotta do this up close.
Peter 2, go right.
Peter 3, go left. On me.
Yeah!
I'm trying to close it.
I can't help that it's not working.
It's fine. You'll do it again.
We'll keep trying.
- All right, we got this.
- Focus and close the portal.
Oh, no. No, no, no.
And that is a lizard and we should go!
Run!
Come on! Come on, this way!
Quick, quick, quick!
Connors, stop!
Yeah.
Leave them. They're mine.
I don't need your help.
I got it just fine.
Dr. Octavius, no.
What are you doing?
Get it off of me.
There you go.
MJ!
- We gotta hide this thing.
- Oh, right.
- Nice, Ned!
- Yeah!
Where is he?
- No!
- Wait, wait, wait.
Before you do anything, Mister--
Doctor Strange, Peter's plan is working.
- What plan?
- He's curing them.
Dr. Connors?
Welcome back, sir.
Well, I'll be damned.
Did you just open a portal?
Yes, sir, I did.
Max?
- Don't worry. I'm all tapped out.
- Are you sure about that?
Back to being a nobody.
- You were never a nobody, Max.
- Yes, I was.
You didn't see me.
- Can I tell you something though?
- Yeah.
You got a nice face. You're just a kid.
You're from Queens.
You got that suit.
You help a lot of poor people.
I just thought you was gonna be Black.
- Oh, man, I'm sorry.
- Don't apologize.
There's gotta be a Black Spider-Man
somewhere out there.
Goddamn eels.
The power of the sun.
In the palm of your hand.
Peter?
Otto.
Oh, it's good to see you, dear boy.
It's good to see you.
You're all grown up.
How are you?
Trying to do better.
- Strange, wait, we're so close.
- Skip it!
I've been dangling
over the Grand Canyon for 12 hours.
I know, I know, I know. I--
I'm sorry about that, sir. I mean...
- You went to the Grand Canyon?
- He could have used your help.
It's okay. These are my new friends.
This is Peter Parker, Peter Parker.
Spider-Man, Spider-Man.
They're mes from other universes.
They're here to help.
This is the wizard I told you about.
I am really impressed that you've managed
to give them all a second chance, kid.
But this has to end. Now.
Can the Spider-Man come out to play?
Strange, no!
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I'm okay.
Are you okay?
Thank you, Mr. Cape, sir.
Ned?
- Ned!
- Hey!
MJ!
Peter?
- Ned!
- Peter!
Hey!
- Are you okay?
- We're okay!
Poor Peter.
Too weak to send me home to die.
No.
I just wanna kill you myself.
Attaboy.
She was there...
because of you.
I may have struck the blow,
but you...
You are the one that killed her.
Peter.
What have I done?
- It's you.
- You okay?
Yeah, I'm good. I've been stabbed before.
- Oh, good, good, good.
- Hey.
- Oh, man.
- Hey, nice catch.
Nice throw.
- What? Is that happening, or am I dying?
- Yeah, no, that's happening. That's real.
Are there people in the sky?
- I gotta go.
- Yeah. I got it. You okay?
What's happening?
They're starting to come through.
I can't stop them.
There's gotta be something we could do.
Can't you just cast the spell again?
- The original way, before I screwed it up.
- We're too late for that. They're here.
They're here because of you.
What if everyone forgot who I was?
- What?
- They're coming here because of me, right?
Because I'm Peter Parker?
So cast a new spell.
But this time, make everyone forget
who Peter Parker is.
Make everyone forget...
- me.
- No.
- But it would work, right?
- Yeah, it would work.
But you gotta understand
that would mean that everyone
who knows and loves you, we...
We'd have no memory of you.
It would be as though you never existed.
I know.
Do it.
You better go and say your goodbyes.
You don't have long.
- Thank you, sir.
- Call me Stephen.
Thank you, Stephen.
Yeah. Still feels weird.
I'll see you around.
So long, kid.
Hey.
I think this is it.
I think you're about to go home.
- Okay.
- All right.
Look, I...
Thank you.
I just wanna-- I want you to--
I wanna tell you that--
I don't know how to say this. I--
- Peter.
- I want you to know that I...
You know. It's what we do.
Yeah, it's what we do.
Right, I gotta find Ned and MJ. I--
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
- I guess I'll see you.
- See you.
Bye.
You're in so much pain, huh?
- I am.
- Yeah.
Oh, you're okay.
So proud of you.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, we're okay.
- Oh, my God, you're bleeding.
- I'm fine. I'm okay.
- You sure?
- I'm fine, I promise.
- Okay, okay.
- I promise.
Good.
We should go, right?
Yeah. You're gonna forget who I am.
- What?
- Forget? What are you talking about?
It's okay. I'm gonna come and find you,
and I'll explain everything.
I'll make you remember me.
And it'll be like none of this
ever happened. Okay?
But what if that doesn't work?
What if that doesn't work?
What if we can't remember you?
I don't wanna do that.
- I don't wanna do that.
- I know. MJ, I know.
There's not something we can do?
We can't come up with a plan?
There's always something we can do.
There's nothing we can do.
But it'll be okay.
You promise?
Yeah, I promise.
I'll come find you, okay?
I know you will.
- Okay.
You better.
If you don't, I'll just figure it out.
I've done it before, I can do it again.
I promise, I'll fix this.
I really hate magic.
Yeah. Me too.
I love you.
- I love--
- Just wait.
Wait and tell me when you see me again.
Sure.
I love you.
It's been a few weeks
since the fiasco on the Statue of Liberty,
and Spider-Man's cultists
continue to contend
that the vile vigilante is a hero.
If he were a hero, he'd unmask himself
and tell us who he really is
because only a coward
conceals his identity.
Only a coward hides his true intentions.
Rest assured, ladies and gentlemen,
this reporter will uncover
those intentions, come hell or high water.
Hi. My name is Peter Parker.
You don't know me, but I...
Hi, my name is Peter Parker,
and you don't know me, but you--
Okay, come on.
- No way.
- Hard to believe, isn't it?
Hey.
One sec. Can I help you?
Hi.
My name is Peter Parker, and I...
would like a coffee, please.
Okay, no problem, Peter Parker.
Doughnut for my fellow Engineer.
- Wait, what?
- MIT, they're the Engineers. The mascot.
Oh, right, right, right.
I should probably know that.
- Look at you with the school spirit.
- Tell anybody, I will deny it.
Oh, okay.
Peter Parker? Peter Parker.
Your coffee.
Right. Thank you.
Are you excited for MIT?
Oh, right. Yeah.
Yeah, I am excited, which is weird
'cause I don't really
get excited about things,
I kind of expect disappointment.
'Cause then you'll never
actually be disappointed.
Right?
Yeah. Right.
I don't know, it kind of feels different
this time for some reason.
Right.
What I was--
You okay?
It doesn't really hurt anymore.
Is there anything else?
No.
Thank you.
No problem.
I'll see you around.
How'd you know her?
Through Spider-Man.
You?
Same.
I lost a good friend a while back.
Felt like this.
Hurts 'cause they're gone
and then it hurts all over again
because you remember
what they stood for
and you wonder, "ls all that gone too?"
No, it's not gone.
Everyone that she helped...
they'll keep it going.
You really think so?
I know it.
- Take care of yourself, okay?
- Yeah. Nice to meet you.
Rent is due on the first
of the month. Don't be late.
Four-three-Edward, do you need EMS assist?
Negative, Central.
We're gonna need a car tow.
Okay.
Okay, I think I got this.
You're saying that this whole place here,
it's just tons of...
super people.
And he has been saying it for hours.
All right, tell me again.
I'm sorry, I'm an idiot.
There was a billionaire,
he had a tin suit and he could fly, right?
Okay, and there was
a really angry green man.
- Hulk.
And you thought
Lethal Protector was a shit name.
Yeah, because it is.
Now tell me again about
your purple alien that loves stones.
'Cause I'll tell you what, man,
aliens do not love stones.
- Eddie, don't start.
- They don't.
Know what aliens love? Eating brains.
Because that's what they do. All right?
Seor, he made my family disappear.
For five years.
Five years?
That's a long time.
Maybe I...
Maybe I should go to New York
and speak to this...
Spider-Man.
Eddie, we are drunk.
- Letis go skinny-dip!
- I don't think we should skinny-dip.
You have to pay the bill.
What is happening? No!
No, we just got here! No, not again!
And there he goes.
Without paying the bill, no tips, nothing.
Don't cast that spell.
-It is too dangerous.
- Why?
We tampered with
the stability of space-time.
The multiverse is a concept
about which we know frighteningly little.
Your desecration of reality...
will not go unpunished.
It was the only way.
But I never meant
for any of this to happen.
Wanda.
Well, I knew sooner or later
you'd show up.
I made mistakes, and people were hurt.
I'm not here to talk about Westview.
Then what are you here for?
We need your help.
With what?
What do you know about the multiverse?
I'm sorry, Stephen.
I hope you understand...
the greatest threat...
to our universe...
is you.
Things just got out of hand.