This is not a drill, soldier.
We clear on that?
This is a live project,
and you're a go.
You're a go.
Training is over.
I'm okay. It's fine.
It's just a headache.
You're burning up.
It's okay.
Just a headache.
Anything new?
No.
It's just bits and pieces.
I can hear Conklin's voice
and there's that photograph, but--
I just can't stay with it.
But you're sure it's
not just a bad dream?
It happened. It was a mission.
And I was there.
You should write it down.
Now, two years we're
scribbling in that notebook.
- It hasn't been two years.
- It's always bad
and now it's just the same
thing over and over again.
But that's why we write it down.
Because sooner or later, you
remember something good.
I do remember something good.
All the time.
I want one final go around.
All teams listen up.
We are standing by
for final green.
Survey Two, I need to know
when you've got eyes.
This is Survey Two. I have eyes.
Copy that.
Survey One, this is Hub.
Do you have visual contact?
Hub, this is Survey One.
Mobile One is in motion.
Survey Three, that is good.
- Hub.
- Director Marshall from Langley.
- Langley.
- Stand by, please.
Martin?
I'm here. So is Donnie
and Jack Weller.
We understand you're using the
full allocation for this buy.
It's where we came out.
It's a lot of money, Pam.
For a thief, a mole.
If it does nothing more than
narrow the list of suspects,
it's a bargain at
10 times the price.
Hub, this is Survey Two.
Escort is breaking off.
Mobile One is entering
the building.
Gentlemen, I have the
seller on-site and in play.
Quite frankly, there's nothing
much more to discuss.
All right, Pam. Your call.
Go.
- We're on.
- Audio contact only.
Switching to channel one now.
- Copy that.
- It's affirmative.
Hub, Mobile One and seller
have entered the office.
Copy that.
This is everything?
Those were shots.
Survey One, come in.
Survey One, I need to
know what happened.
What do you see?
Do you see any movement?
Do you see any shadows?
- I see nothing.
- What is your visual?
Get some men in there. Get
some men in there right now.
Pull it up, Kurt.
Eye contact. I don't
care if it's visual.
Mobile One, can you copy, please?
Are you there, Mobile One?
Damn it. I'm sorry.
What do you see, Teddy?
Eyes up the whole way.
...Petroleum Association's
annual conference here in Berlin
is Pecos Oil chief executive
officer Yuri Gretkov.
In just six years,
Gretkov has turned Pecos
into an oil empire,
which in turn--
He's become one of the
wealthiest men in Russia,
after consolidating drilling
rights in the Caspian Sea
and gaining control
of one of the--
How much?
- Good morning, sir.
- Morning.
He is my friend. There's
been a death in the family.
And I wonder if you've seen him.
- Hey.
- Get in.
- What's wrong?
- We're blown.
How?
We pushed it. We got lazy.
Idiot!
All right. That's twice now
I've seen the same guy.
I saw him in town. He was
at the telegraph office.
Are you sure? How can you be sure?
It's just wrong. The guy, the car he's
driving, what he's wearing, it's just wrong.
But, Jason, let's stay calm.
- This is real.
- It could be anybody.
This is real.
That's him. That's
him right there.
Get your head down. Silver Hyundai.
Get your head down.
How far is he?
How far?
A hundred meters.
Here, take the wheel.
You're gonna drive.
Switch.
Just head to the bridge.
Turn here. Cut through the field.
Hang on.
All right, you keep
going to the shack.
I'll meet you there in one hour.
I'm gonna bail out on the
other side of this bridge.
It's the only way
he can follow us.
What if it's not who
you think it is?
It's them. It's Treadstone.
Jason, don't do it.
- Look, Marie, I warned them.
- I don't want you to do it.
I told them what would happen
if they didn't leave us alone.
It's never gonna
be over like this.
I don't want--
We don't have a choice.
Yes, you do.
Thank you.
Two of these explosive
charges placed
on the power lines, and
one of them failed.
The fingerprint's from the
one that didn't go off.
And the Germans can't match it?
No. Nobody's got it.
We checked out every
database we could access.
But we're hooked into Langley now.
- Run it.
- Okay.
What the hell's Treadstone?
All right. Get me a flight.
We're going to Langley.
Two men dead.
Three million in cash
gone, no Neski files
and all very public.
This is still a
clandestine agency, no?
I don't view this
event as a failure.
You call it a success?
We have a lead.
A fingerprint left
by the assassin.
It's one of us.
Who is it?
What can you tell me
about Treadstone?
Treadstone?
That's where the trail dead-ends.
If you want an answer, you're
going to have to give me
a level five SCI access.
We have a lead, Marty.
All right.
You've got your clearance.
But you're on a very short leash.
And you'll give a full
report to the group.
I wanna know where
you're going with this.
Sir.
- Ward?
- Yes?
Pamela Landy.
Hey, Pam. What can I do for you?
I was hoping you had
some time for me.
Time for what?
I'm free right now, actually.
That sounds ominous.
Let me check my schedule.
Excuse me, I need to--
Excuse me. Can I help you?
Yeah, I'm here to see Mr. Abbott.
20 minutes? See you.
Operation Treadstone.
Never heard of it.
That's not gonna fly.
With all due respect,
Pam, I think you might
have wandered a little
past your pay grade.
That's a warrant from
Director Marshall
granting me unrestricted access
to all personnel and materials
associated with Treadstone.
So, what are we looking at?
I wanna know about it.
Know about it?
It was a kill squad.
Black-on-black.
We closed it down two years ago.
Nobody wants to know
about Treadstone.
Not around here.
So I think you better
take this back to Marty
and let him know exactly
what you're doing.
He does. I've been
down to the archives.
I have the files, Ward.
Let's talk about Conklin.
What are you after, Pam?
You wanna fry me?
You want my desk. Is that it?
- I wanna know what happened.
- What happened?
Jason Bourne happened.
You got the files.
Then let's cut the crap.
Conklin had these guys wound so
tight, they were bound to snap.
Bourne was his number one.
The guy went for a job, screwed
the op, never came back.
Conklin couldn't fix it, couldn't
find Bourne, couldn't adjust.
It all went sideways.
So you had Conklin killed?
I mean, if we're cutting the crap.
I've given 30 years and two
marriages to this agency.
I've shoveled shit
on four continents.
I'm due to retire next year.
But if you think
I'm gonna sit here
and let you dangle me with this,
you can go to hell.
And Marshall, too.
It had to be done.
And Bourne? Where is he now?
Dead in a ditch. Drunk
in a bar in Mogadishu.
- Who knows.
- I think I do.
I had a deal going down
in Berlin last week.
And during the buy, both our case
officer and the seller were killed.
They were killed by Jason Bourne.
They're ready for us upstairs.
Seven years ago, $20 million
of CIA funds disappeared
during a wire transfer
through Moscow.
In the investigation that followed
we were contacted by a Russian
politician, Vladimir Neski.
Neski claimed we had a leak and that
we'd been ripped off by one of our own.
And were we?
We never found out.
We were negotiating a meet with Mr.
Neski when he was killed.
- By who?
- His wife.
The case had gone cold until a
month ago when we found a source.
Another Russian in
Berlin who claimed
to have access to the
Neski murder files.
We thought we had another
bite at the apple.
Turns out the assassin was one
of our own, Jason Bourne.
Now I know Treadstone's not a
very popular subject around here,
but we found some interesting
things when we dug a little deeper.
This is Conklin's
personal computer.
His Treadstone files are bloated
with code keys and case files
that he neither needed
nor had clearance for.
Buried in the hard drive,
we found a deleted file
with an account number
to a bank in Zurich.
At the time of his death,
he was sitting on a personal
account in the amount of $760,000.
You know what his budget was?
We were throwing money at him.
Throwing it at him and
asking him to keep it dark.
It was his own account.
He was up to something.
This is supposed to be definitive?
What's definitive is that I
just lost two people in Berlin.
So what's your theory? Conklin's
reaching out from the grave
to protect his good name?
The man is dead.
No one's disputing that, Ward.
For Christ's sake,
Marty, you knew Conklin.
Does this scan? I mean, at all?
Cut to the chase, Pam.
I think that Bourne and Conklin
were in business together,
that Bourne's still involved
and that whatever information
I was trying to buy in Berlin
was big enough to bring Bourne
out from hiding to kill again.
How's that scan?
Excuse me, sir, but you're
not gonna believe this.
Jason Bourne's passport just
popped up on the grid in Naples.
Okay. Contact Naples. They need
to know who they're dealing with.
Find out what kind of local
assets we have in place there.
No, it's nothing. Some guy's
name came up on the computer.
Yeah. Hey, listen, Tom, I'm
gonna call you back, okay?
All right.
Mr. Bourne, I'm John Nevins.
I'm with the US Consulate.
I just have a few
questions for you.
You're coming out of Tangiers.
Is that correct?
What's the nature of
your visit to Naples?
Look, I don't know what you did,
and I don't know who
you're working for.
But I promise you this,
you're gonna play ball
one way or the other.
This is Nevins.
This is Tom Cronin,
CI Operations Officer
calling from Langley, Virginia.
Do you have a Jason
Bourne in custody?
Yes, I do.
Listen, he's an Agency
priority target.
Detain him and call me back
as soon as he's secure.
I understand.
He's been detained.
Here's the number.
He's being interrogated by a field
officer out of the Consulate.
Hello.
This is Pamela Landy,
CI Supervisor.
Where do we stand?
I think he got away.
Damn it.
Have you locked down the area?
Locked it down? No, no.
This is-- This is Italy. They
don't exactly lock down.
How long have you
worked for the Agency?
Me? For four years.
Well, if you ever wanna
make it to five,
you're gonna listen
to me real close.
Jason Bourne is armed and
extremely dangerous.
Last week in Berlin, he
assassinated two men,
one a highly experienced
field officer.
I want you to secure that area.
I want any evidence secured,
and I want it done right now.
- Is that clear?
- Yes, sir-- Ma'am.
I'm getting on a plane
to Berlin in 45 minutes
which means you're gonna
call me back in 30.
And when I ask you where we
stand, I had better be impressed.
- Berlin?
- I already have a team in place there.
I doubt that Bourne's in Naples
ready to start a family.
You have no idea what
you're getting into.
Do you have any idea? From the
minute he left Treadstone,
he's killed and eluded every single
person that you've sent to find him.
So you read a couple of files on Jason
Bourne and that makes you an expert?
This is my case, Ward.
Enough. I want you
both on that plane.
We are, all of us, going to do
what we were either too lazy or
inept to do the last time around.
We're gonna find this son of
a bitch and take him down.
I'm not having Jason Bourne
destroy any more of this agency.
Is that definitive enough for you?
Yes.
Jason Bourne is armed and
extremely dangerous.
Last week in Berlin, he
assassinated two men,
one a highly experienced
field officer.
I want that area--
...he assassinated two men,
one a highly experienced
field officer.
I want that area secured. I want any evidence
secured, and I want it done right now.
This is not a drill, soldier.
Are we clear on that?
You'd been working at
Treadstone for three years
and your cover at
the time was what?
That I was an American
student in Paris.
And what exactly did your job with
Treadstone in Paris consist of?
I had two responsibilities.
One was to coordinate
logistical operations.
The other was to monitor
the health of the agents.
- Health, meaning what?
- Their mental health.
Because of what they
had been through,
they were prone to a
variety of problems.
What kind of problems?
Depression, anger,
compulsive behaviors.
They had physical symptoms.
Headaches, sensitivity to light.
- Amnesia?
- Before Bourne? No.
The plane's ready.
There's a car waiting for you.
Good luck.
No. You were his local contact.
You were with him the
night Conklin died.
You're coming with us.
Langley pulled an image out of Naples.
It's uploading right now.
It's coming in now.
I need clearance.
He's not hiding, that's for sure.
Why Naples? Why now?
- Could be random.
- Zoom in.
- Maybe he's running.
- On his own passport?
What is he actually doing?
He's making his first mistake.
It's not a mistake.
They don't make mistakes.
They don't do random.
There's always an objective.
Always a target.
The objectives and targets
always came from us.
Who's giving them to him now?
Scary version?
He is.
I emptied it.
It felt a little light.
Put it down.
Front.
Sorry. Old habits.
Use your teeth.
Word in the Ether was
you'd lost your memory.
You still should've moved.
What do you want?
Conklin.
He's dead. Shot dead in Paris.
Dead the night you walked out.
So who's running Treadstone now?
Nobody. They shut it down.
It's over. We're the last two.
If it's over, then why
are they still after me?
I don't know.
Ever heard the name Pamela Landy?
I don't know who that is.
Pamela Landy in Berlin.
What's going on in Berlin?
I don't know.
Why would I lie?
I thought you were
here to kill me.
What'd you do?
I'm sorry.
Did you call it in?
Get up. Come on.
You have a car out front?
The keys are in my coat pocket.
But we should--
- What?
- Go out the back. I have another car.
Pamela Landy, please.
One moment, please.
Thank you.
I wanted to call a guest.
Pamela Landy.
Just one second, please.
Hello?
I'm sorry, sir. The
phone's busy right now.
I'll just call later. Thank you.
Okay. Let's take a look at the timeline.
What's Bourne's objective?
Now, I wanna break
this out in boxes.
Naples outbound. Check everything.
Flights, trains, police reports.
That's box one.
Teddy, that's yours.
Got it.
Box number two. Call it
"Prior Connections."
I want to rerun all Bourne's
Treadstone material. Every footstep.
Kim, box three. I want to
identify his method of travel.
Stay on the local cops.
We need a vehicle, a
parking ticket, something.
Langley's offered to upload any
satellite imaging we need.
So let's find a target for them.
Danny, box four. I
need fresh eyes.
Review the buy where we
lost the Neski files.
Timeline it with what we know
about Bourne's movements.
Turn it upside down
and see what we find.
Come on, guys. We ran this guy's life
with total control for all those years.
We should be a step ahead of him.
You wanna go home?
Find Jason Bourne.
Pamela Landy.
This is Jason Bourne.
- Bourne?
- It's Bourne.
We need 90 seconds to
triangulate his position.
What do you want?
Are you running Treadstone?
Treadstone was closed
down two years ago.
You know that.
Then who's planning
the missions now?
There are no missions. It's over.
Then what do you want with me?
Berlin.
Have you forgotten what
happened in Berlin?
You killed two people, Bourne.
Vladimir Neski.
Bourne?
I wanna come in.
Okay. How do you wanna do it?
We need 35 seconds.
I need someone I
know to bring me in.
Who?
There was a girl in Paris.
She was part of the program.
She used to handle logistics.
Alexanderstrasse, 30 minutes,
under the World Clock.
Send her alone. Give
her your phone.
What if I can't find her?
It's easy. She's standing
right next to you.
- There's just so many of them, sir.
- Here it is.
It's the second quadrant.
Kurt, pull it up.
Where is it?
Get the second quadrant, please,
and pull it all the way up.
The clock is right here. Shit, he's put
her right in the middle of everything.
This is a security nightmare.
There is no way we are
going to get her covered.
Call a mayday into Berlin station.
We need snipers, DOD,
whatever they've got.
No snipers. No snipers.
You put snipers on the roof and it'll
scare him off, and I need answers.
You can't really believe
he wants to come in.
He knows something
about the Neski case.
And I'm not gonna pass up this
chance to find out what it is.
Don't be a fool. Not
when we're this close.
Are we talking about protecting
Nicky or killing Bourne?
We're talking about
killing Bourne.
the next dead body.
It might be Nicky.
It will be someone.
You're not hearing me. Bourne
dead gives me nothing.
Can I talk to you privately?
- What?
- I know how you're feeling.
You lost two men in Berlin, and
you want it to mean something.
But nothing Bourne gives you
will bring your men back.
Nothing in those files makes
their sacrifice worthwhile.
You have to let go.
We're professionals.
When an operation goes
bad, we tie it off.
If there's something you're
not telling me, I want it now
before I send that girl out there.
Do you understand?
You talk about this stuff
like you read it in a book.
What do you want to do?
Put the snipers in place.
If things go bad, we take him out.
You got it.
Hub, this is Survey One.
We have a crowd moving in.
It's some sort of protest march.
I'm sorry. This is as
close as I can get.
Survey Two, can you get
in any closer, please?
Kurt, make sure the
south end is covered.
Roger.
Affirmative.
Copy that.
Hello.
There's a tram coming towards you.
Get on it.
She's moving to the tram.
Where's it going?
The tram is going to
Alexanderplatz Station.
Alexanderplatz.
Survey Five, I can't see him.
I don't see him.
Hub, this is Survey Two,
she's getting on the tram.
She's getting on the tram.
Zoom in on the tram.
Bourne's on the tram.
I don't think he's on the tram.
He's on the tram.
Send them in to follow. Tell
them to keep their distance.
Okay, Delta, let's go. Get on it.
Come on. Let's go.
Tell them to hurry.
There's nothing on the south side.
Alexanderplatz
Station, 25 seconds.
This is Survey Three. There's
a lot of protesters here.
There's no way we can
cover her out there.
Get her out of there.
Go! Delta, move! Now!
She's not here. She's gone.
God damn it!
They are not on the tram.
He's one guy!
- Jason, please don't hurt me.
- What were my words?
What did I say?
I said leave me alone,
leave me out of it.
I did. I swear. Jason, I told
them that I believed you.
I'm gonna ask you some
simple questions.
You're gonna answer me honestly,
or I swear to God
I'm gonna kill you.
Delta, give me something.
I need something.
They're on it! They're on it!
Who's Pamela Landy?
She's a task force chief.
Is she running Treadstone?
No, she's the deputy director.
Why is she trying to kill me?
Last week an Agency field officer
tried to make a buy off
of one of her ops.
He was trying to sell out
a mole or something.
- And?
- And you got to him before we did.
- I killed him?
- You left a print.
And they were partial prints
that trace back to Treadstone.
They know it was you.
- That is insane.
- Why are you doing this?
Why come back now?
Landy will find--
Just stop.
Last week I was 4,000 miles away
in India, watching Marie die.
They came for me, and
they killed her instead.
This ends now.
Find her.
What do you people want with me?
Why are you trying to frame me?
Please! I'm only here because of Paris.
Abbott dragged us--
Abbott? Who's Abbott?
Conklin's boss. He
shut down Treadstone.
- Is he here in Berlin?
- Yes.
Did he run Treadstone?
Yes. Conklin reported to him.
Please. Please, I swear.
All right, what was Landy buying?
What kind of files?
Conklin. Stuff on Conklin.
It was something to do
with a Russian politician.
Neski.
What? What are you talking about?
Training is over.
When was I here in Berlin?
What are you talking about?
For Treadstone. You know my file.
I did a job here.
- When?
- No, you never worked in Berlin before.
My first job. In Berlin.
I did a job here.
You know my file.
No. You've never
worked Berlin before.
My first job!
No, your first
assignment was Geneva.
You fucking people!
I swear! I swear!
I know I was here, Nicky!
It's not in your file!
I know I was here!
No, I swear. Oh, please!
Pam, I want to show you something.
It's in Alexanderplatz.
We got three levels,
we got 15 tunnels.
They're all converging
in a five-block radius.
Over here, Luftschutzbunker.
That was an old war shelter.
How many men are out there?
Two coming down the back stairs.
The rest are fanned
out for a search.
What's our security
situation here?
Where, "here"? The ground?
Here, here. In the building.
Check everything, and recheck all the
stairwells, all the hallways, everything.
It's done.
Okay, let's go public.
Release his photo to
the Berlin police.
And check out his story about
the girlfriend in India, too.
I'm on it.
You're in a big puddle
of shit, Pamela,
and you don't have
the shoes for it.
He said he didn't know
anything about Berlin.
He knew that Nicky
was wearing a wire.
Don't you think that
was for our benefit?
He didn't sound like a
man in control to me.
We know he was in Berlin.
His mind is broken. We broke it.
- And now--
- What now? Terminate him?
You've been pushing that
agenda ever since we got here.
He also said you were running Treadstone.
Should we believe that, too?
I'm convinced that
Bourne knows something.
He knows that you're after him
and in the interest of self-preservation
you might start with that.
Check on those photos.
Have they gone out?
I need to show you something.
All right, I finished my box work
but I wanted to show you
before I showed Landy.
I came down here last night because
none of this is making any sense.
I mean, I'm with you. Conklin was a nut.
But a traitor?
I just can't get there.
What do you have, Danny?
All right, you put a four-gram Kel on here,
it's gonna take out power to the building.
You know that.
There were two charges that were
supposed to go off simultaneously.
The second one,
the one over here, didn't go off.
Now, first of all,
this is nothing.
It's a sub-line for
the breaker above.
And second, why put the
charge all the way down here?
If you're good enough to get
in here and handle the gear,
you're good enough to
know you don't need this.
Bourne would know.
It was staged?
Is it a slam-dunk? No.
But what if somebody were
trying to cover their tracks
by blaming Conklin and Bourne?
What if Bourne didn't have
anything to do with this?
Show me again.
All right.
Well, you put--
Pull over. He's getting out.
This is not a drill, soldier.
We clear on that?
This is a live project,
and you're a go.
I'll see you on the other side.
Good evening, sir.
How can I help you?
Yeah, hi. I want to get
a room for the night.
- Do you have a reservation?
- No.
Actually, is Room 645 available?
I've stayed there before.
I'm sorry, sir. That
room is occupied.
How about Room 644? It's
right across the hall.
Sir?
644?
That's fine. Thank you.
I just need your
passport and signature.
Right here, please.
Have a nice night.
Where?
Brecker Hotel.
Okay, we're there. Take the van!
- Brecker? How far?
- About five, six minutes.
Congratulations, soldier.
Training is over.
Go!
Black coat, possibly leather,
dark T-shirt, dark pants.
The cops out there wanna corral all the
guests together out on the sidewalk
and check them out one by one.
That will really work.
What the hell's he doing here?
Maybe he just wanted
to stay the night.
- They missed him?
- Yeah, so far.
But they found Nicky.
She's back at the Westin.
Bourne let her go.
- He let her go?
- Yeah.
Where's Danny Zorn?
He ought to head over
there and debrief her.
Why did Bourne come here?
We don't know yet.
Landy's upstairs in
one of the rooms.
She said she'd call
you when she's done.
Okay.
I think I'll take a cab
back to the hotel.
So the room he checked
into was across the hall.
Why would he come in here?
What are you thinking?
I recognize this
room from a photo.
There was a chalk
outline right here
around the body of Vladimir Neski.
This is where his wife killed him?
Do you still think
his wife killed him?
Guess he got out
through this window.
We just got word from
the Berlin police.
They found Danny Zorn's body.
I want you two to stay on Bourne.
Check everything that's out there.
Call Abbott. Tell him to
wait for me in his hotel.
I'm coming to see him.
- Da.
- It's me.
They're onto Neski.
This is not a clean phone.
They can't prove
anything without Bourne.
Kill Bourne, and you
kill this investigation.
I'm afraid, Ward, the time has
come for us to part company.
Listen, Yuri, you bought those oil leases
with $20 million in stolen CIA seed money.
You owe me.
I gave you your cut.
We both got rich.
I don't owe you anything.
The plan can still be salvaged.
Just get Bourne. Do you hear me?
He's still out there. Now get him.
Get Jason--
I don't suppose it'll do me
much good to cry for help, huh?
Not much.
You killed her.
It was a mistake.
It was supposed to be you.
There were files linking
me to the Neski murder.
If the files disappeared
and they suspected you,
they'd be chasing a
ghost for 10 years.
So we got in the way.
Is that why Neski died?
Is that why you killed Marie?
You killed Marie,
the minute you climbed
into her car.
The minute you entered
her life, she was dead.
I told you people to leave us alone.
I fell off the grid.
I was halfway around the world.
There's no place it
won't catch up to you.
It's how every story ends.
It's what you are,
Jason, a killer.
You always will be.
Go ahead. Go on. Go on!
Do it! Do it!
She wouldn't want me to.
That's the only
reason you're alive.
I'm a patriot. I serve my country.
And Danny Zorn? What was he?
Unlucky.
Collateral damage.
So what do we do now?
I'm not sorry.
No, no, no, forget it.
Call me as soon as he's here.
No, that's nothing.
We could synch-up.
Who's this guy?
Platform P.
Go ahead. Go on. Go on!
Do it! Do it!
She wouldn't want me to.
That's the only
reason you're alive.
Got a call from Langley.
They're going through
Abbott's records
and Marshall wants to know
what's going on with Bourne.
Wait, Teddy. Teddy, who's this?
Look at this guy.
He's about to enter. Right there!
There!
Right through there.
That's Bourne.
Get down here! We got something!
We got him!
We got a sighting! Check it out!
- There. I got it on the big monitor.
- Hold on.
There he comes again.
Whoa, whoa. Hold on.
He's just entered frame.
It's the coat. That's him!
What train is that?
That's the train to Moscow.
Why the hell would
he go to Moscow?
Get me the Russian
Interior Ministry.
I speak English.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I won't hurt you.
You're older.
Older than I thought you'd be.
That picture.
Does that mean a lot to you?
It's nothing. It's just a picture.
No.
It's because you don't
know how they died.
I do.
No, you don't.
I would want to know.
I would want to know that my--
That my mother didn't
kill my father,
that she didn't kill herself.
What?
It's not what happened
to your parents.
I killed them.
It was my job.
It was my first time.
Your father was
supposed to be alone.
But then your mother
came out of nowhere
and I had to change my plan.
It changes things,
that knowledge.
Doesn't it?
When what you love
gets taken from you,
you wanna know the truth.
I'm sorry.
Pamela Landy.
I hear you're still
looking for me.
Bourne?
What do you want?
I wanted to thank you
for the tape.
We got what we needed.
It's all tied off.
It's over.
I guess I owe you an apology.
Is that official?
No. Off the record.
You know how it is.
Goodbye.
Wait. Wait.
David Webb.
That's your real name.
You were born 4-15-'71
in Nixa, Missouri.
Why don't you come in,
and we'll talk about it?
Bourne?
Get some rest, Pam.
You look tired.