...and I'll tell you what, the
storm system's still moving west.
What are you looking
at, Caroline?
The wind, Mom.
They say the
hurricane is coming.
I'm on a boat.
I'm drifting.
Can I do anything for you, Mom?
Make anything easier?
Oh, sugar...
There's nothing left to do.
Is what it is.
Finding it harder to
keep my eyes open.
My mouth's full of cotton.
There, there, Miss Daisy.
You gonna scratch
yourself to ribbons.
Do you want any more
medication, Mother?
Doctor said you could
have as much as you want.
No need for anybody to suffer.
A friend told me that she
never had the chance
to say goodbye to her mother.
- I wanted to...
- It's okay.
I wanted to tell you how much
I'm gonna miss you so...
Mom.
Oh, Caroline.
Are you afraid?
I'm curious.
What comes next?
They built the train
station in 1918.
My father was there
the day it opened.
He said they had
a tuba band playing.
They had the finest clockmaker
in all of the South
to build that glorious clock.
His name was...
Mr. Gateau.
Mr. Cake.
He was married to a Creole
of Evangeline Parish
and they had a son.
Mr. Gateau was, from
birth, absolutely blind.
When their son was old
enough, he joined the army.
And they prayed God would
keep him out of harm's way.
For months, he did nothing
but work on that clock.
One day,
a letter came.
And Mr. Gateau,
done for the night,
went up, alone, to bed.
And their son came home.
They buried him in
the family plot,
where he would be with
them when their time came.
Mr. Cake worked on his clock,
laboring to finish.
It was a morning to remember.
Papa said there were
people everywhere.
Even Teddy Roosevelt came.
It's running backwards!
I made it that way
so that perhaps the boys
that we lost in the war
might stand and come home again.
Home to farm,
work,
have children.
To live long, full lives.
Perhaps my own son
might come home again.
I'm sorry if I've
offended anybody.
I hope you enjoy my clock.
Mr. Cake was never seen again.
Some say he died
of a broken heart.
Some say he went to sea.
Excuse me.
Do you mind if I make a call?
Somebody's watching my little boy.
Sure.
I hope I haven't
disappointed you.
You couldn't disappoint me.
Well, I know I don't have
much to show for myself.
Find my dark suitcase.
There's a diary.
This?
Could you read it to me?
Is this what you want to do?
I tried to read it a
hundred different times.
Mom, it's not exactly...
it's just the sound of
your voice, darling.
Okay.
It's dated April 4th, 1985.
And it says New Orleans.
"This is my last
will and testament."
"I don't have much to leave, few
possessions, no money, really."
"I will go out of this world the same
way I came in, alone and with nothing."
"All I have is my story,"
"and I'm writing it now
while I still remember it."
"My name is Benjamin.
Benjamin Button."
And I was born under
unusual circumstances.
The First World War had ended,
and I've been told it was an
especially good night to be born.
Thank God it's over!
We won the war!
The Great War is over!
What are you doing here?
Thomas,
I'm afraid she's going to die.
What?
That's enough. All of
you, get away from her.
I came as quickly as I could. The
streets are filled with people.
Thomas.
Promise me he has a place.
Yeah.
She gave her life for me.
And for that, I am
forever grateful.
Mr. Button.
Thomas!
Thomas.
Thomas? Where are you going?
Hey! What are you doing there?
What do you have there?
- Come on, Queenie.
- Now, Mr. Weathers!
Come on, now, you know I ain't got
nothing but work to do around here.
- Come on. Just take some time.
- Stop all this foolishness.
The air is sweet.
You look very handsome
tonight, Miss Queenie.
Handsome as I've ever seen.
The brown matches your eyes.
Oh, hush!
Let's see here. You ain't
no slouch yourself.
Hambert's back in town.
He came home legless,
but he's home.
I know you were sweet
on him one time.
Sweeter than I should've been.
Miss Simone messed herself.
Oh, sweet Jesus.
She got to stop doing that
or it's diapers for her.
- I'll be right there, Miss Jameson!
- Now, Queenie, now come on.
Okay, Queenie'll be right there.
It's awful nice out here.
Come on out back for a moment.
Take your mind off things.
You're so bad.
- What in God's name?
- What's this?
Oh, the Lord done
something here.
Hope I didn't hurt it none
stepping on it like that.
We best leave that
for the police.
Poor baby.
I'll go.
It's for sure nobody wanted to keep it.
Come on, baby.
Queenie? Where are you, Queenie?
Hold your water! You
go deal with it.
Okay. No, go, I'll be back.
Queenie, Apple, she went and
messed herself all over again!
Jane Childress,
start her a bath!
And mind your own business, Mrs.
Duprey.
You'll be messing
yourself soon enough.
Somebody stole my necklace.
Okay. All right, Mrs. Hollister,
I'll be right with you, okay?
Go on back upstairs, hear?
You are as ugly as an old pot
but you're still a child of God.
Queenie, Apple, she won't
take a bath without you!
Mercy.
I'll be right there!
Okay. You just wait right
here for me now, okay?
My sister gave me those pearls.
I can't find them anywhere.
- Somebody's been stealing my jewelry.
- They're right here, Mrs. Hollister. See?
Right around your pretty white neck.
Now, come on. Hush all that noise.
- Is Dr. Rose still here?
- I don't know.
Your heart is strong.
You just want to avoid
any undue stimulation.
I trust you ladies will
help me out with that?
I have something. Could
you come downstairs?
Never seen anything like it.
Nearly blind from cataracts.
I'm not sure if he can hear. His
bones indicate severe arthritis.
His skin has lost all elasticity, and
his hands and feet are ossified.
He shows all the deterioration, the
infirmities, not of a newborn,
but of a man well in his 80s
on his way to the grave.
He's dying?
His body is failing him
before his life's begun.
Where'd he come from?
My sister's child. From Lafayette.
She had an unfortunate adventure.
The poor child, he got the worst of it.
Come out white.
There are places for unwanted
babies like these, Queenie.
No room for another
mouth to feed here.
The Nolan Foundation, despite
their good intentions,
thinks this place is a
large nuisance as it is.
- A baby...
- You said he don't have long.
Queenie, some creatures
aren't meant to survive.
No, this baby, he is a miracle.
That's for certain.
Just not the kind of
miracle one hopes to see.
Y'all listen. Y'all
listen up here.
We're gonna have us a visitor
that's gonna be staying
with us for a little while.
My sister had a child and she
couldn't see right by it, so...
He's known as...
Benjamin.
He's not a well child, so we're gonna
have to take good care of him.
I had 10 children.
There's not a baby I can't care for.
Let me see him.
God in Heaven. He looks
just like my ex-husband.
Look, he's prematurely old.
Dr. Rose said he ain't got
much more time on this earth.
Join the club.
He's smiling!
Hambert sends his
remembrances to you.
Are you right out of your mind?
I know you ain't got all the parts
it takes to make one of your own,
but this ain't yours to keep.
It may not even be humankind.
Mr. Weathers, come back here.
Please.
You never know what's
coming for you.
It seemed I had found a home.
Is any of this true?
You have such a lovely voice.
Mom, it's an ancient
streetcar token.
That clock just kept going,
year after year after year.
But I didn't know I was a child.
Same old crap every day.
I thought I was like
everyone else there.
An old man in the
twilight of his life.
Could you make him stop that?
Stop banging that fork. It's used
for eating, not for playing with.
And use your napkin, please, Mr.
Benjamin.
Queenie!
Hey, boy.
Always had a healthy curiosity.
What was up the street? Or
around the next corner?
Go get him!
Benjamin! That is dangerous.
Come back over here.
Stay put, child.
I loved her very much.
She was my mother.
Mama.
Some days I feel different
than the day before.
Everybody feels different about
themselves, one way or another.
But we're all going
the same way.
Just taking different roads
to get there, that's all.
You're on your own
road, Benjamin.
Mama? How much longer I got?
Just be thankful for
what you're given, hear?
You're already here longer
than you're supposed to.
Some nights, I'd
have to sleep alone.
I didn't mind.
I would listen to the
house breathing.
All those people sleeping.
I felt safe.
It was a place of great routine.
Every morning at 5:30,
no matter the weather,
General Winslow, U.S. Army,
Retired, would raise the flag.
Mrs. Sybil Wagner, once an
opera singer of some note,
well, she sang Wagner.
All right, baby, come on.
We got to put some life into
these old sticks for you.
Get you walking so you can help me
out around here. Come on now, hear?
No matter the season, supper
was served promptly at 5:30.
Molasses.
I learned to read
when I was five.
My grandfather was a dresser
for a famous actor.
He brung home every
play for me to read.
"Kind keepers of my
weak decaying age,"
"Let dying Mortimer
here rest himself."
"Even like a man new
haled from the rack,"
"So fare my limbs with
long imprisonment."
"And these gray locks, the
pursuivants of death,"
"Argue the end of
Edmund Mortimer."
You thought I was plain
ignorant, didn't you?
The actor my grandfather worked
for was John Wilkes Booth.
He killed Abraham Lincoln.
You never know what's
coming for you.
On Saturday nights, Mama
would make me go to church.
Benjamin!
- Amen! Amen!
What can I do for you, sister?
Her parts are all twisted up inside
and she can't have little children.
Lord, if you could see clear
to forgive this woman her sins
so she can bear the
fruit of the womb.
Out, damnable affliction!
- Praise God!
Hallelujah!
- Hallelujah!
And what's this old
man's irrediction?
He's got the Devil on his back,
trying to ride him into the
grave before his time.
- Out, Zebuchar!
- Yes!
- Out, Beelzebub!
How old are you?
Seven. But I look a lot older.
God bless you.
He's seven.
Now, this is a man with
optimism in his heart.
- All right.
- Belief in his soul!
- Yes!
We are all children
in the eyes of God!
- Yes!
- Hallelujah!
We are gonna get you
out of that chair.
- And we're gonna have you walk.
- Amen.
It's all right.
In the name of God's glory...
Rise up!
Come on.
Come on. Walk.
Come on, son. Come on.
- Come on with it, son. Come on.
- Come on.
Now God is gonna see you
the rest of the way.
He's gonna see this little old man walk
without the use of a crutch or a cane.
He's gonna see that you
walk from faith...
- Hallelujah!
- ...and divine inspiration alone!
- Yes.
- Hey, Ben!
- Go, son!
- Now walk.
- Yes.
- Come on.
Don't touch him.
Rise up, old man.
Rise up like Lazarus.
I said, rise up!
Hallelujah!
Yes.
Come on.
Say hallelujah.
- Hallelujah!
Walk.
Walk on. Yes.
That's right, Benjamin.
Now when I look back on
it, it was miraculous.
But you know the saying, the Lord
giveth and the Lord taketh away.
Glory in the highest!
Sweet Jesus!
- No!
There were so many birthdays.
For he's a jolly good fellow For
he's a jolly good fellow...
So we wouldn't run out, we
would spare the candles.
Queenie, you know I don't like
birthdays and I don't like cake.
And death was a common visitor.
People came and went.
You always knew when
someone left us.
There was a silence
in the house.
It was a wonderful
place to grow up.
I was with people who had shed all
the inconsequences of earlier life.
Left wondering about the weather,
the temperature of a bath,
the light at the end of a day.
For everyone that died, someone
would come to take their place.
I've been married five times.
My fifth wife and I are captured
by a neighbor tribe of cannibals.
Oh, goodness gracious.
We escaped across the river.
My wife, she can't swim,
so, sadly, she eaten.
Oh, my God.
My second wife steps
on cobra and dies.
It was very bad luck
to be married to me.
That's Mr. Oti. He's an acquaintance
of an acquaintance of mine.
- The next summer I'm captured...
- He's a Pygmy.
...with three others by
the Baschiele tribe.
They trade us for pigs, shoes, and
beer to a very strange American man.
I hear you're not so
old as you're looking.
You just fooling everybody.
What's the matter? Did
you get Madjembe?
What's Madjembe?
Worms.
I don't think I have worms.
This is just how I am.
- Did you take your pills today?
- No, ma'am.
Come. Let's get a
cold root beer.
I found the medication
under your pillow.
I'm not supposed to.
It's dangerous.
Who said that? Come
on, little man.
Hello, children.
Hold, please.
Then I'm in the monkey house at
Philadelphia Zoological Park.
Three thousand people
show up my first day.
Look.
What's it like living in a cage?
It stinks.
But the monkeys.
They do some tricks there.
I throw a spear,
wrestle with Kowali.
She is orangutan.
When I'm not playing with the monkeys,
they want me to run to the bars
in my cage, with my teeth.
So then what'd you do?
Then I leave zoo, go here, go there.
Wandered most of the time.
You were all alone?
Plenty of time you'll be alone.
When you're different like
us, it's gonna be that way.
But I'll tell you
a little secret.
Fat people, skinny
people, tall people,
white people, they're
just as alone as we are.
But they're scared shitless.
I think about the
river I grew up on.
It would be nice to sit
by my river again.
Come, I have an appointment.
There's my little man.
You ready, sugar?
Always ready. Always ready.
Filamena, Mr. Benjamin.
- It's a pleasure to meet you, sir.
- My pleasure, ma'am.
You can find your own
way home, can't you?
Take the St. Charles
line to Napoleon.
Hey! Hey!
Where in God's name have you been?
Get in here.
I mean, you take my breath
away, you know that?
Oh, Lord, I was so
worried about you.
It had been the best
day of my life.
- How's her breathing?
- It's shallow.
They say it'll reach
us in a few hours,
so I gotta get my baby and
take him to my sister's.
They say there's nothing to worry
about here in the hospital.
Nurses'll be right here if you need them.
Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay reading.
- I shouldn't be more than an hour.
Was there just company?
It was just Dorothy leaving.
Go on, Caroline.
"On Sundays, the families
would come and visit."
it was Thanksgiving, 1930.
I met the person who
changed my life forever.
Well, Benjamin.
Might I say you are looking
strikingly youthful.
Good day, Mrs. Fuller.
A single cane, back
straight as an arrow.
What elixir have
you been drinking?
- Thank you, ma'am.
- Grandma! Look at me!
That was really something.
Come on over here, you.
Now, this is my
granddaughter, Daisy.
This is Mr...
I'm afraid, Benjamin, I don't
rightly know your last name.
Benjamin's fine.
I never forgot her blue eyes.
Good people, supper is served.
Health and food, for love and friends.
For everything thy goodness sends.
Amen.
- Amen!
Did you know turkeys
aren't really birds?
Why do you say that?
They're in the pheasant
family, can't hardly fly.
It's sad, don't you think?
Birds that can't fly?
I love birds that can't fly.
They are so delicious.
- That's terrible.
- I have something to tell y'all
while we're giving thanks
for God's blessings.
I had a miracle happen.
The Lord saw fit to
answer my prayers.
What does she mean,
answered her prayers?
Thanks. Thank you.
She's gonna have a baby, silly.
That's what my mama said when I
was gonna have a baby brother,
but he didn't live long,
'cause he didn't breathe right.
"In the afternoon, when he had
got his beautiful hind legs"
"just as Big God
Nqong had promised."
"You can see that it is 5:00,"
"because Big God Nqong's
clock says so."
isn't that something?
Again, read it again.
Oh, read it again, please.
All right. But afterwards,
you must go to bed.
I promise.
"Old Man Kangaroo."
Are you sleeping?
Who's that?
It's me, Daisy.
Oh, hi!
'Kay, come on.
Where are we going?
Come on. Under here.
Here, you light it.
I'm not supposed to
play with matches.
Don't be a chicken. Light it.
I'll tell you a secret
if you'll tell me one.
Okay.
I saw my mama kissing
another man.
Her face was red from it.
Your turn.
I'm not as old as I look.
I thought so.
You don't seem like
an old person.
- Like my grandma.
- I'm not.
Are you sick?
Well, I heard Mama and
Tizzy whispering.
They said I was gonna die
soon, but maybe not.
You're odd.
You're different than
anybody I've ever met.
- May I?
- Okay.
What are you doing under there?
You come right out here
and get back up to bed!
It's after midnight!
You are not to be
playing together.
Yes, ma'am.
Now you get back to
bed, little lady.
You're too young to be wandering
around in the night on your own.
And you ought to be
ashamed of yourself.
You are a different child.
A man-child.
And, baby, people aren't gonna
understand just how different you are.
What's wrong with me, Mama?
Come here.
God hasn't said yet, baby.
Now go on to bed, hear?
And behave yourself.
Go on. Say your prayers, hear?
Did I ever tell you I've been
struck by lightning seven times?
Once when I was repairing
a leak on the roof.
Once I was just crossing
the road to get the mail.
I never forgot her...
"...blue eyes."
Mom?
Did you get that this Benjamin loved you
from the first time that he saw you?
Not many people experience that.
Want me to go on?
He crosses something out.
When that baby came,
things were different.
Your mama gone away And
your daddy gonna stay
Didn't leave nobody but the baby
Babies were born, people died.
A lot of folks been
through that old house.
I've come to say goodbye.
I'm going away.
Going?
Where?
I haven't figured that out yet,
but I'll send you a
postcard when I get there.
What about your friend,
the tall lady?
We are not friends anymore.
That's what happens with
tall people sometimes.
Well, goodbye.
Spent a lot of time
by myself that year.
Hello?
- Hi.
- I'm moving in today.
Welcome. We've been
expecting you.
Can you please show her up to Mrs.
Rousseau's old room?
I'm sorry, but we usually don't
allow dogs in the house.
Well, she's old as the hills.
She's almost blind.
She won't be a
bother much longer.
Well, all right, long as she
stays from up underfoot.
Right this way, ma'am.
As hard as I try, I can't
remember her name.
Mrs. Lawson, or Mrs. Hartford.
Maybe it was Maple.
It's funny how sometimes the
people we remember the least
make the greatest
impression on us.
I do remember she wore diamonds.
And she always dressed in fine
clothing, as if she was going out.
Although she never did and
nobody ever came to visit her.
She taught me to play the piano.
It's not about how
well you play.
It's how you feel about
what you're playing.
Try this.
You can't help putting
yourself in the music.
There were many changes.
Some you could see,
some you couldn't.
Hair had started growing
in all sorts of places,
along with other things.
I felt pretty good, considering.
Darling, the pain.
All right, Mom,
I'll get the nurse.
Look at this eye. This
is a major hurricane,
a slow hurricane, with maximum
sustained winds of...
Not doing too good?
Nobody seems to know
whether to stay or leave.
I'm gonna ride it out.
There. That should make
things much easier.
Have you had a chance
to say your goodbyes?
My father waited four hours for my
brother to get here from Boger City.
Couldn't go without him.
- She seems like a sweet woman.
- Yeah.
I haven't had as much time
with her as I would've...
- You busy? I could use your help.
- Excuse me.
Sure.
"Queenie would let me go with Mr.
Daws..."
...to Poverty Point to watch the
boats go up and down the river.
These were hard times.
Did I ever tell you I was struck
by lightning seven times?
Once when I was in the field,
just tending to my cows.
My fourth hand didn't show up.
Anybody want to make $2 for
a day's work 'round here?
What's the matter?
Nobody wants to do an honest day's
work for an honest day's pay?
He never pays.
- Nobody wants a job?
- I do.
You got your sea legs
about you, old man?
I think.
Well, that's good enough for me.
Get your ass on board. We'll
sure as hell find out.
I was as happy as I could be.
I need a volunteer!
I would do anything.
Yes, Captain!
Scrape off all this bird shit!
Right away, sir.
And I was actually gonna be paid for
something I would've done for free.
His name was Captain Mike Clark.
He'd been on a tugboat
since he was seven.
Get moving, then.
Come here.
Can you still get it up?
I do every morning.
The old pole, huh?
The high, hard one?
I guess.
When was the last
time you had a woman?
- Never.
- Never?
Not that I know of, sir.
Wait a minute, now.
You mean to say you've been on
this earth however many years
and you've never had a woman?
Damn, that's the saddest thing
I've ever heard in my life.
Never?
No.
Well, then, by Jesus,
you are coming with me.
What did your father do?
I never met my father.
You lucky bastard.
All fathers want to
do is hold you down.
Out on my father's boat,
workin' the two-a-day,
this little, fat bastard.
"Tug lrish, " they called him.
Anyway, I finally work up
the nerve and tell him,
"I don't want to spend the rest
of my life on a goddamn tugboat."
You know what I'm saying?
You don't want to spend the
rest of your life on a tugboat.
Absolutely! Damn right!
So you know what my
father says to me?
He says, "Who the hell
do you think you are?"
"What the hell do you
think you can do?"
So I tell him.
"Well, if you're asking,"
"I want to be an artist."
He laughs.
"An artist? God meant for you to
work a tugboat, just like me."
"And that's exactly
what you're gonna do."
Well, I turned myself
into an artist.
A tattoo artist!
I put on every one
of these myself.
You have to skin me alive to
take my art away from me now.
When I'm dead, I'm
gonna send him my arm.
That one.
Don't let anyone
tell you different.
You gotta do what
you're meant to do.
And I happen to be a
goddamned artist.
But you're a tugboat captain.
Captain Mike?
We're ready for you
and your friend.
Let's go, old timer, eh?
Break your cherry.
- Hello, my lovelies!
- Hey, Captain.
- Hi, Captain.
- Hi.
He gives me the willies.
That is not for me.
How are you tonight, grandpa?
It was a night to remember.
What are you, Dick Tracy or something?
I've got to rest.
Again.
- Thank you.
- No, thank you. You have a nice night.
- Will you be here tomorrow?
- Every night but Sunday.
It sure made me understand the
value of earning a living.
Good night, sweetie.
Come back now.
Things money can buy you.
It's nasty out.
Can I offer you a
ride somewhere?
Well, that's awfully
kind of you, sir.
My name is Thomas,
Thomas Button.
- I'm Benjamin.
- Benjamin.
It's a pleasure to know you.
Would you like to stop
somewhere and have a drink?
All right.
Evening, Mr. Button.
What'll it be, sir?
- I'll have whatever he's having.
- Sazerac for the both of us.
With whiskey, not brandy.
You don't drink, do you?
- It's a night for firsts.
- How's that?
I've never been to
a brothel, either.
Well, it's an experience.
It certainly is. There's
a time for everything.
- True enough.
- Your drinks.
I don't mean to be rude, but your hands.
Is that painful?
Well, I was born with
some form of disease.
What kind of disease?
I was born old.
- I'm sorry.
- No need to be.
There's nothing
wrong with old age.
My wife passed away
many years ago.
I'm so, so sorry.
She died in childbirth.
- To children.
- To mothers.
What line of work you in, Mr.
Button?
Buttons. Button's Buttons. There
isn't a button that we don't make.
Our biggest competition is B.F.
Goodrich
and his infernal zippers.
Would you gentlemen
like anything else?
One for the road, Benjamin?
Only if you let me pay for it, Mr.
Button.
So, what line of work do you do?
I'm a tugboat man.
I enjoyed talking to you.
I enjoyed drinking with you.
Benjamin?
Would you mind if, time to time,
I stopped by and said hello?
Anytime. Good night, Mr. Button.
Good night, Benjamin.
Drive on.
Where have you been?
Nothing. I met some people
and listened to some music.
Oh, sweet Jesus, boy!
Growing up's a funny thing.
Sneaks up on you.
One person is there, then suddenly
somebody else has taken her place.
She wasn't all elbows
and knees anymore.
Benjamin! Come on!
Okay.
I loved those weekends
when she'd come
and spend the night
with her grandmother.
Daisy. Daisy.
You want to see something?
You gotta keep it a secret, so get dressed.
I'll meet you out back.
Come on.
- Can you swim?
- I can do anything you can do.
Here, put this on.
We gotta hurry.
Is he okay?
Captain?
Captain Mike?
Morning, Captain. Can
you take us out?
Do you know what day it is?
Sunday?
Do you know what that means?
Means I was very
drunk last night.
Well, you're drunk every night.
- Is that a girl?
- Close friend.
I want to show her the river.
You're not supposed to go
joyriding with civilians.
I could lose my license.
What are you waiting for?
Pulled in for repair
a wounded duck.
She's flying now, huh?
Ahoy, sailor!
I wish we could go with them.
Did you say something, Mom?
It's getting really bad.
Can you hear me, Mom?
Time just seeped out of me.
"Things were changing quickly."
I don't know how it's possible,
but you seem to have more hair.
What if I told you that
I wasn't getting older,
but I was getting younger
than everybody else?
Well, I'd feel sorry for you,
to have to see everybody you
love die before you do.
It's an awful responsibility.
I'd never thought about life
or death that way before.
Benjamin, we're meant to
lose the people we love.
How else would we know how
important they are to us?
And one fall day, a familiar
visitor came knocking on our door.
You want to go with
me to the drugstore?
She taught me how
to play the piano.
- Amen.
And she taught me what it
meant to miss somebody.
Let's go.
I had gone to a brothel.
I'd had my first drink.
Said goodbye to one friend
and buried another.
In 1936, when I was coming to the
end of the 17th year of my life,
I packed my bag, said goodbye.
- Bye, Benjamin.
- Goodbye.
I knew, life being what it was, I'd
probably never see them again.
Bye, Mr. Benjamin.
- Good luck to you, son.
- Thank you.
- I love you, Mama.
- I love you, too, baby.
I want you to say your
prayers every night, hear?
Be safe, hear?
Benjamin!
- Where you going?
- To sea.
I'll send you a postcard.
From everywhere.
Write me a postcard
from everywhere.
Can you imagine?
He sent me a postcard
from everywhere he went.
Every place he worked.
Newfoundland. Baffin Bay.
Glasgow. Liverpool. Narvik.
He had gone with
that Captain Mike.
Captain Mike had
contracted for three years
with Moran Brothers
Tug and Salvage.
The old ship had been refitted with a
diesel engine and a new sea winch.
We went around Florida and
up the Atlantic seaboard.
We were a crew of seven now.
Captain Mike and me.
Cookie, Prentiss Mayes
from Wilmington, Delaware.
The Brody twins, Rick and Vic,
who got along fine at sea
but, for some reason,
once they were on dry land couldn't
stand the sight of each other.
You know, one in every
eight boats never returns.
There was John Grimm,
who sure fit his name.
All hands lost at sea.
From Belvedere, South Dakota.
And Pleasant Curtis
from Asheville, Notch.
Never said a word to
anyone, except himself.
I wrote him constantly.
I told him I had been invited
to audition in New York City
for the School of
American Ballet.
Please stay.
Thank you. Thank you.
You can stay.
But I was relegated
to the corps.
Another dancing gypsy.
Benjamin!
How is it when you showed up
you were no bigger than a bollard
with one foot in the grave,
but now, either I drink a hell
of a lot more than I think I do,
or you sprouted?
What's your secret?
Well, Captain,
you do drink a lot.
We stayed in a small hotel with a
grand name, The Winter Palace.
You have no idea what
you're talking about.
The hummingbird is not
just another bird.
Its heart rate's 1,200
beats per minute.
Its wings beat 80
times a second.
If you was to stop their
wings from beating,
it would be dead in
less than 10 seconds.
This is no ordinary bird.
This is a frickin' miracle.
They slowed down their wings
with moving pictures,
and you know what they saw?
Their wingtips are doing that.
You know what the figure eight
is the mathematical symbol for?
Infinity.
Infinity!
Everybody, no matter what
differences they had,
the languages, the color of their
skin, had one thing in common.
They were drunk
every single night.
Three, please.
Could you hold, dear,
for us, please?
Thank you very much.
Good evening.
Her name was Elizabeth Abbott.
She was not beautiful.
She was plain as paper.
But she was pretty as
any picture to me.
What are you looking at?
If you must know, we have
a longstanding agreement
never to go to bed sober.
- Isn't that right, darling?
- Whatever you say, darling.
Her husband was Walter Abbott.
He was Chief Minister of the
British Trade Mission in Murmansk,
and he was a spy.
- Darling.
- Oh, thank you, my darling.
- Key, darling.
- Oh, yes.
I broke my heel off
one of my shoes.
I'm not in the habit of walking
about in my stocking feet.
They were long days there.
And even longer nights.
One particular night, I was
having trouble sleeping.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't sleep.
I was gonna make some tea.
Would you like some?
Oh, no. Thank you.
Milk? Honey?
A bit of honey, please.
I hope you like flies
in your honey.
Oh, perhaps not.
Oh, maybe better to let
it steep a little.
Steep?
Soak.
I don't know, I mean, there's
a proper way of making tea.
Well, where I'm from, people
just want it to be hot.
Well, quite right.
- Now, you're a seaman.
- A sailor.
I hope you won't think me
impolite, but I have to ask,
aren't you a little old
to be working on a boat?
There's no age limit, as
long as you can do the work.
And you have trouble sleeping?
Thank you.
I didn't think I did. I
usually sleep like a baby.
Something's been keeping me up.
My father, in his 80s,
he was so convinced he was
gonna die in his sleep,
he limited himself to
having afternoon naps.
He was so determined he
was gonna cheat death.
- Did he?
- Did he what?
Die in his sleep?
He died sitting in
his favorite chair
listening to his favorite
program on the wireless.
He must have known something.
My husband's the British Trade Minister,
and we've been here for 14 months.
- Good God.
- We were supposed to go to Peking
but it never seemed to work out.
Have you been in the Far East?
No. I've never been
anywhere, really.
I mean, outside of harbors.
And where is it
that you're from?
New Orleans. Louisiana.
I didn't know there was another.
And she told me about all the places
she had been, and what she had seen.
And we talked till
just before the dawn.
I'm just a lush, myself.
And we went back to our
rooms, to our separate lives.
But every night, we'd
meet again in that lobby.
A hotel in the middle of the
night can be a magical place.
A mouse running, and stopping.
A radiator hissing.
A curtain blowing.
There's something
peaceful, even comforting
knowing that the people you
love are asleep in their beds
where nothing can harm them.
Elizabeth and I would
lose track of the night
until just before daybreak.
I think I may have given
you the wrong impression.
Beg pardon?
Well, married women don't
customarily sit around
in the middle of the night
with strange men in hotels.
I wouldn't know what a married
woman does or doesn't do.
Good night.
Murmansk.
"I've met somebody, and
I've fallen in love."
Mom?
That was over 60 years ago.
Did you love him, Mother?
What does a girl
know about love?
Well...
- I'm not dressed.
- Oh, you look splendid, just as you are.
Don't waste any time bothering about
the wine or the cheese in Murmansk,
'cause they're really
completely ordinary,
but the caviar and the vodka
are sublime and plentiful.
So.
Savor it.
And don't eat it all at once,
because that way, there's
nothing left to enjoy.
And now, take a little swallow of
vodka while it's still in your mouth.
You haven't been with
many women, have you?
Not on Sundays.
And you've never had
caviar before, have you?
No, ma'am.
When I was 19,
I attempted to become the first woman
ever to swim the English Channel.
Really?
But the current that day
was so strong that,
for every stroke I took,
I was pushed back two.
I was in the water for 32 hours.
And when I was two
miles from Calais,
it started to rain.
That's it! Steady on!
When I couldn't go any further,
I stopped.
I just stopped.
And everybody asked me,
would I try again?
For why wouldn't I?
But I never did.
As a matter of fact, I've never done
anything with my life after that.
Your hands are so coarse.
I can feel the wind
in your cheek.
I'm afraid it's the
witching hour.
It was the first time a
woman had ever kissed me.
It's something you never forget.
I think you make
me feel younger.
You make me feel
years younger, too.
I wish I was.
So many things I'd change.
I'd undo all my mistakes.
What mistakes?
I kept waiting, you know?
Thinking that I'd do something
to change my circumstances.
Do something.
Such an awful waste.
You never get it back.
Wasted time.
If we're going to
have an affair,
you're never to look
at me during the day.
And we're always to
part before sunrise.
And we will never
say "I love you."
Those are the rules.
- Are you cold?
- I'm freezing.
Oh, you! You're frozen.
What an idiot, I'm standing here in
this fur. How thoughtless of me.
She was the first woman
that ever loved me.
You want me to skip some?
No, I'm glad he had
somebody to keep him warm.
"I couldn't wait
to see her again."
We saw each other every night.
We always used the same room.
But each time seemed
new and different.
Come here.
Elizabeth.
Good night.
Until one night.
Yesterday, December 7th, 1941,
a date which will
live in infamy...
it's a meeting, a policy
meeting regarding your future,
possibly beyond.
There's been a change
of plan, lads.
As you may or may not know,
the Japs bombed Pearl
Harbor yesterday.
Frank D. Roosevelt's asked
each of us to do our part.
The Chelsea's been commissioned to
serve in the United States Navy.
To repair, to salvage,
and to rescue.
Anybody doesn't want to go to
war, now is the time to say so.
Once you set foot on that boat,
you're in the Navy, friend.
Yeah, I've been meaning
to talk with you, Mike.
My wife's doing poorly.
I'd like to maybe see
her one more time.
You're free to make your way
home any way you can, Mr. Mayes.
Well, if he's leaving,
who's gonna cook?
Food poisoning's one of the
leading causes of death at sea.
Right after inadequate
safety equipment.
I can cook, Captain. Been
doing it all my life.
I don't know. You're a little
moody for war, Benjamin.
What the hell?
I'll take any man wants to kick the
shite out of the Japs and the Huns.
That's it, pack your gear.
We're going to war, gentlemen!
She had left a note.
She wrote, "it was
nice to have met you."
And that was it.
It wasn't the war
any of us expected.
We would just tow crippled
ships, scraps of metal, really.
If there was a war,
we didn't see it.
There was a man assigned to us.
The Chief Gunner loved the Navy.
But most of all,
he loved America.
There is no other
country in the world.
When you spell America...
His name was Dennis Smith, and
he was a full-blooded Cherokee.
His family had been Americans
for over 500 years.
These pacifists. They say they
won't fight on conscience.
Now, where would be if
everybody decided to act
- according to their conscience?
- Keep it down, would you, Chief?
Hey. I've been watching you.
You seem trustworthy.
If something happens to me,
could you see that
this gets to my wife?
He'd given me all of his pay.
Hadn't spent a dime of it.
I want my family to know I
was thinking about them.
All hands on deck!
The war had finally found us.
All stop!
Pleasant, man that light.
A transport carrying 1,300 men
had been split by a torpedo.
We were first to
arrive at the scene.
- Cut the engines!
- All stop!
We were the only sound.
Fellas!
Sub!
We sure as hell can't
outrun them fuckers.
Battle stations!
Thank you, Chief.
What?
Is that the last one?
Captain!
They shot the hell
out of my painting!
Give me your other hand.
You'll be all right, Captain.
They got a nice spot in Heaven
waiting for you. Nice spot.
You can be as mad as a mad
dog at the way things went.
You could swear,
curse the Fates.
But when it comes to the end,
you have to let go.
Captain?
Thirteen hundred and twenty
eight men died that day.
I said my goodbyes to the
Cherokee, Dennis Smith.
John Grimm, who was right,
he was gonna die there.
I sent Pleasant Curtis'
wife his money.
I said goodbye to the
twin, Vic Brody,
and to Mike Clark, captain
of the tugboat Chelsea.
I said goodbye to all the other
men who had dreams of their own,
all the men who wanted
to be insurance salesmen
or doctors or lawyers
or lndian chiefs.
This don't get fixed.
Out here, death
didn't seem natural.
I'd never seen a hummingbird
that far out to sea.
Before or since.
And in May of 1945, when
I was 26 years old,
I came home.
I'm ready! I'm ready!
I'm coming!
- I'm ready!
- All right, I'm coming, Miss Alfalina.
- Queenie?
- Yes?
Sweet Jesus! Oh, you're home!
Oh, Lord, you came back!
- Let me look at you.
- Who's that, Mama?
- Child, it's your brother, Benjamin.
- I didn't know he was my brother.
There's a shitload of things
you don't know, child.
Get on out there and
finish sweeping.
Come here, wash your hands, help
me with the table. Go on, now.
Turn around. You look like
you've been born again.
Younger than the springtime.
I think that preacher laid hands
on you gave you a second life.
I knew it that moment I saw
you, you were special.
I tell you what,
my knees are sore,
'cause I've been on them
every night asking the Lord,
I said, "God, just bring
him home safely."
Remember what I told you?
"You never know what's
coming for you"?
That's right. Sit down.
Well, you learn anything
worth repeating?
- I sure saw some things.
- Oh, you seen some pain.
- Some joy, too?
- Sure. Sure, I did.
Yeah, that's what I want to hear.
Look at you.
- Where's Tizzy?
- Oh, baby.
Mr. Weathers died in his
sleep one night last April.
- Mama, I'm so sorry.
- Don't you worry about that, baby.
Yeah, well, it's only one
or two of them left now.
They all just about new.
Guess they're waiting their
turn like everybody else, huh?
I'm so glad you're
back home with me!
Now, we're gonna have to find you a
wife and a new job! That's right.
Come on in here, help
me with this table.
Benjamin.
You're wasting your time, baby.
She's stone deaf.
Oh, and you'll be staying in what was Mrs.
DeSeroux's old room.
You're too big to be
rooming with anybody else.
It's a funny thing
about coming home.
Looks the same, smells the
same, feels the same.
Did I ever tell you I've been
struck by lightning seven times?
Once when I was sitting in my truck,
just minding my own business.
You realize what's
changed is you.
And late one morning, not
long after I'd been back...
Thank you.
Hey.
- Excuse me, is Queenie here?
- Daisy?
- It's me, Benjamin.
- Benjamin?
Oh, my God!
Of course it's you! Benjamin!
How are you? It's been
such a long time.
There's so much I want to know.
When did you get back?
Well, I got back
a few weeks ago.
I spoke to Queenie, she said you
were in the war, somewhere at sea.
- We were so, so worried about you.
- Oh, I'm okay.
Well, look at you.
You're so lovely.
You stopped writing.
"When I had left, she was a girl.
And a woman had taken her place."
"She was the most beautiful
woman I'd ever seen."
Beautiful.
"The most beautiful."
- You remember Grandma Fuller?
- Why, sure I do.
- She passed.
- I heard that. I'm sorry.
I just can't believe we're both here.
Must be fate.
No, no, what do they call it?
Kismet.
Do you know about Edgar
Cayce, the psychic?
I don't believe I...
He says that everything
is predetermined,
but I like to think
of it as fate.
I'm not sure how it works,
but I'm glad it happened.
Have you been to Manhattan? It's
right across the river from me.
Now, I can see the
Empire State Building
if I stand on my bed.
What about you? Where
have you been?
Tell me everything. Last time you
wrote, you said you'd been to Russia.
I've always wanted to go to Russia.
Is it as cold as they say?
- Twice as cold.
- My goodness.
We always said you were different.
But I think you really are.
You wrote that you met somebody.
Did it work out?
It ran its course.
Hey, do you remember this?
"This is the picture
of Old Man Kangaroo"
"at 5:00 in the afternoon."
Would you like to have dinner?
Did I tell you that I
danced for Balanchine?
Oh, he's a famous choreographer.
He said that I had perfect line.
You know, in a rehearsal
once, a dancer fell.
And he just... He just put it
right into the production.
I mean, can you imagine that? Like in a...
In a classical ballet?
You know, a dancer,
intentionally falling.
There's a whole new word for dance now.
It's called "abstract."
No, he's not the
only one, though.
There's Lincoln Kirstein and
Lucia Chase, and oh, my...
Oh, there's Agnes de Mille.
She's just torn up all
those conventions,
you know, all that
straight-up-and-down stuff.
It's not about the formality of the dance,
it's about what the dancer's feeling.
As she told me about
this big new world,
names that didn't
mean a thing to me,
I didn't really hear very
much of what she was saying.
It's new and it's modern
and it's American.
They understand our vigor
and our physicality.
Oh, my God. I've just
been talking and talking.
No, no, I've enjoyed listening.
I didn't know you smoked.
I'm old enough.
I'm old enough for
a lot of things.
In New York, we
stay up all night,
watch the sun come up
over the warehouses.
There's always something to do.
I have to go back tomorrow.
- So soon.
- Wish I could stay.
Dancers don't need costumes
or scenery anymore.
I can imagine dancing
completely naked.
Have you read D.H. Lawrence?
- Well...
- His books were banned.
The words are like making love.
In our company, we have
to trust each other.
Sex is a part of it.
You know, a lot of the
dancers are lesbians.
There was one woman who
wanted to sleep with me.
- Does that upset you?
- Which part?
Somebody wanting
to sleep with me.
You're a desirable woman.
I would think most of them
would want to sleep with you.
Let's go back to the house.
Or we could get a
room somewhere.
- We could lay down your jacket.
- I don't know, Daisy.
It's not that I wouldn't like to or
anything. I think I'll just disappoint you.
Oh, Benjamin, I've
been with older men.
You're going back to New
York in the morning.
You should be with your friends.
- You're only young once.
- Oh, I'm old enough.
Daisy, just not tonight, is all.
We could go hear some music.
Our lives are defined
by opportunities.
Even the ones we miss.
You look so handsome
and so distinguished.
They're saying the hurricane's
gonna miss us, blow right on by.
- Oh, that's great.
- I'll stay under the blankets with Mother.
She says nothing... Benjamin?
"Things were becoming
different..."
...for me.
My hair had very little
gray and grew like weeds.
My sense of smell was keener.
My hearing, more acute.
I could walk further and faster.
While everybody else was aging, I
was getting younger, all alone.
Come in.
Benjamin.
- Do you remember me?
- Well, sure I do, Mr. Button.
- What happened to you?
- Darn foot. Got infected, so...
Welcome home, my friend.
I see you're still drinking
your Sazerac with whiskey.
Creature of habit.
You still visiting the
house on Bourbon Street?
Not for a long time.
Interesting times, though.
We went from making 40,000 to nearly
half a million buttons a day.
We employed 10 times
the number of people.
We were operating
around the clock.
Damn shame.
The war has been kind
to the button industry.
You know,
I'm sick. I don't know
how much longer I have.
- I'm sorry to hear that, Mr. Button.
- No...
I don't have any people.
I keep to myself.
I hope you don't mind,
but, whenever possible,
I'd enjoy your company.
I'll certainly do what I can.
Benjamin, do you know
anything about buttons?
Now, Button's Buttons has been
in our family for 124 years.
My grandfather was a tailor, and
he had a small shop in Richmond.
After the Civil War, he
moved to New Orleans,
where my father had the wisdom
to make our own buttons.
So, with his help, the
tailor shop grew to this.
And today, I can't sew a stitch.
That's very, very interesting.
You sure have done
well for yourself.
So, what can I do for you, Mr.
Button?
Benjamin? You're my son.
I'm so sorry I never
told you before.
You were born the night
the Great War ended.
Your mother died
giving birth to you.
I thought you were a monster.
I promised your mother I'd
make sure you were safe.
I should never have
abandoned you.
My mother?
At the summer house on
Lake Pontchartrain.
When I was a boy, I'd love to
wake up before anyone else,
run down to that lake and
watch the day begin.
It was as if I was
the only one alive.
I fell in love the
first time I saw her.
Your mother's name
was Caroline Murphy.
She worked in your
grandfather's kitchen.
She's from Dublin.
In 1903, Caroline and all her brothers
and sisters came to live here,
in New Orleans.
I'd find excuses to go
down to that kitchen
just so I could look at her.
April 25th, 1918.
Happiest day of my life.
The day I married your mother.
Why didn't you just tell me?
I plan on leaving
everything I have to you.
- I have to go.
- Where?
Home.
And what does he think, anyway?
He thinks he can just show up
and everything's supposed
to be fine and dandy.
Everybody's just
supposed to be friends.
Well, he got another thing
coming, that's for sure.
God be my witness, he got
another thing coming.
He left us $18 that
night you was found.
Eighteen ratty dollars
- and a filthy diaper.
- Good night, Mama.
Good night, baby.
Did I ever tell you I was struck
by lightning seven times?
Once, I was walking
my dog down the road.
I'm blind in the one
eye, can't hardly hear,
get twitches and shakes out of nowhere,
always losing my line of thought.
But you know what?
God keeps reminding me
I'm lucky to be alive.
Storm's coming.
May I help you, sir? Up the
stairs, first bedroom.
Thank you.
Wake up.
Let's get you dressed.
Now that's something.
Thank you.
You can be mad as a mad dog
at the way things went.
You can swear and
curse the Fates.
But when it comes to the end,
you have to let go.
Well, it sure is a
beautiful service.
He'll be buried right
next to your mother.
You're my mother.
My baby.
Now, I'd never seen New York.
- Excuse me, I'm a friend of Daisy's.
- Right this way.
- Daisy has company. Daisy! Daisy!
- Yes!
- We need the wardrobe.
- Is somebody looking for me?
- Benjamin.
- Hi.
- What are you doing here?
- Thought I'd come visit.
Spend some time with
you, if I could.
Oh, well, I wish you would've called.
You took me by surprise.
- You can just throw them out.
- No. Thank you, they're lovely.
I couldn't take my eyes off of you.
I thought you were mesmerizing.
Thank you. That's very
kind of you to say.
I better get changed. A group
of us are going to a party.
- Would you want to come?
- Someone told me about a restaurant
I thought you might enjoy.
I made a reservation,
just in case.
Just, all the dancers go out
after the show. You're...
You're welcome to come with us.
I'll get changed. All right?
She choreographs for
the Ballets Russes.
She's divine.
You were breathtaking.
Sweetie.
This is David. He dances
with the company.
- This is Benjamin.
- Who?
- I told you about him.
- Oh, yeah. How you doing?
- I'll go get you a drink.
- All right. Thanks.
So, you were a friend
of her grandmother's?
Or something like that?
Something like that.
Hey, excuse me.
Come on.
Hey!
Now, I had no idea
you were coming.
Lord, Benjamin.
What did you expect? What, you
want me to drop everything?
Now, this is my life.
Babe! You going downtown?
Come on. You'll
have a good time.
There's lots of musicians,
interesting people.
You don't have to do that.
This is my fault.
I should've called.
I thought I'd come here
and sweep you off your
feet or something.
- Daisy! Come on! Let's go.
- Be right there.
Seems nice.
Do you love him?
I think so.
I'm happy for you.
Maybe I'll see you at home.
Okay.
I enjoyed the show!
He came to tell me
his father had died.
- You couldn't have known.
- I was 23. I... l just didn't care.
What did you do next?
Some photographs, I think,
in the front of my bag.
I was as good a dancer
as I was ever gonna be.
For five years, I...
I danced everywhere.
London, Vienna, Prague.
I've never seen these.
Mom.
You never talked
about your dancing.
Well, I was the only American
to be invited to dance
with the Bolshoi, sugar.
It was glorious.
But Benjamin was never
far from my thoughts.
And I'd find myself saying...
Good night, Benjamin.
- "Good night, Daisy."
- He said that?
"Life wasn't all
that complicated."
"if you want, you might say I
was looking for something."
Benjamin? Mrs. La
Tourneau just passed.
- Letter for Mr. Benjamin Button?
- That'd be me.
Thank you.
Miss Daisy Fuller.
- Just a minute. Please have a seat.
- Sure.
Sometimes we're on a collision
course and we just don't know it.
Whether it's by accident or by design,
there's not a thing we can do about it.
A woman in Paris was on
her way to go shopping.
But she had forgotten her
coat, went back to get it.
When she had gotten her
coat, the phone had rung.
So she had stopped to answer it and
talked for a couple of minutes.
While the woman
was on the phone,
Daisy was rehearsing for a performance
at the Paris Opera House.
And while she was rehearsing,
the woman, off the phone now,
had gone outside to get a taxi.
Now, a taxi driver had
dropped off a fare earlier,
and had stopped to
get a cup of coffee.
And all the while,
Daisy was rehearsing.
And this cab driver, who
dropped off the earlier fare
and had stopped to get
the cup of coffee,
he picked up the lady
who was going shopping
and had missed getting
the earlier cab.
The taxi had to stop for a
man crossing the street,
who had left for work five minutes
later than he normally did
because he forgot
to set his alarm.
While that man, late for work,
was crossing the street,
Daisy had finished rehearsing
and was taking a shower.
And while Daisy was showering,
the taxi was waiting outside a boutique
for the woman to pick up a package
which hadn't been wrapped yet,
because the girl who was
supposed to wrap it
had broken up with her boyfriend
the night before and forgot.
When the package was wrapped, the
woman, who was back in the cab,
was blocked by a delivery truck.
All the while, Daisy
was getting dressed.
The delivery truck pulled away,
and the taxi was able to move
while Daisy, the
last to be dressed,
waited for one of her friends
who had broken a shoelace.
While the taxi was stopped,
waiting for a traffic light,
Daisy and her friend came out
the back of the theater.
And if only one thing had
happened differently,
if that shoelace hadn't broken
or that delivery truck had
moved moments earlier
or that package had
been wrapped and ready
because the girl hadn't
broken up with her boyfriend,
or that man had set his alarm
and got up five minutes earlier
or that taxi driver hadn't
stopped for a cup of coffee
or that woman had remembered her
coat and got into an earlier cab,
Daisy and her friend would
have crossed the street
and the taxi would
have driven by.
But, life being what it is,
a series of intersecting
lives and incidents
out of anyone's control,
that taxi did not go by,
and that driver was
momentarily distracted.
Daisy!
And that taxi hit Daisy.
Daisy! Help!
And her leg was crushed.
Daisy?
- Who told you?
- Your friend wired me.
Very kind of you to come all this
way to see that I was all right.
You'd do the same for me.
My God.
Look at you. You're perfect.
I wish you hadn't come here. I don't
want you to see me like this.
Her leg had been
broken in five places.
And with therapy and time,
she might walk again.
But she'd never dance.
I'm gonna take you home with me.
- I want to look after you.
- I'm not going back to New Orleans.
Then I'll stay here in Paris.
Don't you understand? I
don't want your help.
I know I'm feeling sorry for myself,
but I don't want to be with you.
Tried to tell you that in New York.
You don't listen.
You might change your mind.
We are not little children
anymore, Benjamin.
Just stay out of my life.
I was awfully cruel.
He didn't understand. I couldn't
have him see me like that.
"I didn't leave right away."
"I stayed in Paris for a
while to look out for her."
I never knew that.
Oh, darling, could
you get the nurse?
I taught myself to walk again.
I took the train to Lourdes.
Let's take a look. That's normal.
Pulse rate is slowing.
She is gonna
struggle to breathe.
- Will you be all right?
- Yeah.
All right, he says, "I went back home."
And then there's a lot of pages torn out.
"I listened to the sound of the
house." I read that already.
He...
He spilt something on it,
so it's hard to read, Mom.
Something about sailing,
does that make sense?
I learned to sail an old boat of
my father's from the lake house.
I can't lie.
I did enjoy the company
of a woman or two.
Or maybe three.
Don't know why you bother, Sam,
just gonna be there again tomorrow.
Mama.
And in the spring of 1962,
she came back.
- You want to know where I've been?
- No.
How come you didn't write or nothing?
Just disappearing like that.
It was something I
needed to do for myself.
Yeah, well, I never took you
to be the selfish type.
I sure hope I'm not wrong.
I'm usually not
wrong about people.
- Good night, Mama.
- Good night, baby.
Y'all have fun.
- You haven't said two words.
- I don't want to ruin it.
- Sleep with me?
- Absolutely.
I asked her to
come away with me.
We sailed into the Gulf
along the Florida Keys.
I am so glad we didn't find
one another when I was 26.
- Why do you say that?
- I was so young.
And you were so old.
It happened when it was
supposed to happen.
I will enjoy each and every
moment I have with you.
I bet I can stay out
here longer than you.
I bet you can't.
Barely a line or a crease.
Every day I have more wrinkles.
It's not fair.
I love your wrinkles.
Both of them.
What's it like growing younger?
I can't really say. I'm always
looking out my own eyes.
Will you still love me when
my skin grows old and saggy?
Will you still love me when I have acne?
When I wet the bed?
When I'm afraid of
what's under the stairs?
What?
- What are you thinking?
- Well, I was thinking how nothing lasts.
And what a shame that is.
Some things last.
- Good night, Daisy.
- Good night, Benjamin.
Mom?
- When did you meet Dad?
- Some time after that.
- Did you tell him about this Benjamin?
- He knew enough, darling.
Mama?
Queenie?
Hello?
Oh, hi, Mrs. Carter, it's Benjamin.
Where is everybody?
Oh, Benjamin. Queenie died.
I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
She was a great woman.
Our deepest condolences.
We buried her beside her beloved Mr.
Weathers.
And so we might have
memories of our own,
we sold my father's
house on Esplanade.
It is a wonderful
old place, darling.
I think we are going
to be so happy here.
Oh, what a long family
history you have.
They come with the house.
- Come on.
- You have to see the master suite.
We bought ourselves a duplex.
I loved that house.
It smelled like firewood.
Don't... Don't stop, darling.
"It was one of the happiest
times of my life."
We didn't have a
stick of furniture.
We would have picnics
in the living room.
We ate when we felt like it. Stayed
up all night when we wanted.
We vowed never to
fall into routine,
to go to bed or wake
up at the same time.
We lived on that mattress.
Our neighbor, a Mrs. Van Dam,
was a physical therapist.
We lived four blocks
from a public pool.
You know, you might've got a
few more years out of it,
but you chose to do something
so special and unique
that there was only a short
window of time you could do it.
So, even if nothing
ever happened,
you'd still be right
here where you are now.
I just don't like getting old.
They put too much
chlorine in here.
I promise you I'll never lose
myself to self-pity again.
And I think right there and then
she realized none of
us is perfect forever.
She found peace.
She opened a studio and taught
young girls how to dance.
And tendu.
Come back the other way. And
spot, spot, spot. Excellent.
- Good night, Miss Daisy.
- Good night.
You certainly are
beautiful to watch.
Dancing's all about the line.
The line of your body.
Sooner or later, you lose that
line, and you never get it back.
I figure, you were born
in 1918, 49 years ago.
I'm 43.
We are almost the same age.
- We're meeting in the middle.
- We finally caught up with each other.
Wait.
I want to remember us
just as we are now.
I'm pregnant.
You know, I swear the nurse
slipped and said it was a boy.
But I think it's a girl.
- I know you're afraid.
- I'm not hiding it.
Okay.
- What's your worst fear?
- Baby born like me.
Then I will love
it all the more.
Okay. How can I be a father when I'm
heading in the other direction?
It's not fair to a child. I don't
want to be anybody's burden.
Sugar, we all end up in diapers.
I am gonna make this work.
I want this, and I
want it with you.
I want you to have everything
you want, all of it.
I'm just not sure how
to reconcile this.
Would you tell a blind man
he couldn't have children?
Here you go.
You'll be a father for
as long as you can.
I know the consequences.
I've accepted that.
Loving you is worth
everything to me.
I have to go pee.
The oldest woman to ever
swim the English Channel
arrived here today in Calais...
- Keep it.
- ...having made the swim in 34 hours,
22 minutes and 14 seconds.
The 68-year-old Elizabeth Abbott
arrived at 5:38 Greenwich mean time,
exhausted but happy.
Miss Abbott, how would you sum
up, in words, this achievement?
I suppose...
Anything's possible.
- All right?
- Yes. Thank you.
- You ready?
- Thank you very much.
Thank you. Thank you all.
- Yeah.
- You're very kind.
In the spring, on a
day like any other...
I'll be back in an hour!
Honey?
Go and call an ambulance!
The baby's coming.
Operator, I need an ambulance.
- The baby's coming!
- 2714 Napoleon.
There you go. Keep breathing.
Deep breaths. Push.
There we go.
Everyone's fine. She's a
perfectly healthy baby girl.
Honey?
She gave birth to a five
pound, four ounce baby girl.
Did you count the toes?
She's perfect.
"And we named her for
my mother, Caroline."
This Benjamin was my father?
And this is how you tell me?
Excuse me.
...because all the ingredients
are there for a major storm,
possibly even up
to a Category 5.
Hey, I know it's hard.
You can't smoke in here.
Nobody can tell you exactly
where it's gonna hit,
but we have to go with the
guidance that we have,
incorporate that information
and then pass it along to you.
"You grew as the doctor had
promised, normal and healthy."
You're gonna have to find
a real father for her.
What are you talking about?
She's gonna need someone
to grow old with.
She'll learn to accept whatever happens.
She loves you.
Honey, she needs a
father, not a playmate.
- Is it me?
- Of course not.
- Is my age beginning to bother you?
- Is that what you're telling me?
- You can't raise the both of us.
It was your first birthday.
We had a party for you.
The house was filled
with children.
- How are you?
- Hey, man.
Before you turn around, they'll
be in high school, dating.
I sold the summer house
on Lake Pontchartrain,
I sold Button's Buttons,
I sold my father's sailboat, put
it all into a savings account.
And so that you and your
mother might have a life,
I left, before you could
ever remember me.
"I left with just the
clothes on my back."
I don't want to read this now. Can
you just tell me where he went?
I don't really know.
It's for me. 1970. I was two.
"Happy Birthday."
"I wish I could have
kissed you good night."
They're all for me.
Five. "L wish I could have taken
you to your first day of school."
Six. "L wish I could have been
there to teach you to play piano."
1981, 13.
"I wish I could have told
you not to chase some boy."
"I wish I could have held you
when you had a broken heart."
"I wish I could have been your father.
Nothing I ever did will replace that."
I guess he went to lndia.
"For what it's worth,
it's never too late,
- "or, in my case, too early..."
- ...or, in my case, too early,
to be whoever you want to be.
There's no time limit.
Start whenever you want.
You can change or stay the same.
There are no rules to this thing.
We can make the best
or the worst of it.
And I hope you make
the best of it.
I hope you see things
that startle you.
I hope you feel things
you never felt before.
I hope you meet people with
a different point of view.
I hope you live a
life you're proud of.
And if you find that you're not,
I hope you have the strength
- to start all over again.
- "...start all over again."
He had been gone a long time.
I'll see you next Thursday.
- Good night, Miss Daisy.
- Oh, good night, sweetheart.
I'm sorry, we're closing.
Can I help you?
Are you here to
pick somebody up?
Why did you come back?
Mom?
You ready yet?
Mom, what's wrong?
I was just hearing a very sad
story about a mutual friend
who I hadn't seen for
a very long time.
Caroline, this is Benjamin.
You knew him when you
were just a baby.
- Hi.
Hey.
- Oh, I'm sorry, I thought you were done.
- Oh, this is a friend of my family's.
Benjamin Button, this
is my husband, Robert.
- How do you do?
- A pleasure.
Well, it was very
nice to meet you.
- We'll be in the car, darling.
- All right.
Bye.
I'm just locking up.
Wow.
She's beautiful.
Like her mother.
- Does she dance?
- Not very well.
I guess that'd be from
my side of things.
She's a dear, sweet girl.
She seems a little lost.
But then, who isn't at 12?
A lot of her reminds me of you.
My husband, he's a widower, or was...
Was a widower.
He's an incredibly kind, just
bright, adventurous man.
- He's been a terrific father.
- Good.
- You are so much younger.
- Only on the outside.
You were right.
I couldn't have been
raising both of you.
I'm not that strong.
So, where are you staying?
What are you gonna do?
I'm staying at the Pontchartrain
Hotel on the Avenue.
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
But...
They're waiting.
I remember that. That was him?
The hurricane has
changed directions.
It's going to make
landfall sometime soon.
- Am I supposed to do something?
- Arrangements are being made
to move people, but
it's up to you.
No. No, we're... We're staying.
I'll let you know if
anything changes.
"That night, while I was sitting and
wondering why I came back at all,"
"there was a knock at the door."
Come in.
Are you all right?
I'm sorry, I don't know
what I'm doing here.
Nothing lasts.
I have never stopped loving you.
Oh, but, Benjamin, I'm
an old woman now.
Some things you never forget.
...so few people even know
that you were ever in
jail in the first place.
I'll tell you, I am
sick about it, too,
because, please, if they're
not gonna give you an award
like "Man of the Year," at
least what they could do
is stop having you
listed as an ex-convict
which I think is,
again, so unfair.
Good night, Benjamin.
Good night, Daisy.
And as I knew I would,
I watched her go.
That's the last thing he wrote.
Sometime after your
father passed,
there was a call.
Hello.
Yes, speaking.
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
It's the corner house.
Come on in.
- I'm Daisy Fuller.
- I'm David Hernandez,
with the Orleans Parish Department
of Child Welfare Services.
He was living in a
condemned building.
The police found this with him.
This address. It's got
your name in it a lot.
He's in very poor health. He
was taken to the hospital.
He doesn't seem to know who or where he is.
He's very confused.
I was telling Mr. Hernandez
that Benjamin is one of us.
If he needs a place to stay, it's
all right, he can stay here.
Benjamin?
You play beautifully.
He doesn't seem to
like to be touched.
He goes in and out of
states of recognition.
The doctors say, if they
didn't know any better,
he has the beginnings
of dementia.
Do you remember me?
I'm Daisy.
I'm Benjamin.
It's nice to meet you, Benjamin.
Would you mind if I sit with you?
I would love to hear you play.
Do I know you?
- I want some breakfast.
- And every day,
I would stop by to make sure
that he was comfortable.
- No, I didn't.
- You just finished eating.
Don't think I don't
know what you're doing!
You're all fucking liars!
He doesn't believe he
just had his breakfast.
Now, why don't we see
if we can't find something
else for you to do?
I have a feeling there's a lot
of things I can't remember.
Well, like what, sugar?
It's like there's this
whole life I had,
and I can't remember
what it was.
It's okay.
It's okay to forget things.
Many times, he would simply
forget who or where he was.
There he is, he's up
there on the roof.
It wasn't easy.
- Benjamin!
- I can see everything!
- I can see the big river!
- That's right,
you can see everything,
sweetheart.
I can see the graveyard
where Mama's buried,
- and all those other people.
- I want you to come down!
- What if I could fly?
- I knew a man who could fly.
You come down and I'll
tell you all about him.
Somebody go up there.
He was five when I moved in.
Nearly the same age I
was when I had met him.
"This is the picture
of Old Man Kangaroo"
"at 5:00 in the afternoon"
"when he had got his
beautiful hind legs."
The days passed.
And I watched as he
forgot how to walk
- and how to talk.
- What's my name?
I'm Daisy.
Can you say "Daisy"?
In 2002, they put up a new
clock in that train station.
And in the spring of 2003,
he looked at me
and I knew that he
knew who I was.
And then he closed his
eyes as if to go to sleep.
- I wish I'd known him.
- Now you do.
Mom, I think I should
go see what's going on.
Good night, Benjamin.
We're expecting flash flooding
after the levee break.
It occurred in the Ninth Ward.
Some people are born
to sit by a river.
Some get struck by lightning.
Some have an ear for music.
Some are artists.
Some swim.
Some know buttons.
Some know Shakespeare.
Some are mothers.
And some people dance.