Ever seen a shooting star?
Sure. You?
You know what
you're supposed to do, right?
What do you mean, make a wish?
So, if you saw one right now,
what would you wish for?
Well, that's a secret.
What about you?
To know why it took you so long.
All freshman year Biology,
we sat next to each other,
you don't even remember.
No, hey, I remember. Okay?
How about the next year
we had two classes,
do you remember which?
- Never even noticed.
- Oh, hey, that's not true.
So this is it. We're about to graduate
and now you ask me out.
- Now you want to start something?
- Hey, I'm sorry.
Okay? You've gotta forgive me.
Sometimes, you just...
You don't see
what's right in front of you.
Yeah, you don't see.
Okay, so what? You're gonna leave?
You ditch me, we'll be even?
Look, I can't change the past, Emily.
All I know is about tonight.
And tonight you're my wish.
So, uh,
make yourself... You know.
- It's nice, your place.
- Thanks.
Whoa. Is it that late already?
I thought your parents were away.
No. They are.
I just, um, I guess
I lost track of time here.
Uh, can I get you something to drink?
- Sure.
- Yeah? Okay.
- I'll be right back, okay?
- Okay.
Hey.
I wanna show you something.
What?
- Thank you.
- There you go.
To secrets.
- Secrets?
- And sharing them.
Have you ever seen something so scary
that you had to show to someone else?
- Um...
- I mean, like,
you know, a movie or something.
Well...
Okay, I've got the scariest freakin' movie
you'll ever see.
Now.
A buddy of mine
actually turned me on to it.
And, uh, he made me a copy.
So I did one for you.
You brought me here to watch a video?
Well, two minutes. Okay?
Two minutes and it'll all be over.
It's totally underground stuff.
I thought we were gonna just...
No, we will. We will.
You just gotta see this.
I'm telling you, it's...
How about after...?
No, you need to watch it now.
Okay?
So, um...
Just put it in the VCR, and press play,
and as soon as it's over,
I'll be right back in.
- Wait, wait, wait, "back"?
- Yeah, I've seen it.
It's scarier by yourself.
Look, my buddy did this to me. Okay?
This would really
mean something to me, Emily.
You know, like...
Like we're together.
What's so scary about it?
You'll see.
Play it. Just play the thing.
Come on, I got two minutes here, please.
Emily, play the goddamn tape!
- Hello?
- Tick tock, time's up.
What went down, man?
You get someone to watch it?
Yeah, yeah. Yeah, man.
Some stupid chick from my school.
Good thing. I was worried
you didn't believe me.
You don't show somebody else
a copy within a week,
I swear you're dead.
This is freaky stuff, man, freaky stuff.
My cousin, he showed it to his friend,
his friend didn't believe him
he was dead in a week.
Jake?
Are you there, man?
Jake, don't play around with me.
Emily?
Emily!
Emily, what the hell did you do?
I played it, I just didn't look.
Come on, Aidan, let's go home.
It was the right choice. No question.
Aidan, dinner's ready.
Damn.
Aidan!
Okay, now, before you say anything,
I followed the recipe this time.
So just 'cause it doesn't
look like the one in the magazine,
doesn't mean to say it won't taste good.
Those are great, honey.
Got a really good eye.
He'd be proud of you.
Thanks, Rachel.
You know, it wouldn't kill you
to call me Mom now and again.
Ma. Mommy.
Something besides Rachel.
Yeah, I like Rachel.
Well, Mom has its charms too, you know?
But Rachel, you know,
is more your personality.
Really?
Well, Rachel declares dinnertime.
It's working out great, don't you think?
All of this space and fresh air.
We have a yard.
It's really great.
Listen, honey.
We didn't do anything wrong.
We did what anyone would do.
We started over.
Yeah?
- Hey.
Uh, you know how they can tell
you used to work at a real newspaper?
You're the only one who closes your door.
Habit.
Uh, I wanted to talk
to you about my editorial.
Those changes okay?
Well, I asked you to
copy edit it and you rewrote it.
Well, just the part
about the bond measure.
That was the whole thing.
Well, it's the bridge that would
get the money, not the riverfront.
Yeah, uh...
You know, it's kind of a tradition here
that I write the lead editorial.
- I mean, it is my paper.
- Of course.
- I own it.
- Right.
And I hired you.
Uh-huh.
I just wouldn't want to see us
print an opinion that was...
What's the word?
Wrong?
Rachel.
Um...
You know, a big news day in Astoria
is a school board meeting,
a car wreck and a cat in a tree.
That's big news.
You sure this is
the job you're looking for?
Well, I'm around for my son more.
In Seattle, I wasn't.
Good a reason as any.
Um, I'm glad to see
you're settling in. I like the...
Hey, Max, while you're here,
have you given any thought
to that piece for tomorrow?
You know what? Don't you worry about it.
Sorry.
It's 442 Ridgecrest.
Ridgecrest. Ridgecrest!
I've already talked
to the medical examiner.
They're on their way.
Squad 19 to respond.
Squad 19, can we keep
this channel clear, please?
- It's the police, they found a body.
- Possible homicide.
Please, we should be so lucky.
What are they saying?
High school student, male, 17.
Address, 442 Ridgecrest.
Found the house partially flooded,
and a girlfriend hiding in the basement.
Suspect or witness, they don't know.
The guy was dead on the living room floor
right in front of the TV.
They keep on talking about his face.
What about his face?
All emergency units, area Astoria,
switch to Tack Five.
Detective.
Detective, you have a minute?
Was it homicide or wasn't it?
You know how he died, don't you?
I just have a few last questions.
If you could walk me through it again.
It's just horrible. So young.
No.
No, please, not here.
I found you.
We only made one copy.
Oh, God.
- Excuse me, sir.
- Hold on.
Yeah'?
I'm Rachel Keller from the Daily Astorian.
We'll make a statement.
I need to know about the girl.
She hasn't said a word, has she?
You're welcome to wait. Excuse me.
Watch your step. Have a seat here, okay?
Have a seat.
I just want you to relax for me.
You can't keep her here. She's scared.
- Focus on the walls.
- We wanna take her home.
- She'll talk to us.
- I understand your concerns.
I'm just gonna ask
a few questions in private.
It'll just take a minute. Please.
- Be right back, Emily.
- Thank you. Thank you.
All right. Give me his number.
Yeah. All right.
Emily.
Emily, listen to me. I know what happened.
I know.
Now, you have to tell me. The tape.
Did you watch it?
Do you know who else has watched it?
Has anyone else watched it?
No.
Then where is it?
Hey, you, get away from her. Ray.
Emily, talk to me.
I want her out of here. Now.
You can tell me, Emily.
Not here, Samara. Not here.
Rachel?
Rachel!
Rachel! Rachel!
Honey, what is it?
What's wrong? Huh?
What's wrong? Look at me. Shh.
- Okay? What is it?
- I had a nightmare.
That's all right. We all have them.
Oh, God, you're soaked.
And you're freezing.
Let's get you out of
these clothes. Come on.
Aidan?
What happened in your nightmare?
I woke up and you weren't here.
You weren't here.
I'm here now, honey. I'm right here, okay?
Listen.
All you have to do is call my name
and I'll follow your voice.
Okay?
Even if I have to come right down
into that nightmare with you.
So tell me what happened.
Hmm?
I don't remember.
You don't remember?
Aidan.
Honey. Can you hear me?
I've been calling your name.
I'm sorry.
- You ready to go?
- Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Okay.
So we'll just swing by
and see what they have, okay?
And you can keep a watch
on the backyard stuff. How's that?
Look at all this stuff.
Who do you think buys this crap?
Rachel. Hi.
- Hi.
- Hey.
You guys, come here. Here's the new
neighbor I was telling you about.
Rachel Keller.
She works for the Daily Astoria.
Oh, Rachel, meet
Meg Lowry and Audrey Flint.
- Hello.
So looking for stuff to
fill up that new house, huh?
You should see what
Rachel is doing with it.
She's doing with it, a kind of, um,
a country loft look, right?
Did they replace that orange linoleum
that was in the back
bathroom there before you moved in?
Oh, you are so bad.
You know, you really
should get here early, Rachel,
because the good stuff is gone by noon.
I'm sorry, just a sec.
Whatever I say,
walk and keep walking, all right?
I'm sorry. I forgot your names.
Oh, Meg and Audrey.
Aidan, stay with me, honey.
Kids.
Yeah, well, there's
a reason God made them so cute.
Huh?
[I So we don't kill them.
- I really should...
- Oh, we know, we know, we know.
Go ahead, we're around.
We'll run into you.
- It's good to meet you.
- You, too.
Good luck with everything.
- Take care now.
- Goodbye.
Aidan?
Thank you, I owe you one.
Don't you want friends?
Those aren't friends, honey.
They're the secret police.
You still cold?
What's wrong, honey? You all right?
Mm-hmm.
- I'm gonna take a look around.
- All right.
Stay close.
Hello, young man.
Have you received
your free lucky marble today?
I wouldn't, if I were you.
I heard they don't even
make the machines anymore.
Fine with me.
Well, I guess it's proof
there's not a lot to do around here.
Not much happens.
Although, the past three months
we've had a couple of
interesting events, haven't we?
A couple?
What? Something
happened before the murder?
Yeah, well, you came here.
That was interesting.
Is that a line, Max?
More of a question.
Why would you choose to live here?
No one would choose
to live in a place like this.
It's quiet.
Well, I got to tell you,
I think it's too quiet.
I can't sleep, I miss noise.
I miss garbage trucks.
I lived in New York for ten years.
Four years at Columbia,
then the Daily News, and for me,
that place is home.
I thought you were born here.
Oh, yeah, I was. I moved back.
It's not that tragic.
I'm just surprised, that's all.
Found out my parents weren't well,
so I came back to help out for a while.
I'm still here.
Are they still...?
No. I got the house, I got the paper.
And I got the 20 employees in the town
I swore I would never come back to.
- Homesick.
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Terminal case.
- I recognize the symptoms.
- Hey, Max, how are you?
- Good, Dale.
Who's the little cutie?
Uh, new editor, Dale.
Co-worker, colleague.
Whatever you say.
This place will grow on you, Rachel.
Are you ready? You guys all ready to go?
On your mark, get set, go!
Love to meet him.
You should bring him by sometime.
I will.
Paper's the only family I have.
So, I try to treat it like one.
I can see that.
Whenever you want
to tell me, feel free to.
- Tell you what?
- Why here?
Like I said, it's quiet.
Okay.
You don't have kids, do you, Max?
Everything I do is for my son.
Everything.
I should, uh...
Sure.
I really would like to meet him.
See if he's anything like you.
Man, that was genius.
Aidan?
Aidan.
Remember, you gotta wait for the whistle.
Aidan! Aidan!
Are you in there?
Aidan?
Why didn't you answer me, honey?
What are you...
Jesus.
Jesus, you're freezing, honey.
What's going on? Are you sick?
Talk to me, honey.
Talk to me. What's going on?
- What is it?
- I'm cold.
Oh.
It's okay. It's okay.
Honey, when did this start?
Was it last night,
or this morning?
I don't remember.
Look, I know you don't like me prying,
but this is important, okay?
Was it your nightmare?
I really don't remember, Rachel.
I need you to try.
You're sick, all right?
And we need to know what started it.
Aidan.
Was she in your nightmare?
Rachel!
Don't stop.
- Go! Drive, drive!
- What's the matter, honey?
Just don't stop the car!
Just... just don't stop the car!
Get down!
- Why did you say...
- Rachel!
"Don't stop."
You said, "Don't stop."
Oh, my God.
Don't stop.
Okay. Let's see.
That's impossible.
Rachel, what's happening?
Yeah, hi, um,
my son is very sick
and I'd like to talk to someone who...
Right.
Well, it's his temperature.
It's... it"'s five degrees low.
Okay.
Keep him warm.
Oh, my God.
Aidan?
Honey.
Honey, this shouldn't be open.
God.
Aidan, let's go. Get out of bed.
Aidan, what are you doing over there?
Get back in bed right now.
I saw something.
Aidan.
Move, get away. Get away from there.
Honey, let's go. Come on.
I saw it.
- I saw it in my head.
- Let's go.
- Oh, Ms. Keller, about my story. I...
- Not now.
Now, listen, sweetie.
Last night I found a tape.
It was one of hers.
And I made it so
we'd never have to see it again.
But if she knows that,
what I did might make her wanna hurt us.
Am I right?
Do you know something, honey?
Look, if you know why
she's here, you have to tell me.
Aidan.
Is she here to hurt you?
Honey.
She can hear us.
She hears everything.
Except when we sleep.
She can't hear us when we sleep?
What does that mean?
We have to sleep.
Rachel, may I come in, please?
Yeah.
What happened to your car?
Your car. Apparently it's wrecked.
- Are you guys okay?
- Yeah. We got hit.
And no one's hurt?
That's good.
Aidan, right? Hi, I'm Max.
- Is he all right?
- He's sick.
How sick?
Max, I need your help.
- Here.
- I'll get some more blankets.
The house is yours if
there's anything you need at all.
Okay. Thanks.
- Here.
- Thank you.
- Shouldn't he be at a hospital?
- No, he's fine.
The bath?
Yeah, it's just down the hall.
I'll get it started.
Honey.
I'm gonna go home
and get some of our things.
Then we'll leave here
and never come back, okay?
Let's get you warmed up.
Not the best water pressure, but it works.
It's good, thanks.
I don't know why we lost power.
The rest of the block seemed fine.
I have plenty of candles
in case the problem spreads.
Okay. Let's go ahead and get in.
Let's get you warmed up.
Max, I just need to go back to my house,
get a few things, some medicine.
Do you mind if you could...?
- I'll watch him. Of course.
- Okay, thanks.
Honey, go ahead and get in.
Let's go. Let's go.
We need to raise your temperature.
Now, let's get in.
Aidan, what's wrong? It's just water.
We need to raise your temperature,
honey, come on.
I don't want to, Rachel.
Do you want me to get in with you?
Let's go then, Aidan. Come on, let's go.
That's it.
Come on, honey. Let's go, let's go.
That's it. That's it.
That's better, right?
See? It's nice and warm.
It's okay. Just relax.
Hello?
Officer Ray. How you doing?
Yeah, good, good. All right,
what do you got for me?
Mm-hmm. Right.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, well, that all sounds like page 26.
You don't have any headlines?
No.
Well, business is business.
Yeah. No, no, I'm good, real good.
Hey, listen, could you
do me a little favor while I've got you?
Could you look into
your accident reports for today
and see if there was an accident
with a woman and her son?
K for Keller.
No, no, I'm just
trying to get a story straight.
Ray?
Ray, let me call you right back. Okay.
Everything okay in there?
Uh, Aidan, could you,
uh, unlock the door, please?
Aidan, can you hear me?
Aidan, please, unlock the door!
Aidan, open the door!
Aidan. Aidan, Aidan!
He's in the bath,
I don't know. It was open a second ago.
Aidan, open the door!
I'm gonna get something to break it.
Aidan, open up the door. I'm right here.
Honey, can you hear me? Please.
You need to open up the door.
Aidan!
Aidan.
Oh.
Aidan! Aidan.
Please, honey, open the...
Oh, my God.
Oh!
Aidan.
Aidan. Aidan. Look at me.
Aidan, look at me. Look at me.
Mommy!
Rachel, no!
Baby. Oh.
Oh, my God. Baby, I'm sorry.
It wasn't him. It wasn't him.
I was just trying to help.
Okay, Rachel,
let's just get him out of there.
Why is she doing this to me?
I'm here now, baby.
- Why is she doing this to me?
- It's okay, Aidan.
We're gonna get you better.
We're gonna get you to a hospital.
No!
They can't do anything.
You asked for my help,
you're gonna get my help
when he gets to a hospital, Rachel.
All right, everyone, we're back,
continuing with our outdoor theme.
I hope that you're
enjoying the show so far.
Summer finally seems to be here
and I know with Memorial approaching,
it's the official kick off of summer.
One thing we all love to do
throughout the summer months
is spend time outdoors
with our friends and our family.
We've offered you what I think...
is one of the most affordable sets.
This is a really great set because...
set for $1.32 a piece.
Don't hang up, we'll continue to...
is really very, very pretty.
Sorry, I'm starting to perspire a little.
But it's hot out here already in Florida.
I wonder how long it's been going on.
Those bruises.
Iced tea. If you wanted
to make one of those little drinks
that require an umbrella,
you could make it in bulk, if you will.
Put it in the pitcher and away you go.
This is a really great set
because you're getting them
with hibiscuses all over,
it's a hibiscus pitcher,
it's a 30 ounce pitcher, so...
It's his core temperature.
He was at 90 degrees when he came in.
- He wasn't outside overnight?
- No. He was at home with me.
A body doesn't develop
severe hypothermia on its own.
Whatever the cause, he's fighting it.
Seems like he's stabilizing.
- And he's just sleeping now?
- Right.
And having some kind of dream.
What's the story, Rachel?
They stabilized his temperature.
I mean the story with you and Aidan.
You seem awfully hard on him.
Look, I know
it's a stressful time for you.
Moving. It's a whole new life.
Maybe you should tell me.
All I ever tried to do
for him was the right thing.
It only ever made things worse.
Then it wasn't the right thing, was it?
What do you see?
Well, it's Aidan.
- Is that a girl there?
- Why is she in the picture?
- Why? How would I know?
- Why is she in all of them?
Her name's Samara.
She was murdered by her mother.
Left to die at the bottom of a well.
- Wait, she's... she's who?
- She didn't die.
At least, not her ghost.
I kept it alive for Aidan.
I let it out, it spread and then we ran.
What are you talking about?
Look, I know this sounds completely crazy,
but she's here now, she's found us.
And I thought it was just to hurt Aidan,
but it's more than that,
she wants to be him.
And she wants to live for real this time.
You tell me, who can help me?
Who?
Rachel, I'm sure there's
a rational ex plan a...
You take his picture
and tell me why she's in it.
- Rachel.
- You take his picture.
And it's proof that he's what, Rachel?
That he's got a ghost inside him?
No. The proof is what will happen.
Aidan, you said Samara
couldn't hear us when we sleep.
Well, you're sleeping now.
Tell me how to stop her, honey.
Tell me how to help you.
Just tell me, I'll do anything, I swear.
Aidan?
- Aidan?
- Ms. Keller?
Hello, I'm Dr. Emma Temple.
I'm a consulting physician
at County Child Services.
Well, I was hoping to speak
with Aidan when he wakes up.
Is everything all right in here?
Yeah, it's fine. Thank you.
I was hoping to speak with you as well.
It's Rachel, isn't it?
Yeah, about his situation.
I'm sorry, what kind of doctor
did you say you were again?
I'm a psychiatrist.
Yeah. I spoke with
a Dr., um, Koji in Seattle.
Aidan's doctor.
Look, if we could maybe talk later.
Right, um, Dr. Koji mentioned
that you dealt with some PPD
when Aidan was born.
Postpartum depression.
That was the first month. That's all.
I understand. It's very common.
I mean, a lot of women have trouble
adapting to the stresses of motherhood.
What does this have to do with what's
going on with my son right now?
Have you been under stress lately?
Have you ever found that you were
unable to experience love for Aidan?
What?
Have you hurt him,
however unintentionally?
Have you left him alone? Abandoned him?
I'd like to be with my son,
please, if you don't mind.
Yeah, of course.
I'm sorry, Rachel.
Until we can talk further,
I cannot let you be alone with him.
I'm his mother.
There are bruises on his body.
He was hypothermic and very near death.
That is not because of me.
He's gonna be all right, Rachel. He will.
But you need to leave.
Now, please.
You can't have him, Samara.
You're going back to where you came from.
We'll talk in here.
It really will help, Rachel.
Sharing one's troubles never hurt anybody.
- Now, are you a coffee drinker?
- Black.
Yeah, I imagined so.
Dr. Forrest, dial 118, please.
Dr. Forrest, please dial 118.
So, let's call the doctor in Seattle.
I want to know just
how bad her postpartum got.
- Yes.
- Thank you.
The mother is missing.
I want a watch on this room.
She returns, she is not allowed in.
Okay, Dr. Temple.
All I wanna know is what her history
was before the Morgans.
I'm sorry, but
the privacy laws still apply.
Well, was she really adopted?
Can you at least tell me that much?
Was their story true?
Samara Morgan was adopted, yes.
But you won't tell me from who?
I'd lose my job if I did.
Look, ma'am,
my son has a medical condition
that his doctors don't even understand.
This little girl had the same condition.
Now, if I knew what caused that,
it could save his life.
All I can say is
you should speak to the Morgans.
They're dead. They both killed themselves.
Whoa! Look out, early birds.
Marty Savide, Stevens Northwest Realty.
- Hi.
- Uh, come in.
I thought I put 12:30 on the ad.
For the open house.
- How'd you get around the gate?
- Well, I just...
Ah! Who cares? Come on.
Make me an offer
over asking and it's yours.
Okay, then, don't mind me.
My first try with these things,
took off flying.
There we go.
What do you think?
Um, a little color will
really turn the place around.
I tell you what,
it's got a wonderful history.
Working horse ranch. How about that?
And there's even this
cute little tree house thing
way up in the barn.
Um, is the place
being sold unfurnished or...
The previous owners
didn't leave anything behind?
Uh, well, there were
some things that were left,
after they... moved.
We're storing all that
in the basement for the time being.
There's a basement?
Uh, well, you betcha. No extra charge.
Right this way.
Uh, if you don't mind,
I'm the welcome wagon.
Gotta open up the gate for everyone else.
So please, just make yourself at home.
Do you know what happened
to them? The previous owners?
I believe they bought a condo in Phoenix.
Really?
Her mother.
Oh, my. You're awake.
Hello, Aidan, I'm Dr. Temple.
How are you feeling?
Aidan?
You know, I'd really like to help you.
Can you tell me how you're feeling?
Where's my mommy?
Well, she'll be here soon.
She's on her way.
I want Mommy.
Yeah, I know you do.
Your mommy wants to be with you too.
So where is she?
She went home.
She didn't think that
you were gonna wake up so soon.
I wanna go home too.
Well, you will.
We just have to...
we just have to get you...
You're freezing.
I wanna go home to Mommy.
Well, we need to talk about her.
Can you tell me about Mommy a little bit?
She loves me.
I know that she does.
She went looking for me.
She tried to find me.
It means she loves me.
I don't understand.
Can I go home now?
No, honey, you're not well enough.
Can I go home?
No.
I'm sorry.
Then I have to show you something.
It won't stop.
Hi, I'm Sister Diane, how can we help you?
Yeah, I need to know
about a child who was born here.
Is there anyone that can talk to me
who's been here more than 30 years?
Please, come in.
I remember this, yes.
A young girl made it. 16.
She was shy. Quiet.
Beautiful.
- She stayed here?
- Yes.
- Did she have her baby here?
And you arranged for the adoption?
That's right.
Who was she?
She was picked up
wandering the streets and brought to us.
She was from some little town
up in the mountains.
She said she'd been sent away
to live with relatives in the city.
But no relatives were ever found.
Her name was Evelyn.
She came to us eight months pregnant.
- And the father?
- There was none.
Half the mothers that come to us say that.
So, what did she think got her pregnant?
Evelyn wasn't well.
She had been having
problems during the pregnancy.
Hallucinations, visions.
She believed some
thing had come for her baby
from the waters of
the world beyond this one.
I'm sorry. Did you say water?
Well, we all envision
the afterlife differently.
For Evelyn, it's just what she believed.
As you might imagine,
she suffered severe postpartum depression.
She blamed her troubles on her child.
So she tried to kill it.
All babies are a challenge.
But Samara, she never cried.
Never.
Except when
her mother would try to bathe her.
Then she'd scream like
it was the end of the world.
It was the screaming that woke us.
Evelyn, don't!
Evelyn!
Evelyn, stop!
She was trying to drown the baby.
The baby was taken from her, of course.
Evelyn was institutionalized.
And all those pictures
she'd been collecting,
they finally made sense.
Did she say why she did it?
She felt she had to
kill her baby to save it.
I'm here to see a patient.
Her name's Evelyn.
- I don't know her last name.
- Evelyn?
That's right.
Evelyn's expecting you.
Every few years,
one of you comes to see Evelyn.
She's like a freakin'
patron saint or something.
Got a problem with your kid, don't you?
Something wrong?
That song. I know it.
Yeah. They all do.
Hey, Evelyn.
You were right as rain.
You got a visitor today.
Hope she's some help to your troubles.
10 minutes.
My name's Rachel.
But you know that.
Some days I sort of have a feeling.
A feeling?
This is about your child.
It's...
it's about yours.
Samara.
They don't dream, you know.
The dead don't dream.
Look, something's happened to my son.
- You have to sleep to dream.
- And it has to do with your daughter.
And the dead never sleep.
They wait
and watch for a way back.
But they never sleep.
That's why dreams are safe.
I'm sorry, I just,
I don't have a lot of time,
please, I need your help.
I have to know. Can you tell me?
Why did you try to kill your baby?
Why?
Because my baby told me to.
Just like yours will tell you.
And you have to do it.
You have to send it back.
What?
They stopped me.
- Don't let them stop you.
- What?
Listen to the voices.
What are you talking about?
Because it's our fault. We did it.
Yes. We did it, yes.
It was you. It was you, you did it!
What did I do?
Evelyn, that's enough.
I love my son.
Come on. It's all right.
I'm sorry, ma'am, that's enough for today.
Let's go.
What did I do?
You let the dead get in.
Let's go.
What should I do?
Be a good mother.
Listen to your baby.
Aidan?
Hey.
Shouldn't you, uh...
Shouldn't you be at the hospital?
No. I'm here waiting for my mommy.
Okay.
Well, you can't really leave
till the hospital says it's okay.
You were very, very sick.
You're all right now?
The cable setup at my house,
the TV needs to be on channel three.
She loves me. She loves me not.
- Thank you, Max.
- Sure.
She loves me!
Look, Mandy!
! think I'm gonna puke.
Why don't you do something
productive with your life?
Say, Billy, if you like fish so much...
Your mom loves you, you know.
She loves you a lot.
You'd tell someone if
you weren't sure about that, right?
Like, if she'd been hurting you somehow.
Did she ever treat you
like you're someone else?
- I'm not somebody else.
- No, I know, I know.
I'm Aidan.
- Hey, I know.
- We don't need anyone else.
That's right.
We don't need you,
that doctor or anyone else.
Okay?
Okay.
What are you doing?
I was just gonna take a picture of you.
No.
- It'll be for your mom.
- No.
Why not? Why not? What's wrong
with taking your picture?
I'll tell you what's wrong
if you promise not to take it.
But that's only if you promise.
Fine. I promise.
So, Aidan, what's the story?
We're happy when we're sad
; We're always feeling sad
Hello?
How are you? Terrible &
That's why we're happy when we're sad
Max?
Are you here?
- You're home!
- Oh, God.
What are you doing here?
I thought you were at the hospital.
No. I'm here, Mommy.
What did you say?
I said I'm here.
Is Max here?
No.
But his coat.
He went away.
You wanna watch some TV with me?
Uh.
I, uh, I just have to get
something from the car. Okay?
I love you, Mommy.
Max.
Max?
Goldfish must have
water in order to exist.
But goldfish hate cats.
While on the other hand, cats hate water.
Rachel.
Are you sleeping, Rachel?
I am. She makes me sleep all the time now.
Aidan.
Shh. Just keep sleeping, Rachel.
So she can't hear us. It's the only way.
You know you have to show her, Rachel.
Show her she can't stay.
In you.
How? How do I do that?
Take me to where she's afraid of.
You know where she's afraid of.
Take me there
and kill me.
- Aidan, no.
- Shh. Rachel, keep sleeping.
She won't stay if
she knows you'll kill me.
- It's the only way.
- I can't do it. I can't.
Then she stays.
She's heard us.
Honey?
I thought you were sleeping, Mommy.
I was, but I had a bad dream.
You must've had a nightmare.
It's all right. We all have them.
Will you stay with me now?
Stay?
Stay for always.
Yeah. Yeah.
Alrighty. Let's watch some TV together.
Oh.
It's kind of late, honey.
Don't you think you should sleep?
I never sleep.
Then let Mommy make you something.
Something wrong? You seem sad.
No, honey, I'm not sad.
I'm just tired, that's all.
Well, now you have me to protect you.
You ain't the biggest catfish
in the deep blue sea
Take me to where she's afraid of.
You know where she's afraid of.
You have to show her, Rachel.
Show her she can't stay.
Listen to the voices.
You have to listen to the voices.
Be a good mother. Be a good mother.
Listen to your baby.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
But you can't stay.
What are you doing? Rachel!
What are you doing?
It's me.
- It's not her, Rachel.
- I know, baby.
- It's me.
- Shh.
I love you. Mommy, I love you.
I know, baby.
I love you too.
But you're not my son.
Mommy.
Aidan.
Aidan. Aidan, Aidan.
Honey.
Breathe. Baby, breathe.
Please. I know it's you, honey.
Aidan.
Aidan, please.
Rachel.
Yeah.
I'm right here.
You're okay.
Everything's all right, honey.
You were sleeping.
You were just sleeping.
No.
She wants me again.
Rachel, what are you doing?
All she wants is a mother.
That's all she wants.
And she'll keep coming till she finds one.
Come on! Come back!
Get away from her! Rachel!
Get away from her!
You can't have my son.
So take me.
Rachel! No!
Rachel! Rachel!
Samara!
Here I am, Samara.
Just like you wanted.
But you leave him alone!
You hear me?
It's always open.
Her only way out is always open.
Mommy.
Mommy!
- Mommy!
- I'm not your fucking mommy.
Rachel.
Rachel!
- Can you hear me?
- I can hear you.
I'm right here.
Rachel.
Rachel!
You're here.
- You're here, Rachel.
- Of course I'm here.
I followed your voice.
What happened?
It's over, honey.
She's not coming back.
How do you know, Rachel?
I know.
I promise.
I love you, Mommy.
Promise me something?
Yeah, anything, Mom. Anything.
Just call me Rachel.
At least for a while.