Ha! Ha!
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Come, come!
Please! Please! Please!
Aziz. Aziz.
Aziz, light!
Aziz, light.
Good.
We start again.
"When the three planets are in eclipse,
the black hole, like a door, is opened.
Evil comes...
...spreading terror and chaos."
See the snake, Billy?
The ultimate evil.
-Make sure you get the snake.
-Yes, I've got your snakes.
I got all the snakes.
So when is this snake
act supposed to occur?
Huh? Well, if
this is the five...
...and this is the one...
Every 5000 years.
So I've got some time, then.
Ah, you bring them water.
Good boy. I will
take it to them.
Go with God. Be safe from evil.
You see here these different
peoples, or symbols of people...
...gathering together the four elements
of life: water, fire, earth, air...
...around a fifth one.
A fifth...
...element.
Forgive me, lord.
They already know too much.
Ah, Father.
-Yes, how are you today?
-Well, Billy. You have some glasses?
-Of course.
-Father, I'm so glad to see you.
It's the most
extraordinary thing.
I mean, look, it's the
greatest find in history.
Yes. You must be parched.
Oh, yes, yes. I'm sorry.
It's like a battle plan.
Here, the good. Here, the evil.
And here, a weapon against evil.
I'm going to be famous.
Then... Then let us...
Let us toast to your fame.
Oh, yes. To fame.
Salute.
You can't drink a toast with
water. Billy, in my sack, the grappa.
Yes.
This I don't
understand. But this...
This could be something...
...prehistoric.
Maybe. I don't know.
But wait.
Here.
Look, look.
They're here.
This man...
...this perfect being.
I know this is
the key. I know it.
This divine light
they talk about.
What is divine light?
Aziz, light!
Much better. Thank you, Aziz.
My lord.
Father, this is the most
unbelievable thing I have ever seen.
Don't you think...?
Ah... Ah... Ah...
Are you German?
Lord, I know he was about
to discover everything.
But there is no worry.
I was there in time.
Priest, you and
those before you...
...have served us well.
But war is coming.
Stones not safe
on Earth anymore.
This...
...is really amazing.
The fifth element.
Take the stones.
My lord...
...if you take the weapon, we will
be defenseless when evil returns.
In 300 years,
when evil returns...
...so shall we.
Oh, professor.
Professor.
Don't move!
-I have a gun!
-Billy.
Please, understand.
They are our friends.
Friends?
Father, they've killed the
professor! They're monsters!
I'll explain everything. Billy.
-You're with them?
-Billy, look at me.
Look at me. I am your friend.
-No, Father.
-Billy, look at me!
Please, put the gun down.
No.
Billy, no!
Hurry! The wall is closing!
Here is your mission now:
Pass your knowledge to the next
priest as it was passed on to you.
I will do as you command, but
please, hurry, you still have time.
Time not important.
Only life important.
I will fulfill my mission!
You can count on me!
I will pass the knowledge
until your return.
-Anything yet?
-No, sir.
-Not even a temperature?
-The thermo-analyzers have jammed.
One of them shows a million
degrees, the others minus 5000.
Let's see it.
It's taking shape.
Send out a probe.
Ladies and gentlemen, the
president of the Federated Territories.
On air with General
Staedert in 30 seconds.
Oh, I saved this
seat for you, Father.
-President on the line, sir.
-We're in position, Mr. President.
I have to address the Supreme Council
in 10 minutes. Just the facts, general.
There are no results from the
chemical and molecular analysis as yet.
All the calibers are overshot.
We're initiating a
thermonucleatic imaging.
So, what you're saying is,
you don't know what this is.
Not yet, sir. All we know is,
it just keeps getting bigger.
Recommendation?
My philosophy, Mr. President, is
shoot first and ask questions later.
I don't like uninvited guests.
-All right, then, Staedert...
-Mr. President?
Yes?
Priest Vito Cornelius,
expert of astrophenomenon.
I have a different
theory to offer you, sir.
You have 20 seconds.
Imagine for a
moment that this...
...thing is not anything
that can be identified...
...because it prefers not to be.
Wherever there is
life, it brings death...
-...because it is evil. Absolute evil.
-One more reason to shoot first.
Evil begets evil, Mr. President.
Shooting will only
make it stronger.
Probe will obtain its
objective in five seconds.
Growth rate is at 27 percent.
Your theory is interesting, but we
don't have time to go into that now.
Time is of no importance,
Mr. President. Only life is important.
You're right. That's exactly
what we're gonna do.
We're gonna protect the life of
some 200 billion of my fellow citizens.
General, you may
fire when ready.
Up-front loading of a 120-ZR
missile. Marker lights on the objective.
Its structure has just
solidified on the surface.
I think it's anticipating the attack.
Anticipation denotes intelligence.
The most terrible intelligence
imaginable, Mr. President.
120's loaded.
The ship is in combat formation.
Missiles are loaded, Mr. President.
-Staedert.
-Yes, sir.
-I have a doubt.
-I don't, Mr. President.
Staedert?
What happened?
Staedert, can you hear me?
Staedert? What
happened, Staedert?
-Did you destroy it?
-I'm about to, sir.
The planet has increased
in diameter by 200 percent.
It's moving towards the ship.
What...? What do we
have that's bigger than 240?
Nothing, sir.
Staedert, do you hear
me? Get out of there.
I don't want an incident.
Do you hear me, Staedert?
Get out of there. Can
you hear me, Staedert?
Do you understand? Listen.
This is the president.
That's an order.
Do you understand
me? Do you hear me?
Get out of there! Answer me!
Good God!
Four a day.
I'm trying.
To quit is my goal.
Hey, hey, hey.
I'm up.
All right, I'm up.
God.
Yeah. Yeah. Yes?
Hey, dog brain, Finger here.
-Hi, sweetie.
-I love you too, major...
...but you haven't called
me that since basic training.
-I was talking to the cat.
-Oh, yeah, I forgot...
...you still prefer your
cat to the real thing.
At least the cat comes back.
You still pining for that two-timing
slut? There are a million women out there.
I don't want a million
women. I just want one.
The perfect one.
-It don't exist, major.
-Yeah, I know. Ugh.
-What?
-I just found a picture of you.
-Oh, how do I look?
-Like shit.
Must be an old picture.
Listen, you gotta bring me your
hack for a six-month overhaul.
Negative.
I don't need one.
Hey, you forgetting who sat next to you
for 1000 missions? I know how you drive.
Finger, I drive a cab
now, not a space fighter.
Okay, so tell me. How many
points you got left on your license?
Major, how many points?
At least 50.
Know what? You gotta
learn how to lie better.
See you tonight.
Welcome to paradise.
Welcome to Fhloston Paradise.
It's Ruby Rhod, your main
man, and I will tell you live at 5...
...the name of the winner of the
super-green Gemini Croquette Contest!
The winner will go with me for
two days to Fhloston Paradise.
So tune in to Radio Cosmos.
Don't watch it all day,
sweetie. It'll rot your brain.
For a perfect world.
-Give me the cash.
-Been here long?
Yeah, long enough.
Come on, give me the cash.
Is that a Z-140?
Alleviated titanium.
-Neurocharged assault model.
-Yeah. Yeah.
Good thing for
me it's not loaded.
-What do you mean, it's not loaded?
-Well, you have to...
You have to push that
little yellow button to load it.
Take your time.
Oh, God.
You want me to...?
Okay.
There you go.
Give me the cash!
That's a very dangerous gun.
You know, maybe you better let
me hang on to this one for you, huh?
-You don't mind, do you?
-No.
-You sure?
-No. Take it. I don't need it.
That's a very nice hat.
You like it?
God!
Please enter your license.
Yes, yes, just a minute.
Welcome on board, Mr. Dallas.
Good morning. Sleep
well? Yeah, me too.
-I had a horrible nightmare.
-Propulsion 2X4.
You have five points
left on your license.
Yeah, thank you
for reminding me.
Have a nice day.
Why not?
You have 48 hours.
That's the length of time it needs
to adapt itself to our living conditions.
-And then?
-And then it will be too late.
The goal of this thing is not
to fight over money or power...
...but to exterminate
life. All forms of life.
So what you're telling me, Father,
there's nothing that can stop this.
There is only one thing.
The Mondoshawan have
the only weapon to defeat evil.
Four elements...
...gathered around a fifth...
...supreme being, the ultimate
warrior, created to protect life.
Together they produce what the
ancients called the Light of Creation.
Able to bring life to the
farthest reaches of the universe.
But if evil stands there...
Then what?
Then light turns to
dark. Life to death...
...forever.
Sir, there's a Mondoshawan
spaceship at the frontier...
...requesting permission
to enter our territory.
Give it permission to enter our
territory with our warmest regards.
Thank you.
Permission to enter granted.
Showtime.
We are lost.
Aknot, we are
connected to Earth.
Mr. Zorg's office.
It's Aknot.
I'm so glad to hear you, Aknot.
The mission is accomplished.
You'll have what you
asked for in a few hours.
Good. I'll meet
you at my factory.
The attack was launched
by two unregistered warships.
Close all borders and
declare a state of general alert.
Yes, sir.
Try to make contact
with the Mondoshawans.
-We owe them an explanation.
-Sir.
Three hundred years
of waiting, for nothing.
Father, you should
go home now and rest.
No.
The Mondoshawan...
I am their contact on
Earth. They will come for me.
Father, this is government business
now. I will keep you informed.
The rescue team has reported
from the Mondoshawan crash site.
Any survivors?
Only one.
That what you call a survivor?
A few cells are still alive.
It's more than I need.
-Have you identified it?
-We tried...
...but the computer
went off the charts.
You see, normal human beings
have 40 DNA memo groups...
...which is more than enough for
any species to perpetuate itself.
This has 200,000 memo groups.
-Sounds like a freak of nature to me.
-Yeah, can't wait to meet him.
You okay, general? Over here.
Excuse me.
Okay, general, I want to
show you something here.
This is a normal human
DNA chain, okay?
You, me, anybody, right?
Watch this.
The compositional elements of
his DNA chain are the same as ours.
There's more of them, tightly
packed, with infinite genetic knowledge.
Almost like this
being was engineered.
-Is there any danger?
-No, no, no.
We put it through the
cellular hygiene detector.
The cell is, for lack
of a better word...
...perfect.
Okay, go ahead.
But Mr. Perfect
better be polite.
Otherwise, I turn
him into cat food.
Activate it.
Tissue processing.
Ten seconds to
ultraviolet protection.
This is the last phase.
The cells are bombarded
by greasy solar atoms...
...which forces the body
to react to protect itself.
That means growing skin.
Wonderful.
Reconstruction complete.
Remove the shield.
I told you. Perfect.
Thermal bandages.
I'd, um, like to take
a few pictures...
...for the archives.
-What's she saying?
-I don't know.
Activate the phonic detector.
Is, uh...? Is that thing solid?
-Unbreakable.
-Good.
If you want out...
...you're going to have to learn to
develop those communication skills.
General alert.
Perfect.
Ladder on 18.
Two men with me. The
rest in the main ventilation.
Okay, sir.
This way.
Okay, lady, stay calm.
This is the police.
There's nowhere else to go.
So you're gonna slowly turn around
and put your hands on the floor.
Do you understand me?
She doesn't.
I think we need
a flying unit here.
This is the police.
We are processing
your identification.
Please put your arms up
and follow our instructions.
She has no file.
She dove off.
You just had an accident.
Yes, I know I just had an
accident, you daffy bastard!
-You have one point left on your license.
-You have one point...
Look out!
No, no! Left!
I can't believe it. Shit.
Any survivors?
Hi.
Are you okay?
[SPEAKING IN DIVINE LANGUAGE]
Boom.
Boom. Yeah, I understand "boom."
Bada boom.
Big. Big bada boom.
Big...
Bada big boom.
-Big boom.
-Yeah.
-Yeah, big bada boom.
-Bada boom.
Big boom. Big bada boom.
You're lucky you're not dead.
This is a police control.
Please keep your
hands on the wheel.
You have an unauthorized
passenger in your vehicle.
We are going to arrest her.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Sorry, honey.
Looks like this is your ride.
Open the door.
-Akta.
-Better do what they say.
[SPEAKS IN DIVINE LANGUAGE]
Sorry.
"Please...
...help."
I've only got one point
left on my license...
...and I need that to get back to the
garage and get the cab a six-month overhaul.
You understand?
Can you please open
the passenger door?
Ple... Please...
...help.
I can't.
I repeat...
...can you please open
your passenger door?
Yeah, yeah, sure.
Why not?
Thank you for your cooperation.
Help.
Finger's gonna kill me.
Emergency! Emergency!
One point has been
removed from your license.
Yes, I know!
...on your license.
This is so stupid.
All units assist in pursuit
of yellow cab, Level 10.
Unit 47, we're on the way...
...as soon as we finish lunch.
Two golden menus.
-Thank you.
-I'm too old, too tired...
...and too hungry to go
chasing some hot rod.
Thank you so much.
And I'm definitely too thirsty.
Look out!
Whoa.
We got lucky.
If they don't chase you after
a mile, they don't chase you.
Maybe it's two miles.
Hang on.
[YELLING IN DIVINE LANGUAGE]
Look, lady, I only speak two
languages: English and bad English!
Run an ID.
Don't get me wrong, I'm for conversation,
but maybe you could shut up for a minute!
I get nothing. He's
got a scan blocker.
Means he's a car
thief. Blast him.
I don't know what you
did to piss these guys off...
...but they are really
pissed off! Hold on!
I think we're safe for a while.
You want to play it
soft? We'll play it soft.
hard? Let's play it hard.
[SPEAKING IN DIVINE LANGUAGE]
We make it to the
fog, we'll be all right.
If we make the fog.
How do they expect us
to find anything in this shit?
We're just gonna wait here for a little while
until things quiet down, if you don't mind.
Hey.
Shit.
You okay?
Priest.
You don't need a priest, you just
need a doctor. You'll be all right.
Vito Cornelius.
What?
Priest.
Yes?
I'm, uh, looking for a priest.
Weddings are one floor
down, my son. Congratulations.
She's not my
bride. She's my fare.
She's looking for a priest
named Vito Cornelius.
The phone book
said he lived here.
Yes, that's me, but I
don't know who she is.
Nobody knows who she
is. No file, no ID, nothing.
She's got a tattoo
on this arm here.
Tattoo?
Fifth...
...element.
Finger's gonna kill me.
-Hey! Wake up!
-Who are you?
I brought the girl,
remember? The redhead.
She just dropped in on me. Started
speaking this bizarre language.
It's not bizarre. It's
the divine language.
-The ancient language...
-Okay.
...spoken throughout the
universe before time was time. He...
He's a she.
You noticed that, huh?
Yes.
-It's a miracle.
-Miracle she's not dead.
We've not a moment
to lose. Wake her up.
But gently, because this woman is
mankind's most precious possession.
She is perfect.
Perfect.
More dignified.
Hey, lady...
...wake up.
You're right, I shouldn't have
done that. I shouldn't have done that.
It was wrong to kiss you.
He said to wake you gently.
You're right. You're right.
[SPEAKING IN DIVINE LANGUAGE]
Just thought you might
remember me from the cab.
Remember?
"Bada boom"?
-"Big bada boom"?
-Boom?
Boom. Big bada boom.
In the cab. Here, look.
I drive a cab. This is me.
Korben Dallas.
Korben. You understand?
Here. Take it, go ahead.
You can call me when you
learn how to speak English.
Oop. Ah.
Just kidding. Kidding.
And you... What is your name?
You.
Korben.
Leeloo Minai Lekarariba-Laminai-Tchai
Ekbat De Sebat.
Good. That's...
That whole thing's
your name, huh?
Do you have...
...a shorter name?
Not "yeah, yeah, yeah, ooh."
Short.
Korben Dallas.
Leeloo.
Korben, Leeloo.
Leeloo, Korben.
Father, are you sure
she's a supreme being?
Absolutely sure.
Old friends. Okay.
Yeah, you're right.
Listen, do you think you could ask
her if I could have the gun back, please?
-What's your name?
-Korben Dallas.
Thank you, Mr. Dallas, for all
your help. Thank you so much.
You've been so kind, but
now the girl needs rest...
...because she's
been on a long trip.
Yes, I know. I was
there when she landed.
Wait, wait, hey.
Wait, wait, Father.
She said something I didn't understand.
Well, I didn't understand any of it...
-...but what does "ekto gamat" mean?
-"Never without my permission."
That's what I thought.
I shouldn't have kissed her.
Oh, no. I'm so sorry.
I forgot your food.
How about some nice
Thai food to apologize, huh?
Yeah, yeah, hold on. What?
Hey, buddy, I'm
waiting all day here.
-Finger.
-Where is the cab?
Car's running fine.
Purring like a kitten.
"Fine." What "fine"?
I know you, Dallas. "Fine"
ain't in your vocabulary.
Come on, you can tell your old
buddy Finger what happened.
-What? You save the planet?
-Listen.
You dinged the fender again. Right?
You dinged the goddamn fender.
Finger, I was on my way over to
see you and a big fare fell in my lap.
You know, one of these really
big fares that you just can't resist.
Oh. How big?
Five-nine...
...blue eyes...
...long legs, great skin.
You know. Perfect.
Uh-huh. I see.
And this perfect
fare, she got a name?
Yeah.
Leeloo.
What's she doing?
Learning our history, the last
5000 years that she's missed.
Been asleep for quite
a while, you know.
Father, I know she's been through
a lot, but we don't have much time.
Yes, you're right.
Chicken. Good.
Chicken.
I'm really sorry
to interrupt you...
...but the case...
...with the stones...
...where is it?
[SPEAKING IN DIVINE LANGUAGE]
Stolen?
Who in God's name
would do such a thing?
Excuse me, sir. The council is
worried about the economy heating up.
They wondered if it'd be
possible to fire 500,000.
Maybe from one of the smaller
companies where no one would notice...
...like one of the
cab companies.
Fire one million.
But 500,000...
One million. Fine, sir.
Sorry to have disturbed you.
Oh, it's, uh...
-It's for the Supreme...
-Yes, yes, yes.
Oh, sorry.
I didn't know your size, and I
found you this makeup box, okay?
-You just put it like that.
-Thank you.
Yes, there was a
man with a limp...
...came here about a month ago
asking questions about the stones.
He said he was an art dealer.
[SPEAKING IN DIVINE LANGUAGE]
What was his name?
I'm so bad with names.
-They really make her...
-Perfect, I know.
[SPEAKING IN DIVINE LANGUAGE]
What did she say?
She says she knows
exactly where they are.
My dear Aknot, how about those
two little planes that you borrowed?
Aknot, is that you?
What an ugly face.
It doesn't suit you.
Take it off.
That's better.
Never be ashamed of who you are.
You're warriors. Be proud.
So what if the federal government
scattered your people to the wind.
What doesn't kill you
makes you stronger.
Your time for revenge
is at hand. Voilà.
The ZF-1.
It's light. Handle's adjustable for easy
carrying. Good for righties and lefties.
Breaks down into four
parts, undetectable by x-ray.
Ideal for quick,
discreet interventions.
A word on firepower:
Titanium recharger, 3000-round
clip with bursts of 3 to 300.
With the replay button, another
Zorg invention, it's even easier.
One shot...
...and replay sends every
following shot to the same location.
And to finish the job, all
the Zorg oldies but goldies.
Rocket launcher.
Arrow launcher with exploding
or poisonous gas heads.
Very practical. Our
famous net launcher.
The always-efficient
flamethrower.
My favorite.
And for the grand finale,
the all-new ice-cube system.
Four full crates
delivered right on time.
And what about you, my dear Aknot?
Did you bring me what I asked you for?
Yes.
Magnificent.
This...
This case is empty.
-What do you mean, empty?
-Empty...
...the opposite of full.
This case is
supposed to be full!
Anyone care to explain?
[SPEAKING IN DIVINE LANGUAGE]
The Guardians gave the stones
to someone they could trust.
Who took another route.
She's supposed to
contact this person...
...in a hotel.
And she's looking
for the address. Easy.
Dot.
It's Planet Fhloston, in
the Angel Constellation.
-We're saved.
-I'm screwed.
You asked for a case.
We brought you a case.
A case with four stones in it!
Not one or two
or three, but four!
Four stones!
What the hell am I supposed
to do with an empty case?
We are warriors, not merchants.
But you can still count! Look,
it's easy. Look at my fingers.
Four stones, four crates.
Zero stones, zero crates!
Pack everything
up! We're out of here!
We risked our lives.
I believe a little
compensation is in order.
Oh. So you are
merchants after all.
Leave him one
crate for the cause.
I don't like warriors. Too
narrow-minded, no subtlety...
...and worse, they fight
for hopeless causes, honor.
Honor's killed millions of
people. Hasn't saved a single one.
I'll tell you what I do
like, though: a killer.
A dyed-in-the-wool killer, cold-blooded,
clean, methodical and thorough.
Now, a real killer, when
he picked up the ZF-1...
...would've immediately asked about
the red button on the bottom of the gun.
Bring me the priest.
I got everything here we need to
know about Fhloston Paradise...
...and a detailed
blueprint of the entire hotel.
Good work, my son. Now all we've
got to do is find a way of getting there.
It's not gonna be easy. There's a
charity ball on Fhloston tomorrow.
Flights are full, and with the celebrities,
the hotel will be guarded like a fortress.
But there must be a
way of getting there.
No.
I'll get it.
Weddings?
Not really.
-Mr. Zorg would like to talk to you.
-Mister who?
Mr. Zorg.
Jean-Baptiste Emmanuel Zorg.
It's nice to see
you again, Father.
Ah, I remember you now.
The so-called art dealer.
I'm glad you got your memory
back, because you're gonna need it.
Where are the stones?
I don't know. And even if I did know,
I wouldn't tell somebody like you.
Why?
-What's wrong with me?
-I try to serve life.
But you only...
...seem to want to destroy it.
Ah, Father...
...you're so wrong.
Let me explain.
Life, which you
so nobly serve...
...comes from destruction,
disorder and chaos.
Now, take this empty glass.
Here it is, peaceful,
serene, boring.
But if it is...
...destroyed...
Look at all these little
things. So busy now.
Notice how each one is useful.
What a lovely ballet ensues,
so full of form and color.
Now, think about all those
people that created them.
Technicians, engineers.
Hundreds of people who will be
able to feed their children tonight...
...so those children can grow big and
strong and have children of their own...
...and so on and so forth.
Thus adding to
the great chain...
...of life.
Water. Fruit.
You see, Father, by
creating a little destruction...
A cherry.
...I'm, in fact,
encouraging life.
In reality, you and I are
in the same business.
Cheers.
Where's the robot to
pat you on the back?
Or the engineer?
Or their children, maybe?
You see now how all your so-called
power counts for absolutely nothing?
How your entire empire of
destruction comes crashing down...
...all because of
one, little cherry.
You saved my life...
...and in return,
I'll spare yours...
...for now.
You're a monster, Zorg.
I know.
Torture who you have to,
the president, I don't care.
Just bring me those stones.
You have one hour.
It's gobbling up all the
communications satellites in the galaxy.
Why in the hell is it
eating up all the satellites?
We're working on
it, Mr. President.
I've contacted the Mondoshawan.
They deplore the incident...
...but they accept
our apologies.
And the stones? Did you
find them in the wreckage?
-The stones weren't aboard the ship.
-What do you mean?
The Mondoshawan never
fully trusted the human race.
They gave the stones
to someone they do trust.
Her name is
Plavalaguna. She's a diva.
And she's going to sing at a charity
ball in Fhloston Paradise in a few hours.
She has the stones with her.
The Mondoshawans have
accepted an offer to help.
All we have to do is send someone to
get the stones and bring them back to her.
Excellent.
I want this operation to
be discreet as possible.
No troops. No big operation.
I want your best
man to go undercover.
I have the perfect one.
-You got a message.
-Yeah.
Not gonna open it?
Could be important.
Yeah. Like the last
two I got were important.
First one was from my
wife telling me she's leaving.
The second one was from my lawyer
telling me he was leaving with my wife.
That is bad luck.
But grandfather say:
"It never rain every day."
This is good news, guaranteed.
I bet your lunch.
Okay.
Come on.
You are fired.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Well...
At least I won lunch.
Good philosophy.
See good in bad. I like.
-Hello.
-Korben, sweetheart.
You got broken fingers?
You can't punch my number?
-Hi, Mom.
-Seventeen messages.
Don't tell me your machine is broken.
Those things are good for 1000 years.
Mr. Kim, you should go.
This is gonna take a minute.
You wouldn't even feed your pussycat,
who you obviously love more than me.
-But she didn't breast-feed you. I did.
-Goodbye, Mr. Dallas.
Ah, fortune for you.
...Up on me. Oh, Christ,
I'll never be a grandmother.
-It bring you good luck!
-Yeah, sure.
[MR. KIM SINGING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
You know my poor body's failing
me. You have to take me on this trip.
Ma, what are you talking about?
I get it. You want to make
your only mother beg. Is that it?
No, I don't want to make you beg. All
I want is an explanation. I just got in.
I just smashed my cab. I
lost my job. I got mugged.
Besides that, everything's
peachy. Thanks for asking.
Now, will you just settle down
and explain this to me calmly.
Oh, so you don't know you won a trip
to Fhloston Paradise for two for 10 days.
I suppose you're just gonna leave me
on the lunar surface to freeze my ass off.
If I'd have won a trip, I'd know about
it. Somebody would've notified me.
Korben, they've been blaring your
name out on the radio for the last hour.
Ma, I'll call you back.
General Munro, how nice
to see you in the 5000 block.
Nice apartment, major.
Looks like you settled into a
wonderful life. Heard you lost your job.
You heard that, huh?
Well, don't worry.
I'll get another job.
Don't bother. We
have one for you.
"Major Dallas, you've been selected
for a mission of the utmost importance."
-What mission?
-To save the world.
"You leave immediately
for Fhloston Paradise.
Retrieve four stones from the diva
Plavalaguna and bring them back."
-Any questions?
-Yeah, just one. Why me?
I retired six months
ago, you remember?
Three reasons.
One, as a member of the Elite Special
Forces Unit of the federated army...
...you are an expert in the use of weapons
and spacecraft needed for this mission.
Two, of all the members of your
unit, you're the most highly decorated.
-And the third one?
-Of all the members of your unit...
...you're the only
one left alive.
You check your messages?
No, I've had enough
good news for one day.
Might be important.
You're a winner!
You've won the annual Gemini Contest
and a trip to Fhloston Paradise for two.
Here are your tickets.
-You rigged the contest?
-Uh-huh.
Congratulations.
You couldn't think of anything
a little more discreet, huh?
Old tricks are the
best tricks, eh?
Major Iceborg will
accompany you as your wife.
I am not going.
Why not?
Excuse me, general.
Who is it? Who is it?
-My wife.
-You remarried?
Yes. No. I just met this
girl, but I'm gonna marry her.
I love her, but she
hates the military.
She knows that the military
ruined my last marriage.
She can't have anything to do
with it. If she sees you, she'll kill me.
-Major...
-Look, you gotta hide somewhere.
You gotta help me.
Just hide somewhere.
There's only one door,
where can we hide?
-Major, we don't have time for this.
-It's just for one minute.
You have no idea how
much you're helping me.
No idea... You have no idea.
-I'm going to be happily married.
-Major! Major! Major!
-What?
-The three of us won't fit in there.
Sure you will.
Major!
You're on my foot.
Major! Major!
[SPEAKS IN DIVINE LANGUAGE]
Hi.
I'm really sorry to have to resort
to these methods, Mr. Wallace...
-Dallas.
We heard about your luck on the radio,
and we need your tickets for Fhloston.
Is this the way priests
usually take vacations?
We're not going on
vacation. We're on a mission.
What kind of mission?
We have to save
the world, my son.
-You're gonna save the world?
-Yes!
Down there. Down there.
This is a police control.
This is not an exercise.
Come on, get in.
One minute, all right?
Just stay here for
one minute, I promise.
-This is a police control.
-Don't touch anything.
This is not an exercise.
Can you please
spread your legs...
...and place your hands
in the yellow circles?
-What are you doing?
-I'm gonna save your ass...
...so you can save the world.
Yeah, but I...
I think this is the door. There's
no name and no number.
Let's see it.
Sir, are you
classified as human?
Negative. I am a meat Popsicle.
I found him.
Mr. Korben Dallas?
Sir, can you put your hands
in the yellow circles, please?
Smoke you!
Wrong answer.
The police control
is now terminated.
Thank you for your
cooperation. Have a nice day.
Okay, we got the guy. Wasn't
easy, but we bagged him.
-Thanks for the tip.
-Glad to be of help, my friend.
The guy's just been arrested
for uranium smuggling.
Everything's going as planned.
All I have to do now is go to
the airport, take his place...
...and I'll be in Fhloston
in less than four hours.
Don't come back
without the stones.
Korben Dallas. We got him.
Perfect.
Akanit, take command.
Go to Fhloston
and get the stones.
If Zorg really wants them...
...he'll have to negotiate.
Revenge is at hand.
Oh, I'm so sorry. I forgot
about the autowash.
There's an autowash
in that shower.
I'm so sorry.
Autowash.
Autowash, yes.
Autowash, in the shower.
You know, it's funny.
I've met you twice today.
Both times, you've
ended up in my arms.
It's my lucky day.
Lucky day.
Yeah.
Did you hear something?
Cornelius.
Autowash.
-I'm so sorry. Sorry.
-I don't need your help.
-Want a cup of coffee?
-Yes, please.
Autowash.
Coffee's not
really my specialty.
But you must drink a lot of
coffee, being a priest, huh?
No, I know. I'm not proud
of what I did. I had no choice.
I'll take the mission.
[WOMAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ON LOUDSPEAKER]
-Did you get them?
-Yeah, I got them.
Good.
-"Leeloo Dallas."
-"Multi-pass."
"Korben David Dallas." Perfect.
[SPEAKING IN DIVINE LANGUAGE]
No, no. I can't possibly be
your husband. I'm too old.
Now, David is...
...in great shape.
He'll protect you.
Now, please, go to the diva, collect
the stones and meet me at the temple.
Now. Yes.
Okay.
Final call for
Fhloston Paradise.
Last call for Fhloston
Paradise. Hurry up.
Uh...
The tickets.
-ID, please.
-I'm sorry.
-There.
-In here?
Thank you!
Mr. Dallas?
Uh... Yeah.
Congratulations on
winning the contest.
Oh, right. Okay.
-Sorry for the mess.
-The mess?
The garbage.
Oh, right... It's K...
[SPEAKING IN DIVINE LANGUAGE]
Whoo! Made it!
I was so afraid I wasn't
gonna make this flight...
...so I sent David here to come
and pick up my boarding pass.
-But, um...
-But now David has to go.
Thank you. Bye.
I am Korben Dallas.
Please report infractions
to the spaceport.
And this is?
Leeloo Dallas. Multi-pass.
-Yeah. Lee... Multi-pass.
-Multi-pass.
She knows it's a
multi-pass. Leeloo Dallas.
My wife. We're newlyweds.
Just met. You know how it is.
Bump into each other, sparks happen...
Yeah, she knows it's a multi-pass.
Yeah. Anyway, we're in love.
I mean, I know she's
made to be strong.
She's also so fragile, so
human. You know what I mean?
-Do you want some more?
-Yeah.
Make that two.
Oh, David. David?
-Where's Leeloo?
-She's on the plane with Mr. Dallas.
-What?!
-I'm sorry, Father.
I didn't know what to do. I
thought he was gonna kill me.
But this is not possible.
This is not possible.
You want some more?
This is all my fault.
I am the servant. It is my mission.
I shouldn't have given it to you.
I know.
-Here's the key to the temple.
-Oh, no.
Prepare for our arrival. I
go to face my destiny. Yes.
I don't want to go to Egypt.
Thank you!
Dallas? Korben Dallas?
Yeah, that's me.
Just a minute, please.
It will take just
one more minute.
We'll be right back.
Oh, Mr. Dallas. Oh, um,
we really need you right now.
Ruby Rhod is broadcasting live
and he needs you for an interview.
Miss?
Multi-pass.
Tell Aknot that plan A
flopped. Go to plan B.
Aliens ahead. Spread out.
Backup unit, zone 18.
Mr. Ruby Rhod is the
biggest radio star, you know.
It's a great honor to
be on his talk show.
-He's so green.
-Yes, I'm sure you're very excited.
But I'm on my vacation and
I don't want to be bothered.
I prefer to remain anonymous.
Korben Dallas!
Here he is! The one and only winner
of the Gemini Croquette Contest.
This boy is fueled like fire,
so start melting, ladies...
...because the boy is hotter
than hot. He's hot, hot, hot!
The right size, the right
build, the right hair, the right on.
Right on.
Right on, right on.
And he's got something to say...
...to those 50 billion
pairs of ears out there.
Pop it, D-man.
Um, hi.
Unbelievable.
Quiver, ladies, quiver. He's
gonna set the world on fire.
Right here from 5 to 7.
You'll know everything there
is to know about the D-man.
His dreams...
...his desires...
...his most intimates
of intimates.
And from what I'm looking at, intimate
is this studmuffin's middle name.
So tell me, my man...
...you nervous in the service?
Not really.
Freeze those knees because Korben's
in the place and he's on the case.
Yesterday's frog will
be tomorrow's prince...
...of Fhloston Paradise!
The hotel of a thousand and one
follies, lollies and lick-them-lollies.
A magic fountain flow of
non-stop wine, women...
...and hootchie-kootchie-koo...
...all night long.
♪ All night long All night ♪
Ooh.
Start licking your
stamps, little girlies...
...because this guy's gonna
have you writing home to Mama.
Right, here, from 5 to 7, I'll
be your voice, your tongue...
...and I'll be hot on the trail
of the sexiest man of the year:
D-man, your man...
...my man.
End of transmission.
Okay, Ruby. See
you tomorrow at 5.
How was it?
-Oh! Wow.
-Oh!
It was just absolutely green.
Green like what?
Crystal green.
Any kind of green you want...
...tree green,
emerald, pond green.
Korben, sweetheart, what was
that? It was bad! It had nothing!
No fire! No energy! No nothing! You
know I have a show to run here. You know?
And it must pop, pop, pop!
So tomorrow, from 5 to 7...
...will you please act like you have
more than a two-word vocabulary.
It must be green! Okay? Okay?
Can I talk to you for a
second? Can I just talk to you?
I didn't come here to
play Pumba on the radio.
So tomorrow, from 5 to 7,
you're gonna give yourself a hand.
-Green?
-Super-green.
Dallas? Korben Dallas?
That's me.
I only have one Korben Dallas on my
list, and he's already checked in, okay?
That's impossible.
I am Korben Dallas.
Sorry, sir.
Boarding is finished.
Wait, wait, wait!
Hey, hey, hey! I need
to talk to someone!
I don't believe this!
This is a police control.
-Okay, I'm sorry. I'm calm.
-Put your hands in the yellow circles.
There's been a mistake.
To make your flight
as short as possible...
...our flight attendants are
switching on the sleep regulator...
...which will regulate your
sleeping during the flight.
Thank you.
Hi.
-Oh, you speak English now.
-Yes. I learn.
Good.
Leeloo, we are not on vacation.
I'm on a very important mission. I
work for some very important people.
If I hadn't come to get you, you would
be in big trouble. Do you understand that?
-Do you understand? Big trouble?
-Yes.
But you, no trouble.
Me, fifth element.
Supreme being.
Me protect you.
Sleep.
-Sweet dreams, Mr. Dallas.
-No, wait...
Sleep regulator operative
in zone one, captain.
Thank you. Zone
two, are you operative?
Zone two?
Yeah, everything's
ready, captain.
-Mr. Rhod.
-What?
You're gonna have to
assume your individual position.
I don't want one position,
I want all positions!
Mr. Rhod!
-Parasites in landing gear.
-Ground, you copy?
Got it. Front gear.
Hey, man, give
me some heat, man!
We need some heat here,
man! Give me some heat!
Some heat over here, man!
Good shit, man. Put
the heat over here, man!
Thank you! Thank you very much!
Come, come, come, come.
Give me this. Give me this.
Take that.
Mr. Rhod!
You can call me Ruby.
Fueled and ready to go.
-Yep.
-I'll buy you one, man.
Have you taken off already?
-I'm not on the plane.
-What?
The real Dallas took my
place. I don't understand.
Are you making fun of me?
No, no, no! I swear! I swear!
I never felt this way
before with a human.
-Really?
-Yeah!
I've tried everything, sir. There's
no other way of getting on this plane.
-Ground is clear.
-Roger. Ready for lift-off?
Confirmed.
Not there. No, please,
not there. Please, not there.
-Power pressure?
-Primed.
-Protection?
-Confirmed.
Power increase.
Ten seconds.
I am...
...a little...
-...disappointed.
-Five.
And if there is one
thing I do not like...
-Three...
-...it is to be...
...two...
-...disappointed.
-...one...
Sorry, sir. This will
never happen again.
-I know.
-...lift-off.
-Landing gear secure.
-Roger. Checklist for light speed.
Sir, we're finally
getting something.
It's sending radio wavelengths.
-What does it want with radio waves?
-Maybe it wants to make a call.
Zorg's office.
I told you I did not
want to be disturbed.
I know you don't want to be
disturbed except if it's Mr. Shadow...
...and it's Mr. Shadow
on the line.
It's Shadow again.
Zorg here.
-Am I disturbing you?
-No, no, no, I was just...
Where are you?
Not far now.
Good.
Good, good.
How are the stones?
Fine. Fine. Just
fine. I'll have the...
I'll have the four stones that
you asked for any time now...
...but it wasn't easy.
My costs have tripled.
Money is of no importance.
I want the stones.
The stones...
...will be here.
I'll see to it personally.
I will be among you...
...soon.
-We lost it.
-We lost the signal.
Damn!
We've begun our descent.
The local time is 3:20 p.m.
Auto-temperature is currently
85 degrees Fahrenheit.
We do hope you've enjoyed your
flight and hope to see you again soon.
Welcome to paradise.
[SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Excuse me, dear. Excuse me.
Thank you. Excuse me, please.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Wow.
Parasites in main ventilation.
Again? Don't worry, I'll get it.
Aah!
-Have we arrived yet?
-Yeah.
Oh, good.
We have 12 swimming
pools and two on the rooftop.
All the restaurants are
between Level 2 and Level 10.
The planet Fhloston has 400
beaches, all accessible until 5 p.m.
Then the airship goes higher to
offer you a better view with your dinner.
-Is the diva here yet?
-Not yet.
Are there any tickets left for
this opera? I'm a really big fan.
You have a seat
reserved, front row...
...next to Ruby Rhod!
He's so talented, don't you
think? I just love him. He's so sexy.
Anyway, he has your ticket for the
show, and he'll be here in 20 minutes.
Do you know where I
can get something to wear?
-Enjoy your evening, Mr. Dallas.
-Thank you.
Hello?
I never should've
pushed you out.
-Ma?
-I was in labor for days...
...and this is how you repay me?
-I should've just gotten a robot.
-Come on, Ma.
Don't "come on, Ma" me.
I should be there, not you.
-I need a tan. I need a cocktail.
-Ma...
Get the case in.
Hello, Ms. Diva. I'm Fog.
Welcome to the...
I am, uh, security.
Welcome to the... Tall...
-Can I talk to you for a minute?
-Sure. Yeah.
-What's your name?
-Fog.
Ms. Plavalaguna wants you to
know how glad she is that you're here.
She'll give you what you've
come to get after the concert.
Stay here.
You're listening to Radio
Cosmos and it is now 5 p.m.
-Helm to 108.
-Yes, sir.
Helm 108!
Helm to 108.
Time to join Ruby Rhod
and Korben Dallas...
...the lucky winner of the
Gemini Croquette Contest.
Coming at you
live from Fhloston...
...Paradise!
Ruby Rhod at your service for two
hours with Korben and the hotel manager...
...and Miss Gemini
Croquette in person...
...and 8000 other
lucksters here...
...to enjoy the privilege of the
unique concert of Miss Plavalaguna!
Bzzz!
And now we enter what must be...
...the most beautiful concert
hall in all the universe!
A perfect replica of
the old opera house...
...but who cares?
To my right, a row of ministers,
more sinisters than ministers.
To my left, Baby Ray,
star of stage and screen.
He's not gonna get much out of
this concert, because he's stone-deaf!
To who?
And here we have Roy
Von Baker, king of laser ball.
And here, the Emperor of Kodar
Japhet and his lovely daughter.
"I love to sing," she
recently confessed to me.
By the way, I have a
recording of her talented voice.
I'll play you the rest of the song
after the concert, because right now...
...it's time for Korben to
say the word of the day.
So tell me, my man, you
happy here in the big world?
Thrilled.
And now champagne!
Commercial! Commercial!
Break for 30 seconds.
Bzzz!
Showtime.
[SINGING INVA MULLA TCHAKO'S
ARIA OF "LUCIA DI LAMMERMOOR"]
Commander, I have a ship in trouble
requesting permission to dock for repairs.
Put him in the docking garage.
-Inform security.
-Sir.
Permission granted for one hour.
More than I need.
Yes?
Champagne for the diva.
I'll take it.
I found it.
Get her!
[SINGING INVA MULLA
TCHAKO'S "THE DIVA DANCE"]
Huh?
It was an ambush.
If it's war they want,
it's war they'll get!
Bravo! Bravo!
My compliments, little lady.
Thank you for doing all the dirty work. I
couldn't have done a better job myself.
Hand over the stones.
Nobody move! We're
taking over the ship!
Hands up!
Ruby! Ruby!
I know this music.
Let's change the beat.
Something's happening here.
I think we're being attacked.
I don't know who they are,
but they're everywhere. Wait.
I see one of them. They're
warriors, and they're ugly.
They got big teeth and they got big
foreheads and big ears, and they stink.
Mangalores.
The government sent me
to help you. Just stay calm.
If somebody hears this, come
and get me. I'm in the first row.
-You must give her the stones.
-Who?
The fifth element.
The supreme being sent to
Earth to save the universe.
-Leeloo?
-Yes.
But she's more
fragile than she seems.
She needs your help...
...and your love...
...or she will die.
-No, no, no. Stay with me.
-Help!
If you want something
done, do it yourself.
Come on, honey. You can't die.
Come on. Listen to me. Wake up!
-Where are the stones?
-What?
The stones. Where
are the stones?
The stones.
They're not here.
The stones, where are they?
In me.
What? What?
Oh, my God, Korben.
Korben, another one coming.
Korben. Korben, I
think we should go.
One minute. Just
give me a minute.
Hey, you!
I said, you.
-I'm not with him.
-Where's the other?
I said, one minute.
Ruby, hold this gun.
-What? What do you want me to do?
-Hold this gun.
-Come on. Put your hand on it.
-Oh, my God.
-Got it? Hold it.
-What do I do?
If he moves,
squeeze the trigger.
I don't feel right. I
don't feel right, Korben.
The stones are "in me."
Korben, I got a
headache. This ain't me.
Ruby...
Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
Think he's gonna be okay?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God,
Korben. Another one coming.
Aw, shit. Three
coming, Korben. Three.
Listen, you guard
this with your life...
...or you're gonna look like
this guy right here. You green?
-Green.
-Super-green?
-Super-green.
-Is that your idea...
...of a discreet operation?
Don't worry, sir. I know my
man. He'll calm things down.
All right.
Move! Move!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Ladies and gentlemen. Ladies
and gentlemen, this is amazing.
-Let me do it.
-Right.
Oh, my God. Korben Dallas, Korben,
my man. Korben Dallas is in trouble.
Hey. Ray!
The gun!
Give me the gun.
The gun. The gun!
I'm gonna go and try to see if I
can see something a little closer.
Yes, the gun. Yeah.
Thanks, Ray.
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Don't shoot! I'm not armed!
Get up!
You've got the wrong
guy! Don't shoot!
I'm not armed! I'm not armed!
Oh, my God.
I'm on vacation.
It's... Don't shoot me, please.
I'm on a vacation. I won a...
...contest.
Gemini Croquette's
to Fhloston Paradise.
Down.
-Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
-Get down!
I think he's trying to
say something to me.
Get down!
Sorry. Sorry, my man.
Korben. Korben?
Where are you, man?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Korben.
They're coming.
Korben, they're coming.
Korben!
-Don't move.
-What?
-What you doing?
-Count to 10.
-Korben? Was that a bomb?
-Just shut up and count!
One, two, three, four, five...
...six, seven, eight...
...nine...
Ten.
I am very disappointed!
Korben, my man. Korben,
what are you looking for?
Control room.
-This is it.
-I'll be over here, all right?
Let's go! Let's go!
Quiet! Quiet!
-You in charge?
-Yeah.
How many of them are out there?
-I don't know.
-Let's count.
Seven on the left.
Five on the right.
Four on the right.
Two on the left.
We need to find the leader.
Mangalores won't fight without the leader.
One more shot and
we start killing hostages.
-That's the leader.
-Send someone to negotiate.
I've never negotiated.
You mind if I try?
No, no. Sure, sure. Sure.
We're sending
somebody in to negotiate!
Anybody else wanna negotiate?
Where did he learn
to negotiate like that?
I wonder.
Where's Ruby?
I thought he was dead.
Master!
It was nothing, really. It
was just a helping hand.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is Ruby Rhod...
...still alive. Aah!
What's wrong with you? It hurt!
Wow. Zoom.
Korben, I realize that you
must be pretty mad at me...
...but I want you to know that I
am fighting for a noble cause.
Yes, you're trying to save
the world. I remember.
Right now, I'm trying
to save Leeloo, Father.
-Leeloo's in trouble?
-When is Leeloo not in trouble?
-There. Where is that?
-That's the diva's suite.
Leeloo.
Leeloo. Hang on.
Here, come on. How the hell do
you get yourself into these positions?
Come on.
Yeah, I'm here. It's all right. It's
all right. Everything's okay now.
Listen.
I got the stones. All right,
just take it easy, all right?
My man, my man, my man. What's
this thing with all these numbers?
It's... It's...
No, no, no.
Because if it was a bomb...
...the alarms would go off because all
these hotels have bomb detectors. Right?
This is a Type A alert.
For security reasons, the
hotel must be evacuated.
Please proceed
calmly to the lifeboats...
Stay calm!
...located in the main hallways.
Please, stay calm!
Korben. Korben, my man,
you know how to stop this, right?
Korben?
Two minutes to
complete evacuation.
-Get back!
-Evacuation! Evacuation!
Sorry, sir, you can't stay here.
There's a bomb in the hotel.
I know.
-I don't want to die.
-Please, my son.
Get in. Get in.
One minute to total evacuation.
This one.
Forty-five seconds.
Get her strapped in.
Korben, Korben. Korben, my
man, you know how to fly this thing?
Just like driving a cab.
But the door? How we
gonna get out the door?
Fifteen seconds.
Ten, nine, eight...
...seven, six, five...
For the honor.
Oh, no.
You should hold on.
Come on.
Like driving a cab.
Ladies and gentlemen, it is
now 7 p.m. Time for the news.
See you tomorrow
for a new adventure.
End of transmission.
That's the best show I ever did.
Mr. President, Major Dallas
has the five elements on board...
...and the priest is guiding
them directly to the temple.
We're saved.
The diva said that I
should take care of you.
Humans act so strange.
What do you mean?
Everything you created...
...is used to destroy.
Yeah.
We call it human nature. You
learn about that on your screen?
I'm not finished
yet. I'm up to V.
V is good.
Some very good words in V.
Like what?
Valiant.
Vulnerable.
Very beautiful.
Oh, of course, Munro!
-Mr. President?
-Yes, now what?
We have a problem.
What do you mean,
it's advancing?
It's moving at incredible speed.
We're having trouble following it.
And do you have any
idea where it's heading?
Korben, there's a
general on the phone.
I'll give you to the president.
Major Dallas, I first would
like to salute a warrior.
You're a shining example
of this army's might.
-Mr. President.
-In the name of the Federation...
-...and its territories...
-Any idea when you're gonna be...
...getting to the point?
Okay. There's a ball of fire 1200 miles
in diameter heading straight for Earth...
...and we have no idea how
to stop it. That's the problem.
How much time do we have?
If its speed remains constant,
in an hour and 57 minutes.
I'll call you back in two hours.
Hello? Hello? Hello?
They just landed in the desert.
Good job, David.
-Put her in the center.
-Where? Here?
You got it figured out, Father?
This one should be fire.
-You know how all this works?
-Theoretically, yes.
-Theoretically?
-The four stones should go around.
The fifth element
should be in the middle...
...and then the weapon
against evil should work.
You've never seen this
work before, have you?
No.
Every weapon has a manual.
I'm sure this has one too.
That's it. That's it. Match
up the symbols. Go! Go!
Wind.
My man, what you doing?
-What?
-What you doing?
Trying to keep you
in the DJ business.
Fire.
Done.
-So, what happens now?
-So now, we have to open them.
-And you know how to do that, right?
-Theoretically...
-...no.
-No.
Leeloo, wake up, honey,
wake up. You have to help us.
Leeloo. How do you
open these stones?
Wind blows.
Fire burns.
Yes, I know all that. But how
do you open these stones?
Rain...
...falls.
Leeloo. Leeloo.
What does it mean?
I think that...
-Maybe it's a charade.
-What?
A game or something.
If we don't get these stones
open in five minutes, we're all dead.
-Dead?
-Yes, dead.
Too late.
-We've lost contact with them.
-Three minutes.
I think mine is broken. Why
I gotta get the broke one?
We're never gonna make it.
Korben. Korben, it moved!
What'd you do?
Show me what you did.
-Nothing.
-Shut up, shut up!
Calm down. Show me what you
did. Take me through it, step by step.
-I was just standing here like this.
-Quickly.
Okay, and I put my hands
on the top like this, and I said:
"We're not gonna make it."
That's it?
Korben, my man.
Wind.
She said, "Wind... Wind blows."
Everyone take a stone.
Water for water. Fire for
fire. Earth for earth. Go, now!
Earth.
-Open the other one.
-Okay.
K... Korben.
Korben, my man, I have no fire.
I have no matches. Do
you have any matches?
I stopped smoking. If I knew...
I mean... Father, you smoke?
Got some matches?
Matches? We need some fire.
We all gonna die.
Don't breathe.
Fire.
One minute.
Let's go. Let's go. Leeloo.
Wake up. Wake up. It's
time for you to work now.
Protect life...
...until death.
No, no, Leeloo! Listen to
me! Listen to me. Listen.
Listen, I know you're very
tired. I know you're very tired.
I'll take you on a vacation when
we're done. I swear, just you and me.
But if you don't do something right
now, we're all gonna die. You understand?
What's the use of saving life
when you see what you do with it?
It'll be entering the
atmosphere in 40 seconds.
Leeloo, you're right.
But there are some things...
...very nice things worth
saving, some beautiful things.
Beautiful things.
Like love?
Yes, love. That's
good. That's good.
That's a good example. Like
love. Love is worth saving.
I don't know love.
I was built to
protect, not to love.
So there's no use
for me other than this.
No, no, no, you're wrong.
You're wrong. You're wrong.
I need you. I need
you, very much.
Why?
Because...
Tell her, Korben.
Tell me. Please.
Why do you need me?
-Because...
-Tell me.
-Because I...
Because I love you.
I love you.
Ten, nine, eight, seven...
...six, five, four, three...
...two, one.
Scanner imaging has
confirmed the dark planet: dead.
The planet seems to have
stopped at 62 miles from impact.
Yes!
What's wrong with you?
What you screaming for?
Every five minutes, it's
something. A bomb or something.
I'm leaving. Bzz!
Mr. President.
Let me introduce you to Professor
Mactilburgh who runs the center.
It's an honor to receive
you, Mr. President.
Yes, well... Where
are my two heroes?
Oh, they were so tired from their ordeal,
we put them in the reactor this morning.
I have 19 more
meetings after this one.
Yeah. I'm sorry. Let
me see if they're revived.
Thank you.
We go live in one
minute, Mr. President.
Mm-hm.
Ah...
They're...
...not ready.
They need...
-...five more minutes.
-You have 20 seconds.
No, ma'am. No, no,
I tried. No, ma'am.
Who's that?
Some woman. Claims
to be Korben's mother.
Well, give it here.
Mrs. Dallas, this is the president.
On behalf of the Federation...
Please, that doesn't
even sound like him.
The president's an idiot.
You don't sound like an idiot.
If you don't want to talk to your
mother, just avoid me like usual.
I'll just throw myself in traffic. I'll
just Saran Wrap myself to the bed...
[R.X.R.A.'S "THE LITTLE
LIGHT OF LOVE" PLAYING]
♪ Rely on your light
♪ On your inner loving power
♪ A little light
as sole religion
♪ We will lead a light of love
♪ A little light of
love and freedom
♪ A little light
as sole religion
♪ We will lead a light of love
♪ A little light will
solve our freedom
♪ Just a little light of love
♪ A little light
as sole religion
♪ Take this little light of love
♪ A little light of
love and freedom
♪ Take me
♪ A little light
as sole religion
♪ A little light of
love and freedom
♪ A little light
as sole religion
♪ A little light of
love and freedom
♪ A little light
as sole religion
♪ A little light of
love and freedom
♪ A little light
as sole religion
♪ A little light of
love and freedom
♪ A little light
as sole religion
♪ A little light of
love and freedom
♪ A little light
as sole religion
♪ A little light of
love and freedom
♪ A little light
as sole religion
♪ A little light of
love and freedom
♪ A little light
as sole religion
♪ A little light, a little light
♪ A little light of
love and freedom
♪ A little light
as sole religion
♪ A little light of
love and freedom
♪ A little light
as sole religion
♪ A little light of
love and freedom
♪ A little light
as sole religion
♪ A little light of
love and freedom
♪ A little light
as sole religion
♪ A little light of
love and freedom