Excuse me?
Come on, honey.
Let's get you ready for bed.
I am no one special.
Just a common man with common thoughts.
I've led a common life.
There are no monuments dedicated to me,
and my name will soon be forgotten.
But in one respect,
I've succeeded as gloriously as
anyone who ever lived.
-Looking good, Duke.
-Feeling good.
I've loved another
with all my heart and soul...
...and for me that has always
been enough.
How's it hanging, Harry?
I keep trying to die,
but they won't let me.
Well, you can't have everything.
Big day today.
You say that every day,
you old devil.
lt's a lovely day outside.
Let's take a walk.
I don't think so.
Well, we've got to get you out
of this room.
Come on now, honey.
Some fresh air would do you good.
Hello?
I'm sorry. lt's not a good day.
I don't think she's up for anything.
Hello?
This is Duke.
He's come to read to you.
Read?
No.
I don't know.
Oh, come on. You'll like him.
He's Very funny.
All right, now.
Where did we leave off?
Oh, yeah, yeah, I know.
lt was the night of the carnival.
Noah was there
with his friends Fin and Sara.
-Noah?
-That's where they met.
June sixth, 1940.
Allie was 1 7 years old.
Little man wins a prize.
-Thank you for playing.
-You're real funny.
Man, I clobbered that thing.
I'm telling you, these games are fixed.
Hello.
Hi. What's your name?
-Who's this girl with Sara?
-Her name's Allie Hamilton.
She's here for the summer
with her family.
Dad's got more money than God.
-Hi, Fin!
-Hi, honey.
Look, I won you a prize.
Fin, thank you!
You want some cotton candy?
You want to dance with me?
No.
Why not?
Because I don't want to.
Noah, she's with us.
Allie, you want
to ride the Ferris wheel?
Good idea.
-I'd love to.
-All right.
Excuse me.
-Noah Calhoun.
-What?
Works down at the lumberyard with Fin.
He was about two inches away
from my face.
Yeah, I saw. That's Noah, though.
You know,
I'm surprised he even came over.
I think he likes you.
-Hey quit it, you jerk!
-Get off me!
Have you flipped your lid?!
What are you doing?
-You can't do that!
-I'll pay you when I get down, Tommy!
I'm Noah Calhoun.
-So?
-So it's really nice to meet you.
-Allie, who is this guy?
-I don't know. Noah Calhoun.
-I would really like to take you out.
-Friend, do you mind?
You can't sit more than two people
in a chair, Noah!
Okay, Tommy. All right.
Get down, Noah!
You're going to kill yourself!
Noah, cut it out.
Well, will you go out with me?
What?
No!
-Never?
-No!
-Why not?
-Hey, pal, she just told you.
-I don't know, because I don't want to.
You leave me no other choice, then.
Oh, my God.
-Stop fooling around!
-What are you doing?
-Noah, grab the bar!
-I'll ask you one more time.
Will you or will you not go out
with me?
Goddamn, my hand's slipping.
Then grab the bar, you idiot!
Not until she agrees.
Go out with him.
-Fine! I'll go out with you.
-What?!
-No, don't do me any favors.
-No! I want to!
-You want to?
-Yes!
-Say it.
-I want to go out with you!
-Say it again.
All right, all right, we'll go out.
You think you're so smart, don't you?
That wasn't funny, you idiot!
Oh, it's okay. I'll take care of this.
What are you doing?
Please don't do that.
-Don't do that.
-I can't believe it.
Oh, God.
You're not so cocky now, are you?
I'll get you for that.
Maybe you will, maybe you won't.
Oh, will you look at that.
lt's that girl from the carnival.
You remember me?
Yeah, sure. Mr. Underwear, was it?
How could I forget?
Yeah, I'm really sorry about that.
lt was really stupid to crawl up
the Ferris wheel to talk to somebody.
But I had to be next to you.
I was being drawn to you.
Oh, jeez. What a line.
You use that on all the girls?
No.
Right. I saw you the other night
with Little Miss Ribbons.
-What are you doing tonight?
-What?
Or tomorrow night, or this weekend.
-Why?
-Why? Our date.
-What date?
-The date you agreed to.
-No.
-You did. You promised and you swore it.
Well, I guess I changed my mind.
I know you get a dirty guy coming up
to you you don't know,
you don't know me. But I know me.
And when I see something that I like,
I got to h-- I love it.
-I go crazy for it.
-What are you talking about?
Well, you.
-You're good.
-What?
-No. You're getting me wrong.
You're fantastic. You really are.
I'm impressed.
-I'm not usually like this. I'm sorry.
-Oh, yes, you are.
I can be funny if you want.
Pensive.
Smart.
Superstitious.
Brave.
And I could be light on my feet.
I could be whatever you want.
Tell me what you want
and I'll be that for you.
You're dumb.
I could be that.
Come on, one date.
What's it going to hurt?
I don't think so.
What can I do to change your mind?
Guess you'll figure something out.
-Are you sure she's coming?
-Relax.
lt's all set up. We're meeting them for
the late show. Look. What'd I tell you?
Oh, my goodness. What a coincidence!
Look who's here.
Allie, you remember Noah, don't you?
Yes, I remember.
Come here.
-Hi.
-lt's nice to see you again.
-You too.
-You look great.
-Oh, thanks.
Really, really great.
You do look great. You look great.
And I know I look great.
So can we please go see this movie?
Show's about to start.
After you.
-You come back here, Li'l Abner!
-You ain't going to catch me, Daisy Mae!
lt's Sadie Hawkins Day,
I'm supposed to catch you!
-I'm faster than you!
-Oh, get over here.
No! No! No!
I'll get you!
Go on and git!
Here I come!
You catch-um Polecat fair and square.
Wait for me!
What happened in that movie?
-Here you go.
-Thank you.
-What are you guys doing?
-Want to walk with me?
-Get in.
-What's going on?
We'll walk.
You guys love each other?
-I get it. You guys do love each other.
-Don't do anything I wouldn't do.
Okay, goodbye.
All right.
That was fun.
I haven't seen a movie in ages.
Really?
Not since I was a little kid.
What?
I'm busy. I don't have a lot of time.
You're busy?
I have a very strict schedule.
My days are all planned out.
I get up in the morning.
Breakfast, math tutor,
Latin tutor, lunch...
...tennis lesson, dance lesson,
sometimes both.
French tutor, piano lesson,
then I eat dinner.
After dinner I spend time
with my family
and then I catch up on some reading.
-Sounds like the road to success.
-You bet.
I'm applying to all these colleges.
Radcliffe, Sarah Lawrence.
Those are the ones we want.
And who's ''we''?
What?
You just said, ''The ones that we want.''
Oh.Mama and Daddy.
We decide everything together.
Everything?
No, not everything.
But the important things, yes.
And everything else you get
to decide all by yourself?
Don't be rude.
I'm sorry.
Just trying to figure out
what you do for fun.
What do you mean?
I mean...
I don't know,
...all those things are things you
have to do, right?
So, what do you do because
you want to?
I just told you.
I don't know.
You're surprising me.
What?
I always figured you were kind of....
Kind of what?
Just...
...free.
What?
Free.
I am free.
You don't seem like it.
Well, I am.
I want to show you something.
-What are you doing?
-Just come on.
You'll get run over.
By all the cars?
My dad and I used to come out here and
lay down and watch the lights change.
Watch them go from green
to red to yellow.
You could try it if you wanted to.
-No.
-Why not?
Because-- I don't know.
Will you just get up?
That's your problem. You know that?
You don't do what you want.
Ok.
What happens if a car comes?
You die.
-What?
-Just relax.
Just trust.
You need to learn how to trust.
Ok.
Painting.
You asked me what I do for me.
I love to paint.
You?
Most of the time I have all these
thoughts bouncing around in my head.
But with a brush in my hand,
the world just gets kind of quiet.
Get out of the street!
Are you okay?
Why are you laughing?
That was fun.
Do you want to dance with me?
Sure.
Now?
Here?
-Not supposed to dance in the street.
-Supposed to dance in the street.
We don't have any music.
Well...
...we'll make some.
You're a terrible singer.
I know.
But I like this song.
''Southern summers are indifferent
to the trials of young love.
Armed with warnings and doubts...
...Noah and Allie gave a remarkably
convincing portrayal...
...of a boy and a girl traveling down
a very long road...
...with no regard
for the consequences.''
They fell in love, didn't they?
-Yes, they did.
-Good.
I like this kind of story. Go on.
''After that night,
Allie and Noah spent
every waking hour together.
And soon, they were inseparable.''
-Noah, come on!
-I'll beat you there.
Come on!
-That looks really nice.
-Try that. lt's really good.
That's really nice.
''--the primitive apples,
the pebble-stones
Beautiful dripping fragments...
...the negligent list of one
after another...
...as I happen to call them to me
or drink to them...
The real poems,
(what we call poems
being merely pictures )
The poems of the privacy
of the night...
...and of men like me
This poem, drooping shy and unseen...
...that I always carry,
and that all men carry....''
Not bad for Whitman.
Hey, looks like you got a visitor.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to interrupt.
Well, don't apologize.
Come on up here, darling.
We could use a little something
around here besides the smell of lumber.
-Dad, this is Allison Hamilton.
-Allison, glad to meet you.
-Allie.
-Pleased to meet you, Mr. Calhoun.
-Am I old or something? Call me Frank.
Hey, come in and have a seat.
-Allie. Well, she is purty, son.
-Yes.
She's a lot prettier than you let on.
-Oh, is that right?
-No, it's not right. Don't believe him.
What is this you got?
I brought you something.
Well, let's see. Let's have a look.
Did you do this?
Well, that's beautiful. Look at that.
That's a damn picture there.
Well,
I know just where we can put that.
Thank you.
That was a lovely poem. What was it?
-Well--
-Whitman.
See, when he was a little kid he used
to stutter real bad.
-Dad.
-Well, you did.
-I didn't know that.
-I stammered.
Stammered, stuttered,
what's the difference?
Couldn't understand him.
So I got him to reading poetry out loud.
lt wasn't very pretty at first,
but then his stutter went away.
-That's a good idea.
-Yeah, I thought so.
Unbelievable. Unbelievable.
I'm a Tennyson man myself
and he likes Whitman for some reason.
I don't know.
Say, how would you like some breakfast?
-Breakfast?
-Yeah.
Dad, it's 10:00.
So? You can have pancakes any damn time
of the night you want.
-Come on, you want some breakfast?
-Sure.
''lt was an improbable romance.
He was a country boy.
She was from the city.
She had the world at her feet...
...while he didn't have two dimes
to rub together.''
Noah, come on!
Look at them.
What are we doing?
You think in another life
I could have been a bird?
What do you mean?
Like reincarnation.
I don't know.
I think I could.
Say I'm a bird.
No.
-Don't do it.
-Say I'm a bird.
-Stop it. Stop it, now.
-Say it.
-You're not.
-Say it!
You're a bird.
Now, say you're a bird too.
If you're a bird, I'm a bird.
-Come on, darling.
-What are you doing?
On the count of three, okay?
Real easy. On three. Ready?
One.
-Two.
-Three!
-No! I can't.
Get in the water.
-Come on, chicken.
-Get in!
I'm sorry. Get in the water, baby.
Baby, would you get in.
-Get in the water!
-I can't.
-Just go!
-Get in the water!
-One!
-Jump.
-Two.
-Three!
No, no, no. Get to a good place
and move!
And keep it!
I don't understand
what you're talking about!
''They didn't agree on much.
ln fact, they rarely agreed
on anything.
They fought all the time.
And they challenged
each other every day.
But despite their differences they had
one important thing in common.
They were crazy about each other.''
Okay, I have to go.
-No!
-Yes, I do.
Allie.
Daddy.
Oh, Daddy, you--I didn't see you there.
You kind of scared me.
Awful friendly
with that boy down there.
Yes.
You bring him to the house on Sunday.
I want to meet this young man.
Night, Daddy.
Good night.
Oh, boy.
This boy goes, ''Daddy,
I don't understand.'' He goes, ''Well...
...in theory,
we're both millionaires...
...but in reality we live
with a bunch of whores.''
Bishop Stevens told me that.
Olivia, remove the liquor decanter from
in front of my husband.
He's had a little too much to drink.
So, what do you do, Noah?
I work at the lumberyard with Fin.
Mainly milling and receiving logs
and stripping the bark.
That's lovely, dear.
Thank you.
If you don't mind my asking,
how much do you earn?
How much money do I make?
Forty cents an hour.
Yeah, it's not much,
but I don't need a lot
and I save most of it.
Let's eat, shall we?
Oh, yes! Oh, it looks delicious.
So, Noah, you and Allie been spending
a lot of time together.
Must be very fond of each other.
lt's getting pretty serious, huh?
Yes, ma'am.
Well, summer's almost gone.
What will you do?
Charleston's only a couple
of hours away.
But Allie's going to Sarah Lawrence.
Didn't she tell you?
No, she didn't tell me that.
I just got the letter.
I was going to tell you.
lt's okay.
And Sarah Lawrence is in New York.
I didn't know that.
Anne, this conversation's too stuffy
for the dinner table.
Let the children have fun
and no bringing
in the Spanish lnquisition.
My lips are buttoned right now.
I do know another joke about the nun
and the four stallions.
Stop it. I'm leaving the table
if you tell another joke.
Going to do it! Yeah!
-No!
-Ready!
That child's got too much spirit for a
girl of her circumstance.
No, it's just a summer love.
Trouble is what it is.
Is that Allie out there?
Do you want to go somewhere?
Wait here.
Allie!
Come on.
All right. Big step.
Step. No, don't--
All right, stay there.
Don't open your eyes.
The Windsor Plantation.
lt was built in 1 772.
Rumor has it that Francis Marion
proposed to his wife on these steps.
Watch out. Be careful.
These are broken. Look at that.
This place is gigantic.
Yeah, a gigantic piece of crap.
lt is.
But I'm going to buy it one day.
I'm going to fix it up.
All it needs is a new floor.
-And new walls and roof.
-Is that all?
And plumbing and electric.
-And furniture.
-Yeah, and some furniture.
But it's right on the water.
And there's a big old barn up there.
I could turn that into my workshop.
Well, what about me? Now,
don't I get any say in this?
Do you want a say in this?
Yes, I would.
What do you want?
I want a white house
with blue shutters...
...and a room overlooking the river
so I could paint.
-Anything else?
-Yes.
I want a big old porch that wraps
around the entire house.
And we can drink tea
and watch the sun go down.
-You promise?
-I promise.
Good.
-Where you going?
-ln here.
I can't play ''Chopsticks''
with you doing that.
Make love to me.
-Noah?
-Yeah?
I know I said that
I wanted you to make love to me...
...but I think you're going
to have to talk me through this.
-Really? Everything?
-Yeah.
-Did I hurt you?
-No, no.
I'm just--
I'm just having a lot of thoughts.
Never mind.
Like, what are you thinking?
What are you thinking right now?
You know, right this second.
Did you know that this would happen
when you brought me here?
-No.
-No?
No? You didn't think about it?
-Of course I thought about it.
-You did?
Well, what did you think?
I'm talking too much, aren't l?
Okay, I'm just going to shut up.
Mum's the word.
-You all right?
-Yeah.
All right.
I just don't understand
how come you're so quiet.
You don't have one thought?
I'm going crazy over here,
but, Noah, with you, everything's fine.
You don't have a care in the world?
Sorry.
I wanted this to be so perfect
and now I can't shut up.
I love you.
Did you know that?
I love you too.
You don't have to do this
if you don't want to.
No. No, I want to. I do.
Noah!
-Noah!
-What?!
Fin, get out of here!
Sorry, but Allie's parents
are going crazy.
They got all the cops looking for her.
-You sent the police for me?
-Yes.
lt is 2 a.m. We sent the police.
Thank God you're all right.
Where you been?
All this is my fault.
Would you give us a moment, please?
Like to talk to my daughter.
Alone, young lady.
-Thanks for everything, lieutenant.
-You bet, John. Anytime.
You get straight home now. lt's late.
Sir, it's really not her fault.
I lost track of time.
Sit down.
I'm sorry, Daddy.
''I'm sorry, Daddy.''
Think you can bat your eyelashes at
your father and get away with it?
No. This time there's going to start
being some rules around here.
Like what?
If your father won't enforce them,
I will.
Like what, Mother?!
-You are going to stop seeing Noah.
-No.
She is out fooling around
with that boy till 2 a.m.
and it has got to stop.
I din't spend 1 7 years raising
a daughter and giving her everything...
...for her to throw it away
on a summer romance.
She'll wind up broken-hearted
or pregnant.
Now, he is a nice boy.
He's a nice boy, but he's...
-He's what? He's what?! Tell me!
-He is trash! Trash! Not for you!
-Trash?!
-He's a laborer. He's a woodworker.
So what?!
Are you going to live
in his father's house
and pop out a few dirty kids?!
I wouldn't mind!
Don't touch me!
You won't see him anymore. That's final.
-No, it's not.
-Yes, it is.
No, it's not final!
You're not going to tell me
who I'm going to love!
-Love?
-Yes, Daddy, I love him.
I love him.
He's not suitable for you, baby.
I know he is not what you want for me.
He's poor and unrefined and uncultured
and all wrong.
I love him.
-I love him.
-You know nothing about love.
Oh, and you do?!
You don't look at Daddy the way
I look at Noah.
You don't touch or laugh.
You don't play.
You don't know anything about love.
Noah?
You're leaving?
I am so sorry.
I don't even know what to say.
I'm humiliated.
-lt's all right.
-No, it's not.
-Yeah.
-I'm going to go.
-No, I don't want you to go.
-I got to think about some stuff.
-What do you got to think about, huh?
Come here. Talk to me.
Talk to me.
About what? You want to--
You're going away.
You're leaving...
...and I'm staying here.
I'm so happy that you're doing that...
...but you'll have
a million things to do.
-You got so much ahead of you.
-Don't talk like that.
lt's true.
I'm not going to have nice things,
fancy things.
lt doesn't--
lt's never going to happen for me.
lt's not in the cards for me.
-I don't have to go to school, okay?
-Yes, you do.
-I can stay here
-No.
That's exactly what I'm talking about.
You can come with me.
-To New York?
-Yes.
what am I going to do in New York?
Be with me.
Yeah.
I don't know.
We don't got to figure
all this out tonight, you know?
WE'll finish out the summer
and see what happens.
Are you saying you want to break up?
I'm saying we see how it goes later on.
Are you breaking up with me?
I don't see how it's going to work.
I see.
Please don't do this.
You don't mean it.
Oh, hell, well,
if you're going to do it,
then why wait until the summer ends?
Why don't you just do it right now?
Come on.
-Come on.
-What are you doing?
Do it!
Do it right now!
Stop it!
You know what?! I'll do it!
lt's over! Okay?! lt's over!
-Come here.
-Don't touch me!
I hate you! I hate you!
I'm going to go.
Why don't you just go now!
Leave!
Go! Go!
No, no.
We're not really breaking up, are we?
This is just a fight we're having...
...and tomorrow it'll be like
it never happened, right?
Gone?
Gone.
-Well, she must've been devastated.
-She was.
He was only trying to do
the right thing.
But what he really should have done is
just told those parents to go to hell.
Yeah, you're right. Probably should've.
''The next day, Allie woke up to find
her world completely changed.''
What's going on?
We're going home.
We're going now?
We're not due to leave for another week.
Get dressed and have some breakfast.
-Will will pack your things.
-I'd be happy to pack your things.
I don't want you to touch my stuff.
I'm not going.
-Yes, you are.
-No, I'm not.
Well, yes, Allie, you are going whether
you like it or not.
Now, even if Aaron has to drag
you the whole way, you're going.
All right, let's go.
We have to have all these done by lunch.
Quit standing around. Here we go.
Let's go! Come on!
Where's Noah?
He's out delivering a load.
What's going on?
I'm leaving town.
Leaving? When?
Now. Right now. Like, today.
I need you to tell Noah something.
Tell him that I love him
and tell him that
I'm sorry for everything, okay?
Look...
...I was up all night with him, Allie.
I've never seen him so low.
lt's over. Don't make it any harder
than it already is.
No. No, it's not over.
We had a fight last night.
We said some things we didn't mean.
-But it's not over.
-lt is over.
Leave it alone. Let it go.
I'm coming! Mama, I'm coming!
Look...
He understands.
lt's hard but he really does.
When the summer's over,
it's time to go home.
If he wants to talk to you,
he'll write. If not...
Okay, can you just tell him that
I love him, then?
Can you do that?
I'll tell him.
Bye, Fin.
Go on.
''Summer romances end
for all kinds of reasons.
But when all is said and done,
they have one thing in common.
They are shooting stars.
A spectacular moment
of light from the heavens.
A fleeting glimpse of eternity.
And in a flash...
...they're gone.
Noah was desperate.
He wrote to Allie that he was sorry
and stupid for breaking up with her.
He wrote to tell her that
he still loved her
and he wanted to see her.
And that if she would write back,
he would come to wherever she was.
He wrote one letter a day for a year.
365 letters.
But they all went unanswered.''
Hey, Fred!
Nothing?
Sorry.
All right, thank you!
''Finally, after a year of silence...
...he decided to put it all behind him
and start a new life.
So he wrote a farewell letter.
And he and Fin packed their bags
and headed for Atlanta.''
Noah!
Come on! Listen to this!
A state of war...
...has existed...
...between the United States and...
''--Constitution of the United States...
...against all enemies foreign
and domestic.''
''Noah and Fin enlisted together.
And after two years of chasing Rommel
through the North African desert...
...they were deployed
to Patton's 3rd Army in Europe.''
Fin!
''Do I contradict myself?
Very well then I contradict myself.''
''Allie was in her third year of college
when she volunteered as a nurse's aide.
To her, the broken men with shattered
bodies who filled the ward...
...were all Noah...
...or someone who fought beside him...
...in the jungle
or a forzen snow-swept road.''
Going to lift you up.
Ready?
Good.
There we go.
We'll bring this leg over...
...down.
You okay?
Miss...
...can I ask you a question?
I noticed that
you weren't wearing a ring...
...and I was wondering
if I could take you out.
Excuse me?
Oh a date.
Now, before you go and say no...
...I'll have you know that
I am an excellent dancer...
...and my intentions
are completely dishonorable.
Okay, Casanova, come on.
Let's just get you better,
then we'll talk about a date, okay?
Would you get a load of him?
Oh, my gosh, he is dreamy.
What is he doing here?
He's staring at you.
Oh, miss?
I'm all better.
Now, how's about that date?
''Allie was surprised how quickly
she fell in love with Lon Hammond.
He was handsome, smart...
...funny, sophisticated and charming.
He also came from old Southern money
and was fabulously wealthy.''
What?
-We're going to dance.
-What's happening? Where are they going?
-See you later, sweetheart.
-Look at that.
I've been thinking about why
we shouldn't get married.
I give up. Why shouldn't we get married?
I couldn't think of anything at first.
Then it dawned on me.
Your parents.
-My parents?
-Absolutely. Dear old Mom and Dad.
The problem is, is that they love me.
-I'm the type they want you to marry.
-They do? Really?
I'm wealthy, I'm from the South.
I've got a decent job.
I'm an incredible dance.
I'm a really smart guy.
You know, I'm very--
-So, what's the problem?
-I like to think-- Just listen.
If you marry me...
Now, listen close.
If you marry me,
you'll lose a lifelong battle
in defiance against them.
-Oh, my goodness, what will we do?
-I do not know.
Hey, man, you feeling all right?
You say:
See, Allie, I think-- Damn it,
I think you have to marry me.
I think you need to marry me.
-I do?
-Yes, you do.
If you do, your parents'll always know
the unhappiness that you feel...
...for not being able
to disappoint them.
-You may have overlooked a minor detail.
-And what's that?
Well, you see,
you have to get their permission first.
And I think you may have overestimated
their affection for you.
Is that right?
Oh, I don't think so.
Why not?
I asked them already and they said yes.
What?
One more thing.
I love you.
Will you marry me, Allie?
I know I kid around a lot,
but I am crazy about you.
Marry me?
Make me the happiest man in the world?
Yes.
Yes. Yes.
-I'll tell them.
-Where you going?
Mama!
Stop th band.
Excuse me.
I'd like you all to know
this young lady
and I are getting married!
''She agreed with all her heart...
...but couldn't understand why
at the very moment she said yes...
...Noah's face came to her mind.''
Hey, look at you!
Good to see you. Let me see you.
You bleeding anywhere? No?
-Everything good?
-Yeah.
Oh, I love you.
-There's something I got to show you.
-All right.
Come on.
what's going on? What is this?
Here.
I sold the house.
You sold the house?
Yep. Got to be out by the end
of the month.
Between that and your GI Bill you ought
to be able to get it now.
Get what?
Your dream house.
The Windsor Plantation.
-Dad--
-I don't want to hear about it.
I already talked to the bank.
They'll give you the loan.
-Well, I can't let you sell your house.
-lt's done.
lt's a good thing, you should do it.
Wait a second. You sell the house,
where you going to live?
With you, dummy. Where do you think?
Somebody's got to help you fix it up.
''Noah took a look at the house,
but only saw one thing:
Allie.
He decided right there
to fulfill his lifelong dream.
He would rebuild the old house
from the ground up.
And when Noah went to Charleston
to get the building plans approved...
...fate stepped in...
...and dealt him a sweet card.''
Stop the bus!
I can't stop till I get to the depot.
No. Please stop the bus now.
You understand English? No one gets off
till we get to ghe depot. Sit down!
God--
Move!
What are you doing?!
He's right over there.
Baby. Hello.
''After seeing Allie that day...
...something inside Noah snapped.
He got the notion...
...that if he restored the old house
where they had come that night...
...Allie would find a way
to come back to him.
Some called it a labor of love.
Others called it something else.
But in fact, Noah had gone a little mad.
-When--''
-Excuse me?
lt's time to eat.
Lunch is in the sun room today.
The melon is good. I had a bite.
Do they ever see each other again?
Noah and Allie?
You don't want me to spoil the end
before I get to the good part, do you?
Where did I leave off?
''I shall not want...''
''When Noah's father died in November...
...the house was all he had.
ln time, Noah finished the house.''
Smile. Here we go.
''He took a good look at what
he had accomplished...
...got rip-roaring drunk for 10 days...
...thought seriously
about setting it on fire...
...and finally put the house up
for sale.''
I'm prepared to offer you this much.
''He had a number of interested buyers.
But he always found a reason
not to sell it to them.''
No.
''Either their bids were too low...
...or if they met his asking price,
he felt it was worth a lot more.''
lt's a lot of money...
...but I'll take it.
Fifty thousand dollars.
That's more than my asking price.
That's right. lt's a great deal more.
''He told the man that offered him $5000
over his price...
...that no one in his right mind
would do that...
...and he wouldn't have a lunatic
living in his house.
He worked out his frustration with life
on the creek every morning.
And in the evenings,
to temper ths ting of loneliness...
...there was Martha Shaw.
Martha was a war widow who lived
in Quail Ridge, a town away.''
So you want to go out to eat tomorrow?
I got to work.
We can go down to the river if you want.
Next week sometime.
Maybe we could take a drive somewhere.
No.
Well, I'm just asking you.
What do you want, Noah?
What do you mean what do I want?
From me.
sometimes when you talk to me
you don't even see me.
Look, a woman knows when a man looks
into her eyes and sees someone else.
Now, you know I want to give you
all the things that you want.
Right?
But I can't...
...because they are gone.
They're broken.
All right?
Is the veil too much?
Are you kidding? You look perfect.
You're the most beautiful bride.
-You look gorgeous, honey.
-Thank you.
Wait until Lon sees you in this dress.
He's going to go crazy!
He won't be able
to take his eyes off you.
Or his hands.
Oh, you are so bad.
Have you seen this morning's paper?
The Daily Journal says you are going to
be the social highlight of the season.
The season?
This'll be a celebration the lokes of
which this town had never seen!
She doesn't plan,
she plots, doesn't she?
Mana, look, the governor's coming.
He better. Letme see.
Oh, boy.
-Savannah, where are we at?
-We're at 82 now.
-Memphis, where are we at?
-We're at 89.
-Great. Up from 85.
-Sir?
-Yes?
-You have a visitor.
Well, hello.
Baby, I didn't know you were coming.
I'm so sorry. I should've called.
What are you talking about?
You don't have to call.
-Guys, could you give us a minute?
-Yes, sir.
-Miss Allie.
-Ma'am.
So, what's up?
I don't paint anymore.
I used to paint all the time
and I really loved it.
I didn't know that.
Yeah.
So paint.
I will.
Yeah, I'm going to start.
Great.
Is everything okay?
I need to get away.
Okay.
I need to take care of a few things.
I need to clear my head.
Okay, should I be worried?
No, I don't think so.
Well, that's reassuring.
-Listen, are you all right?
-Yeah.
Okay. Then go. Take your time.
Do whatever you need to do.
lt's okay to be nervous.
lt's normal to get cold feet
before your wedding.
No. No second thoughts, Lon.
I love you.
And I'm going to be back from Seabrook
in a couple of days, Okay?
Seabrook.
Yeah. Seabrook.
Hello.
I waw your picture in the paper.
The one with you and the house.
and I just wanted to come
and see if you were okay.
I mean, I wasn't in the neighborhood
or anything. I just...
So are you okay?
Okay, good.
I'm a stupid woman.
I shouldn't have come.
You want to come in?
Okay.
this is a good story.
I'm glad you like it.
I think I've heard it before.
Yes.
Perhaps more than once?
Doctor needs to see you.
Me? Now?
No. Him.
But he hasn't finished reading
the story.
I'll read more
when I'm through with the doctor.
lt shouldn't take too long.
-All right.
-Don't you go away. I'll be right back.
While you waiting,
maybe you'd like to play the piano.
You do like that.
I do?
I don't know any tunes.
You can read music.
No kidding.
Who are you?
I'm Dr. Barrwell,
one of the new attending physicians.
We haven't met,
so I thought I'd examine you myself.
Okay, so I see here that
you've had two heart attacks over
the last 18 months.
Yeah, minor ones.
I think one was angina.
Okay, any complications?
Nope. Feel fine.
Okay. Deep breath for me.
Okay. One more time.
And deep breath.
And one more.
Terrific. Terrific.
You still taking your medication?
Every day, twice a day.
Good, good, good, good, good.
Okay, you can put your shirt on.
So I understand that
you read to Miss Hamilton.
Yep. To help her remember.
You don't think it'll help.
No, I don't.
She remembers, doc.
I read to her and she remembers.
Not always, but she remembers.
Senile dementia is irreversible.
lt's degenerative.
After a certain point,
its victims don't come back.
That's what they keep telling me.
I just don't want you
to get your hopes up.
Well, thanks, doc.
But you know what they say:
Science goes only so far
and then comes God.
Then comes God.
Damn, they forgot
to turn the page for her.
You through with me?
I guess they flipped that page.
No.
That, she's playing by memory.
His name is Lon Hammond, Jr.
Hammond?
As in Hammond Cotton?
As in Hammond Cotton.
Well, your parents must love him.
He's a really good man, Noah.
You'd really like him.
You love him?
Yeah.
I do. I love him very much.
Well, that's that.
You marry Lon, and we can be friends.
Right?
Right.
Are you hungry?
You want to stay for dinner?
I have to warn you, I'm a cheap drunk.
Couple more of these and you'll be
carrying me right out of here.
Well, go slow, then.
I don't want to have to take advantage
of you.
You wouldn't dare. I 'm a married woman.
Not yet.
What?
Why are you looking at me like that?
Just memories.
This room.
This--
Is this where--?
This is the room?
I'm full.
Me too.
''O, how your fingers drowse me.
Your breath falls around me like dew.
Your pulse lulls the tympans of my ears.
I feel immerged from head to foot.
Delicious, enough.''
lt was real, wasn't it?
You and me?
Such a long time ago.
We were just a couple of kids.
But we really loved each other,
didn't we?
I should go.
Goodbye.
You think you could come back
tomorrow morning?
There's some place I'd like to show you.
Please?
Okay.
''She had come back into his life
like a sudden flame...
...blazing and streaming into his heart.
Noah stayed up all night...
...contemplating the certain agony
he knew would be his...
...if he were to lose her twice.''
Oh, I do wish I could figure out
the end of this story.
The children are here.
Children?
Not yours, his.
Do you mind?
Oh, I'd love to meet them.
-Come over here.
-Hi Daddy.
-How are you?
-Good.
-How you doing, Maggie?
-Hi, Daddy.
Hi. I'm Allie.
-Hi, I'm Mary Allen.
-Mary Allen.
-Nice to see you.
-Hi.
-Maggie.
-Maggie, how are you?
Hello there, honey.
Hi. Davanee.
-what a pretty name.
-Thank you.
Oh, my. Thank you.
-And who's this?
-Edmond.
Hi, Edmond.
You know, I think I'll run on up
and take my afternoon nap. All right?
-Come on, honey. Let's go.
-There you go.
-All right. Good.
-Thank you.
I'll read some more later.
All right. Thank you.
I'm so happy to meet you all.
-Goodbye.
-Nice to meet you.
-Bye.
She seems good today.
She is good.
I don't know,
there's something about today.
Maybe it's a day for a miracle.
Daddy...
...come home.
Mama doesn't know us.
She doesn't recognize you.
She'll never understand.
We miss you.
This is crazy, you living here.
Yeah. You know, we'll all help with Mon.
We can take shifts visiting.
Look, guys...
...that's my sweetheart in there.
I'm not leaving her.
This is my home now.
Your mother is my home.
-Hello?
-Hey there.
Hi.
Who is this?
lt's Lon. Who were you expecting?
Nobody. I'm just surprised.
How did you find me?
Well, there's only one hotel
in Seabrook.
And when you didn't call, I got worried.
Where have you been? Are you all right?
I feel like an idiot because I called
your hotel about a hundred times.
I'm fine.
-Anything you want to tell me?
-No.
No?
No.
Okay.
Lon, I love you.
Call you tomorrow?
Okay.
Noah?!
Hey there.
Well, we better get going.
The rain's coming in.
You like it?
lt's like a dream.
Do you want to feed them?
Yeah.
What are they all doing here?
I don't know.
They're supposed
to migrate to Wadmalaw Sound.
They won't stay here?
No.
They'll go back where they came from.
You're different.
What do you mean?
Just the way you look.
Everything.
You look different too,
but in a good way.
You know,
you're kind of the same, though.
Yeah?
Yeah.
And you really did it.
What?
Everything.
The house.
lt's beautiful what you did.
Well, I promised you I would.
Great.
We got to go.
Noah!
Why didn't you write me?
Why?
lt wasn't over for me.
I waited for you for seven years.
And now it's too late.
I wrote you 365 letters.
I wrote to you every day for a year.
-You wrote me?
-Yes.
lt wasn't over.
lt still isn't over.
You got to be kidding me.
All this time,
that's what I've been missing?
Let's do it again.
Noah.
Wake up.
-Hi.
-You're trying to kill me, woman.
I need rest.
I need food so I can regain my strength.
Okay.
What do you want?
Some pancakes.
Okay.
And some bacon...
And some chicken.
She's the one, isn't she?
Can I meet her?
-I'd really like to meet her.
-l don't know if that's a good idea.
So this is Martha?
Hi.
I'm Allie.
I've heard a lot about you.
I've heard a lot about you too.
You want to come in?
Are you sure?
Yeah. Yeah. Noah was just saying
how hungry he was.
You know you could put on a pot of tea.
Come on in.
-lt was nice meeting you, Martha.
-Nice meeting you too.
-Bye.
-Take care.
She's sensational.
She really is.
I'm really glad that I came, Noah.
I'd forgotten what it's like.
For the first time since
I lost Richard...
...I feel like I've got something
to look forward to.
Lon is on his way here.
I'm afraid your father spilled
the beans about Noah.
When Lon didn't hear from you again,
he decided to come.
Well, that's great.
That's just terrific.
You, me, Noah and Lon.
One big happy family.
Tell me about the letters, Mother.
Is it true?
Yes.
You watched me cry myself to sleep
for months and months...
...and you never said anything.
-How could you do that?
-I'm sorry.
-You're sorry?
-Yes, I am. I am sorry.
Because of you,
my entire life was ruined.
Yes, I stole your letters. lt was wrong.
But stop being dramatic and at least
take some of the resposibility.
You came down here.
You knew what you were doing.
You knew this would happen.
so now I'm a tramp?
You are unbelievable. Unbelievable.
Come on. Get some clothes on.
Let's take a drive.
''Let's take a drive.''
Why would I want to go anywhere
with you?
Because I might know you
a little better than you think.
I don't want you waking up one morning
thinking if you'd known everything...
...you might've done
something different.
What are we doing here, Mama?
Do you see that man there?
Doesn't look like it now,
but 25 years ago...
Oh, my goodness.
He was really something.
We were out of our minds in love,
let me tell you.
Wow.
Well, naturally your grandfather
was furious,
so we decided to run away.
We didn't even maked the next town
before the police picked us up.
But that was then.
You know, sometimes
when I'm in the area...
...I just stop here and watch him...
...trying to picture how different
my life might have been.
I want you to know that
I love your father.
Mama...
No, goddamn it, this is important
and you need to hear it.
I do. He is a wonderful man.
He is good to me,
and I don't deserve him.
I love him, Allie, I do. I love him.
I know you love him, Mama.
I know.
Oh, my God.
This is just very embarrassing.
I am a stupid woman.
Look at me, a big old bawl bag.
lt's crazy...
...but I don't even know
who that person is.
Oh, boy.
Allie!
Here.
I hope you make the right choice.
lnteresting morning.
Yeah.
Lon's here in town.
He's here?
Yeah we saw his car on the way,
at the hotel.
I see you got my letters.
Finally.
What are you going to do, Al?
I don't know.
We're back to that?
Are we back there?
What about the past couple of days?
They happened, you know.
I know they happened
and they were wonderful.
But they were also very irresponsible.
I have a fiance waiting for me
who'll be crushed when he finds out--
So you make love to me
and then you go back to your husband?
Is that your plan?
-Was that a test that I didn't pass?!
-No! I made a promise to a man.
I gave him my word.
Your word is shot to hell now,
don't your think?
I'll find out when I talk to him.
This is not about keeping your promise.
And it's not about following your heart.
lt's about sceurity.
-What is that supposed to mean?
-Money!
-What are you ta--?
-He has a lot of money!
-I hate you, you smug bastard.
-I hate you.
If your leave here, I hate you.
Haven't you paid attention
to anything that's happened?
I guess not. I must have misread
all of those signals.
Yeah, I guess you did.
You're bored! You're bored
and you know it.
You wouldn't be here
if there wasn't something missing.
Arrogant son of a bitch.
Would you just stay with me?
Stay with you? What for?
Look at us. We're already fighting.
Well, that's what we do. We fight.
You tell me
when I'm an arrogant son of a bitch.
I tell you
when you're a pain in the ass,
which you are 99% of the time.
I'm not afraid to hurt your feelings.
They have a two-second rebound rate...
...and you're back doing
the next pain-in-the-ass thing.
So what?
So it's not going to be easy.
lt's going to be really hard.
We'll have to work at this every day,
but I want to because I want you.
I want all of you forever.
You and me every day.
Will you do something for me?
Please?
Will you just picture
your life for me...
...30 years from now, 40 years from now.
What's it look like?
If it's with that guy, go.
Go! I lost you once,
I think I could do it again...
...if I thought it's what
you really wanted.
-But don't you take the easy way out.
-What easy way?
There is no easy way.
No matter whta I do, somebody gets hurt.
Would you stop thinking
about what everyone wants?
Stop thinking about what I want.
What he wants. What your parents want.
What do you want?
-What do you want?
-lt's not that simple.
What do you want?
Goddamn it, what do you want?
I have to go.
My dearest Allie:
I couldn't sleep last night
because I know that
it's over between us.
I'm not bitter anymore because I know
that what we had was real.
If in some distant place in the future
we see each other in our new lives...
...I'll smile at
your with joy and remember...
...how we spent a summer beneath
the trees...
...learning from each other
and growing in love.
The best love is the kind that awakens
the soul...
...and makes us reach for more.
That plants a fire in our hearts
and brings peace to our minds.
And that's what you've given me.
That's what I had hoped
to give to you forever.
''I love you. I'll be seeing you. Noah.''
lt's beautiful.
lt's a beautiful story.
Yes, it is.
I don't know why,
but it makes me feel sad.
I know you feel lost right now,
but don't worry.
''Nothing is ever lost or can be lost.
The body, sluggish, aged, cold...
...the embers left from earlier fires...
...shall duly flame again.''
Did you write that?
No.
That was Walt Whitman.
I think I knew him.
I think you did.
Shall we go in?
I'm feeling a little chilly.
Thank you.
Who did all of this?
I did, with a little help
from my friends on the nursing staff.
I've never seen anything so beautiful.
Neither have l.
Shall we?
-Some grape juice?
-I'd love it.
Wow, so many pills. How sick are you?
Well, ''sickness'' has
become a relative term for me.
I think of it now as more
a general wearing-out process.
To you.
So, what happened?
ln the story?
Which one did she choose?
The way I see it, I got three choices.
One, I can shoot him.
Two, I can kick the crap out of him.
Or three...
...I leave you.
But all that's no good.
You see, because...
...none of those options give me you.
And in spite of everything...
...I love you.
I love you too.
I meant what I said
when I gave you that ring.
I did too.
lt's just that when I'm with Noah
I feel like one person...
...and when I'm with you
I feel like someone totally different.
Look...
...it's normal not to forget
your first love.
I love you, Allie.
But I wnat you for myself.
I don't want to have to convince
my fiancee she should be with me.
You don't have to.
I already know I should be with you.
''And they lived happily ever after.''
Who?
Who did?
Oh, yes.
Of course.
I remember now.
lt was us.
-lt was us. lt was us.
-Oh, my darling. Oh, my sweetheart.
I love you so much.
Oh, my baby.
Noah. Noah.
I love you, angel.
What happened to me?
Nothing.
You just went away for a little while.
How much time to we have?
I'm not sure.
Last time it was no more
than five minutes.
Hey...
...I brought along an old friend.
-How are the children?
-Oh, they're fine.
They were here today.
Little Noah. Davanee too.
They're getting so big.
Oh, boy.
How fast the time goes.
Just flies right on by.
Oh, yes, it does.
Will you tell them I love them?
Of course I will.
And that I'm sorry.
I'll tell tem, sweetheart.
Remember that story
you were reading to me?
Yes.
Do you think that
I could be her tonight?
Would that be all right?
You know what we could do?
Maybe we could get a car
and we could go for a ride.
We could get out of here,
just go someplace. You want to?
I don't think so. Not tonight, darling.
Come on. Why not?
Wait a minute.
Why did you call me darling?
I don't know you.
What's going on here?
Am I supposed to know you?
-Allie.
-No. No! No!
Sweetheart.
-I love you. Stay with me. Don't leave.
-No!
-Who are you?
-I'm Noah. I'm Noah and you're Allie.
What do you want?
What are you doing here?
-Come on, baby.
-Don't come near me. Don't come near me.
-Allie, Allie...
-Help! Help!
-Help me!
-Calm down, Allie. Calm down.
Calm down. lt's all right, sweetie.
-lt's all right, baby. Come on.
-Leg me go!
-Calm down, Allie.
-Leave me alone.
lt's all right. Doc!
-Somebody help me!
-Allie, calm down. Doctor!
-Talk to me.
-Hurry up. She's sundowning.
Somebody help me!
-Calm down. Get here arm.
-Okay, two cc's Halop--
-Calm down, Allie.
-One. Two.
Three.
Allie, it's all right.
-lt's all right.
-You're okay. Let's take a look.
-Let's take a look. Yeah, she's fine.
-Good.
-Just breathe. Stay calm.
-Just fine.
-Breathe in and out through your mouth.
-Relax.
-You're going to be okay, Allie.
-Relax. lt's all right.
You're fine now.
Morning, Mr. Calhoun.
Mr. Calhoun?
Call Dr. Fonatant at MUSC, okay?
I've got no BP, no pulse, nothing.
Let them know we're in full arrest.
-Call me on my cell!
-Okay, will do.
We talked about this.
lt's all right, now. Come on.
Come on, precious. Come on. Let's go.
lt's okay, baby.
Come on. You know Mr. Holmes.
Oh, Mr. Calhoun.
Welcome back.
-How do you feel?
-Fine. Fit as a fiddle.
Where you going?
I was just taking a walk. I can't sleep.
You know it's against the rules.
Yeah, I know.
You weren't really going for a walk,
were you?
You were going to see Miss Allie.
I just got out of the hospital
and I miss her.
Mr. Calhoun...
...I'm sorry but I can't let you
see her tonight.
You'll have to go back to your room.
As for me...
...I'm going to go downstairs
and get myself a cup of coffee.
I won't be back to check
on you for a while.
So don't do anything foolish.
Hi.
Noah.
Hi, sweetheart.
I'm sorry I haven't been able
to be here to read to you.
I didn't know what to do.
I was afraid you were never coming back.
Oh, I'll always come back.
What's going to happen...
...when I can't remember
anything anymore?
What will you do?
I'll be here.
I'll never leave you.
I need to ask you something.
What is it, sweetheart?
Do you think...
...that our love can create miracles?
Yes, I do.
That's what brings you back
to me each time.
Do you think our love...
...could take us away together?
I think our love can do anything
we want it to.
I love you.
I love you, Allie.
Good night.
I'll be seeing you.