Okay...
"Cover me, go left. "
Wait for my three count.
And one, two...
Unbelievable.
FBI! Freeze!  FBI!
Hands on top of your head!
On your head!
Hey, calm down, tough guy.
Surprise.
We've checked everywhere.
There's nothing.
Well, place is clean, Ashburn.
Looks like your theory
has a few holes in it.
Let's roll, boys.
Oh, here we go.
Yeah, that's what they...
that's what they said last year
right before I arrested
the Red Falls Killer.
I don't know. Maybe I'm wrong.
Or...
...maybe I'm not.
Yeah. Airtight.
Dipped in wax.
I respect that.
I especially like the meat
to distract the dog.
And while that may have fooled
the loudest breather
in the world,
it did not fool me.
And, unfortunately,
it's not what I'm looking for.
I don't know anything
about any guns.
Interesting.
Mm, wait for it.
Maybe these guys are...
are right for a change.
Mm, that's a trap.
Meteors, comets.
Somebody married Pete,
and he can't even
count to three.
Uhuh.
So frustrating.
You know,
they loved these houses
during the Prohibition Era.
No. No, it was, uh, alcohol.
People loved to drink it, even
though they weren't supposed to,
and these houses
had all these little
nooks and crannies
where they could hide it.
Like this one.
Fuck.
Now you can roll.
Gentlemen.
Nice work, dick.
Jesus.
Let's go. Ooh...
Hard to believe she's single.
Oh!
Immediately below that,
you feel a little crease...
We'd want to make an incision
right through there.
Pretty amazing.
Pumpkin!
Here, kitty, kitty.
Go on home.
I'll see you tomorrow.
There you go.
Pumpkin, I told you
to stay away from
that weird lady.
Yo, taxi!
Mmhmm.
No, no, no,
o  lo  lo... lo siento.
No, hay a poder
llegar temprano,
llamar de los vecinos
y diles que...
Lo siento. Perdón.
Oh, boy.
Oh, just, uh, letting you know
that I have been
observing the agents,
overseeing what
they've been up to,
you know,
keeping an eye on them.
Yeah. Supervising.
Supervising. Yes, sir.
Look, Ashburn...
I haven't made
any decisions yet.
Oh... of course not.
Every...
everyone deserves a shot.
I don't know if you are the
right person for this position.
Walk with me.
Sir, I don't...
I don't understand.
I've closed more cases
than any agent here.
You are a solid agent.
There are many other
solid agents.
Well, none of them
have closed
the Red Falls Killer case.
Ashburn, it's no secret
that none of the other agents
like you.
I've gotten countless
complaints of arrogance
and competitiveness,
showmanship.
Just give it a rest.
All right.
We've got a situation in Boston.
The Feds picked up chatter
on a guy moving in.
Simon Larkin.
We don't know
what he looks like,
where he comes
from, nothing.
We believe this guy is doing
the legwork for him.
Julian Vincent,
nasty son of a bitch.
Murder, extortion.
This is his M.O.
The problem with guys
like that is that
everyone's too scared to talk.
Pack your bags.
I'm sending you to Boston.
You know how to get
inside people's heads.
You want to find Larkin,
get to Julian.
You do well with this,
we can talk about the job.
Hey, Rojas sent me over.
He said you were really nice.
Not exactly.
Hey, Mullins.
Captain wants to know
when you're coming in.
Tell him I'll be there
sharply at, uh,
gofuckyourself o'clock.
Thank you.
No, baby, I'm not
going to break a hundred.
All right, let me see.
I don't think I have that.
Wow.
Oh.
Okay, well, it's... I think
this is just kind of...
between her and I, so let's...
Kind of.
I don't want to do that.
Let me see if this
will help you.
All right, look,
I... I just wanted to...
Oh.
Well, it... it's, uh...
it's a good thing I didn't
get the drugs from you.
That would have been...
That would have been crazy.
That would have been bad.
Whew!
You'd better wipe that brow.
Listen, um...
Thanks.
I got to ask,
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
you know, whatever...
Oh, we were just, um...
She looked kind of sad,
so I just...
I kind of thought I'd help her
out and give her a ride home.
That's nice, like
a Good Samaritan.
Yeah, I was kind of
cheering you up.
Yeah, good for you.
Hey, maybe you can put him
in the back of your car...
You know what,
let's open up the...
Frank, you want to shit your
pants and get in the...
Oh, good, it's open.
I can put, uh, Frank in there.
Okay.
He can shit and piss himself...
...until he's happy.
I got some towels.
I can put some towels...
Um...  Yeah, hey, let me just
take the whole thing.
I don't...  Yeah, it's good.
It's... I got it.
Oh, good.
I got nervous that maybe
you didn't have
a wife and a whole bunch
of kids, but...
but luckily, you do.
Her name is Bella.
Oh, Bella. Good.
My... yeah, my...
my battery's out.
Because I asked you
for your phone.
Give me your fucking phone.
Shut your mouth.
Yeah, I'll give you one chance.
No, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no!
That's... Don't do that.
Don't do that.
Ow! My God!
Yes, this is Officer Mullins.
God!
I'm here with your husband.
No.
No, he's not been in
an accident, unfortunately.
I just, uh... II do have him
here with a known prostitute.
God! She's lying!
Bella, she's lying!
God.
Yeah, that's him.
He's crying 'cause I'm
breaking his fucking hand.
God.
Oh, she said do it harder.
All right, Bella.
Ow! God!
That's for Bella.
Well, you got to go with
your instincts, Bella.
Yep, you're welcome.
Yep, she's probably going to
burn your shit today, so...
She just had a baby. There's
a lot going on down there.
I'm not going to touch that.
Why don't you take your, uh,
Oh, come on, please... come on.
Yeah.
No, you seem like
a reasonable guy.
You look like you got...
Take your fucking belt off.
And you look like
you got some compassion.
Listen, I love... I love
the sound of a guy that,
after his wife gives him
his fifth fucking child,
complains about
her messy vagina.
And then you don't want
to fucking touch her!
Get out of the fucking car.
I can unlock the door for you.
Come on!
Get up against the car.
Good! I hope it burns
your fucking dick off!
Hey, it's Rojas,
my favorite asshole.
Yeah, look what I found.
That's a real shame.
Lady, I don't even know
what you're talking about.
I just stand on this corner,
And you want to tell me
that you're
just here coincidentally,
right in the...
You should be ashamed
of yourself,
trying to break down
a successful black man.
And don't play that race
bullshit card with me!
Nine out of ten guys I fuck
are black guys.
Lady, what I think
you need to do...
And go get your groove back.
Take off.
Yeah, that's what I thought.
I'm not a part of this!
Shut up! Shut up!
Stop! Oh! Oh!
Oh, my God!
Oh, it's on!
She's crazy!
Come on, please let me out.
I get really carsick.
Please, please, please, please
Oh, no, that's terrible.
No, come on. Oh, my God!
I got him now.
I got him, I got him.
You are a meth head!
Oh, my God!
Hey, look who's here.
Oh!
You just hit him!
Yeah, you better run.
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
I got him. I got him!
Oh, God!
You piece of shit,
I said stop.
I said... I said stop!
I said stop!
Just get off me!
You're crushing my balls!
I hope they fucking rupture!
Lady, get the fuck off of me!
You're going to fucking...
Bella, I'm sorry!
Let me go!
Hold still, you piece of shit!
Ow! My leg, lady!
Let me go!
No!
I'll tell you what the hell's
the matter with me.
It's you, piece of shit.
Son of a bitch.
Stop moving!
Leave me alone.
Leave me alone!
Get off me!
Shit.
Yeah.
Ah, hell, no!
See, I told you
you was a racist.
Yeah, let's see what you
got in... Oh, look at this.
Look at this.
Not even my birthday.
Hey, man, you planted
that shit on me, man!
Yeah, I planted it, yeah.
You planted that on me!
I'm innocent!
Shut up before I feed you
watermelon. Get up.
Yeah.
Federal Agent Sarah Ashburn
I'm going to need all your files
on all known drug dealers
of the area.
Right. We heard you were coming.
Actually, I was expecting you.
Ah.
I'll show you to your desk.
Oh, that won't be necessary.
I won't be here long.
Okay. Okay.
So I can carry these. Thank you.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey! Ashburn!
Ashburn!
Oh! Ooh.
Oh, God.
Lowend dealer just brought
into the East Boston precinct.
All right.
Name's Terrell Rojas.
Oh. Oh, okay.
Good. Thank you very much.
Good... good luck out there.
It's not about luck, pal.
Not about luck.
Wow.
That was almost cool.
Almost.
Come on, come on, come on.
All right.
Here we go. Finally.
Hey! I'm moving in there!
No, don't...!
Hey, hey, hey!
No, get back in your car.
Hey! Hey!
Hey, asshole!
Goddamn it.
FBI.
Hey, you need to sign in.
Come on. Let's go.
Special Agent Sarah Ashburn.
We got intel recently
that you brought in
a dealer by the name
of Terrell Rojas.
Uh, yeah, but Detective Mullins
isn't back from lunch yet.
I'm sure he won't mind.
Well, he's a she, and we're not
really allowed to go
near her collars.
Let me tell you what I think.
I think that every second
we're standing here
is interfering with
the federal investigation.
So, if you'd be so kind
as to show Mr. Rojas
to an interrogation room.
Thank you.
This way.
Okay.
Shit.
You are looking at
possession with intent,
which is a class D drug charge,
chapter 94C, section 32A.
I had a joint and a few
little bags of coke.
The answer to your question
is always.
And with your priors,
you are looking at 25 years
and some pretty stiff fines.
That's 25 years!
Never mind.
Let's see what
you make of these.
What I make of them is
that somebody doesn't want
somebody else selling
on their turf.
But you're still here.
Nobody! If I tell you,
that's my ass
chopped up into a million
motherfucking pieces!
Goddamn it.
Fucker.
God.
Push!
This motherfucker!
Everybody's got to fucking park
in my spot.
Goddamn it!
Shit!
Suitwearing, god...
Ow! Fuck!
God.
Yeah, I said I'm...
fucking parking there.
That doesn't...
Steal my goddamn fucking space.
I don't want you to do time.
I don't want you to get
chopped up into little, tiny,
mothereffin' pieces.
Oh.
I can protect you.
I can.
But you got,
you got to help me.
I can help you.
Tell me where I can find Julian.
I don't deal with him like that.
I get my stuff from this bitch
named Tatiana on Newkirk Avenue.
Well, she got brown eyes.
Okay.
Mm, she got some
bigass "breastses. "
Big breastses.
Okay.
Uh... like...
her breastses is like this.
Okay. Thank you.
That's a shame.
Don't.
Oh, haha, oh, yeah!
We're at a comedy party, yeah.
Move the fuck
out of my way.
Get a room.
Tim, you still owe me 40.
Yeah, tomorrow it's 60.
Fucking dickweed.
He's in interrogation.
Theythey came and got him.
It was a lady. She was...
No, no, it was a different lady;
she was nice.
I'm fuckin' nice.
No, no.
She made me give her the keys.
I'm gonna make you
fucking bend over,
and I'm gonna reach up your ass
into your pocket and get
the keys to your house.
And then I'm gonna
drive there,
come in your front fucking door
and kill you in your sleep.
I think I have a clear idea
of what we're looking for,
and I appreciate
your time.
Wow, lady, you're on
a real fuckin' roll.
Yeah, no, I won't excuse you.
I just spent the last 30 minutes
thinking of different ways
to kill you.
I'm Special Agent Sarah Ashburn.
You can get all of that,
get it up,
and get it the fuck out of here,
'cause this is my room.
I am a detective,
and that's my perp.
Ah.
Ah, I... I understand now.
Well, um, Detective,
Mr. Rojas will be continuing on
with me at this point.
No.
It's a jurisdictional issue.
No, not gonna happen.
And so, uh, youryour efforts
areare duly noted. Thank
you so much.  Oh, great.
And if you're okay
with everything,
could you justjust
maybe close the door
I'll shut the door on you.
And I'll slam it about
157,000 fucking times.
Aw, shit, girl, you better run.
You need to shut your mouth.
Run like you on fire.
You need to be quiet.
You're gonna get up,
and we're gonna
settle this outside.
Okay, now I'm...
I won't be going outside.
You're gonna get up and
you're gonna come outside.
No, ma'am. Not going outside.
Fine. We'll do this inside.
Can somebody please
remove this person
Mental illness is
nothing to be ashamed of.
It runs in many families.
I'm gonna hit you.
You're not gonna hit me.
Please don't.
I'm gonna hit you and knock
all your little buttons.
Do not point your finger...
I'm gonna hit you there...
No, do not put your
finger in my...
Stop touching my buttons,
stop touching...
Well, stop wearing buttons.
Don't you...  Don't you move
those fucking hands again.
I'll get that stupid barrette.
H  Hey, hey!
I'll take that barrette
right out of your fucking hair!
Hey, stop!
Oh, stop, stop, stop!
Hey, both of you, my office now.
Nope. Not in there.
There is nothing
I can do, Mullins.
The FBI has jurisdiction.
Maybe they're in here. Maybe
they're in here.  Aw, come on.
Nope, they're not in
there. Let me see.
She's looking for my balls.
Oh.
Hey, if anyone sees
the captain's balls,
let me know!
They're about this big,
but a lot tinier.
They're like a pea,
or like a, like a ball bearing,
or like, if you've ever
seen a mouse ball,
about half that size.
Incredibly tiny.
They're like really, really
tiny, little girl balls,
if little girls had balls.
So if you find
little, tiny, girl balls
that are so fucking tiny
and shriveled up, let me know,
'cause I'll put them
right back up his scrotum!
Knock it off, Mullins.
Uh, I'd like you to have my back
and stop being so goddamn
disappointing like
everybody else.
Oh, well, that was professional.
Let me, let me be professional.
Let me help you
pick up your bag.
That's very mature.
Let me just
straighten that shit up.
Oh, wait, hey, hey!
Good news! Good news!
I found his balls!
Yeah, in a clear sack!
Yeah, enjoy that.
Shove those
back up there.
Cop of the Year!
Keep it up!
This job is destroying me.
I'm 43 years old.
Mmhmm, mmhmm.
Well, I always,
see, I always round up.
I have a fiveyearold son
who calls me Grandpa.
So, uh, anywho,
uh, sir, if, um...
if you could just, you know,
keep her away from me,
that would be...
be very helpful.
She's probably at O'Flanagan's.
It's a bar down the street.
Now, it's a little divey.
You might want to wear a vest.
Oh, wow. Wow,
okay, so there is.
With... with your fin...
with your finger. Please.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Hand them over.
Give me the keys. Now.
Oh, my God.
Apologize. Apologies.
You are so concerned about
taking down a guy like Rojas
when we have just wasted
all this time, when I could
have stopped a drug lord
who is far more dangerous and
supplies to people like Rojas.
I think I said bullshit,
is what I said.
Here you go. Here's
some bull poopoo.
Oh, come on.
I got a kid here.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I'm, I'm very
sorry, very sorry.
Wait a minute,
this is a bar.
This is a b...
No, absolutely not.
Nononononono.
Nonononono.
Uh, that would
probably be because
the FBI knows
more than you do.
Uh, anything that's happening
in my neighborhood,
I have a right to know.
Uh, no, you actually don't.
You want to know.
And you do not have the
clearance that would allow you
Okay, all right!
You know,
when bad shit happens
in my neighborhood, I get
a little passionate about it.
I shouldn't have
read your files.
I went too far.
Well, I... I accept
your apology.
But you need to understand
that this is a highly
important case
and the information is
highly, highly sensitive.
Therefore, we have these
clearances that mean...
I don't have the clearances.
I mean, you're...
you are, wow, FBI.
Yes.
I mean, you are...
you're a goddamn
angel of the law.
Well, I... that's a little...
You know, I want you to spread
those wings out and just soar.
While I appreciate
the sentiment...
Hey!
...it's certainly not...
Watch it.
You watch it.
I'm a federal agent.
Well, guess what, you dick.
I'm a federal agent, too.
I work at the post office.
Well, I... I appreciate
the work you do for us
down on the ground.
Thank you. Thank you.
Bet your ass you do.
I can see no one will be
getting their mail today.
Wow.
Good burn. Good burn.
You got burned,
you big drunk paddy!
Kiss my cunt, you twat!
Yeah.
So we are...
Thank you.
Hey, America thanks you.
And I, it.
And it, you.
Thank you.
Whoaoa.
Yes, okay.
Good day.
Dumbass.
All prisoners, clear the yards.
Uh, I never heard of him.
Don't fucking lie to me.
You're my goddamn brother;
I know when you're lying.
I'm just a lowlevel guy.
Yeah, well,
he's a goddamn animal,
and I'm trying to keep him
from meeting you.
What, are you gonna
storm through Boston
Yeah, I might.
Yeah, unfortunately.
Yeah, shut up.
I... I'm coming home.
I'm gonna be fine.
Oh! Jesus!
Never approach me
if I'm not expecting you!
You said you would
stay off my case,
Right here in front of
Tatiana's apartment.
Oh, okay, that's hilarious.
That you stole
a confidential FBI case file.
Oh, that's funny,
I don't remember any of that.
I'm gonna say this
one more time.
Stand down, Officer.
Fuck off, Officer.
Now you've really done it.
I'm gonna call my boss.
Yeah, you do that,
tattle tits!
Fucking narc!
Unbelievable.
Hale.
It's Ashburn, sir.
I'm gonna need authorization
to suspend a police officer
from my investigation, sir.
Ashburn, why is working
with local authorities
I understand how this might
sound coming from me,
but I... I think this individual
might actually be
mentally unstable.
According to her captain,
she grew up on those streets
and she knows them
better than anyone.
That seems like an asset
to our investigation.
Nonono.
Sir, I...
Just work with her.
Just show me you can do this
or forget the promotion.
Well, sir, no need, no need
to take someone's badge.
I think I can, uh...
I think I can work
something out, sir.
All right.
Thank you.
Byebye.
You know, uh...
I just, I think just...
I think you and I
got off on the wrong foot.
Oh.
I don't know Boston,
and you obviously have
a  a lot of resources
and a lot of knowledge about
the area thatthat could be,
you know, could be useful.
Probably very.
So, uh, maybe we can
work together on this.
Yeah, I don't need your help
to take down Larkin.
You know, you wouldn't even
have known about Larkin
if it wasn't for me,
so obviously the FBI can
And there's a lot more
where that comes from... a lot.
Maybe I just need
to hear a little
"I need your help, Mullins. "
No, I won't be doing that.
Okay, well, get your ass
back in your car.
I'm an FBI agent,
you're a police officer.
It's not...
"I need your help,
Mullins. "
I need your help, Mullins.
I want that third floor
to hear it.
"I need your help, Mullins. "
And then maybe give me
a little echo on that "Mullins. "
I need your help, Mullins!
Mullins, Mullins...
Just move, move, move!
God.
Even in that,
you're annoying.
I will work with you,
as long as we're clear
that this is my case.
That's actually not correct.
This isn't your...  Awesome.
Glad you see it my way.
Careful of the car.
Goddamn it.
Stand down.
I got it.
If you just, if you just let go.
I think I have it, just...
I got it.
Just let me...
Geez.
Oh, shit.
Ma'am, you, uh...
Just go. Just go.
Okay, now let me
take the lead on this.
I just thought we were
gonna go in there
and bring in some heat on her.
Me and you, we're the heat.
We go in there,
we interrogate her,
we scare the shit
out of her...
See, we don't say
"interrogation. "
It's, it's much
too aggressive.
catch more
with sugar than a stick.
That's a horrible
fucking saying.
Okay, well, what we like to
do isis create aa genuine
personal interest
in the subject,
allowing them to open up.
But from then, I'm going to...
Oh, God.  ... uh, perform instant
personality assessments
based on the
MyersBriggs theory, uh,
Thematic Apperception
Tests, and a few...
well, a few others I won't,
I won't bore you with.
Oh, my God, well, that's...
I am balls deep in boredom.
All right,
as long as you don't do
that whole goddamn
long explanation again,
we'll try it your way first.
Okay.
Only 'cause you're older.
Oh, my God.
Tatiana Krumova.
I'm Special Agent
Sarah Ashburn,
and this is Detective Mullins.
Detective Mullins.
And we'd like to ask
you a few questions,
if you could give us a moment.
Oh, shoot, you know, now is bad.
Oh.
I'm making butter.
Oh. Oh, that's...
Right fucking now.
Well, Tatiana, thank you.
This is,
this is very kind of you.
So...
I've lived here
since I moved in.
Shit.
Okay, that's very,
very helpful.
Okay, we'll get a
little more specific.
Uh, what do you do
I know what this asshole
does for a living.
Okay, sugar, no stick.
No, I'm fucking French.
Oh, Jesus.
Tatiana...
I don't understand
what you're saying.
Nice bullshit Bulgarian.
I mean, I don't understand
what you're talking about.
Ah, okay.
So she did understand
what I was saying,
she just didn't understand
the context
in which I said it to her.
Oh, sweet God.
Okay, okay, all right,
Rosetta Stone, you're done.
God.
Oh, Jesus.
I'll get comfy.
When my foot's up your ass.
Wow.
That'll make me really comfy.
Stop.
Don't poke me.
Listen, Tatiana,
I want to get really real.
Let's get real.
Okay, we both
know you've been
blowing shit
up your nose all day.
Man, I get it.
There's nothing more
I'd love to do than
slip into my camisole, put
my feet up, have a little smack.
Real good time,
maybe a couple cold ones,
a little chip and dip,
watch some cartoons.
I'd get a big bowl
of fucking coke, I'd just
put my face right in it,
cut it with a little Ritalin.
Sure.
I'd camp out all week
for tickets to that show.
All fucking week,
I'd camp out for that.
But you, you piece of shit,
you've been rolling
deep for a long time,
and now it's time
you open up that goddamn mouth
and tell us what
we want to know.
You got good point.
I tell you what.
I open my mouth.
You get the fuck
out my house now!
Fuck out!
Get fuck out!
Yeah. I'll get
the fuck out.
All right.
You should really stop smoking,
'cause, uh...
it's an awfully bad habit.
You're leaving half your
lipstick in the ashtray.
I had a, uh,
great aunt that lost
most of her teeth
to, uh, smoking.
Good to know.
A lot of fistfights, too,
but, uh, mostly smoking.
We're gonna get
out of your hair.
So we're just gonna...
Put your hands where I
can fucking see them!
Don't fucking move.
Oh, my gosh. Oh, my goodness.
That's my mother!
You break my fucking door!
Stand down, Officer.
Get out!
Humans do.
Get out now.
You get out.
D  Don't touch underpants!
Thank you.
Get out, bull in china shop!
Out of my house!
Wow, you are just
all stick and no sugar.
Uh, uh, yeah, yeah,
ofofof course I did.
Yeah.
I snagged these matches, too.
I think our guy likes
to go to Club Ekko.
Okay, hold on.
Yes, yes, really.
All right, hang on.
That couch was disgusting;
I need to wash my hands.
That's what I said.
Oh.
Wow, your windows are all...
all boarded up.
Yeah, I've got the glass,
I just don't have the, you know,
the window blankets.
That's just my family.
That's...
Oh.
Yeah, it's sweet.
I didn't finish my submarine
sandwich from the other day.
Oh, God, no, thank you.
Thank you.
Well, I'm sorry I don't have
poached eggs in rubies for you.
No, I... I don't,
I don't mean to be rude,
but one could catch aa MRSA
infection in here, that's all.
Just for your,
for your own wellbeing.
I mean, for example, that door.
That door has absolutely
no way of locking.
Someone could barge in
at any moment.
It's not safe.
No one's coming in here,
'cause they know I keep this
fully stocked.
Oh, my God.
Yeah, I know.
Yeah.
Yeah. Nice one.
Yeah. You didn't even
mention my baby.
Look at this.
Oh, oh. Wow, wow.
My little pride and joy.
Okay.
This little beauty could
vaporize an aboveground pool,
You don't,
unless you're an asshole.
Wow.
No, God, that's...
occasionally ticks.
Put it back slowly.
Okay, okay.
Slowly!
I'm sorry.
Like, half that speed.
That's... God, okay.
Half that speed.
Stop sha...
Put your pinky down.
I got it on eBay.
It was supposed to be
bigger and different.
It doesn't matter.
I'm gonna "bad feedback"
his ass though.
All right, ladies.
Here's the DNA results
from the book of matches
and the cigarette butt
you got from Tatiana's.
We pulled two sets of prints.
First one's a real nut job.
Reckless driving,
assault, arson.
He's my assistant.
What...
God, I... I really feel the need
to finish reading your files,
because this is just, um...
I feel the need for you
to stay out of my business
so I don't punch you in the teeth.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Okay. Hank LeSoire.
Local businessman.
Got tons of ties to
the drug world, black market,
as well as prostitution rings.
Coowner of Club Ekko.
Well, it looks like we
found our distributor.
Hey! I'm not into you.
Your breast is invading
my space. It's just...
Well, keep your finger
out of my areola.
Well, contain your areola.
There. Now we're even.
Well, he looks like
a real Chatty Cathy.
I haven't been able to.
Guy gets a new prepaid
every other week.  Yeah.
By the time I can
get his phone number
and hack in,
he's got a new one.
Well, let's get a bug into
the phone this guy does have.
I want to know
what he's saying this week.
Yeah, just get
a court order and a bug,
and we'll just do it ourselves.
Right.
If you're gonna
boss me around,
you can at least
buy me dinner first.
No.
Okay. Cool.
I'll get that to you ASAP.
You gotta work on
your game.
That was weak.
I don't know
what to say to that.
Now I just feel bad for you.
Okay, so LeSoire
coowns Club Ekko.
Let's get over there
and start surveilling it
and figure out how to get
a bug in his phone.
Tell me everything
you know about it.
It's just a shitty
club downtown.
I've never been inside of it,
but there's always a line
of awful people
around the corner,
and they've called PD a couple
of times to break up fights...
Oh, shit.
Justjust don't look,
don't look... don't look!
Just act like we're talking.
Hey, Shannon.
Hey, Robin.
I really enjoyed our
night together, Shannon.
You just disappeared on me.
Yeah, I know.
I was there.
God, buddy, do you not
hear how pathetic
I mean, there's a girl
out there for you,
but it's not, it's not me.
Maybe it's her.
Her lady business is
like an old dirty attic.
It's full of broken Christmas lights
and, like, doll shoes and shit.
Why don't you
clean that out for her.
Uh, that's a,
that's a misrepresentation
of my vagina.
You sleep with a guy
one time,
and he wants to get
married to you.
Jesus Christ.
Yeah, I know
what you mean.
My mom.
Ortiz settles into
the batter's box.
Verlander with the pitch
and a ground ball
right side through the legs
of Cabrera into right field.
Pedroia is headed
for second base.
He slides and he is...
Oh, God.
Let's see.
I went to undergrad at Yale.
I have been with the
Bureau for about 12 years.
Um, up for a promotion.
See, I... I caught the,
um, I caught the Red...
the Red Falls Killer.
Yeah, I remember thinking
that guy was innocent.
Yeah, he's been in jail
for 11 months.
That would make me
a horrible person,
if any of what you said
was actually factual, so...
Well, you can just tell
the judge you fucked up.
I w... I... I... I didn't,
eh, I did not "F" up.
Listen, don't get
your panties in a wad.
Just...  They're not wadded,
I'm just... my...
I'm intuitive,
I say what I feel.
I'm usually right.
Oh.
Take it or leave it.
Oh, I didn't, I did not know.
Okay.
Hey, say hi to Tommy.
It's Tommy.
All right,
there's our guy.
I... I see him as well.
Over there.
We got to get past
those bodyguards.
We're not gonna have to,
'cause he's
gonna come to us.
Excuse me!
Step aside, please.
All right.
This is, this is
gonna go fast.
When I, when I pull
the alarm,
the crowds are gonna head
towards the two exits.
He's gonna head
towards the nearest one,
which is northeast; I will
bump into him in the crowd.
I will grab the cell,
place the bug within the phone,
tell him he dropped his phone.
It's, it's, uh, something I like
to call a "cop drop. "
Yeah. Got it.
Okay, here we go.
My God, there are absolutely
no wires attached to this thing.
All right, he's on the move.
Okay, we got to get
out there and shake
our asses like the
rest of the foxes.
Ah, oh, yes, yes, yes,
dancing to get close to him...
that is a fantastic idea.
Okay, here we go.
Jesus, don't do it.
But, but he's over that way.
Just... let's go
find a bathroom.
I told you, I don't have
to use the bathroom.
You are killing us
out there.
You don't fit in.
Take off that
fucking jacket.
Well, this is a, this is
a good jacket. This is...
and do their fucking taxes.
Take off your jacket.
Okay, jacket's off,
okay, jacket's off.
No, no, I can't watch whatever
process is about to happen.
Now unbutton
your buttons.
I'm a federal agent.
I don't...  Yeah, I know,
and you look like one.
Oh, God.  You think you're
gonna bump into him
I don't know how it's happening.
I think it's getting worse.
I... my fear is that I'm
gonna put you in a bikini
and you'll still look like
a fucking bank teller.
I'm trying to
make a point.
I'm saying your face
and whatever is underneath
this shitty outfit is maybe
not terrible.  Oh, okay.
I'll have you know
I dress appropriately.
I, I, I like to...
I got it, I got it.
It's when this...
your big flapping mouth...
starts running,
and then you put
th  this getup on top of it,
and it's, it's just a...
it's a boner killer,
and I'm gonna help you.
What are you doing, what are
you doing, what are you doing,
Oh, my God, just...
I, I only brought five
of these to Boston.
Then, I'll, I'll
cut the other four.
God, that's
terrible fabric.
This was...
Just get that off your wrist.
This was one
of my favorite ones.
Well...
God, just take it off,
take it off!
Just give me a second,
I'll take it off!
Okay, I, I look like
I've been attacked.
That's not my fault.
Let me even out the bottom.
I'm making shorts!
Everybody likes shorts.
Oh, my word.
Jesus, hold still.
Oh, please, just...
W... hey.
That feels awkward, weird.
Just don't touch that area.
Well, don't duck down.
You're gonna suck
my hand up there.
Stop pulling my pants off.
Stop, stop it.
They're my Spanx, they hold
everything together.
Nothing! It just keeps
everything
where it's supposed
to be, like in...
No, no, not medically,
just to...
Uh, just keeps it right
where it's supposed to be.
You got to, you got
to vent that furnace.
Okay.  That's a lot of
compression and heat.
It gets plenty of ventilation,
thank you.
My hand's a foot off and it's on fire.
Okay, okay, well, then
why don't you cut
these shorts shorter
Go ahead.
I'll cut 'em shorter.
No, I'm... stop it, we're finished.
Okay, let's
just do you now.
Come on, let's just...
I, I don't need,
I put out my sexuality
through motion.
When this starts
going, it's all...
You'll get it.
I know, it's not fair.
Oh, my God.
We got to tackle
the helmet.
Shit, you got to... you
got to flip that shit over.
You look like Darth Vader.
Just flip it over.
God Almighty.
God, just...
I gotta just finger tease
the shit out of this.
I'm going to
finger tease it.
Not what you want it to mean.
Hit it!
I like how your friend's shorts
make me feel in my shorts.
I am sorry, that was much cruder
than I meant it to be.
I stand corrected
on the shorts.
Let's proceed.
Oh, God, we're dead.
Ah, one o'clock, one o'clock.
Mm, yeah.
Let's do this.
All right.
Get in there,
get in there.
Yeah, baby, yeah, let's go.
Get in there.  Whoa.
Get your hands in, get your
hands in and get the phone.
Okay, Pinky. Yuck!
Do the fucking
cop drop.
I'm trying to!
Do the fucking cop drop!
Oh, baby.
I can't do it from this position!
No, no, no, no!
Okay, coming in one more time.
Get her away, get her away.
Aah!
I got her, I got her, I got her!
You're like a fucking gnat!
Picture time! Yes!
I got it, I got it, I got it,
I got it, I got it, I got it!
Let go, let go,
let go, let go, let go.
Thanks a lot, bro, and
close a couple buttons.
You Ahole. Ahole!
Club policy. Whoa, Jesus.
There we go.
God bless.
I got it,
I got the orange one.
Oh, my God, I need,
I need some water.
Stop it, stop it, stop it.
My God,
I will fucking kill you,
I will fucking kill you.
Get in there, get in there, go.
Okay, coming one more time.
Get her away, get her away.
Oh, my God.
Jesus, there's
too many of 'em.
Hey, all right, hi, hi.
Your moves are weird as shit.
I got it.  Aah!
Oh, yeah, oh,
it's the shampoo move.
Use your boobs.
Oh, yeah, uh, okay.
Use your boobs!
Yeah, look at 'em, look at 'em.
Oh, my... oh, my God.
I'm looking, I'm liking.
Shake it, yeah, shake it.
Oh, yeah.  Shove him in there,
shove him in there.
I'll get her, I'll get her.
Get her away.
Whoa, yeah!
No.
There we go.
Get in there, get in there.
Whoa, please.
Hi.
You know, you're the
first chick over 40
to give me a boner.
Great, great.
Okay, yeah.
Maybe, maybe.
It's the only reason
girls hit on me, I think.
'Cause every night,
the hottest chicks...
they come in here,
they're like,
"Hey, there's
LeSoire. "
Short skirts, too much
makeup, just looking
Yeah.
They turn into more sluts.
Fuck it.
Give me a whiskey.
I just noticed that lion,
that lion.
It's just... that is amazing.
Fuck, who the fuck keeps
Fourteen dollars.
Obviously.
Okay, all right.
Yeah, let's... I like
where this is going.
Me, too; me, too.
I love foam.
My nephew knows Seal.
Trying to get Seal
to come up in here.
Oh! I would love to, oh!
We're having a, uh...
Oh, I look forward...
Hey, hey!
Oh, shit...  I'm plastered.
So sorry.
Fuck, get up.
Let's go.
God, I am so sorry.
Hey!  Come on, honey,
get up. Drunk bitch.
Get her the fuck out
of here, guys, come on.
Oh, God, she holds her
liquor like a fiveyearold.
I'm so sorry.
Let's go.
I'm sorry.
All right, sweetheart, you're out.
I'm a pony!
Time to go.  Sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Get her the fuck out of... yeah,
take her home.  Come on, pony,
...let's go.  Hey, I got to drive
the school bus tomorrow.
It's my shift!
Here we go.
Come on, sweetheart, go.
I didn't get your number.
It's 21... 22...
I'll find you, I'll find you.
I have to say, that
was pretty awesome.
It really was, man.
Put 'er there.
Yeah... no, put 'er,
put 'er there.
Oh.
Aah!
Don't do that.
I'm trying so hard
not to lash out at you,
and you make it
really fucking
impossible.
Oh, shit.
Hold on,
No, I was a precision
driver at Quantico.
They thought I was the
instructor; I was that good.
Oh, shoot.
Let me steer it, I...
Stop it, stop it, I got it.
Hold on.
Ha!
And that, that is
how you lose a tail.
Nicely done.
Yes.
I'm surprised.
Our friends are back.
Just tell me what
you're doing.
Watch out!
Aah!
FBI! Drop your weapon!
Oh, my God.
Special Agent Garrett, DEA!
Drop it!
DEA. Drop your fucking gun!
Now!
Shit.
I'm, I'm very sorry
about earlier.
I just thought you
were an assassin
'cause of your weapon.
And because you
look evil as shit.
No, no, that's not...
Yeah.
That's not what we were...
Yeah, well, I'm DEA.
Hmm.
And let me tell
you something.
Two months we been
sitting on that club,
and then you two come
in here one night
like a couple of
fucking amateurs,
and you almost blow the whole thing!
All right,
obviously you have no idea
who you're speaking with.
I'm Federal Agent
Sarah Ashburn...
Yes, I am sure your
credentials are
quite impressive, as is your
choice of wardrobe there.
Nice hot pants.
You might want to try
shshaving above the knee
next time.
This whole "female
professionals
But here's the problem, all
due respect, with you people...
is that you get
all excited,
you let your emotions
take over,
your hormones kick in,
you're riding the cotton pony.
The next thing you know,
you're complimenting the bad guy
on his fucking couch!
Oh, well, all due respect
to you, who's your wife,
Hey, hey, hey,
hey, listen, ma'ams,
we've been cramped inside this
van for two months, all right,
and we're not gonna let you
swoop in from out of nowhere
and take all the credit.
I don't want to see you two
anywhere near this case.
We have got informants
everywhere.
We've got surveillance
We do not need
the two of you
coming in with your estrogen
flying at full speed,
sticking out in the middle
of broad daylight,
fucking things
up for us.
'Cause the two of
us are gonna bring
these guys in.
Shit.
Fuck you,
chalk balls.
Not even on your
birthday, sweetheart.
That's right, keep walking.
This isn't over.
And FYI, women were b...
we were born
with hair on our legs.
Yeah.
You don't have to stop.
Whoawhoawhoawhoa
whoawhoawhoa!
Get...
Nothing.  I saw your face when
you were looking at the footage.
It looked like you
saw someone you knew.
You did not read that
from my fucking face.
God, you're an asshole.
Okay, yes,
I read your file, but
it is my job to know
everything about a case,
including who I work with.
I don't like that.
We should talk
to him tomorrow.
Probably at my parents'.
Well, then, let's go
to your parents'.
I'm the one that put him in jail.
Okay, never mind.
It's not like
I liked doing it.
You know, he got mixed up with
a lot of really bad people
and then he started...
he started using that shit,
and I just had
to get him out of there.
You know, iironically, a lot
of people become addicted
when they're in...
in prison.
I think it's like 80,
85% of the inmates
require treatment.
I hate you.
Yeah, I know;
I'm sorry.
But I... you know,
I actually wasn't finished.
I was going to say...
These are cloth, they're nice.
I could have shot you.
Oh, I'm sorry,
Oh, come on.
I, I glanced at your file.
You broke into my home.
I care about who
I'm working with, too,
and it's a little
uncomfortable
that you feel the need
to travel with trophies.
Okay, well, it's,
it's not what you think.
They moved me up here, they
rented this apartment, and,
and this is all my stuff.
Yes.
Oh, God.
I don't think that could be
any sadder if you threw it all
in the trash bag and started
dragging it behind you.
Oh, my word, you,
you use coffee filters
for toilet paper at your house.
I'm buying 'em anyway;
they have a dual purpose.
That's not what they're for.
Yeah, real fancypants.
I see it; I see it in here.
Because you weren't.
My favorite part is,
you only have two signatures,
both by teachers.
Mrs. Burke said,
"Have a good summer. "
That's a personal touch.
And then my real favorite
is this one.
"It'll get better. "
Yes, fine.
Okay, now we're even.
Okay.
I see you have a cat.
Yep.
you know, pet him and stuff.
He ran away, uh,
when I was in New York.
Oh, God,
that kind of tears me up.
Yeah, it was, um, it was a loss.
That cat got one look
at your shitty life
and said,
"No fucking thanks, man.
I am out of here. "
I'm still
kind of just grieving
a little bit about it.
That fucking tabby is
an asshole, that's what he is.
Fuck you.
Fuck you...
that's what I say to that cat.
Goddamn it.
Oh.
Such a shitty, shitty little life.
Even the... you can't
even keep a cat.
Ah, you know, that just
hurts a little bit.
That's just the grief.
No, not the grief.
It's just the, the pounding
a little bit, just...
Oh.
All right, well, don't be
a dick about it, but...
Well, thank you for that.
That was...
I gotta change.
It's, it's pajamas.
Well, excuse
the shit out of me.
I didn't realize you slept
in a fucking tux.
W...
Go ahead, get your top hat.
You could get a girlfriend
and get a job.
You don't swear at me.
This is the place
where you're supposed
to be civilized.
Okay, stop yelling at everybody.
be a mother.
I don't know why your whole family
is jealous of me, then.
Be a mother for once
Oh, great, this asshole.
All right, just take it easy.
Hey, Pop.
Hey, pork chop.
Ah, well, well, well,
look who it is.
Yeah, the rat's back in the house.
Nice.
Hey, you know, I saw Ma threw
a can of, uh, Diet Coke
in the garbage the other day.
She didn't even recycle it.
Dad here... he's splicing cable
off the neighbors next door.
Hey, come on, now, Mark.
Petey over here,
how many, how many songs
Ten, 20,000.
20,000.
Mikey stole a laptop
from his work
the other day.
I deserved
to fucking take it.
Exactly... no health insurance.
That balances out, but not you.
Uh, actually she could,
'cause these are
horrible examples.
Here are the nuggies.
All right, here we go.
This kind of animal,
right here.
Shut up, shut up.
I was the only one
that got him off the street.
None of you fucks did.
You should never
arrest your family.
Well, tell Gina I'm going to
strangle her at the table.
Hey, she is
my best friend.
You touch her, you got
to go through me first.
I'll kill you and kill her
with your fucking dead body!
Okay, everybody calm down.
Shannon's right.
This one has no business
chiming in on a family matter.
She wears sweatpants
to your mother's dinner,
that's why.
Those are
her classy sweatpants.
They don't say
"Insert Here" on the ass.
Her ass is hanging out!
Look at her, look at her breasts
at the table!
Welcome home.
Hey.
No, she's... Ashburn.
Let's go, let's go.
We need to talk. Go.
Sit down.
Get your hands off me.
Uh, that is, uh,
that's one of the,
uh, better Jesus sportsthemed
paintings I've seen.
That's very good, nice.
'Cause I know everything,
that's why.
No, no, this guy Julian...
he sent for me
because he wants me to
start working for him,
but I told him, "No,
I'm getting a straight
job," and it's fine.
We're... everybody's cool now.
Wewe... parted amicably.
A knock. I d... I'm sorry,
I don't know what that is.
A knock.
Yeah, listen to him.
I'm gonna sound
it out for you.
Are you or are you not...
A fucking knock.
Like Johnny Depp
in 21 Jump Street.
Ah, I see, I see,
okay, aa narc.
A knock, yes.
Ah, yes, yes... no, I...
I was missing the "R"
when you were saying...
I heard "knock",
but apparently there's a "C. "
He said, he said "knock. "
I said,
It's hot out.
Eh, I'm, I'm a little
fluey, I was...
It's nothing.
You want, you want me
Mercy, mercy, mercy.
Straighten that arm.
Uh, it looks worse
than it is.
ItIt's not a big deal.
This guy Julian,
you know,
they don't want me to stop
working, they like me.
You tell me where I can find
Julian right now.
No, just stay out of it.
They're fucking maniacs.
They'll chop you up oor
gun you down or worse.
Okay, we're...
Jason, tell me what you fucking know.
I don't know anything.
I, I... ouch!
D  D  DDon't.
Okay, Sal, Sal Natale.
I'll rip it open.
Of course I know Sal Natale.
He was going to steal
this huge shipment
they got coming in,
so they popped him.
He's in the trunk
of his Caddy
under the Charles
River Bridge.
I want you to stay
in this house.
If I catch you
out of this house,
I'm gonna hurt you
worse than them.
I'm a special agent, and I...
Well, we don't use that word.
We say "special needs,"
but II have a very high IQ.
That's a fair question.
Uh, I'm, I'm female.
No kidding.
All woman.
Um...
From birth, yes.
I need to go,
but I'll be back to, um...
...to... uh, yeah, thank you.
Yep, that's Sal Natale,
all right. Hmm.
Bullet hole
through the head.
That's unusually
civilized for them.
Oh, they cut out
his tongue, too.
Ah, there you have it.
They like to send
a message.
Shoved it up his anal cavity.
Mmm.
Ooh, that's a weird message.
Yeah.
The tip of the tongue
was sticking out of the rectum,
so it made it appear as if
his buttocks were giving
the police the raspberry.
No.
Seems like kind of
an opportunity missed.
That would have been funny.
Well, II feel that they were
just trying to be
tongueincheek.
God, don't do that.
No.  We're still looking
for their base camp.
Well, if there's anything on him
that will tell us,
I will find it.
I don't think so.
It's more like a coating.
Same traces found
on all the victims' shoes.
All of them had...
That's right.
Yeah.
And each sample was made up
of the same ingredient,
which probably means
that they...
They were all killed,
same place.
Exactly.
I checked it out.
Wow.
There are three places
that have this kind of powder.
Paint factory. Yes.
Yeah.
I think we all know that.
Well, it's...
Take a look at this.
This one right here is centered
in the location...
Where all four...
Where all four dead...
... bodies were found. Yeah.
... dead bodies were found.
Right.
That's what I thought.
This one shut down years ago,
owned by a man by the name
of Leif Sa...
Samber...
Old Sagglemint.
Santino.
Santino. Santino.
Oh, Santino. Santino.
Get me the address
to that paint factory ASAP.
Okay, this is a little awkward.
Uh, it's nothing personal,
but as a rule,
I... I make it a point
not to date my coworkers,
so... thank you.
I was wondering if you would not
talk to me in that tone.
Oh. Oh! Yes, of course.
That's a little different.
Of course, yeah.
Just, we should go
to the paint factory.
It got real awkward
between you guys.
Uh, we're...
We're really good.
Same page.
Yeah.
'Cause I don't want any bad...
I think we are.
Let's go to the paint factory.
She doesn't want
to date coworkers,
so spread the word.
Shut up.
Stop it.
Just cover me and go right.
Well, then, say that.
Stop making me want
to shoot you.
I don't know
what your problem is,
but we told you...
stay out of the city.
I don't know what it is.
Shh.
I got to do something
with you, man.
Look, Julian.
I'm sorry.
I'll sell for you guys,
whatever you want me to do.
I'm just trying to make
some extra money.
Relax. I totally get it.
Thank you, man.
I'm not going to shoot you.
Okay.
It's cool, man. Thanks.
He is.
Wait, wait, hold on,
hold on, hold on!
Shit.
All right, if...
if we grab Julian,
I can get into his head
and we'll have Larkin
by tonight.
Two against two.
I like those odds.
I'm going to call
for backup.
It's already here.
Oh, hey.
Shit.
I was looking for you.
Um, I forgot to get
your number.
Cool. Yeah.
Uh, it's 1800
givemeyourfuckingguns.
That's... that's, uh...
that's... that's too many numbers.
Okay.
Met these disasters
at the club the other night.
Now they're both here.
Give me a break.
even older in this lighting.
Come on.
Fuck you.
Fuck you!
It's not "fuck me. "
It's "fuck you. "
Because I'm about
to fuck you up.
Pick it up.
Do it.
Give me a reason
to shoot you in the face.
I don't know.
Maybe 12 hours, hopefully less.
I have... I have to find out
what drives him.
We could just go in there
and beat him with a phone book.
It is crucial... crucial
that you remain patient.
It's also crucial
that you stop wearing
I mean, you have one
on your head.
Yeah, on top of my head,
like a normal person.
Okay, if you enter that room,
Just please, please,
trust me on this one.
Yeah, I do.
I will.
Okay. All right.
Hello.
I drink a little more coffee
than I probably should.
I... Aah!
Oh, my...
You thinking you're
going to make me talk.
Yeah, you're talking
right now, dumbass.
You know, you look like one
of the Campbell's soup kids
who grew up and
became an alcoholic.
Oh, surprisingly catty.
You're a fucking genius.
I asked you to stay outside.
I need to go tough on him.
No.
I'm doing good cop/bad cop.
You know,
I can hear you.
Shut up.
Just, please,
don't do anything crazy.
I'm not going to do
anything crazy.
You said nothing crazy,
and that is a nono.
Nono!
Turn around. I need you
to pass a polygraph.
Put it away.
Turn around.
No!  Don't worry.
She's not going to do it.
She's not going
to do anything.
Oh, okay, so you want
to just...
you just want to go
and gamble
Okay, gamble away.
Just go to the corner.
I'm in it.
I'll tell you what
we're going to do.
We're going to play
a little game.
Except for this one,
'cause this is my favorite.
I'm going to keep that in there.
And then you're going to tell me
where Larkin is,
and you're going to tell me
where and when
Right now.
I'm going to kill you
and everyone you know.
Aah! God, no.
Hey, straight arrow, take the
gun out of this one's hand.
Hey, hey, all right!
ThThere's a shipment
on Wednesday.
I swear.
I swear to God, I don't know!
Tell her! Just tell her where it is!
I swear to God!
I don't know! Jesus Christ,
don't shoot me in the dick!
I don't know!
It's going to be on Wednesday!
That's four shots!
Don't take any more shots!
Don't shoot my dick off!
No! Just tell her
where it's coming in!
Honest to God, I don't
know where the drop is!
Don't shoot me in the dick!
Hey! Enough! Stop it!
Hey! Hey!
Wasn't too smart.
Oh, okay, so you're
not supposed
to arrest someone
when they commit murder
and then turn around
and try and kill you
You shouldn't even
have been there!
Larkin is the big catch here,
not those two.
Now we're never going to be able
to bring these fucking guy...
Enough. Craig, calm the hell
down. We can all hear you.
Yeah, dogs can hear you.
Yeah, of course
dogs can hear me.
'Cause you...
you look really pale.
It's a genetic condition!
Ashburn, come here.
Fucking snow cone.
Oh, I get it.
That's a good one,
'cause I'm really white.
I'm good.
All right. I'm going to be
right over there.
Right there.
Thank you.
Ashburn, why didn't you
alert anyone
Sir, it was an unconfirmed lead.
I wasn't going to waste anyone's
time until I knew it was real.
Just give it a rest.
I want you to stand down
while I figure out
how to repair
all this shit with the DEA.
Sir, no, please.
I... I swear, I've...
I've been doing everything
that you sent me out here to do.
I... we've been doing
such good work.
I know. I know you are.
It's just...
I don't know, it's...
never easy
when you are involved.
Fuck that guy.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
We should go get a drink.
That's what I'm talking about.
Oh, II said just...
I just want one.
Yeah, oh, no, no. Here.
It is one. It is one.
Sometimes he just...
he likes to do this thing,
he pours them
in three little glasses,
but it's one.
All right. Here we go.
Fair enough.
Let's loosen that up.
Okeydokey.
There you go.
Keep a pace.
Okay.
Don't spit that shit out.
It's not free.
Let's go.
Keep that in.
Hey.
Ooh.
I haven't heard
from you.
Shit.
No. Yeah, you haven't.
Okay, here we go.
It's not you; it's me.
Uh, I'm still working on myself,
so I can't be a part of two
until I'm a better one.
Okay, don't.
You don't have to do that.
Uh, wait, I still...
my favorite's coming.
Oh. You make me want
to be a better woman.
Yeah, I... we did have
a lot of fun.
And now we're
going to move on.
Let it go.
Okay.
All right. Cool.
All right.
Oh...
Okay.
Okay, hit it.
Hit it.
Okay. Okay.
Bye.
Bye. That's good.
I don't know how
else to say it.
It's pretty clear.
Yeah.
That's why you don't...
you don't feed strays.
Yeah.
Six.
I don't know, Mullins.
It's hard.
I know we're not
supposed to say this,
but being a woman
in this field is hard.
Well...
And then you put your
personality on top of that,
and it is...
Mmhmm.
...it is offputting.
You know, I was, uh...
I was actually married for...
for six some years... same guy.
Yeah, he didn't, uh...
he didn't understand
how much the job meant to me,
so I thought it'd
probably be best
to just be alone
rather than to, you know,
compromise the work.
I get that.
Yeah. Yeah.
It's kind of weird that it does
get lonely a little bit.
You know, and it's...
it's hard to make
female friends.
Yeah.
I hung out, you know...
really just with my...
my brothers and stuff
growing up, and...
Yeah.
they just kind of all turned out
to be terrible people.
So that's kind of a bummer.
Your f... your family loves you.
I mean, in their own
unique... unique way,
but they... you know,
theythey love you,
and that's a wonderful...
Very unique.
That sounds like
it's coming from...
somebody
that's an only child.
No, I...
I was actually raised with
a lot of children, so I had...
Uh, no, just in...
in the houses.
Oh, my God.
You're a foster kid.
Yes, I was.
Oh, my God.
Yes.
No...  Jesus, that
clears up a lot.
Foster... foster kid.
That makes sense.
That's a tough go of it.
No, it was totally fine.
There was a lot
of benefits
toto being a foster kid.
on Christmases, there was
thisthis local drug store
it would sponsor...
sponsor us
and give us little baggies of,
you know, toiletries, and stuff.
On Thanksgiving...
Oh, shit.
we would... we would hit
these different
puttputt golf courses.
It was, you know,
you'd meet all kinds of
Yeah, no. No, no, no.
Oh, Jesus.
That is the saddest series
of images I've ever heard.
No, I don't think it
affected me...
I mean, in the long run,
at all; at all.
You're probably fine.
You know, I can see how maybe
it was, you know,
like, a little bit,
but not anything that's...
A little bit.
Oh, God, my life.
Yeah. Okay.
Ugh. Oh, God.
All right. Yep.
All right. Let it out.
That's it.
Oh, God.
Good for you to start
working through it.
I don't feel well.
Oh, Jesus.
I don't feel well. I don't...
I... Wow.  Well, you're
not making me feel great.
All right.
Get it, get it.
Blow it out.
Really let it go.
You've got more than that.
You've got more than...
Oh!
Good job. Hey.
Oh, God, I don't feel well.
Oh, God.
Oh, God, I feel sick.
Let's hear it!
This is for you.
Sex walk.
Look at it,
look at it, look at it!
Look at it.
Giving it to you, and...
"My name...
You'd better lay
your ass down. "
I smell bacon. I smell bacon.
I smell bacon.
Ooh, ooh.
Biscuits are done.
Big finish. Big finish.
Yes!
Yeah!  Let's do it again.
Let's do it again.
No!
Because you played it
26 fucking times.  Hey!
She's a foster kid.
Yeah.
She got, like, Q  tips and...
tampons and shit
for Christmas.
Yeah.
She's had a horrible,
Yeah. Yeah!
fucking, miserable life.
Look at her!
Yeah!
All right.
Play the goddamn song.
Don't you fucking swear at us.
Ooh...
Oh, are we going to...
Yes.
You celebrate your music.
Okay. Okay.
Everybody, get up.
Come dance! Come on!
Get up, you fuck!
Whoo! Get on.
Look, it's a frenzy.
We started a frenzy.
You're covered in nuts.
You're having a bad dream.
Uhuh.
let's give them
a little something...
Hold... God, hold still.
I love this place.
Yeah. Yeah.
Hey, to this...
to this place.
To this place.
I don't feel it.
Keep it up.
Oh, crap.
Oh, f...
Hey. Hey.
Hey.
Oh, crap.
Okay, focus.
Here's this.
This counts as something.
That's it.
I'm all in.
Jesus, you've got to get
a mint in that Dumpster.
Oh, God.
Yeah, you kept
taking them out
of people's mouths
and smoking them.
Oh, God, that's so nasty.
Oh, yeah, don't worry about it.
I'll get it right back.
All right,
let's see what you got.
Oh, shit.
That's great.
Good evening.
There you go.
I didn't think you were
going to care that much
about your jacket.
You didn't care at all
when you gave away your car.
Wayne.
He just walked out of here.
You were sitting
on his lap all night.
You had your tongue
down his throat.
Oh, God.
Feels like we've been
hibernating.
Didn't bother you
last night.
Oh, Jesus,
ten missed messages.
Hey, Wayne! Ashburn wants
her underwear back!
I do not!
You cannot take that car.
It's government property.
Well, I pay taxes,
so fuck the government!
Wayne, get out of
the car, you asshole.
Oh, God.
Oh, my God.
Oh, shit, Wayne.
God, your first boyfriend.
You two were electric.
Federal marshals transferring
him got ambushed.
We're not sure whether Larkin's
men followed the marshals
or if they got information
from the inside.
Oh, fuck you!
I know when I smell
a fucking albino rat.
If you want to be pointing
a finger around here,
All right, yeah.
No, because if
you two hadn't
brought Julian in,
then Larkin would've never even
known that we were onto him.
And then this whole case
wouldn't be
the giant mixedup bucket
of shit that it is right now.
So fuck you
and your albino prejudice!
Now Larkin knows who you are,
and Julian's angry as shit.
If I were you, I would
get out of town.
Ashburn, he's right.
This isn't a choice.
No! No way!
You're not my boss,
Puss in Boots.
And even if you were my boss,
you still couldn't stop me.
I have more invested in this
case than any of you assholes.
Yep, thanks.
That's another
fuckedup area of my life.
Thanks for bringing it up.
No, this was
just emailed to me.
Yeah, I'm gonna step back and
see what you assholes can do.
Yeah, go USA. Let's go.
We got to get my
family out of there.
They're gonna kill them.
You know, let me
just talk to Hale.
The FBI can
arrange everything.
And I'm assuming it's
the fucking albino,
but we don't know.
Could be Levy.
It could be somebody
from my own precinct.
It could be your boss,
Puss in Boots.
We are going in there by
ourselves and doing it now.
Okay, okay.
This is bullshit.
Go.
Hey, don't talk to her like that.
It's not her fault.
No, but it'd be like
Schindler's List. Dad! Come on!
We cannot
fit that in the car!
I don't want them to take
my treasures.  Jesus.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
I'm hoping, I'm hoping it's Vegas.
I thought you were outside.
Say byebye.
'Cause I'll get my boobs
done if we go there.
Say byebye. Say byebye.
Say byebye.  No, no, no, no.
I'll call you when
I get there.  Ow.
You are so rude.
I know. I'm so sorry.
This is my house.
Can you just go outside.
I'll be right there.
Outside.
Holy shit, I can see through
your shirt.
Just let 'em try to come over
here, Shan. Just let 'em try.
They're not going to throw softballs at
you... they're going to shoot you, moron.
Get your bag.  Oh, would you
get over yourself, for Christ sake.
Bring it on, motherfuckers!
Not you, Mrs. Amendola.
No, but if you could
make your way around...
Why don't you get
out and I'll drive.
But if you could make your...
I'm a really good driver.
Mullins!
Your mom, your mom.
Our lives are in danger.
Ma! Ma!
I may have to change my name.
Hey, come on.
from someone named Carla, it's me.
Stop! God Almighty!
All right, seat
belts, everyone.
Come on, buddy.
Right in here, buddy.
No, no. Highly allergic.
That's my puppy. I got him four months ago.
Highly allergic.
I named him Kevin Garnett.
No. No.
You're an asshole.
You got to see the cock on this thing.
We're going to a motel.
We're not bring... Move.
We're not bringing this
fucking horse to a motel.
Because you put
her fucking life in danger!
Nobody gives a
shit about her.
If I'm going, Gina's going.
Get in there.
I'm not going unless we get Gina.
Just get in.
We're getting Gina.
Move your feet!
I'll chop them off.
Thank you.
Shut up!
We're going to Gina's!
Everyone put your seat belt on.
God, I hope a truck hits us
and we all die.
Oh, God.
Go get your girlfriend,
for God's sake.
Um, okay, please.
She's fine, Ma!
I forgot my curling iron,
Mrs. Mullins!
Come on, Gina!
Get in the car!
I got you the rollie
so you could roll the bag,
so get over here!
Gina, come on.
Let's go.
I'm gonna get you
a dicksucker for Christmas,
so I don't have to do it
no more.
Go get her!
I'mI'm going!
Jesus Christ!
Gina!
You really...
you didn't say that.
Oh, that got
your attention.
Go on, go get her.
Come on, Pete,
just break up with this girl,
for fuck sakes.
This'll help.
Come on, you're making a scene!
Let's go, let's go!
Knock it off!
Just knock it off!
I got this, I got this!
Come on.
Hey, assholes!
Get in the car.
You animals!
Whoa!
Get in the car!
You don't get this one!
No.
So, uh, Jason, your
family seemsseems nice.
Yeah, we, uh, we have
our good days.
But my makeup is in that one!
I'll rip
your fucking pants off!
If we just knew
where that shipment was
coming into, we would have,
we would have Larkin and
we would have Julian,
they would both be there,
and we could get them.
I'm just happy that Jason, you
know, is out of there for now.
Yeah.
It's a shame, though.
Having your brother
on the inside
would be a, would
be a coup for us.
'Cause you're saying that
out loud.
You would say exactly the same
thing if it wasn't your brother.
We're done talking about this.
So, if it was just
some random drug dealer,
If it was
someone like,
I don't know, Rojas,
you wouldn't...
We're talking about Jason,
my brother, you fuckwit.
a lot to lose
if we don't catch Larkin.
You don't give a shit
about my family
or if Jason gets out there
and gets killed.
I feel that you're not
being honest.
Because nobody,
nobody forced your brother
to get involved with drugs.
You're an asshole for that.
See, I'm trying to
create a dialogue.
Note that I am starting my
statements with "I feel. "
I feel...
Oh, I feel like you're an asshole.
I feel that you have
worn that shirt
every single day this week,
and I feel that you turning it
inside out does not
make it a new shirt.
Well, I feel like it does.
Must be nice.
for you to just know everything.
To be so much smarter
than everybody else.
I... I don't profess
to know everything,
but I do know quite a bit.
And what I know is accurate
and scientifically proven,
and I just share
that information with you.
If you have a problem with that,
tune me out
like you always do.
Help! He's choking!
Okay, I've got it, I've got it.
He's choking, help!
Sir.
Somebody call an ambulance!
Okay, I got it. I got it.
Call...
Check his mouth,
check his mouth!
Nothing in there!
Okay, all right.
Let's lay him down.
Sir, just relax.
Everything will be just fine.
Let me get his head back.
He's choking.
You're gonna be okay.
I need a, I need a knife
and a straw please!
I need a knife
perform an emergency
tracheotomy.
Vodka! It's a Denny's!
Uh, for sterilization...
hot water.
Technically, technically,
no, but I've been,
I've been doing some
research, and I feel
Jesus! He's still choking,
you know. It isn't time to stop.
Okay, sir, what I'm gonna do
is I'm gonna find your...
Oh, God, don't, please don't
put that in there.  Shh.
Stop touching me... so, the
cricothyroid membrane...
I think, I think
it's right here.
I'm gonna make a small incision.
Please don't do that.
Let go of my hand, let go of
my hand, let go of my hand.
I'm gonna make
a small incision.
The reason I'm
doing this... Oh!
Oh, God.
...is because
you're choking.
I'm gonna cut in...
Wow, okay,
just a little bigger.
Wow, okay, that goes in
deeper than I thought.
I'm gonna insert my fingers in
here because what's happening is...
Don't put your
finger in there.
Don't put your finger in there.
Wow, that feels a lot different.
It's a fucking horror show!
Don't put your fingers
in there!
Sir, what I'm gonna do
is I'm going to insert
the straw in the hole.
And it's gonna allow the
oxygen to get to your brain.
Now if you give
it one moment,
you're gonna feel the oxygen
flow into your brain.
There we go.
That's not oxygen!
Jesus Christ, that's not oxygen!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Oh, my God, ah!
Oh, Jesus!
Oh, my God, there's
so much blood!
I don't know
what I'm doing!
Stop crying! You did this!
I'm so sorry!
I got it, I got it, I got it, move!
So much blood!
You asshole!
Oh, my God!
You probably could have just
pulled the piece of pancake
out of his throat.
Yeah, neither are you.
Okay.
Yeah, byebye.
You're a reckless person.
See you later. Yeah, thank you.
Okay, thank you.
Byebye.
Not you.
Oh, my God.
Ashburn.
Fuck you.
You... "F" you.
Look, I talked to them,
Nothing's weird, we're good.
Nonono, nonono!
It doesn't work that way, Jason.
They know you're my brother.
Yeah, but they also know
you arrested me,
and I made it seem
Shut up for a minute.
Okay, I don't give a shit
about the shipment!
Let me talk...
Look, I'm gonna stick around
and work it or they're
gonna know something's weird.
Get off me.
No, it's my phone.
Please trust me... I... I'm trying
to do the right thing here.
Jason, Jason. Ow.
Jesus Christ. Jason!
Ow! Let go of my vest.
Shan.
Ow. Jason, it's Ashburn.
Don't talk to her!
Look, the shipment's coming
into the Boston Harbor Shipyard
at 11:00.
No, I got it, I got...
They're gonna be heavily armed,
Okay, okay.
God, get off!
The ship is called the, uh,
I promise we'll be there.
All right, II got to go.
Thank you.
I'll break
your fucking arm!
God!
Okay, take it easy.
Just take, just take it
easy, just take it easy.
Just...
Shit!
You just made
my brother a dead man!
No, no, he's
gonna be fine.
Mullins, I swear,
he'll be fine.
We'll... we're gonna
have thethe full power
of the, uh,
the Boston FBI
down on that terminal tonight,
I promise you.
He's gonna be fine.
It really is
a good thing.
You'llyou'll thank me.
Shut up!
All right.
Ship's coming in.
Time to lock and load.
Okay, here we go.
Here we go.
Police. Put your hands up.
FBI!
Get your fucking hands
in the air! Now!
Let's see them!
Boat's clean.
It'sit's not clean.
We found a joint in
that girl's purse. If...
Oh, now,
this is really a mess.
Sir, we just, we just have
to hit the streets again.
We hit the streets,
a  and if the shipment came in...
Ashburn, enough.
It's over. I'm sending you
back to New York.
Sir, sir, nononono,
please, please.
I'mI'm telling you,
I'm so close.
I'm so close, and this was
just a little hiccup.
No, it wasn't a hiccup.
Lo siento.
Don't...
Don't even... Oh, God.
Uh, um, sorry.
Oh, hospital.
Some kind of family emergency.
Oh, God.
He's in an induced coma.
They shot him and left him
out in the street.
I'm so sorry, Mullins.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, he was trying
to move on.
He had a job interview.
I... I saw the résumé.
It was a terrible résumé.
He... mentioned prison,
and in "special skills,"
he said, "Keeping it real,"
but he...
he was trying.
Well, they're not talking to me.
Blame me more now than ever.
It's not your fault.
Yes, it is.
Damn it, I should have
handled it by myself.
No, you're not.
You're another
fucking disappointment.
I just want you to know
that I'm gonna find
the man responsible for this.
Hey, Shan.
Uh, that was wicked rude.
Ugh, God.
Hi.
Hey.
I'll give these back to you.
Thank you so much for your help.
Anytime.
Hey...
We're gonna miss you
around here.
Oh, I don't think so.
I might.
Oh...
You did a good
job out there.
Just keep your fingers
out of guys' necks.
It's nasty.
Bye.
All right, if anybody
has any questions,
you come to Adam or myself.
That's all we got.
All right.
We sent out alerts to airports,
train stations.
Now, although this is
a joint task force, we're also
working with the Boston PD.
Right. Adam and I are gonna be
handpicking all the officers
so we don't wind up with this.
Ooh, ooh.
Hey.
Hey, that's not right.
No, it's not.
No, that officer
that you're making fun of,
the one that you're all
laughing at, has more integrity,
more commitment, more courage
and more guts
than anybody in this room.
Yeah.
But less mental stability.
Okay, okay, so, um,
justjust to be clear,
If that's what
mental instability looks like,
sign me up for the crazy house.
That officer right there
is a better
law enforcement officer
than anybody in this room.
Myself included.
She is better than you,
she is better than you,
and she's definitely
better than you.
Put it away.
God, you guys are just...
You're such,
you're just such jerks!
You're just such...
You're just a shitjerk!
You're just a shitjerk
dickfucker!
You're a shitjerk
dickfucker assholer!
And you all can just
go fuck yourselves!
Not... sorry, senor, not you.
Pardon, please.
Just, all you fuckers!
Get on the ground!
You are under arrest! Put your
hands where I can see them,
and tell me
where the fuck Larkin is!
Hey.
I think it'd be much more better
if you put your hands up.
Drop the gun and take
a grammar course, you idiot.
We're the fuckin' heat.
All right.
Yeah, we do.
Get up, asshole.
Let's go.
I don't know
who the fuck that is!
Right there!
Got your pizza.
Got your pizza, mister.
Just a minute, Lou.
Fresh hot pizza.
Get on your knees!
I'm waiting to get some
from a new distributor.
Oh, shit, man.
Guess who.
Surprise.
Hey, man, come on, man!
Listen, I don't know
what y'all doing here!
I'm out the game.
I'm a different man.
This is not mine.
I just bought that refrigerator
the other day.
This must have been in there.
We want to know where all
this new shit is coming from.
I'm out!
Mm, no.
No, I think I have
something better in mind.
Oh, shit!
I don't know shit!
Come on!
I don't know, you're getting
awfully heavy, Rojas.
Yeah, lie to me again.
I want to feel your body sliding
through my delicate hands.
I don't know shit!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
I can't, I can't hold you.
No, I don't want to die!
I don't want to die!
Okay, okay!
It's at a warehouse
on Summer Street!
I'm almost disappointed.
Get me up!
All right, let's
pull him up.
No, wait, I'm not
kidding anymore.
No!
I can't lift him.
Shit, I've only done this
one other time,
and it was a really tiny hooker!
Lift my ass up!
You ain't fucking putting
nobody over no rails
you can't fucking lift them out!
Okay, okay.
Uh... just tuck your head
and relax your body.
God...
Crap. Crap.
Get me up! Let me out!
Thankthank you again.
Thank you.
That was on me.
I take that.
I hope this ain't my car.
Oh, shit!
My 2003!
Let's load up.
Nonononono.
Yes, yes.  No, no,
you said that thing ticks.
Yeah, but not for days.
I got a sandwich
I didn't finish.
It's cheese.
Cheese doesn't go bad.
Baby formula.
Yeah.
Cartels have been
smuggling cocaine
in baby formula for years.
Two of them, two of us.
I like those odds.
Boston PD!
FBI!
Get down on
the ground!
That's right, that's how we roll.
Come on.
You guys all coming back
Unfortunate.
You guys get less attractive
every time I see you.
Put the fucking guns down.
No, thanks.
Nice entrance,
Teen Wolf.
I've held someone at gunpoint
for 72 hours before... let's go.
It's the, it's the best thing.
Okay, just put the gun
in the bag.
No, get your... hold your gun up.
Just give them the bag and
give them everything! Come on!
Goddamn you.
I thought you had my back.
Put it in the bag
and slide it over, now.
It's in the bag!
Slide the bag over.
Sorry.
Well, 'cause you just gave me
a ring, motherfucker!
Oh, shit.
Shit.
Oh.
Get up. Get up already.
Ow.
Oh, God.
No, no, stop, stop, stop,
stop, stop!  Pull it out.
Okay, that feels broken.
Pull it out.
It's out!
Nice work.
Hey...
How funny.
This is like when you
were interrogating me,
only now you're tied up
and I got all these knives.
You know, I don't like, uh...
I don't like to shoot people.
I like cutting people up.
It's kind of what I do.
That's athat's a... I like that one.
It's...  That's a good one.
It's a good choice; it's small.
... a small one.
Not too flashy.
This is actually
a oystershucking knife.
Not at the moment.
Not me. Not me.
You know,
I got to tell you,
I've done this a...
lot of times to a lot of people,
Larkin's here.
Larkin.
Upstairs.
The fun'll have to wait.
The boss is here.
Sure. Take...
Yeah, take your time.
... whatever time you need.
Okay, cool. Cool.
Oh, also, um...
Well, mymy hands are tied,
but I can...
Oh, okay. Let me help you.
Ooh!  Jesus!
Thanks.
Fuck! Fuck! FF...
Shh.
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
Shh...!
Breathe through the pain.
Yeah, do that.
Do that, do that.
Breathe it out, breathe it out,
Oh, my God.
breathe it out.
Okay, Mullins.
Oh.
If we should perish in here...
We're not gonna.
All right, just shh...!
I know I'm not very good
with my feelings... oh, God...
Okay, you are...
you are smart,
you are smart
and you are intuitive,
and you're the best cop
I'veI've ever worked with.
Oh, God.
You, too. Thank you.
You were right... I went back
and looked at the evidence,
and I think the Red Falls Killer
is innocent. Oh...
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck.
Did you happen to
mention that to anybody
No, no, I didn't!
No, I didn't!
Jesus! Good luck.
You're taking that to
your grave, probably.
Fuck, the other leg!
Oh, God.
I got it. I got it.
I am moving my chair!
Just grab the knife.
Grab the knife.
Take it. Take it.
Take it, just take it.
I'm sorry.
I got it!
Waah!
Shh. Shut up.
Waah! Waah!
I am doing it as
fast as I can.
It's almost there, it's almost
there, it's almost there.
Whew... Come on.
Got it!
Hurry up, hurry up...
hurry up, hurry up.
I got to put it back in,
and I'll put my hands
behind my back,
and then when he gets
close to me, I grab him.
But you got to shut up
and let me put it back in.
Okay, just put it in,
put it in...
Sorry, it doesn't go in
that fuckin' easy.
Just... just...
Just shut up, shut up.
Ow! Motherfucker.
Oh...
I'm sorry.
Oh, shit.
I'll pretend... I'll pretend
to keep my hands tied.
Shut up! Shut up!
Oh, no, Scoob!
Velma and Daphne got captured!
Ah, I never thought I'd be happy
to see you guys.
Come on, we got to get her
to the hospital.
Yeah, I sent a fuckin' owl
with a note.
We followed you.
I knew you weren't
gonna give up that easily,
especially not after
they greased
your shitbag brother.
Fuck you.
You know, it takes
a lot more than Larkin
to take down a Mullins.
Come on, Adam.
Larkin is on his way.
Why are you so...
Oh, my God.
You piece of shit.
You guys are working
with Larkin.
I really wish
you hadn't said that.
Oh, God! Oh, God.
Shit!
God, that felt good.
God, it wasn't the albino.
I feel bad.
Yeah, no, he wasn't
working for Larkin.
He just wanted you
off the case
'cause he's
a misogynistic asshole.
I was, in the beginning.
Six years dealing
with these lowlives,
making shit money.
Ah.
You're Larkin.
Holy shit.
Makes perfect sense.
Uh, well, now I'm bragging,
but it's very nice
having a second income.
That guy was hilarious.
Boss, I don't think that was
such a good idea.
Yeah, well, you spend three
years in a van with him
and you'd kill him, too.
We'll pin it on LeSoire.
I've got to go to the hospital
to finish Jason.
You deal with these two.
No loose ends.
Mmhmm.
Fuckin' rat.
We told you
to stay out of the way.
Goodbye.
You fuckin' rat!
See you, buddy.
Don't call me buddy.
He's actually a great guy.
All right, uh...
let's have some fun.
I've been waiting
to do this a long time.
Campbell's soup...
you're up first.
Please don't hurt us.
I didn't mean to say
that shit I said.
Please don't hurt us.
Aah! God!
Come on!
Son of a bitch!
Mullins, gun at 2:30! Mullins!
Get...
Get off!
Don't!
You take one step, and
your partner gets it.
Oh. Ah.
Shit!
Nice.
Oh, my God...
Oh, my God.
Look at me.
Oh, God.
I think I'm gonna throw up.
My God, it was
a really bad headbutt.
Yeah.
Yeah. It was good.
But you're gonna feel it.
Go, go, go.
Get yourself untied.
And then we're gonna
go get Jason.
Go, go, go, go, go.
Oh, dickfucker!
Damn it, get off
the fuckin' phone!
Useless!
We got something.
I got it. I got it.
Get her on the stretcher.
No, no, I got it.
I got it! I got it, I got it, I got it.
Okay, thank you.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Oh, crap.
There you go.
All right, got to turn.
Call 911.
Well, just...
yeah, call it, call it.
Okay, you know, it's that kind
of language from your family
that forced us to move him to
the east wing of the hospital.
I don't know why...
Move, dipshit!
Jason, I'm coming!
Come on, come on.
Stupid, stupid chair!
Screw it.
Eee... Eee...
Eee...
Shit.
You know,
it's amazing
what a little air
in the bloodstream does
to the human heart.
You may not want
to watch this.
Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
I just want you to
know that... I get it.
I get it.
I mean, I've been on the...
Eee... Eee...  I've been on
the job a long time, and...
you just see
so many bad things and...
and bad people, and you...
you just start to wonder
if, you know,
is anybody good
anymore, and...
I just want you
to know that, you know,
you don't have to do this.
You don't have to do it.
I know.
But I do, because I have plans
that don't involve me going to
prison with people I put there.
So say goodbye
to your mick brother.
Wait, wait, wait!
Drop it, or I'm
gonna fire this weapon.
Or I inject...
Oh, you shot him in the dick.
Twice.
Oh, shit!
I took a page right out
of your book, partner.
Oh, God, but I've
never done it.
I just... you know,
I just aim it at it.
I don't actually do it.
That's ffuckin' crazy.
I mean, Jesus,
I'm not fuckin' crazy.
Oh, my God, don't make me
feel about it. God!  No, no, I know.
Hey, no, come...
Ooh, watch that leg.
You did good,
little buddy.
You saved my
brother's life.
Doing good.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Shit.
Internal Affairs
is going to open
a toptobottom investigation
of every department now.
Nice work.
Well, it was...
it was a team effort, sir.
Yeah. We put out
an APB on Julian.
Oh, don't bother;
he's in the trunk.
Oh, and, uh, sir...
uh, we're gonna have to reopen
the Red Falls Killer case.
Good for you.
I don't know.
I thought that would feel good,
but it felt awful.
You know, that's
probably gonna...
just keep feeling bad.
I'm glad you did it.
Probably not.
Spin it, spin it.
Okay, did it, did it.
Now, let's...
let's take this one though.
I'll get you...
It's clean enough.
Oh, my God, that smells.
Get off the leg, get off the leg.
Like several people
died on here.
Oh, my... Let me just sit.
Let's get your legs up.
No, I don't need
to be on my face.
You know, you can
help the process.  Ow! God!
Not clean.
Inchworm it up.
Come on. Come on.
Okay, okay, that's good.
Just flip me.
Get off the leg,
get off the leg,
off the leg.
Don'tdon't fall off.
Oh, my God. Okay.
Okay, I want this place
locked down, people.
Nobody goes in or out
without talking to me.
I want you three
stationed at each end
of the east wing.
Let's go.
All right, let's clear
this hallway, people!
Let's go!
What are you...
You two, get the
press out of here.
Yeah, yeah, I'm good, I'm good.
Yeah, I knew you would be.
I'm good, too.
Excuse me.
This is one of the best
agents in the FBI.
You make sure she's
well taken care of.
That was...
I would look into that.
Yeah...
All right. All right, let's go.
Oh, Christ.
Um, you actually
have to stay here.
do what you can
to save that leg.
Oh, I'm not a doctor.
All right, fucktard,
I know you're not a doctor,
but tell it to the doctor.
All right, I'll wait
right here for you.
Throw out that sandwich.
I'll bring you that sandwich!
No!
Throw it out!
You got it, buddy.
For outstanding service,
Officer Shannon Mullins.
There you go, Shan!
That's what
I'm talking about!
There you go, Shannon!
Hold it up!
Hold it up! Yeah!
Take out the gun.
Just a little snooze, man.
I'd like to cake toast to Jason.
Cake toast.
Yeah! To Jason.
Yeah, dude.
I wanted you to have this...
it was your grandmother's.
Aw.  She would've been
very proud of you
taking care
of your brother.
Yeah, that's...
that's awesome.
Take a picture.
No cell phones.
Ashburn.
Hey, it's me.
Hey!
Yeah, yeah, they're pretty...
pretty sweet.
We got a lot of scumbags
we need to take down
here in Boston, Mullins.
Hey, uh...
Yeah.
Oh! God, I haven't even
opened it yet. I'm sorry.
It's crazy, 'cause your dad
sent me something, too, so...
It's, like,
the Mullins' gift day.
Hold on.
Oh. Okay.
I signed... signed it in front.
Yeah, it's amazing how that door
just opens up all by itself.
Okay, I see it.
That's very funny.
No, I know. I was just kidding.
Just look at the...
look at the back.
Oh, you wrote
something else mean
Okay, here it is.
Well...
don't make it weird.
Later, nerd.
Takes a nerd to know a nerd.
Okay. You made it weird.
Bye.
I left my baby in the car.
Hi.
Hey. There's, uh,
there's been something
I've been thinking about a lot,
and it's been bothering me,
and... well,
I got you something.
Oh. Okay.
Oh.
I found your friend.
Pumpkin!
I drove all the way
to New Jersey,
and I was up and down these
streets and looking all over,
and, you know, I was
just about to give up,
and I was over
by your old place.
All of a sudden I hear
this little bell,
and I thought,
wait a minute.
I looked in your neighbor's
window, and I saw
this asshole sitting
right on the couch.
I said, "You are coming with me,
even if you don't want
to go back with her... "
Wow.
Pretty hard, but I'm just glad
that, you know,
I could kind of make this...
reuniting... Yeah.
Oh, wow.
What a surprise this is. Huh.
Look at where you are.
Goddamn it, put him in the box.
Put him in the box.
Just don't.
He likes to snuggle.
Don't make me put the
cat down and punch you.