One, two, three, knock on the wall!
One, two, three, knock on the...
Run! I'm going to catch you!
Good Shepherd Orphanage. Hello?
It's all ready.
She's playing. We haven't told her yet.
Laura will be very happy
in her new home. Don't worry.
See you in the afternoon.
Your friends will miss you a lot, Laura.
Got you!
THE ORPHANAGE
Mommy!
I'll go, it's my turn.
I'm coming!
Simon!
They're outside. Listen.
Come on, go to sleep.
Simon, darling.
Oh, I see!
Watson and Pepe
have been playing until very late...
and now they can't get in, right?
Come on, in you go.
Aren't you a bit old for this?
Weren't you scared here,
when you were little?
No, darling. You couldn't be afraid.
There was a gang of us...
and the lighthouse was on all night.
- Lighthouse?
- It's still there...
but it doesn't work anymore.
I'll show you tomorrow
when we go to the beach.
Why doesn't it work?
Can you keep a secret?
Actually, it does work.
But the light's invisible,
and it protects us from danger.
Invisible light?
OK, try this.
Look at the window, you'll see.
Over there. Don't move.
Can you see it?
What? Did you see it?
Those kids that are coming...
why can't they stay at home?
Darling, because they're
special children...
and they need a lot of special care.
They can't come and go,
because they're too far away.
Do you understand?
Can I sleep with you tonight?
You're pushing it!
Dad, are you not coming to the beach?
Aren't Watson and Pepe going?
No, they didn't sleep a wink last night.
You're such a smart-ass!
You have friends only when it suits.
OK, wise guy, take your pill.
"S" for Simon!
Go upstairs and get your bag.
Dad'll meet us there later, OK?
One of us should talk to Simon.
About his invisible friends.
It's normal, don't worry.
He's lonely, he's bored.
He'll forget them
as soon as the real kids arrive.
- Calm down!
- OK.
Everything will work out.
We'll have a great home.
I'm so glad we're here together.
- Pirate.
- Cave.
- And lighthouse.
Let's see.
Once upon a time, there was
a very, very bad pirate...
who hid his treasures
in a cave, near a lighthouse.
- And what treasures?
- Stolen treasures.
- But it wasn't easy...
- But...
...to get into the cave.
- They'd click a stone...
- And how did they get in?
...in a gap in the rocks...
...that big stone inside the other stone...
...and the rock did...like this.
And there's were they used to hide
all of their treasures.
Hello?
Siméon?
Simon, let's go!
What's your name?
I'm Simon. Do you want to play?
Why? Can't you play?
Do you want to come to my house
to play later?
Simén...
what are you doing there?
We are playing.
But Watson and Pepe
weren't going to come.
It's not them, it's another boy.
Then tell him to play somewhere else.
It's dangerous here.
Come on, let's go.
Can he come home to play?
Why are you dropping shells, Simon?
It's a path for my friend to follow...
so he can come home and play.
- He made a new friend. How's that?
- Another one?
We won't have room for all these kids.
- Hello.
- Good afternoon.
Sorry I didn't call,
but I couldn't get your number.
I'm Benigna Escobedo.
I'm a social worker.
I'm sorry you've come so far...
but I hadn't arranged
any interviews for today.
Interviews? No, I'm here for Simon.
What a sitting room!
It's a beautiful house.
How did you find it?
I grew up here. It was an orphanage.
I always wanted to return,
so we thought of the home.
Home?
For special children.
That's not why you came?
You'll need a lot of people for that.
It's not that kind of a home.
We'll be happy with 5 or 6 children.
More would be too complicated, right?
What about Simén?
Yes, yes. Of course.
I received his file yesterday...
and thought, "I should visit them
in case they need anything."
Will you make many changes
in the house?
Sorry, but I don't understand
why you're here.
This information is old.
I know, but I received it all.
There are new treatments,
an experimental program...
that requires an application,
and I thought you might be interested.
As you might know,
my husband is a doctor.
We're aware of all treatments
for Simoén's disease.
Now please leave.
Simon doesn't know he's adopted,
or about his illness...
and I like to deal with these issues
when my husband is at home.
CHANGE OF ADDRESS
HIV POSITIVE
Carlos.
I'll go. It's my turn.
Who's there?
What are you doing here?
Carlos! Carlos!
What is it?
Planning to bash the old lady's head in?
Sleep with Simon tonight.
If she shows up again,
we'll call the cops.
Mommy!
Can I wake up?
Mommy...
- Can I wake up?
- Simén, please.
You are already awake.
You can get up now, darling.
WENDY GREW UP
Wendy grows old and dies?
Wendy grows old, but Peter Pan takes
her daughter to Neverland every year.
Why doesn't Wendy go too?
Well...
If Peter Pan came to get me,
would you come too?
No, I'm too old
to go to Neverland, darling.
- How old are you?
- 37.
At what age will you die?
What sort of question is that?
Not for a long time, until you're very old.
I won't grow old.
I'm not going to grow up.
Will you be like Peter Pan?
Like my new friends.
- There's more than one?
- Six.
- They won't grow up either?
- They can't.
What are they holding?
Treasures. To play with.
I see. Your invisible friends
play together?
Sure.
They steal your treasure...
something you love,
and you have to find it.
That's the game?
Finding what they took from you?
Yes, but following the clues.
If you find it, they grant you a wish.
Well, now. And you have a treasure?
Special coins.
An old man left them in the park.
I think they're gold...
and very valuable.
Want to see them?
Don't look yet.
- Where'd you get all this?
- I found it.
What's this?
The first ice cream I had
after my tonsil operation.
The special coins.
They're not coins,
they're your baby teeth.
- Where'd you find them?
- Can't you see?
They're the first clue.
They've got my coins.
You want to play treasure hunt?
The game's started.
Remember where you kept
my baby teeth.
If I find my treasure, I can make a wish.
Sand. Where do you find sand?
You set this up, right?
- The beach?
- No, no, it has to be at home.
What's this?
The sewing box!
Simon, wait!
Come on, hurry up!
This rings a bell.
I know, the key in the kitchen!
My treasure!
- Those are Daddy's...
- I can make a wish! I can make a wish!
- I can make a wish!
- Leave that alone!
- Simon!
Those are our things,
you shouldn't touch them.
- Is that clear?
- I didn't. It was them!
- Don't lie to me.
- I'm not lying.
You're lying! You say you're my mother...
and you're not!
- What?
- You're not my mother.
- Who told you that?
- My friend told me.
- What friend?
- Tomas.
Tomas told me the truth,
that I'm just like them...
I have no mother or father!
And I'm going to die!
You're not my mother, you're a liar!
We wanted you to be a bit older
to talk about certain things.
If you want to ask us anything...
Is Santa Claus a lie too?
Listen, Simon...
you heard Mommy and that lady talking...
saw the envelope
and invented the game...
because you were afraid to ask about it.
What if I don't take them?
Nothing would happen.
If I don't take them,
how soon would I die?
It would take many days,
many weeks, even, right?
Don't worry, we'll take care of you.
You won't get sick or die.
OK?
You don't love me! It's a lie! It's a lie!
It's a lie! It's a lie!
Simdén, come down, son!
Simon!
Hurry, the first kids are here! Come on!
We can't go yet.
I want to show you something.
- Really? What is it?
- Tomas' little house.
- Not now. Tomorrow, when we are alone.
- No!
- Not now, Simon.
- Now!
Go downstairs right now!
I don't want to!
- Go downstairs!
- I said come and see Tomas' house!
OK, if you don't want
to go downstairs, don't.
No one is forcing you.
WELCOME
Where is the mask?
Siméon?
Simon!
Darling!
Darling?
Simon!
Siméon?
Simon, darling.
Carlos!
What's going on?
Darling!
Siméon?
Simon!
Simon! Simon!
Darling! Simén!
Simon!
Laura!
No!
The tide is rising!
Simon!
- Simon!
- Laura!
He's over there, He's over there, Carlos!
There's no one, Laura! Come on.
- There's no one! We can't stay here!
- He's there, Carlos!
EMERGENCIES
Carlos is here.
He spoke to the police...
and now he wants to talk to you
if you feel better.
How are you?
He's not in the cave.
But I saw someone, Carlos.
You must have imagined it
in all the confusion.
Believe me, he wasn't there.
I'm Pilar.
I know it's hard, but you must know
we're doing all we can...
to locate your son as soon as possible.
Pilar is a psychologist.
She works with the police.
They're working hard to find Simén.
I have a few questions.
Your husband told me
about the adoption...
and your son's illness.
As he was adopted...
there are possibilities we must consider.
What possibilities?
He could have been kidnapped
by a relative.
I heard you recently found...
a woman intruder on the grounds.
Benigna Escobedo, a social worker,
came a few days ago.
We can't find a social worker
with that name.
Could you describe her?
She was about 70, with white hair...
pale eyes, very thick glasses.
Don't worry, we will find her.
You can be sure of that.
How can they trust me
with their kids after this?
Let's do something.
Wear my grandmother's Saint Anthony
medal, you know I'm very fond of it.
To bring us good luck.
You don't believe that.
Exactly. It will work if you have it.
But it's not a present,
I am lending it to you.
Give it back when we find Simon.
Carlos!
Simon Sanchez's parents
feel more and more forsaken.
The 7-year-old boy disappeared
from his home 6 months ago.
The situation is even more desperate...
because Simon is ill and needs
daily medication. His parents...
My son disappeared 6 months ago.
His name is Simon.
There are posters everywhere.
You may have seen them.
We've tried everything...
but not one clue...
not even a trace.
My son had imaginary friends.
We never paid much attention...
but I have the feeling
they're in the house.
I saw my daughter.
A year after her death.
It was at night, we were asleep.
I woke up...
and without knowing why,
I went to her room.
And there she was.
Smiling. Calm.
I think that was her way of telling me...
"I'm fine, I'm safe.
"Don't suffer for me."
It is not unusual to feel, in some way...
the presence of a loved one
after their death.
All of us in this bereavement group
could tell you similar stories.
You don't understand.
My son is not dead.
His friends took him. I saw one of them
the same day he vanished.
He was at home.
I'll do whatever it takes
to recover my son.
I'm not crazy...
believe me.
I know what I'm saying.
...Cities on state of alert
due to gales, rain and snow.
The heaviest snowfalls
will be recorded in the north.
North of Asturias.
Tonight, in some cities...
20 cm of snow are expected
in the Cantabrian Mountains region...
cities that usually end up isolated
during these storms. And...
It's her.
The woman who came to the house.
Benigna?
Simon!
He destroyed her. He destroyed her.
She's dead.
We went to Benigna's house.
We found some pictures...
and old Super 8 films.
I'd like you to see them.
Are any of the faces familiar?
Antonia, the principal,
and these are the orphans. My friends.
This is Martin.
She liked to be called Martin.
Rita.
Victor... I think his name was Guillermo.
That's Alicia, she was blind.
And this is me.
- Benigna?
- The woman that went to your house...
worked at the orphanage.
That's impossible. I'd remember.
She wasn't there very long.
She had a son. Tomas.
It seems that the child
was born deformed...
he was kept away from the others.
No one knew about him.
It was a total shock for the village
when they found the body.
What do you mean?
It seems he disappeared while playing.
CHILD'S BODY FOUND ON BEACH
Shortly after your adoption.
One of the orphans later confessed...
that they had played a trick on him.
They went into the caves with Tomas...
and took his mask off
to see if he'd come out.
But he never emerged. He drowned.
They found his body at low tide.
The children weren't blamed.
They were only playing.
That boy was in my house.
We asked everyone at the opening party.
No one remembers a child
with a sack over his head.
I can't remember what it's like
to sleep through the night.
I can't stop thinking.
Remember what we called Simon
when we met him?
"Two Little Kilos".
You used to say,
"My two little extra kilos."
That's all he weighed.
The doctors said it wasn't enough.
But it was plenty for us.
Although we knew that...
there was little chance
he could ever be normal.
But when we saw him...
saw his smile for the first time...
his eyes, his bright eyes...
Simon made us strong, Carlos.
Together, we're strong.
Together.
Forgive me if I get upset, but it's hard.
Carlos, someone's in the bathroom.
- What is it?
- Someone was here.
Carlos, don't give me that look.
Feel, it's still warm.
Sure, I just got up.
Someone got into the bed.
I'm convinced.
That's what Jung means when he says...
it's in the subconscious that
the living coexist with the dead.
The Germans have another name
for "the herald of death".
Doppelganger.
A being that appears in one's own image.
A double.
To glance at him...
or at any of the others I've shown you...
means, without the slightest doubt...
a passport to the other world.
How long has your son been missing?
Nine months.
Strange things are happening.
Things linked to his disappearance.
I don't know who to turn to.
It's not that simple.
You won't find an exorcist
in the yellow pages.
I tore it from my son's kidnapper's clothes.
The police say he's been dead
for over 30 years.
Someone has my son.
I don't know why.
But I won't sit at home and wait.
There's someone in this field,
someone I trust.
I'm talking from the heart.
Would you allow a medium
to visit your home?
This wasn't a children's room
in the orphanage, right?
No, the bedroom was back there.
Then we should start here.
Enrique.
Perfect, give me an hour.
I want an old object from this house...
something related to its history,
and, if possible...
some clothing from the past.
We're not alone.
There's a police psychologist, Pilar...
who would really like
to attend the session.
If you don't mind.
Perfect. Perfect.
Cops are cool!
What does she need that doll for?
Aurora needs an object
to facilitate her trance.
Clothing and objects get her into it...
and begin the regression.
- Regression?
- A psychic summoning.
Past, present and future
are superimposed, and cross.
Like a sort of time travel.
It may sound like witchcraft...
but you mustn't fear parallel perception.
If there's anything, Aurora will see it.
If there's anything, I hope we'll all see it.
Everything's ready, Enrique.
Ready, whenever you want.
- Aurora, can you hear me?
- Perfectly. I'm ready.
Here we go.
Everything around you
is beginning to fade.
Darkness is forming
a circle around you...
it's closing in on you.
Everything is fading.
We're no longer here.
Now you're alone in the darkness...
and the darkness begins to disappear.
I'm going to count down...
from ten...
and once I've finished...
you can go wherever you want...
and will be able to see...
anyone who is hiding in this house.
Ten...
nine...
eight...
seven...
SIX...
five...
four...
three...
two...
one.
You can open your eyes.
It's cold...
the window is open.
Aurora...
I want you to look around you.
Is there anyone with you in the room?
I can hear someone.
I can hear...
I can hear something.
The sound comes and goes.
I can't hear it anymore.
I think I've lost them.
I can hear something.
...all alone.
Children...
I'm sure it's children.
At the end of the hall. I think it's them.
I can't open it.
It's closed.
But there's someone.
Why are you crying?
- We're sick!
- Who's sick?
I won't hurt you.
Don't be afraid. Open the door.
Don't be afraid.
Open the door.
We want you to open the door!
What have they done to you?
What have they done?
Aurora...
tell me what you see.
Five children.
They're very sick. They're crying.
What happened?
They're dying.
Who would want to poison you?
Someone's going to kill us.
Is my son there?
Aurora, is Simon with you?
Is Simon here?
Aurora? Aurora, can you hear me?
Let's get her.
Aurora, stay in the middle of the room.
I'll count from ten.
Ten...
nine...
eight...
seven...
SIX...
five...
four...
three...
two...
one.
I was in this house, but...
everything was different.
The beds, the toys, the décor,
everything was much older.
The light from the lighthouse
came through the windows.
Are you sure you didn't see Simon?
It was too dark, I'm sorry.
I couldn't recognize anyone.
But the children were there.
You saw the children. Is that right?
- That's right.
- You're talking about ghosts.
And what is a ghost, Carlos?
There's something here,
and we all saw it.
When something terrible happens...
sometimes it leaves a trace...
a wound that acts...
as a knot between two time lines.
It's like an echo...
repeated over and over,
waiting to be heard.
Like a scar...
Oh, I'm sorry.
Like a scar or a pinch...
that begs for a caress to relieve it.
Laura...
we who are close to death...
we are more receptive
to these messages.
You mean my son
could see those children...
because...
Well, Laura... I think that's enough.
Please take your things and leave.
Carlos, we can't let them go like this.
Laura, this is a farce...
a sideshow trick.
I can't believe this. Why?
For what reason?
They're right, aren't they?
- They don't want money.
- Not yet.
What should I do?
Tell me, what should I do?
Over a long time,
the police haven't found a single clue...
not a single clue...
as to where my son can be,
whether dead or alive.
What do I do, just sit and wait?
Can it hurt to listen?
- Laura, stop!
- No, you stop!
Tell me, Pilar...
how many similar cases
have you had in this damned village?
Get another distraction,
I didn't invite you here.
What should I do?
My dear...
you are a good mother.
Your pain gives you strength,
it will guide you.
But only you know
how far you are willing to go...
to find your son.
I don't know what to do.
You hear, but don't listen.
Seeing is not believing.
It's the other way around.
Believe...
and you will see.
THE SEARCH FOR SIMON CONTINUES
What are you doing?
We can't stay here any longer.
We should go, at least for a while.
The children are here.
Aurora saw them. I can't leave.
You heard the voices.
Enrique was upstairs for one hour,
playing around with the cables.
Can't you see it could be a set-up?
That's Pilar's theory, a set-up?
- Her rational theory?
- Pilar is protecting us.
From what?
Things like this evening.
People entering our home
and fucking up our lives even more.
- They just want to help.
- Help?
Didn't you hear them?
Did they mention finding Simon?
No. They just want
to contact the dead, Laura.
If Simén's alive,
I can't see how they can help us.
If he's not, they won't recover him.
I'm neither willing nor able
to keep taking this shit.
Please, Laura, let's leave this house.
Carlos, you can't ask me to give up.
Neither you nor Pilar.
Laura, we can survive this. Many couples
lose a child and pull through.
I just want to be with Simén,
don't you understand?
If you want to go, I can't stop you.
I just want to see him, Carlos...
that's all I want!
Where are you?
I'm not afraid.
You want to play?
Are you playing with me?
Benigna?
God, don't let it be him.
Please. Please,
don't let it be Simén. Please.
- There are five, right?
- Yes.
All my friends.
Martin, Rita, Alicia, Guillermo, Victor.
Benigna killed them.
That's why she went back to the shed,
to recover their bodies.
I've thought it out.
Their game killed Tomas...
and now they're playing
with Simén and me, don't you get it?
Simon's in danger
and I don't know how to play.
I don't know how to play.
- Laura, you're making it up.
- Carlos, I saw it myself.
And this afternoon?
Who laid out the clues?
Simon made it all up
to get your attention.
Who?
Tell me! Come on, who?
I've packed. I don't want us to stay here.
I can't leave yet.
I won't live here...
and you're not staying alone.
I can't just leave,
there are too many memories, Carlos.
I have to say goodbye.
Two days.
Alone.
Please, I need this.
Please.
Please bless what you have given us.
Thank you for letting us
gather once again...
and be together.
What else do you want from me?
What more must I do?
I have no time, I have no time.
I have no time,
You want to keep playing? Is that it?
Let's make a deal. I'll play a while...
then you tell me where Simén is, OK?
OK?
One, two, three, knock on the wall!
One, two, three, knock on the wall.
One...
One, two, three...
Wait, wait, wait! No.
Wait, I won't hurt you.
I just want to find Simon.
Siméon?
Mommy, why are you crying?
Oh, my darling!
Are you OK? You're freezing.
Don't worry about a thing.
Don't be afraid, I'll get you out.
Stay and play with us.
No, darling, we can't stay to play.
Listen to me, Simon.
Imagine it's just you and me here. OK?
Think about before we came
to this house.
Remember, darling?
Think only about that, OK?
Think only about that...
think about Daddy...
think about next Christmas...
and all the things we'll do together.
So many things, darling!
Close your eyes.
Close your eyes, tight, tight, tight, tight.
That's it, really tight...
and think about what you'll be
when you grow up.
What would you like to be, darling?
Think about the schools you'll go to,
the friends you'll make.
And just believe for a moment that...
that Tomas and the other children
aren't real.
This is a fantasy, my darling...
like a nightmare.
Do it for me, Siméon, OK?
When you open your eyes...
make them go away.
Please. Please, make them go away.
Please.
Close your eyes, darling...
and keep on playing with me, OK?
Keep on playing, darling, OK?
- What is it?
- Tomas' little house.
Nooo!
No!
Nooooo!
I found you. This isn't fair.
I found you.
I want Simon back.
Mommy, Mommy, can I wake up?
Of course you can, darling.
Of course you can.
Mommy, Mommy...
I found the special coins.
Now I just have to make a wish.
I wish you'd stay and look after all of us.
It's Laura!
Laura!
She's grown old, like Wendy in the story.
It's Laura.
Laura.
Come, don't be afraid.
The house. The beach. The lost children.
Once upon a time...
there was a house near the beach...
where the lost children lived...
In memory of Laura and Simén...
and of the orphans...
Martin, Rita,
Guillermo, Alicia, Victor, and Tomas.
THE ORPHANAGE