I've been here before...
over and over again,
and each time the same question.
- Is this it?
Will this time be the one?
And each time the same answer.
And I'm just so tired of it.
You good?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
You travel?
I did.
And I got you something.
What's that?
Ooh, first edition Don Quixote.
-That couldn't have been cheap.
-It wasn't.
So why am I here, Booker?
You remember Surabaya
eight years ago, right?
CIA.
Yeah. The guy who hired us,
James Copley, reached out.
He's freelance now.
He has a hostage situation in South Sudan.
No, Booker. We don't do repeats.
You know that.
It's too risky.
Andy.
Joe and Nicky?
At the hotel.
Come back again.
Thank you. Welcome to El Fenn, sir.
Checking in?
- What brings you to Marrakesh?
- Family.
Say, "Marrakesh!"
Marrakesh!
Would you like me to take one for you?
Thank you so much.
I just really suck at taking selfies.
There you go.
Thank you!
-You look great.
-You look okay.
Thank you! Thank you!
And I have something for you.
Nicky!
Baklava.
Five hundred, Booker.
No.
All right.
- All in. Here it is.
- Really?
- All in!
Hazelnut, not walnut.
The Black Sea.
Rosewater.
Pomegranate.
Eastern Turkey.
No, no, no. Don't worry.
Admit it, boss. You missed us.
I did.
It's a job, guys.
We can do some good.
Have you been watching the news lately?
Some good means nothing.
I don't know about this, guys.
We're not helping.
I know you needed a break,
but it's been over a year, boss.
This is what we do, Andy.
I'll hear him out.
Mr. Copley.
Mr. Booker, bonjour.
-It's a pleasure to finally meet you.
-Last time I checked,
you had to be American to be in the CIA.
I was born in Boston.
Moved to London when I was three.
So why did you leave the agency,
Mr. Copley?
My wife got sick.
ALS.
She died two years ago.
Just haven't found my way back yet.
-Sorry for your loss.
-Thank you.
You haven't aged a day, Booker.
- Trust me, I have.
- Yeah.
Yesterday afternoon local,
a school southwest of Juba
was attacked by a militia.
They murdered the teachers and abducted
17 of the students at gunpoint.
The youngest was eight...
oldest, 13.
South Sudanese asked the US for help,
but current administration's policy
is to deny aid to any nonstrategic allies.
Some of my ex-colleagues at the CIA
feel differently.
They reached out to me,
and I'm reaching out to you.
The last overfly confirmed
the personnel on site.
No food or water being brought in.
That means
they're moving them soon.
And when they do,
most likely they'll be separated,
and odds are we'll never find them again.
Has to be done quickly...
by the best,
and your team's the best I've ever seen.
You can name your price.
We'll invoice you when it's done.
Peace be with you.
What the...
Are we too late?
Motherfuck...
Room clear!
- My God!
- Shit!
Look out! Reload!
What the hell?
- Everyone still with me?
- Yeah.
Joe?
Very pissed off.
So where are the girls?
There never were any girls.
We've been set up.
Yeah, I got it.
Yeah.
One has to admire
Mr. Copley's attention to detail.
Those shoes were a particularly
grotesque touch.
I knew this was gonna happen.
I said it.
We did it right, Andy.
-For the right reasons.
-And what did it get us, Nicky? What?
Nothing.
We've done nothing.
The world isn't getting any better.
It's getting worse.
I checked him completely, and...
everything seemed legit.
I'm sorry, guys.
They know who we are.
They know what we are.
We have to find Copley.
We have to tie this thing off.
-And then what?
-And then nothing.
The world can burn for all I care.
I'm done.
Freeman, where you at?
Here, Sergeant.
The women are holed up in the house
with the arches.
Take a right at the building
with the red carpet.
-Get me some information.
-Roger that.
Keep it respectful.
Don't we always?
Never hurts to repeat it.
My name is Nile.
I am an American Marine.
We are looking for this man.
He has killed many of our people
and many of yours.
Have any of you seen him?
You do not disrespect your family
by telling us where he is.
There are no men here.
To use women as shields
is to be no man at all.
Thank you for allowing us into your home.
We will leave you in peace.
Breach!
Stop!
- Clear! Covering!
- Clear!
Lima 3, this is India 5. Contact, over.
Jay, go check on the women.
On it.
Look at all this shit.
It's jackpot.
Not if he bleeds out.
They wanted him alive, remember?
Do not... Do not touch me.
I'm trying to save you, man.
Dizzy, a little help, please?
No! Medic!
Man down!
No! Jesus! Medic!
Stay with me!
My...
God! Jesus, no.
Come here. Stay with me. Look at me.
Look at me. You're gonna be okay.
Nile! Nile!
You're okay. It's okay.
Stay with me. Just look at me. Look at me.
Okay. Medic's on their way.
Medic's on their way.
No, no. It's okay. It's okay.
The medic's coming!
What the...
No.
No, not another one.
Not now.
It was a woman.
A black woman.
I saw an older woman in a hijab.
What did you see?
I saw... I saw part
of a name tag.
Yeah. Free... free something.
-Yeah.
-Dirt floor, clay walls.
And a medevac.
Yeah, so maybe a...
a coalition...
medical team.
The knife was a pesh-kabz. Pashtun.
I felt her die.
She's a Marine.
Combat.
Or near-combat duty.
Afghanistan.
It's been over 200 years.
Why now?
Everything happens for a reason, boss.
We have to find her.
No, we stick to the plan. We find Copley.
-So we just leave her out in the open?
-No, we're in the open.
-We're the ones who are exposed now.
-Not like her.
Nicky... Not like her.
You can't tell me you don't remember
what it was like.
Whoever she is,
she's confused, and she's scared,
and she's more alone
than she has ever been in her entire life.
We all remember what it was like.
She needs us.
I'll handle the retrieval.
Hey, boss, come on.
If we're dreaming about her,
she's dreaming about us.
That makes her a beacon straight to us.
-What do we do in the meantime?
-Get to France.
Use the Charlie safe house.
I'll meet you there.
Find Copley.
Jesus.
She's just a baby.
I know I saw her die.
A little blood can look like a lot.
Adrenaline flying,
everyone was seeing shit they didn't.
I was holding her neck together
in my hands.
You'd rather we sent her home
in a body bag?
No, of course not.
So come on.
Hey, look who's up.
Nile?
What's up, Jay?
What's up, Dizzy?
So let's see the trophy.
Fuck me.
Nile, there's not even a scratch.
Yeah, they...
They used this new skin graft
or something.
That what the doctor said?
Yeah.
That's what they said.
Our average lifespan is 78
in developed nations.
Actually, two more years if you're
lucky enough to be born a female.
What can I say, ladies?
Now, all of this is because
of everyone's favorite love-to-hate...
Big Pharma.
At my company,
our research on telomere extension
has reversed the chromosomal clock
of human stem cells.
Dr. Kozak's manipulation
of the klotho hormone will, in time,
completely arrest
common cognitive decline.
Yes, we can all wave goodbye to dementia.
Now... wait!
Our work will add years of life
to the collective world population.
Years. Decades.
But it's not cheap.
We need investment.
Investment drives my enthusiasm
to take risks.
These risks improve countless lives.
My God.
You've seen my research.
Now you know they're for real.
What about the hard proof?
Blood, tissue, bone, DNA.
Recovering an uncontaminated sample
of the site proved impossible.
But you promised me hard proof.
There was an unanticipated
amount of carnage.
-But the footage...
-No, no.
The footage is
a two-million-dollar snuff film.
It doesn't give her the how.
I need all of them, Copley.
-I think I can get you one.
-No. No, not one. All.
These are extraordinary individuals.
They are extremely resistant to capture.
Well, consult with Keane, make a plan,
make it happen.
And quickly,
before my competitors get wind of this.
Corporal Freeman.
-Aye, Sergeant.
-Orders just came through.
They're sending you to Landstuhl, Germany
for more tests.
But I'm fine.
Plane's fueling. Pack your bags.
-Sergeant...
-We took these off you when it happened.
Didn't think you were coming back.
That's her.
Corporal Freeman.
Been looking for you.
Wheels up on your ride.
-Who are you?
-Andromache the Scythian.
But you can call me Andy.
Why does it have to be so goddamn slow
the first couple of times?
You shot me.
I did.
I need you to get back in the car, please.
This isn't real.
No, none of this is real.
You haven't figured this out yet?
You can't die.
Get up.
Argh! Fuck!
Can you please not do that again?
Who are you?
I lead a group of immortals.
An army, I guess.
Soldiers. Fighters like you.
Look...
You've got questions, kid.
I get it.
You want answers?
Get back in the car.
Put those on.
-Where are you taking me?
-Paris.
-You've got blood in your hair.
-Wonder why?
This guy's a drug runner.
This the shit you into?
Well, sometimes you gotta work with people
you don't wanna eat with.
Is this even safe?
Does it really matter?
Hey, boss.
You found Copley?
Nothing but dead ends.
He knows we're hunting him.
Keep looking.
He's doing the same to us.
I have the new one.
And?
Well, she stabbed me,
so I think she has potential.
I'll see you soon.
So why is this happening to me?
I wish I knew.
You said you had answers.
I didn't say you'd like them.
Are you praying?
God doesn't exist.
My God does.
You know, there was a time
when I was worshiped as a god.
Was that Him?
Don't worry, I can't do shit like that.
None of it means anything anyway.
You said there were others.
How many?
Four.
You're an army of four?
So that's why you took me?
So I could join your army?
Yeah.
No. This is some bullshit.
You must...
...must have hypnotized me, or...
or, drugged me or something.
And that was a blank
that you shot me with.
And I was the one who cut your throat.
Right?
Listen, kid.
You already believe in...
You should just keep following
that illogic.
You're already on board
with the supernatural.
If I were you, I'd get some sleep.
We're not going to Paris.
Andrei.
Come here.
Sit your ass down!
- Stand up!
- You do not listen to her.
You listen to me.
Land this plane.
Trust me. She's not gonna shoot you.
I am.
Who's gonna fly the plane?
We don't need a pilot.
We can jump and survive.
I am not jumping from a plane!
Whoa! Shit! Maybe we do need a pilot.
I can fly a plane.
You don't speak Russian, do you?
Why?
Because I told the pilot to play dead.
You really want to do this, kid?
We're done.
I said we're done.
You're very good.
What's your name?
Nile.
You see? You're already healing faster.
Is this real?
I got people that love me.
People that are gonna worry.
I'm a Marine.
-They think I went AWOL.
-You're not a Marine anymore.
They're going to lock you up.
I thought you said
we were going to Paris.
We're just outside of Paris.
This is Goussainville.
This place has been abandoned
for 50 years.
Why?
So are you good guys or bad guys?
Depends on the century.
We fight for what we think is right.
How are you all in my dreams?
We dream of each other.
They stop when we meet.
Why?
I believe it's because we...
we're meant to find each other.
It's like destiny.
No, more like misery loves company.
What he said.
It used to take years to track a new one.
Booker was the last.
1812.
No way.
Yeah, I died fighting with Napoleon.
So... you're even older than him.
Nicky and I met in the Crusades.
The Crusades?
The love of my life was of the people
I've been taught to hate.
We... We
killed each other.
- Many times.
- Yeah.
You're the oldest.
Yeah.
So how old are you?
-Old.
-How old?
Too old.
So we really never die.
Nothing that lives lives forever.
But... you said that we were immortal.
I know what I said.
And we mostly are, but we can die.
And one of us did.
He...
He was a warrior, just like us.
A long time ago.
One day your wounds
just don't heal up anymore, and...
we don't know when or why.
So if we can die,
then why would you shoot me?
You could have killed me.
You're too new.
It is a lot to understand.
I think you should get some rest.
Come with me.
I'll show you.
She wants to talk to her family.
That's not gonna help her.
You tell her that.
What's going on?
What happened?
It's just a... a bad dream.
I'm sorry.
Tell us.
I saw flashes of it before...
when I first dreamt of all of you.
But now it's clearer.
I dreamed about
a woman locked in an iron coffin...
under the sea.
She kept...
drowning and then coming back to life.
She was hammering her bloody fists
and knees against the iron.
She felt like something insane,
something furious.
But she kept fighting...
and she kept drowning.
Her name was Quynh.
She was one of us.
The first immortal Andy found.
They had been alone so long,
when she found her...
Quynh had given up.
Way back, it was her and Andy.
Before me and Nicky,
it was just the two of them.
They ran through the world together.
Fought thousands of battles side by side.
She was a pit viper in a fight.
They were in England,
freeing so-called heretics
from the witch trials.
But then, Andy and Quynh,
they were accused of witchcraft
themselves,
- and they were trapped and caught.
- Killers!
Some will rot in hell!
When they didn't die,
it proved their case,
and they got sentenced again and again.
I've never been burned alive before.
What do you think it's gonna be like?
Excruciating.
Just you and me.
Until the end.
No! No!
No, not this.
- No!
- Where are you taking her?
You are too powerful together.
For creatures such as you,
there is no salvation.
Please! No!
Quynh!
Andromache!
No!
After Andy escaped,
we spent decades searching for her
or anyone on that ship
who could tell us where she was cast off.
She's lived
with that guilt ever since,
but she blames herself for Quynh's fate.
Why do you blame yourself?
I lost a soldier.
I feel her pain.
Her rage.
She feels crazy.
Over 500 years in a box...
at the bottom of the ocean...
would make anyone insane.
That's the reason
why we dread capture.
Spend eternity in a cage.
Nile.
I don't want this.
I don't want any of it.
I know. I know.
There isn't one good thing in any of this.
I know this is hard.
It's happening
whether you want it or not.
I know you're scared, Nile.
Me and those three men in there
will keep you safe.
Like Quynh?
We're all you've got.
What's happening?
They found us.
Joe? Nicky?
Shit.
Booker.
You still with me?
Clear the back room. Find Joe and Nicky.
Hey.
Book.
Come on.
Come back to me.
You're still in this shitty game with me.
You hear me?
Now wake up.
Wake up!
They're not here.
Welcome back, asshole.
Thanks for taking your time.
It hurts everywhere.
How bad is it?
It's an improvement.
How many?
I don't know.
-Where are Nicky and Joe?
-I don't know!
I... I turned on the game.
A grenade hit me.
Lost the plot after that.
- Two in transport.
- No, no. We need the woman.
Wasn't there,
and the other guy's in pieces.
She's there.
-Copley.
-Copley?
They're coming back.
They want all of us.
You stay here.
Wait for my signal.
What signal?
- What does that even mean?
- You'll know it when it comes.
And, by the way,
it's not always like this now.
Big wounds take longer to heal.
Sure.
Bravo Team approaching church.
Go, go, go.
Come on! Move! Move!
We've gotta get out there!
We need to help her.
No, that's not the signal.
Mr. Keane,
I strongly recommend
that we leave right now.
Come on!
Let's move!
Wait for the signal.
How the hell can you even tell?
Let's go!
Andy did all this herself?
Yeah. That woman has forgotten
more ways to kill
than entire armies will ever learn.
Who are they? How'd they find you?
I don't know. Let's go!
Nicolo.
- Quiet.
- Nicolo, wake up.
- I said...
- I know what you said.
What are you gonna do? Kill me?
Wake up.
Wake up!
I'm here.
Wherever here is.
In an armored van.
They used gas.
I told you, shut up!
I need to know he's okay.
That's sweet.
What is he? Your boyfriend?
You're a child.
An infant.
Your mocking is thus infantile.
He's not my boyfriend.
This man is more to me than you can dream.
He's the moon when I'm lost in darkness
and warmth when I shiver in cold.
And his kiss still thrills me,
even after a millennia.
His heart overflows with the kindness
of which this world is not worthy of.
I love this man beyond measure and reason.
He's not my boyfriend.
He's all and he's more.
You're an incurable romantic.
I don't suppose it would be possible
to get these chains off of us?
Get 'em out! Get 'em out!
Get 'em on the plane now!
I guess not.
We are usually
a better judge of character.
I suppose you are taking us
to the person who paid for your betrayal.
It's a nice plane.
There's a TV, Joe.
Champagne?
What is this place?
An abandoned mine.
We stumbled on it
during the Baussenque Wars.
1150s maybe?
I used to keep my stuff here.
Here...
Is this a Rodin?
Yeah.
This is an honest-to-God Rodin.
Wait.
Did you know him?
Probably biblically.
Get to work finding Copley.
He's got Nicky and Joe.
It can hardly be unique
if they can make another copy.
I've got to go.
Gentlemen, welcome.
I am truly honored to meet you.
Together, we shall do such things.
What they are yet, I know not,
but they shall be
the terrors of the Earth.
Or, um, rather the saviors.
Lear...
Shakespeare.
Um, can we take the cuffs off?
No, sir. We can't.
My apologies.
Let's get off on the right foot, shall we?
I'm Steven Merrick,
youngest CEO in pharma.
Our work here is all about balance.
How do we push the scientific frontiers
whilst also turning a little profit?
There's your balance, asshole.
- Mr. Merrick?
- Yes, yes, yes.
Watch it.
Mr. Copley provided me
with footage of your unique talent,
but I prefer my evidence
to be indisputable.
No!
Mr. Merrick!
God damn it!
Shit!
What do you see?
The Nobel Prize.
And a fair few quid to boot.
We brought a cancer drug
to the market last quarter.
It's already saved
hundreds of thousands of lives.
Yet, in development,
it killed a quarter of a million lab mice.
Now, I didn't ask
for their little permissions.
I'm not gonna ask for yours.
He thinks you're a mouse, Nicky.
There's genetic code inside you
which could help
every human being on Earth.
We're morally obliged to take it.
What?
- What is that? Wait!
- Hey!
No!
I'll keep you informed of my progress.
Yes. Yes, you do that.
Mr. Merrick...
this is about science,
not profits...
or sadism.
You owe me two more.
Come on, Book.
You've been working on that for hours.
He's a security expert.
He leaves no footprints.
It's gonna take time.
You got a satellite link?
Yeah.
Follow the money.
Whoever he's working for, maybe?
That's how we track militants.
I'm sure you already tried that.
Yeah, it won't hurt to try again.
You know how it works, Nile.
Get some sleep while you can.
I brought you a change of clothes.
I'm going out for a bit.
- Are you all right, boss?
- Yeah.
Just because we keep living
doesn't mean we stop hurting.
Why us?
Yeah.
That way madness lies.
I thought you were
the brains of this outfit.
Tell you what I do wonder...
is why you?
And why now?
How old is Andy?
Well, she says she...
she doesn't remember.
And she may not. I don't know.
But what I do know
is she was alone for a long time
before she found anyone like her.
A very long time.
What about you? You have someone?
Just my family.
I had three sons.
And the youngest one, Jean-Pierre...
was the last one to die.
He was 42 when...
cancer took him.
The only way is forward now.
What do you mean?
You'll always and forever
be the young woman right there...
but everyone around you,
everyone you love...
is gonna grow old,
is gonna...
is gonna suffer and is gonna die.
And if you try to...
if you try to touch their lives...
well, they will get to learn your secret.
They will beg you to share it with them,
and you won't be able to.
And they won't believe you, of course.
And they will tell you...
that you don't love them.
That your love is weak...
or selfish.
And you will never forget...
the hate...
and despair in their eyes.
And you will know what it is to lose...
everyone you've ever loved.
Do you have a bathroom?
No.
But we have a storeroom.
Do you need help?
Stitches would be better, but...
this will help.
You haven't asked.
Your business is yours.
You need help.
What does it matter why?
Today, I put this on your wound.
Tomorrow...
you help someone up when they fall.
We're not meant to be alone.
There.
This should do.
Thank you.
Andromache, help me!
Why won't it stop?
This can't be happening.
Lykon.
It's time.
It's impossible.
It...
It's time.
How long will the testing take?
Until we have results we can replicate.
Do you feel the wound trying to close?
You don't need them for that.
You've got the samples,
blood, tissue, DNA.
Well, you know
the concept of proprietary data,
and they're the product.
They go in the vault.
They stay there under lock and key.
For... ever?
We can't have them strolling back out
into the world...
into my competitors' laps.
If this takes years, maybe decades,
what does it matter to them?
If we can unlock their genetic code,
the world will be begging us for the key.
Remarkable.
You will not be able
to give him what he wants.
You think I go too far?
That I am unethical?
I would say immoral.
I believe this can change the world.
A fine justification.
I've heard it so many times before.
As much as I like watching you sleep,
I'm glad you're awake.
Bed head?
Nicely tousled.
Do you know, I was thinking about Malta.
What time in Malta?
That time in Malta.
We should go back there.
That would be nice.
Your mom and brother?
You have my phone?
Where's your father?
Killed in action when I was 11.
Here...
My mom, she was drowning after he died.
South Side of Chicago,
a million different ways
we could have went left.
She fought for us.
Never backed down.
Never let us back down either.
You come from warriors.
Yeah.
I do.
I can't remember
what my mother looked like.
Or my sisters.
None of them.
Time steals it all away, I guess.
It's not what time steals...
it's what it leaves behind.
Things you can't forget.
I gave up searching for her.
I made Quynh a promise and I broke it.
I'm getting Joe and Nicky back.
Whatever it takes.
"Whatever it takes"?
Yes.
Guys, I found something.
An address just outside of London.
We gotta go.
Go scout the back.
I can't do this.
Yes, you can.
I mean, I'm not doing this.
You're one of us now.
We would do the same for you.
-I never even had a choice.
-None of us had a choice.
There isn't a choice.
The day I died,
I killed the guy that killed me.
They try to condition us, you know?
Thousands of hours of training.
Two shots, quick kill.
But they can't teach you how
to live with it.
You've gotta feel it, Nile.
Every one.
I saw what you did in that church.
All those bodies.
Is that supposed to be me?
Is that what we're supposed to do,
and we don't even know why?
You think knowing
is gonna make you sleep better at night?
I can't be that.
My family,
they're gonna get old and I won't,
but it'll be years
before they realize that.
I still have time with them.
Here.
Take the car,
and when you ditch it, ditch the weapons.
You gonna be okay?
Always.
Where's Nile?
You and me, Book. Now and always.
Guildford station
in one mile.
Empty?
Shit.
Andy.
Where are they?
Andromache the Scythian.
The eternal warrior.
-Book?
-I'm right here.
Where are Joe and Nicky?
What are you doing?
Calm down.
-What are you doing?
-Andy, calm down!
No!
Shh.
You set us up?
Please listen.
When my wife died,
I devoted myself to your work.
I learned your secret history,
written in the margins...
passed on like legend.
What was dismissed as a myth was,
in fact, immortality.
You could help end... needless suffering.
Humanity needs you to share your gifts.
Humanity can screw itself.
- Andy...
- Don't, you fucking coward.
Why?
Why, Book?
-Andy, listen...
-Why?
If Merrick can discover
how we keep living,
he might find a way how to end it.
Hey.
That's what you wanted.
Book. What have you done?
Not like this, Book.
What's going on?
You're still bleeding.
What? Shit.
She's not healing.
-What?
-Look at this. She's not healing.
Go get something. Go on! Go on!
Andy, look at me.
Look at me.
Why didn't you tell me?
It wouldn't have changed anything.
Hurry up!
Come on.
Careful.
Get her out of here.
Secure him.
Nice work, Copley.
Look at you.
She's wounded. Gunshot.
Why isn't she healing?
I don't know.
She's not immortal.
-What do you mean, "not immortal?"
-I mean it's gone.
You're a bloody mess.
Now, how old are you?
Come closer and I'll tell you.
Let's get them home.
- Let her go.
- Cover me.
- No! No!
- Let her go!
Get her up.
No!
I'm sorry, Andy.
I'm sorry.
Hold him still.
Mr. Merrick, look. If it's true and
she's somehow not immortal anymore,
then she might not survive the testing.
-This will be murder.
-As if the CIA never disappeared anyone.
As if they never conducted
covert research.
No.
No, this is not what we agreed.
We don't stop.
Andy.
What happened?
She's not healing.
I killed her.
I need to get a line in her
and stop the bleeding.
Keep her alive at all costs.
Don't you see? Between Sudan and now,
something's changed.
- Find out what.
- This will stabilize her,
but I have to stitch her
- and give her antibiotics.
- Good.
All things die.
What was that?
Everything has to die, Mr. Merrick.
The only reason we haven't...
is that it's not our time yet.
If it's now Andromache's,
nothing you can do will stop it.
You'd be surprised by
what my products can do.
I will carve slices off you for years
to get what I want.
Your time is coming.
As is yours.
I expect results!
Andy.
Are you Copley?
-He sent you to finish me off.
-Who?
Where's Andy and Booker?
Who are you?
Son of a bitch!
You're another one.
Yeah. I'm new.
-Where are they?
-They're in a lab...
being tested.
Tortured.
Merrick...
he only cares about her immortality,
not what she's done with it.
"What she's done with it"?
Montenegro, 1916.
She saved a family of refugees
whose daughter would discover
the technique
for the early detection of diabetes.
This one...
Her grandson would save 317 people
from the Khmer Rouge in Cambodia.
This guy...
This man prevented
an accidental nuclear exchange in 1978
and likely saved civilization as a result.
The famous...
and the unknown names.
She saves a life,
two, three generations later,
we reap the benefits.
She's in it.
She can't see it.
But you could.
You could and you gave them up.
I thought it could be the end of disease.
I thought it could be
the end of suffering.
She couldn't talk...
at the end...
my wife.
She couldn't breathe.
I couldn't do...
anything.
It was supposed to be a gift...
to the world.
It wasn't your gift to give.
Why would the immortality end?
What?
She wouldn't stop bleeding.
Is she alive?
I know where they are.
There's no cameras here.
That's how he gets people
in and out unseen.
- How many shooters on site?
- At least 30.
Their boss, Keane, is ex-Special Forces.
What kind of CEO rolls around
with his own personal army?
These days?
Most of them.
-What are you doing?
-I'm gonna make this right.
Your dying won't do that.
But I'm supposed to let you
walk in there by yourself?
Out of the two of us,
I'm the one
who will walk out of there again,
one way or another.
You got me here.
There's a private lab on the 15th floor.
It's empty.
This will get you access.
You should get out of here
before the noise starts.
Good luck, Ms. Freeman.
Floor's closed. How'd you get up here?
Sorry, I was just looking...
Hands! Let me see your hands.
Zero, this is Alpha 2-2.
Sir.
Zero. Send.
We've had an intruder.
Target is down.
See if you can get an ID off the body.
Shit!
TAC teams, find Merrick now!
-You selfish piece of shit!
-Joe, leave it. Please!
What do you know
of the weight of all these years alone?
- You're a very pathetic man, Booker.
- Joe, Stop.
You and Nicky
always had each other, right?
And all we had...
was our grief.
Well, now you have even more.
-Who the hell are you?
-Where's the lab?
Shit!
There's another one!
She's going for the rest of them.
Doctor's lab, now!
I'm locking you down in the penthouse
until this is over.
Nile.
Behind you!
Nile!
There's four shooters at the door
and more coming.
Andy.
Immortal or not,
you made a promise.
Whatever it takes.
I've seen it, Andy.
I know all the good you've done.
You came back.
Yeah.
No, just leave me here.
No man left behind.
There's always a first time.
He's nothing but a traitor. That's...
Stop! This is not the time for it.
We don't get a say in when it ends.
We never have.
But we can control how we live.
And to be honest, Book,
you and I,
we've been doing a shit job of it.
Now, get up.
Let's go.
We stop Merrick here and now
or he never stops coming after us.
Andy.
Are you sure?
This changes nothing.
We walk out of here like always.
Together.
Let's get this motherfucker.
Cover Andy.
Andy!
Man! Andy!
Joe, Nicky, we're moving out!
Assault team, move! You two, flank.
What's your location?
Enough of this shit.
Let's go. Andy.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Shit! Jammed!
Where's Andy?
Hold at the bridge.
- Roger that.
- Fuck.
Where's Merrick?
Penthouse.
What do you think? Oslo, '67?
São Paulo, '34. Nile's with me.
What happened in São Paulo in 1934?
1834.
You'll see.
First team, hold the hall.
First team.
Wait for the signal.
This gonna be like the last signal?
Go big or go home.
Keane.
Keane, how many more do we have coming?
This is it. Dig in.
I'll make the entry.
Stay tight to me, okay?
I'll protect you.
I go through first.
I always go first.
Andy, put on the damn armor.
It's like Nicky said,
"If it's my time, it's my time."
If this doesn't work out,
next time, you go first.
What the hell are they waiting for?
Shit!
You shot Nicky.
You shouldn't have done that.
The elevator is going down!
-Merrick is getting away!
-Go!
I'll stay with Andy.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
It just hurts.
Actually, everything hurts.
Well, wait until tomorrow.
Can't wait.
I think you showed up
when I lost my immortality.
So I could see what it was like.
So I could remember.
Remember?
Remember what it...
what it was like to feel unbreakable.
Remarkable.
You reminded me there are people...
still worth fighting for.
I know how I want to spend the time
I've got left.
You're gonna spend it with us, Andy.
You selfish little bitch!
I will kill her!
All the lives you could save.
Don't you see what we could do here?
You are priceless.
Hey, Nile.
Do you think he speaks Russian?
Play dead, motherfucker.
Nile?
Hey.
She's okay.
Come on.
Faster than the elevator.
It's okay, Nile.
Give me your hand.
Let's go.
How's it going?
They're still deciding.
There's not much to decide.
It's not like they can kill me.
She gave it back?
Yeah.
Talked to Copley.
Said he could fix it.
Make it look like I was killed in action.
My family will mourn, but...
...they'll be able to move on.
It's just like what we did with my dad.
I just really want to hear my mom's voice
one more time.
You're a good kid, Nile.
You're gonna be great for the team.
There's got to be a price.
One hundred years from today,
they'll meet you here.
Till then, you're alone.
I hoped for less, but...
I expected more.
Nile was gonna let you off
with an apology.
Just give her some time.
I'm gonna miss you.
Um...
I won't see you again.
Have a little faith, Book.
This is only what I've found
going back the last 150 years or so.
When you think about how old you are,
the good you've done for humanity
becomes exponential.
Maybe this is the why, Andy.
It's nearly impossible to disappear
in the world we live in today.
There are too many people like you
who can bend it to your will.
Too many with bad intentions.
We don't have all the answers,
but we do have purpose.
And you're going to help us.
When we leave a footprint in the sand,
in the snow, in the ether,
you're going to sweep it.
You're going to protect us
from those who want to put us in cages,
and you're gonna help us
find those jobs...
that are best suited to us.
She's not asking.
I'd be honored.
Then let's go to work.
Booker.
It's nice to finally meet you.