You're live in two minutes,
Your Royal Highness.
Sir?
Thank you.
Let the microphone do the work, sir.
I'm sure you'll be splendid.
Just take your time.
Time to go.
Good afternoon.
This is the BBC National Programme
and Empire Service
taking you to Wembley Stadium
for the closing ceremony
of the Empire Exhibition,
where His Royal Highness,
the Duke of York,
will read a message from his father,
His Majesty King George V.
Fifty-eight British colonies
and dominions have taken part,
making this the largest exhibition
staged anywhere in the world.
Remember, sir, three flashes,
then steady red means you're live.
Using the new invention of radio,
the opening ceremony was the first time
His Majesty the King
addressed his subjects on the wireless.
At the close of the first season,
the heir to the throne,
His Royal Highness, the Prince of Wales,
made his first broadcast, and today,
his younger brother,
His Royal Highness, the Duke of York,
will give his inaugural broadcast
to the nation and the world.
I have received...
...from His Majesty the...
...the...
...the King...
Inhale deep into your lungs,
Your Royal Highness.
Relaxes your larynx, does it not?
Cigarette smoking calms the nerves,
and gives you confidence.
Now, if Your Royal Highness
would be so kind as to open your hand.
Sterilized.
One, two,
three, four,
five, six...
...seven. Now, if I may take the
liberty, insert them into your mouth.
Excuse me, Doctor.
What is the purpose of this?
It's the classic approach.
It cured Demosthenes.
That was in Ancient Greece.
Has it worked since?
Now, if you would be
so kind as to read.
"A wealth of words."
Fight against those marbles,
Your Royal Highness.
Enunciate.
A little more concentration,
Your Royal Highness.
I nearly swallowed the bloody things!
Thank you so much, Doctor.
It's been most, um...
- ...interesting.
- Your Royal Highness.
Insert marbles.
He can insert his own bloody marbles.
Tick, tock. Tick, tock.
You know you can't
keep doing this, Bertie.
- I know.
- Mmm.
Promise me...
Promise me no more.
Subtitle
www.movieddl.me
Ah!
Hello?
- Is anyone there?
- I'm just in the loo.
Ah, Mrs. Johnson, there you are.
I'm sorry, I don't have a receptionist.
I like to keep things simple.
"Poor and content
is rich and rich enough."
- I'm sorry?
- Shakespeare. How are you?
- How do you do?
- Oh, chuff tog along.
Um, now, this is slightly awkward,
but I'm afraid you're late.
- Yes. I'm afraid I am.
- Where's Mr. Johnson?
Ah... He doesn't know I'm here.
Well, that's not a very promising start.
No. No, look,
my husband has seen everyone.
To no avail.
I'm awfully afraid he's given up hope.
- He hasn't seen me.
- Awfully sure of yourself.
Well, I'm sure of anyone
who wants to be cured.
Of course he wants to be cured.
My husband is, um...
- Well, he's required to speak publicly.
- Perhaps he should change jobs.
- He can't.
- Indentured servitude?
Something of that nature, yes.
Well, we need to have your hubby pop by.
Uh... Tuesday would be good.
He can give me his personal details,
I'll make a frank appraisal
- and then we'll take it from there.
- Doctor, forgive me.
Uh, I don't have a "hubby."
We don't "pop."
And nor do we ever talk about
our private lives.
No, you must come to us.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Johnson,
my game, my turf, my rules.
Mmm.
You'll have to talk this over
with your husband,
and then you can speak to me
on the telephone.
Thank you very much for dropping by.
Good afternoon.
And what if my husband
were the Duke of York?
- The Duke of York?
- Yes. The Duke of York.
I thought the appointment
was for Johnson. Forgive me, Your...
- Royal Highness.
- ...Royal Highness.
Yes, Johnson was used during the Great
War, when the Navy didn't want the enemy
- to know he was aboard.
- Am I considered the enemy?
You will be, if you remain un-obliging.
You'll appreciate the need
for absolute discretion.
Of course.
How did you find me,
Your Royal Highness?
The President of The Society
For Speech Therapists.
Eileen McCleod?
She's a sport.
She warned me your Antipodean methods
were both "unorthodox"
and "controversial."
I warned her those
are not my favorite words.
I can cure your husband.
But for my method to work,
I need trust and total equality, here
in the safety of my consultation room.
No exceptions.
Oh, well. In that case...
When can you start?
- She's still sounding a bit rough.
- You make me drive too slowly, Dad.
- Did you pick Mum up from bridge?
- Yeah, I've hardly been out of the car.
I had a special visitor this afternoon.
- May I please leave the table?
- How special's special?
You must stay, bored stupid, listening
to your parents' inane conversation.
- Thanks, Dad.
- And Mum.
- Me, too.
- You meeting Jean?
- No. Someone else.
- Doctor? Doctor?
- Hmm?
Go and help your brother
with the washing up.
- I'm fine.
- Who is it, Lionel?
Why bring it up
if you can't talk about it?
Myrtle, it's just a woman
looking to help her husband.
Oh, and I had a call... for an audition.
- One of my favorites.
- Aren't they all?
Could be a lot of fun.
I'm sure you'll be splendid.
In the amateur scene,
they're a highly regarded group.
From Putney.
No, that's all girls.
Tomorrow, chapter four, "The Flight."
Mama,
I long to know where they fly to.
- I can't wait!
- Oh, to fly away.
Weren't they lucky?
Now Papa, tell a story.
Can't I be a penguin instead?
Well, no, I want a penguin story.
Very quickly.
Once there were...
two princesses.
Princess Elizabeth
and Princess Margaret,
whose papa was a penguin.
This was because he'd been
turned into one by a wicked witch.
This was very inconvenient for him
because he loved...
...to hold his princesses in his arms.
But you can't if you're a penguin
because you...
- ...you have wings like herrings.
- Herrings don't have wings.
Penguins have wings which are...
are shaped like herrings.
And what made matters worse is that
she... she sent him to the South Pole,
which is an awfully long walk back if...
...if you can't fly.
So when he reached the water, he...
...he dived in, through the depths,
so fast that he was in
Southampton Waters by lunchtime.
And from there,
he took the 2:30 to Weybridge,
changed at Clapham Junction, asked a...
...a passing mallard the way
to Buckingham Palace,
swam up The Thames,
out through the plughole
and gave the cook, Mama
and Mrs. Whittaker quite a shock.
Now, when the girls
heard all the commotion,
they ran to the kitchen,
where they gave him a...
...a good scrub, a mackerel and a kiss.
And as they kissed him...
...guess what he turned into?
- A handsome prince.
- A short-tailed albatross.
- Oh.
- With wings so big,
that he could wrap them both around
his two girls together.
Now, girls. Time for bed. Come on.
- And take those horses to the stable.
- Quickly, now.
- You have exactly a minute.
- Good night.
Feed them, brush them and to bed.
- Will Mrs. Simpson be there?
- My brother's insisting.
- Is he serious?
- About her coming to dinner?
No. About her.
- A married woman? He can't be.
- She can.
By the way, I think I've found
someone rather interesting.
On Harley Street. Doctor.
Out of the question.
I'm not having this conversation again.
Mat... Matter's settled.
Mmm. His approach
seems rather different.
Now?
Now.
Now is the winter of our discontent,
made glorious summer
by this sun of York.
And all the clouds
that lour'd upon our house
in the deep bosom of the ocean buried.
Now are our brows bound
with... victorious...
Thank you.
- Lovely diction, Mr...
- Logue. Lionel Logue.
Well, Mr. Logue,
I'm not hearing the cries
of a deformed creature
yearning to be king.
Nor did I realize Richard Ill
was King of the Colonies.
I do know all the lines.
I've played the role before.
- Sydney?
- Perth.
Major theater town, is it?
- Enthusiastic.
- Ah.
I was well reviewed.
Yes.
Well, Lionel,
I think our dramatic society
is looking for someone slightly younger.
And a... little more regal.
- There you are.
- Thank you.
- Oh.
- Mmm.
No, you have to shut that one first.
Close that one first. That's it.
Where did you find this... physician?
Classifieds. Next to a
"French model, Shepherd's Market."
No, he comes highly recommended.
Charges substantial fees
to help the poor.
Oh, dear. Perhaps he's a Bolshevik.
Ah, there's no receptionist.
Likes to keep things simple.
Uh... The Johnsons.
You can go in now, Mr. Johnson.
Lionel says wait here
if you wish, Mrs. Johnson.
Or, it being a...
...pleasant day...
...perhaps take a stroll.
Was that all right, Lionel?
Marvelous, Willie.
You can stay here and wait for your mum.
Mrs. Johnson.
Mr. Johnson. Do come in.
Would you like a sweetie?
He's a good lad, Willie.
He could hardly make a sound, you know,
when he first came to me.
My boys make those.
They're good, aren't they?
Please, make yourself comfortable.
I was told not to sit too close.
I believe when speaking with a prince,
one waits for the prince
to choose the topic.
Waiting for me to...
...commence a conversation,
one can wait rather a long wait.
Ah, yes, well...
Do you know any jokes?
- Timing isn't my strong suit.
- Cup of tea?
- No. No, thank you.
- I think I'll have one.
Aren't you going to start treating me,
Dr. Logue?
Only if you're interested
in being treated.
Please, call me Lionel.
No, I... prefer Doctor.
I prefer Lionel.
- What will I call you?
- Your Royal Highness.
Then... it's "sir" after that.
It's a little bit formal for here.
I prefer names.
Prince Albert Frederick Arthur...
...George.
How about Bertie?
- Only my family uses that.
- Perfect.
In here, it's better if we're equals.
If... if we were equals,
I wouldn't be here.
I'd be... at home with my wife,
and no one would give a damn.
Please, don't do that.
I'm sorry?
I believe sucking smoke into your lungs,
well, it will kill you.
My physicians say it relaxes the...
- ...the throat.
- They're idiots.
- They've all been knighted.
- Makes it official, then.
My castle, my rules.
Thank you.
What was your earliest memory?
- What on earth do you mean?
- Your first recollection.
I'm not...
...here to discuss personal matters.
- Well, why are you here, then?
- Because I bloody well stammer!
- You have a bit of a temper.
- One of my many faults.
- When did the defect start?
- I've always been this way.
- I doubt that.
- Don't...
- ...tell me, it's my stammer.
- It's my field.
I can assure you, no infant
starts to speak with a stammer.
When did yours start?
- Four or five.
- That's typical.
So I've been told.
I... I can't remember not doing it.
I can believe that.
Do you hesitate when you think?
- Don't be ridiculous.
- How about when you talk to yourself?
Everyone natters to themselves
occasionally, Bertie.
Stop... Stop calling me that.
I'm not going to call you anything else.
Then we shan't speak.
Are you charging for this, Doctor?
A fortune.
I'll just let that brew.
So... when you talk to yourself,
do you stammer?
No... of course not.
Well, that proves that your impediment
isn't a permanent part of you.
What do you think was the cause?
I don't... don't know.
I... I don't... I don't care.
I... I stammer.
No one can fix it.
I'll bet you that you can read
flawlessly, right here, right now.
And if I win the bet,
I get to ask you more questions.
- And if I win?
- You don't have to answer them.
One usually... wagers money.
A bob each to keep it sweet?
- Let's see your shilling.
- I don't... carry money.
I had a funny feeling you mightn't.
I'll stake you, and you can
pay me back next time.
- If there is a next time.
- I haven't agreed to take you on yet.
So please stand, uh,
and take a look at that.
From there.
I... I can't read this.
Well, then you owe me
a shilling for not trying.
To be...
...or not to be, that...
- Can't read it.
- Uh-uh-uh! I haven't finished yet.
I'm going to record your voice and then
play it back to you on the same machine.
This is brilliant.
It's the latest thing from America.
It's a Silvertone.
Pop these on.
There's a bob in this, mate.
You could go home rich.
- You're playing music!
- I know.
So how can I hear what I'm saying?
Well, surely a prince's brain
knows what its mouth's doing?
You're not... well acquainted
with royal princes, are you?
Hopeless.
Hopeless!
You were sublime.
Would I lie to a prince of the realm
to win 12 pennies?
I've no idea...
...what an Australian
might do for that sort of money.
Let me play it back to you.
No.
All right, then, well,
I get to ask you the questions.
Thank you, Doctor. I don't...
...feel this is for me.
Thank you for your time.
Goodbye.
Sir.
The recording is free.
Please keep it as a souvenir.
No.
Oh, well.
Bugger.
For the present, the work
to which we are all equally bound
is to arrive at a reasoned tranquility
within our borders,
to regain prosperity
at this time of depression
without self-seeking,
and to carry with us
those whom the burden of the past years
has disheartened or overborne.
To all, to each,
I wish a happy Christmas.
God bless you.
And off air.
Easy when you know how.
Sir?
Have a go yourself.
- Congratulations, sir.
- Ah, Mr. Wood.
Splendid fellow.
Chap who taught me everything I know.
- Let the microphone do the work.
- Sir.
- Thank you.
- Gentlemen.
Sit up. Straight back.
Face boldly up to the bloody thing
and stare it square in the eye,
as would any decent Englishman.
Show who's in command.
Papa, I don't... think I can read this.
This devilish device will change
everything if you don't.
In the past, all a king had to do
was look respectable in uniform
and not fall off his horse.
Now, we must invade people's homes
and ingratiate ourselves with them.
This family's been reduced to those
lowest, basest of all creatures.
We've become actors.
We're not a family, we're a firm.
Yet at any moment,
some of us may be out of work.
Your darling brother and future king,
the only wife he appears interested in
is invariably the wife of another.
- He's broken off with Lady Furness.
- And taken up with Mrs. Simpson.
A woman with two husbands living.
I told him straight.
No divorced person
can ever be received at court.
He said it made him
sublimely happy.
I imagine that was
because she was sleeping with him.
"I give you my word,"
this is what he said.
"I give you my word,
we've never had immoral relations."
Stared square into
his father's face and lied.
When I'm dead,
that boy will ruin himself,
this family and this nation
within 12 months.
Who will pick up the pieces, hmm?
Herr Hitler intimidating half of Europe.
Marshal Stalin the other half.
Who will stand between us,
the jackboots
and the proletarian abyss?
You?
Well?
With your older brother
shirking his duties,
you're going to have to do
a lot more of this.
Have a go yourself.
Through the...
- ...wireless...
- Get it out, boy.
...one of the...
...marvels of...
"Modern." Just take your time.
Form your words carefully.
...science...
...I am enabled...
Relax.
Just try it!
...this Christmas Day...
...to speak to all my...
Do it!
Lying... bastard.
- You're playing music.
- I know.
So how can I...
hear what I'm saying?
Well, surely a prince's brain
knows what its mouth's doing.
You're not... well acquainted
with royal princes, are you?
"To be or not be,
that is the question.
Whether tis nobler in the mind to suffer
the slings and arrows
of outrageous fortune,
or to take arms
against a sea of troubles,
and by opposing end them?
To die, to sleep no more,
and by a sleep to say the end
is the heartache
and the thousand natural shocks
the flesh is heir to.
Tis a consummation hopeless."
Hopeless!
Strictly business. No...
- ...personal nonsense.
- Yes, I thought I'd made that clear
- in our interview.
- Have you got the shilling you owe me?
- No, I haven't.
- Didn't think so.
Besides, you... you tricked me.
Physical exercises
and tricks are important,
but what you're asking will only deal
with the surface of the problem.
Is that sufficient? Uh, no.
As far as I see it, my husband has
mechanical difficulties with his speech.
- I...
- Maybe just deal with that.
I...
- I'm willing to work hard, Dr. Logue.
- Lionel.
Are you...
Are you willing to do your part?
All right. You want mechanics?
We need to relax your jaw muscles,
strengthen your tongue,
by repeating tongue twisters.
For example, "I'm a thistle-sifter.
I have a sieve of sifted thistles
and a sieve of unsifted thistles.
- Because I am a thistle-sifter."
- Fine.
And you do have a flabby tummy,
so we'll need to spend some time
strengthening your diaphragm.
Simple mechanics.
- That's all we ask.
- All that's about a shilling's worth.
Forget about the blessed shilling!
Perhaps, upon occasions...
...you might be requested to assist...
...in coping with...
...with some minor event.
Would that be agreeable?
Of course.
Yes, and that would be the full extent
of your services.
- Shall I see you next week?
- I shall see you every day.
Feel the looseness of the jaw.
Good. Little bounces. Bounces.
Shoulders loose, shoulders loose.
Beautiful, beautiful, beautiful.
Now, loose.
Take a nice deep breath.
Expand the chest.
Put your hands onto your ribs.
Deeper. Good.
- How do you feel?
- Full of hot air.
Isn't that what
public speaking's all about?
My wife and I are glad
to visit this important...
Take a good deep breath,
and up comes Your Royal Highness.
And slowly exhale,
and down comes Your Royal Highness.
- You all right, Bertie?
- Yes.
It's actually quite good fun.
Mmm... Mother.
Shorten
the humming each time.
Mother. Mmm...
- ...- manufacturing district...
- Another deep breath.
- And Jack and Jill.
- Jack and Jill.
- Went up the hill.
Now, just sway.
Perfect.
- ...will not permit us to...
- Loosen the shoulders.
Ding dong bell,
pussy's in the well.
Who put her in? Little Tommy Tin.
You have a short memory, Bertie.
Come on.
- A cow, a cow...
- A king.
A... a king...
Anyone who can shout vowels at an open
window can learn to deliver a speech.
- Fourteen, 15!
- Good. Deep breath, and...
It is...
- Let the words flow.
- No, it doesn't bloody work.
Come on, one more time, Bertie.
You can do it.
A sieve of thisted siphles.
Gah! Mah! Bah!
Father.
- Father.
- Aim for the a-t-h.
Father. Father.
- Hello, Bertie.
- Hello, David.
- Nice of you to come out.
- Not at all.
You been waiting long?
Christ, bloody freezing.
Where have you been?
- I've been busy.
- So have I.
- Elizabeth has pneumonia.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- She'll recover.
- Father won't.
I'll drive.
Old bugger's doing this on purpose.
- Dying?
- Departing prematurely.
To... To complicate matters with Wallis.
For heaven's sake, David.
You know how long he's been ill.
Wallis explained. She's terribly clever
about these things.
Whereas my letters patent
under the Great Seal
bearing date of Westminster
the 11th day of June 1912,
His Majesty King George the Fifth
did constitute order
and declare that there
should be a Guardian...
- What's going on here?
- ...custos regne...
I cannot follow you.
I'm confused and I don't understand...
It's the Order
of the Council of State, sir.
So that we may act on your behalf...
...much clearer to me, I'm afraid...
- Well, I'm so confused that...
- Approved.
Thank you.
- Let me help you, sir.
- Ah, yes...
- Thank you, sir.
- Thank you.
- Feeling a little better, sir?
- No, I'm not feeling any better.
I feel dreadful. Ah...
Been, uh, ice skating? Ice skating?
No. No, George.
Yes. Yes, all right, of course.
I know, darling.
A talk, even a lovely long talk
is a poor substitute
for holding tight and making drowsy.
Nor making our own drowsies either,
as we've had to do too often lately.
- David. Dinner.
- I'm on with Wallis.
It's Bertie.
No. No, it's not important.
I don't want to.
No. Telephone me later?
All right, goodbye.
- Wallis misses me terribly.
- Mama says you're late for dinner.
She forgets Papa's bloody clocks
are all half an hour fast.
How's the King?
I... I hope he's not in pain.
No, no, sir.
His Majesty's quieter now.
Thank you.
David, if your father were here,
tardiness would not be tolerated.
None of this unpleasantness
would be tolerated.
You know, sir, I appreciate
that you are different from your father,
both in outlook and... temperament.
I want you to know that whenever
the King questioned your conduct,
I tried, in your interest,
to present it
in the most favorable light.
Mmm. I can always trust you
to have my best interests at heart.
I fear our vigil will not be
of long duration. Please continue.
Let us commend our brother George
to the mercy of God,
our Maker and Redeemer.
Long live the King.
I hope I will make good
as he has made good.
- What on earth was that?
- Poor Wallis.
Now, I'm trapped.
And in these last 25
crowded, troubled, glorious years,
if there is one thing
that King George has taught,
it is the art of the leader who
is also a brother to his followers.
As long as he lived, he was
the guiding star of a great nation.
- Dad?
- Mmm-hmm?
- When he died...
- Time for a Shake, Dad?
...the little children
cried in the streets.
- You sure?
- Go on.
Put your thinking caps on.
- I bet it's the Scottish play.
- No, it's Othello. It's always Othello.
Art thou afeard?
- Be not afeard.
- Caliban.
Oh, for heaven's sake.
That was a lucky guess.
Don't listen to egghead. Go on, Dad.
The isle is full of noises,
sounds and sweet airs
that give delight, and hurt not.
Sometimes a thousand twangling
instruments will hum about mine ears,
and sometimes voices, that,
if then I had waked after long sleep,
will make me sleep again. All right,
clever clogs, so what comes next?
And then, in dreaming,
methought the clouds would...
- The clouds methought.
- The clouds methought would open,
and show riches ready to drop upon me,
that when I waked,
I cried to dream again.
That's such a sad thought.
My next patient must be a bit early.
You better go, lads, I'm sorry.
Won't be a moment, Clifford.
Bertie?
They told me not to expect you.
I'm sorry about your father.
- I don't wish to intrude.
- Not at all. Please, come in. Come in.
I've been practicing. An hour a day.
In spite of everything.
What's going on there?
Oh, I was... Sorry.
Mucking around with my kids.
Do you feel like working today?
- Curtis biplane.
- I'll put on some hot milk.
Logue. Logue.
I'd kill for something stronger.
I wasn't there
for my father's death.
- Still makes me sad.
- I can imagine so.
- What did your father do?
- He was a brewer.
At least there was free beer.
Here's to the memory of your father.
I was informed, after the fact,
that my father's...
My father's last words were...
..."Bertie has more guts than the
rest of his brothers put together."
Couldn't say that to my face.
My brother.
What about him?
Try singing it.
- I'm sorry?
- What songs do you know?
- Songs?
- Yeah, songs.
- Swanee River.
- I love that song.
- It happens to be my favorite.
- Sing me the chorus.
No. Certainly not.
You know...
I always wanted to build models.
But... Father wouldn't allow it.
He... collected stamps,
so we had to collect stamps.
You can finish that off if you sing.
♪ My brother David
Dum, dum, dum, dum... ♪
- I'm not going to sit here warbling.
- You can with me.
- Because you're peculiar.
- I take that as a compliment.
Well...
Rules are rules.
I'm not... crooning Swanee River.
Camptown Races, then.
♪ My brother David said to me
♪ Doo-dah, doo-dah ♪
- Continuous sound will give you flow.
- No.
Does it feel strange
now that David's on the throne?
To tell the truth, it was a relief.
Knowing I...
...wouldn't be... King.
But unless he produces an heir,
you're next in line.
And your daughter, Elizabeth,
would then succeed you.
♪ You're barking up
the wrong tree now, Doctor, Doctor ♪
♪ Lionel ♪
See? You didn't stammer.
Of course I didn't stammer,
I was singing.
Well, as a little reward, you get
to put some glue on these struts.
- Your boy... won't mind?
- No, not at all.
David and I were... very close.
Young bucks, you know.
Did you chase the same girls?
David was always very helpful
in... arranging introductions.
We shared the...
...expert ministrations
of Paulette in the Palace.
Not at the same time, of course.
- Did David ever tease you?
- Oh, yes, they all did.
"B-B-B-Bertie."
Father encouraged it.
Said, "Get it out, boy!"
Said it would make me stop.
He said, "I was afraid of my father
and my children are...
damn well gonna be afraid of me!"
Are you naturally right-handed?
Left.
I was... punished,
and now I use the right.
Yes, that's very common with stammerers.
- Any other corrections?
- Knock knees.
Metal splints were made.
Worn... worn day and night.
- Must have been painful.
- Bloody agony.
Straight legs now.
Who were you closest to in your family?
Nannies.
Not my first nanny. She...
She loved David. Hated me.
When we were...
...presented to my parents
for the daily viewing,
she would... she'd pinch me
so that I'd cry and be handed back
to her immediately.
And then she would...
Sing it.
♪ Then she wouldn't feed me
♪ Far, far away ♪
Took my parents...
three years to notice.
As you... as you can imagine,
caused some stomach problems.
Still.
What about your brother, Johnnie?
Were you close to him?
Johnnie... sweet boy.
Had...
...epilepsy.
And he was... different.
He died at... 13.
Hidden from view.
I'm... I'm told it's not... catching.
Do you want a top-up?
Please.
You know...
...Lionel, you're...
...you're the first
ordinary Englishman...
- Australian.
- ...I've ever really spoken to.
When I'm... driven through the streets
and I see the, you know,
the common man staring at me, I...
...I'm struck by how little
I know of his life
and how little he knows of mine.
- Thank you.
- What are friends for?
I wouldn't know.
I sifted seven...
...thick-stalked thistles
through a strong, thick sieve.
- I sifted seven thick-stalked...
- That's enough now, darling.
Listen, I have to keep doing this,
it's awful. I sifted seven...
- Oh, no.
- ...thick-stalked...
One-hundred-year-old spruces
removed to improve the view?
Who does she think she is?
Nonetheless, we must try
to be pleasant towards Mrs. Simpson.
- She calls me "The Fat Scottish Cook."
- You're not fat.
I'm getting plump.
Well, you seldom cook.
- I sifted seven...
- Shut up.
...thick sieves...
I sifted seven...
Three, two, one and...
Their Royal Highnesses
the Duke and Duchess of York.
Oh, how lovely to see you both.
Welcome to our little country shack.
I came at the invitation of the King.
Your Majesty.
- You all right?
- Sorry we're late.
Very nice to see you... Mrs. Simpson.
Very nice.
Hello, David. Making some...
...changes to the garden, I see.
Yes, I'm not quite finished yet.
Don't tell me I behaved badly,
Mr. Churchill.
On the contrary, Your Royal Highness.
Etiquette decrees that royalty
should be greeted by the official host,
in this case, the King. Not a commoner.
Thank you.
- What is her hold on him?
- I've no idea.
Apparently, she has certain skills
acquired in an establishment
in Shanghai.
David.
Just be a sec, darling.
Would you excuse me?
- David, I've been trying to see you.
- I've been terribly busy.
- Doing what?
- Kinging.
Really? Kinging is a...
...a precarious business these days.
Where's the Russian tsar?
- Where's cousin Wilhelm?
- You're being dreary.
Is kinging laying off 80... staff
and buying more pearls for Wallis,
while people are marching across Europe
singing The Red Flag?
- Herr Hitler will sort them out.
- Who will sort out Herr Hitler?
Where's the bloody 23?
And you put that woman
in our mother's suite!
- Mama's not still in the bed, is she?
- That's not funny.
Here it is. Wallis likes the very best.
I don't care what woman
you carry on with at night,
as long as you... show up
for duty in the morning.
Wallis is not just some woman
I'm carrying on with.
We intend to marry.
- Excuse me?
- She's filing a petition for divorce.
Good God.
Can't you just give her
a nice house and a title?
- I'm not having her as my mistress.
- The Church doesn't recognize divorce,
- and you are the... head of the Church.
- Haven't I any rights?
- Many privileges.
- Not the same thing.
Your beloved common man
may marry for love. Why not me?
If you were... a common man,
on what basis could you...
possibly claim to be King?
Sounds like you've
studied our wretched Constitution.
- Sounds like you haven't.
- That's what this is about.
Brushing up.
Hence, the elocution lessons.
- That's the scoop around town.
- I'm trying to...
Yearning for a larger audience,
are we, B-B-Bertie?
Don't...
What's that?
I'm sorry, I...
Younger brother trying to push
older brother off the throne.
P-P-Positively mediaeval.
Wallis.
Ah. Where have you been all this time?
- Who have you been talking to?
- Never you mind.
What a very complicated
little King you are.
I try to be.
All that work... down the drain.
My own brother.
I couldn't say a single word
to him in reply.
Why do you stammer so much more
with David than you ever do with me?
Because you're bloody well
paid to listen.
- Bertie, I'm not a geisha girl.
- Stop trying to be so bloody clever.
What is it about David
that stops you speaking?
What is it about you that bloody
well makes you want to go on about him
- the whole bloody time?
- Vulgar but fluent.
- You don't stammer when you swear.
- Bugger off!
- Is that the best you can do?
- Well, bloody...
...bugger to you, you beastly bastard.
Oh, a public school prig
could do better than that.
Shit.
Shit, shit, shit.
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit, shit!
Yes, defecation flows
trippingly from the tongue.
- Because I'm angry!
- Do you know the "f" word?
- Fornication?
- Oh, Bertie.
Fuck. Fuck!
Fuck, fuck, fuckin' fuck!
Fuck, fuck and bugger!
Bugger, bugger, buggedy, fuck!
- Fuck, ass!
- Yes!
- Balls, balls, fuckety shit.
- You see? Not a hesitation.
Willy, shit and fuck! And tits.
- Dad, what's going on?
- Sorry.
Just finish your homework.
Well, that's a side of you
we don't get to see all that often.
No.
No, we're not supposed to, really.
Not publicly.
- Let's get some air.
- No, I don't think that's a good idea.
What's the matter?
Why are you so upset?
Logue, you have no idea.
My... my brother
is infatuated with a...
...woman who's been married twice.
She's asking for a divorce,
and he's determined to marry her.
- Jesus.
- Mrs. Wallis Simpson
- of Baltimore.
- That's not right.
- Queen Wallis of Baltimore.
- Unthinkable.
- Can he do it?
- Absolutely not.
But he's going to anyway.
All hell's broken loose.
- Can't they just carry on privately?
- If only they would.
Where does this leave you?
I know my place. I...
I... I will do anything...
...in my power to keep
my brother on the throne.
Is it that serious?
- Your place may well be on the throne.
- I am not an alternative to my brother.
- You can outshine David.
- Don't take liberties!
- That's bordering on treason.
- I'm just saying you could be King.
- You could do it.
- That is treason.
I'm trying to get you to realize
you needn't be governed by fear.
I've had enough of this.
- What are you so afraid of?
- Your poisonous words!
Why did you come to me?
You're not some middle-class banker
who wants elocution lessons
so you can chitchat...
Don't attempt to instruct me
on my duties!
I am the son of a... King.
And the brother of... of a King.
You're the disappointing son
of a brewer.
A jumped-up jackeroo from the outback.
You're a nobody.
These sessions are over.
Through here, sir.
It's not because she's an
American. That is the least of it.
It's because she's a soon
to be twice divorced American.
And the King,
as head of the Church of England,
cannot marry a divorced woman.
And, sir, I apologize
for the nature of this.
According to Scotland Yard,
the King has not always
possessed exclusive rights
to Mrs. Simpson's...
favors and affections...
...sharing them with a
married used car salesman,
a certain Mr. Guy Trundle.
In addition, it is also
rumored Hitler's ambassador,
Count von Ribbentrop,
sends her 17 carnations every day.
Should His Majesty continue to ignore
the advice of his government,
he must abdicate.
Otherwise, his government
has no choice but to resign.
Prime Minister,
you'd leave a country without a...
...a government?
Does the King do what he wants?
Or does he do what
the people expect him to do?
As crowds in Downing
Street watch ministers come and go,
there is raised an age-old problem:
can a king separate his personal life
- from his public duty...
- What's the matter, love?
I'm just having trouble with a patient.
That isn't like you.
- Why?
- He's scared.
He's afraid of his own shadow.
Isn't that why they come to you?
This fellow could
really be somebody great.
He's fighting me.
Perhaps he doesn't want to be great.
Perhaps that's what you want.
I might have overstepped the mark.
Apologize. Do you both good.
I'm very sorry, Mr. Logue,
the Duke is busy.
I'm happy to wait.
Or I could come back later.
As I said, the Duke is terribly busy.
Thank you.
Parliament will not support
the marriage.
But there are other reasons for concern.
He was careless with state papers.
He lacked commitment and resolve,
and there are those who are
worried about where he will stand
when war comes with Germany.
- We're not coming to that?
- Indeed we are, sir.
Prime Minister Baldwin may deny this,
but Hitler's intent is crystal clear.
War with Germany will come.
And we will need a King
whom we can all stand behind, united.
I fear my...
...brother is not of sound mind...
...at this time.
Have you thought
what you will call yourself? Hmm?
Certainly not Albert, sir.
Too Germanic.
What about George?
After your father?
George the Sixth
has a rather nice continuity to it.
Don't you think?
David. Thank God.
You look exhausted.
How are you bearing up?
Bertie, the decision's been made. I...
I'm going.
- I can't accept that...
- I'm afraid there's no other way.
I must marry her.
My mind's made up. I'm... sorry.
That's a terrible thing to hear.
Nobody wants that.
I, least of all.
At long last,
I am able to say a few words of my own.
I have never wanted
to withhold anything,
but until now it has not been
constitutionally possible
for me to speak.
A few hours ago,
I discharged my last duty
as King and Emperor,
and now that I have been succeeded
by my brother,
the Duke of York,
my first words must be
to declare my allegiance to him.
This I do with all my heart.
You all know the reasons which have
impelled me to renounce the throne,
but you must believe me when I tell you
that I have found it impossible
to carry the heavy burden
of responsibility
and to discharge my duties as King,
as I would wish to do
without the help and support
of the woman I love.
And I want you to know,
this decision has been
made less difficult to me
by the sure knowledge that my brother,
with his long training
in the public affairs of this country,
and with his fine qualities,
will be able to take my place forthwith
without interruption or injury
to the life and progress of the Empire.
I meet you today...
...in...
...in circumstances which are...
- I'm sure you'll love it.
- There you go.
Thank you, darling.
Saddles. Margaret.
- There's Montezuma.
- Oh, here's one.
- Mama, here's a horse and saddle.
- Thank you. Oops.
- Don't worry, Sally. We'll get you...
- Mama?
- Yes?
- Will we have space for our horses
- in our new home?
- Course we will, darling.
We'll have a palace of rooms.
Curtsey.
Your Majesty.
How was it?
I was trying to...
familiarize myself
with... what a state paper looks like.
It's a...
...dispatch from Mr. Baldwin,
which I don't understand a word of.
David's finances.
Christmas... broadcast.
- Think that would be a mistake.
- No, don't worry about that.
Oh.
Plans for the Coronation.
Think that would be
an even bigger mistake.
- I'm not a King.
- Oh, shush.
I'm a Naval officer. That's all I know.
I'm not a King. I'm not a King.
- I'm sorry.
- No.
- No, don't be silly. Please.
Oh, my dear.
My dear, dear man.
- I'm sorry.
- You know,
I refused your first
two marriage proposals,
not because I didn't love you,
but because I couldn't bear
the idea of a Royal life.
Couldn't bear the idea of a life
of tours, public duty, of...
Well, a life that no longer
was really to be my own.
But then I thought, he stammers
so beautifully, they'll leave us alone.
Waiting for a King to apologize,
one can wait rather a long wait.
I'm afraid we're slightly late.
This is home.
Myrtle's at bridge.
I made sure the boys were out.
It's lovely. Absolutely lovely.
- Oh! May I sit down?
- Yes, of course.
- Would you like some tea, ma'am?
- Yes, I'll help myself.
Now, off you go.
Or must I knock your heads together?
Here's your shilling.
I...
I understand...
...what you were trying to say, Logue.
I went about it the wrong way.
I'm sorry.
So, here I am.
Is the nation ready for two...
minutes of radio silence?
Every stammerer always fears
going back to square one.
I don't let that happen.
If I fail in my duty,
David could come back.
I've seen the placards.
"God save our... King."
They don't mean me.
Every monarch in history
has succeeded someone who's dead
or just about to be.
My predecessor is not only alive,
but very much so.
It's a bloody mess.
Couldn't even give them
a Christmas speech.
- Like your dad used to do?
- Precisely.
He's not here anymore.
Yes, he is.
He's on that shilling I gave you.
Easy enough to give away.
You don't have to carry him
around in your pocket.
Or your brother.
You don't need to be afraid
of the things you were afraid of
when you were five.
You're very much your own man, Bertie.
Am I?
- Your face is next, mate.
- Lionel, dear!
Myrtle.
- Is this your wife?
- Yes.
Bertie. Come here.
- Are you all right, Logue?
- Yes.
- Shouldn't we go through?
- Trust me, it's important.
- What is it?
- Oh!
- You're...
- It's "Your Majesty" the first time.
After that, it's "Ma'am." As in "ham."
Not "malm" as in "palm."
I haven't told her about us.
Sit down, relax.
I'm told your husband
calls my husband Bertie.
And my husband calls
your husband Lionel.
I trust you won't call me Liz.
Your Majesty, you may
call me Mrs. Logue, ma'am.
Very nice to meet you, Mrs. Logue.
- Logue, we can't stay here all day.
- Yes, we can.
- Logue!
- I need to wait for the right moment.
- Logue, you're being a coward.
- You're damn right.
Get out there, man.
Hello, Myrtle, darling.
You're early.
I believe you two have met,
but I don't think you know...
- ...King George the Sixth.
- It's very nice to meet you.
Will Their Majesties
be staying to dinner?
We'd love to, such a treat,
but alas a...
...previous engagement. What a pity.
- Archbishop.
- Welcome, Your Majesty.
What a glorious transformation, sir.
I hope you'll forgive us
if we continue our preparations?
Now, allow me to guide you
through the ceremony.
We begin, of course,
at the West door into the nave.
I see all your pronouncements
are to be broadcast, Archbishop.
Ah, yes. Wireless.
It is, indeed, a Pandora's box,
and I'm afraid I've also had
to permit the newsreel cameras.
The product of which
I shall personally edit.
Without momentary hesitations.
This is Dr. Logue of Harley Street.
He's... my speech therapist.
- Your Grace.
- Had I known that Your Majesty
was seeking assistance, I should
have made my own recommendation.
Dr. Logue will...
...will be attending the Coronation.
Of course I'll speak to the Dean,
but it will be extremely difficult.
I should like the...
...doctor to be seated in the...
...King's Box.
But members of your family
will be seated there, sir.
That is why it is suitable.
And now, if you don't mind, Your Grace,
we need the premises.
My dear fellow,
this is Westminster Abbey.
The Church must prepare His Majesty.
My preparations are equally
as important.
With complete privacy,
if you don't mind.
Those are my wishes, Your Grace.
I will place the Abbey
at Your Majesty's disposal,
this evening. Your Majesty.
I can't believe I'm walking
on Chaucer and Handel and Dickens.
Everything all right?
Let's get cracking.
I'm not here to rehearse, Dr. Logue.
Call me Lionel.
True, you... never...
...called yourself Doctor. I did that...
...for you.
No training.
No diploma, no...
...qualifications.
Just... a great deal of nerve.
The Star Chamber inquisition, is it?
You asked for trust.
And... total equality.
Bertie, I heard you at Wembley.
I was there.
My son Laurie said, "Dad, do you think
you could help that poor man?"
- What, as a failed actor?
- It's true.
I'm not a doctor.
And yes, I acted, a bit.
Well, I recited in pubs.
I taught elocution in schools.
When the Great War came,
all our soldiers were returning
to Australia from the front,
a lot of them shell-shocked,
unable to speak.
Somebody said, Lionel,
"You're very good at this speech stuff.
Do you think you could possibly
help these poor buggers?"
I did muscle therapy,
exercises, relaxation,
but I knew I had to go deeper.
Those poor young blokes
had cried out in fear.
No one was listening to them.
My job was to give them faith
in their own voice,
and let them know that
a friend was listening.
That must ring
a few bells with you, Bertie.
You give a very noble
account of yourself.
- Make inquiries. It's all true.
- Inquiries have been made.
You have no idea who I have
breathing down my neck.
I vouched for you, and you have no...
- ...credentials.
- But lots of success.
I can't show you a certificate.
There was no training then.
Everything I know,
I know from experience.
And that war was some experience.
My plaque says,
"L. Logue, Speech Defects."
Not "Doctor."
There are no letters after my name.
- Lock me in the Tower.
- I would if I could.
- On what charge?
- Fraud.
With war looming, you've saddled
this nation with a voiceless...
...King. You've destroyed
the happiness of my family,
all for the sake of ensnaring
a star... patient you couldn't...
...possibly hope to assist.
It'll be like mad...
...King George the Third.
I'll be... Mad King...
...George the Stammerer...
...who let his people down
so badly in their hour of need.
What are you doing? Get up!
You can't sit there! Get up!
- Why not? It's a chair.
- No, it... That is not a chair!
That is... That...
- That is Saint Edward's chair.
- People have carved their names on it.
That chair is the seat
on which every King...
- It's held in place by a large rock.
- That is the Stone of Scone!
- You are trivializing everything.
- I don't care how many royal assholes
- have sat on this chair.
- Listen to me! Listen to me!
- Listen to you? By what right?
- By Divine Right, if you must.
- I am your King!
- No, you're not.
You told me so yourself.
You said you didn't want it.
Why should I waste my time
listening to you?
Because I have a right to be heard!
I have a voice!
Yes, you do.
You have such perseverance, Bertie.
You're the bravest man I know.
You'll make a bloody good King.
- What on earth is going on, sir?
- It's quite all right, Archbishop.
Mr. Logue, you must know that
I've found a replacement English
specialist with impeccable credentials.
Hence, your services
will no longer be required.
- I'm sorry?
- Your Majesty's function
is to consult and be advised.
Now, you didn't consult,
- but you have just been advised.
- And now I advise you.
In this personal matter,
I will make my own decision.
My concern is for the head
on which I must place the crown.
I appreciate that, Archbishop.
But it's my head.
Your humble servant.
Thank you, Bertie.
Shall we rehearse? Come on.
Up on your perch.
Now, when you and Elizabeth
enter through the West door,
you will be greeted by the hymn
"I was glad when they said unto me."
Actually, you won't be that glad because
they do sing it for a very long time.
Then your friend, the Archbishop,
will ponce up the stairs towards you,
and say, "Sir, is Your Majesty
willing to take the oath?"
- "I am willing."
- Well, of course you are.
I'm gonna see what this sounds like
in the cheap seats,
so even your old nanny can hear.
"Will you govern your peoples,
Great Britain, Ireland, Canada,
Australia and New Zealand,
according to their lands and customs?"
- "I solemnly promise to do so."
- Louder.
- I can't hear you up the back.
- "I solemnly promise to do so."
Very good. "And will you, to your power,
cause Law and Justice, in Mercy to be
executed in all your judgments?"
"I will. I will!"
Then there's a very long bit
about upholding the faith. It goes on,
rubbish, rubbish, rubbish,
to which you finally say...
"The things which I have...
here before promised,
I will perform and keep.
So help me God."
And that's all you say.
Four short responses.
Kiss the book, sign the oath,
and you're King.
Easy.
You nearly crowned him backwards,
Archbishop.
Someone had removed the thread
marking the back of the crown, sir.
Try not to lose the thread, Archbishop.
Archbishop, we're missing Papa.
- God save the King.
- Very good.
Very good, Archbishop.
Well, I hope Your Majesties
are thrilled with the result.
- You can switch that machine off.
- No, wait. Keep going.
- Nazism has held its great convention.
- Do take a seat, Archbishop.
Masses of uniformed men,
stupefying to the eye,
and incredible to the imagination
have stood in spellbound audience
of the Fuhrer.
- Papa? Papa, what's he saying?
- Hmm?
I don't know, but he seems
to be saying it rather well.
Sir... I have asked to see you today
in order to tender my resignation
as Prime Minister.
I'm so sorry to hear that,
Mr. Baldwin.
Neville Chamberlain will
take my place as Prime Minister.
It's a matter of principle.
I was mistaken.
I have found it impossible to believe
that there is any man in the world
so lacking in moral feeling as Hitler,
that the world may be hurled
for a second time
into the abyss of destructive war.
Churchill was right all along.
This was always Hitler's intention.
I'm only very sorry to leave you
at this great time of crisis.
I'm very much afraid, sir,
that your greatest test is yet to come.
I am speaking to you...
...from the Cabinet room
at 10 Downing Street.
This morning,
the British ambassador in Berlin
handed the German government
a final note
stating that unless
we heard from them by 11:00,
that they were prepared at once
to withdraw their troops from Poland,
a state of war would exist between us.
I have to tell you now that
no such undertaking has been received,
and that, consequently, this country
is at war with Germany.
At last, sir, here is your speech.
You are on air at six.
I have timed it
to just under nine minutes.
The wording is fully approved.
The Prime Minister
will be joining you for the broadcast,
which will go out live
across the nation, the Empire
- and to our armed forces.
- Get Logue here immediately.
- There's the barrage balloons.
- Yes.
- They got them up there quickly.
- Yeah.
- Shall we pull over and find a shelter?
- No, no. Go straight there.
We'll be all right.
- Yes, sir?
- Lionel Logue.
Major Hartley is expecting me.
This is my son, Laurie.
- Thank you, Laurie.
- Good luck, Dad.
- The King's speech.
- Thank you, sir.
We have about 40 minutes
to the broadcast.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
There may be dark days ahead...
- ...and...
- Try again.
There may be dark days ahead, and...
Turn the hesitations into pauses and say
to yourself, "God save the King."
I say that continuously,
but apparently no one's listening.
Long pauses are good.
They add solemnity to great occasions.
Then I'm the solemnest king
who ever lived.
You know, if I'm a king,
where's my power?
Can I... can I form a government?
Can I... can I... levy a tax?
Declare a... a war? No.
And yet I'm the seat of all authority.
Why? Because...
...the nation believes
that when I... I speak,
I speak for them. But I can't speak.
Let's take it all again from the top.
"In this grave hour."
In this grave hour...
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
Perhaps the most fateful
in our history... Bugger, shit, shit.
♪ I send to every household of my...
You see, "P" is always difficult,
even when I'm singing.
Bounce on to it. "A peoples."
A people. A people.
Household of my peoples,
both at home
- and overseas.
- Beautiful.
This message... ♪ Doo-dah
♪ Spoken with the same depth of feeling
Doo-dah day ♪
For each one of you,
as if I were able to...
Shit, fuck, bugger! ...cross your
threshold and speak to you...
In your head now. "I have a right
to be bloody well heard."
Bloody well heard,
bloody well heard myself!
Now, waltz. Move.
Get continuous movement.
♪ For the second time
in the lives of most of us
- ♪ We are at... ♪
- "We are," take a pause.
- Lionel, I can't do this.
- Bertie, you can do it.
- Have a look at the last paragraph.
- Bertie. It's time.
- Archbishop.
- Your Majesty.
A great moment, sir.
- Prime Minister.
- Your Majesty.
Nice to see you... again so soon.
Good of you to be here.
I'm sure you have a...
- ...a rather busy day.
- I hope we have no more interruptions
- from those damn sirens, sir.
- Or the wretched dogs.
Congrat... Congratulations.
- First Lord of the Admiralty.
- Your Majesty.
The long... walk.
Good luck, sir.
I, too, dread this apparatus.
Had a speech impediment myself,
you know.
- I didn't.
- Family secret. Tongue-tied.
An operation was considered
to be too dangerous.
I eventually made an asset of it.
- Thank you, Mr. Churchill.
- Sir.
Darling.
- How long, Logue?
- Just under three minutes.
- Mr. Wood.
- Good luck, Your Majesty.
Mr. Wood.
- You've redecorated, Logue.
- I made it cozy.
- Some fresh air.
- There you are, darling.
I'm a thistle-sifter.
I've a sieve of sifted thistles
and a sieve of unsifted thistles.
A sieve of sifted thistles
- Because I'm...
- Bertie. Darling.
Make sure it's not switched on.
Remember, the red light
will blink four times,
then I've asked them to turn it off.
'Cause we don't want that evil eye
staring at you all the way through.
One minute, sir.
I'm sure you'll be splendid.
Forty seconds, sir.
Logue.
However this turns out...
...I don't know how to thank you...
for what you've done.
Knighthood?
Twenty seconds.
Forget everything else,
and just say it to me.
Say it to me as a friend.
In this grave...
...hour...
...perhaps the most fateful
in our history...
...I send...
...to every household of my...
...a-peoples...
...both at home...
...and overseas...
...this message...
...spoken with the same
depth of feeling...
...for each one of you...
...as if I were able
to cross your threshold
and speak to you... myself.
For the second time
in the lives of most of us...
...we are... at...
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
...at war.
Very good.
Over and over again...
...we have tried to find...
...a peaceful way out
of the differences...
...between ourselves...
...and those...
...who are now our... enemies.
But it has been... in vain.
We have been forced into a conflict,
for we are called
to meet the challenge of a principle,
which, if it were to prevail,
would be fatal to any civilized order
in the world.
Such a principle,
stripped of all disguise,
is surely the mere...
...primitive doctrine that might...
...is right.
For the sake of all
that we ourselves hold dear,
it is unthinkable
that we should refuse to meet...
...the challenge.
It is to this high purpose
that I now call
my people at home,
and my peoples across the seas,
who will make our cause their own.
I ask them to stand calm
and firm and united
in this time of trial.
The task will be hard.
There may be dark days ahead,
and war can no longer be confined
to the battlefield.
But we can only do the right
as we see the right,
and reverently commit
our cause to God.
If one and all we keep
resolutely faithful to it,
then, with God's help,
we shall... prevail.
It was very good, Bertie.
You still stammered on the "W."
Well, I had to throw in a few,
so they knew it was me.
Congratulations, Your Majesty.
A true broadcaster.
Thank you, Mr. Wood.
- Congratulations, Your Majesty.
- Sir.
- Thank you.
Ready.
- Good?
- Perfect, sir.
Your first wartime speech.
Congratulations.
I expect I shall have to...
do a great deal more.
Thank you, Logue.
Well done.
My friend.
Thank you...
...Your Majesty.
I knew you'd be good.
Thank you... Lionel.
Onwards.
- Congratulations, sir.
- Well done, sir.
Couldn't have
said it better myself, sir.
Your Majesty, I am speechless.
- Congratulations, sir.
- Gentlemen.
- So how was Papa, Elizabeth?
- Halting at first,
- but you got much better, Papa.
- Well, bless you.
- And how about you, Margaret?
- You were just splendid, Papa.
Of course I was.
Are we all ready?
Come on, girls.