It is an extremely common mistake:
people think the writer's imagination
is always at work,
that he's constantly inventing
an endless supply
of incidents and episodes,
that he simply dreams up his stories
out of thin air.
In point of fact, the opposite is true.
Once the public knows you're a writer,
they bring the characters
and events to you,
and as long as you maintain
your ability to look -
...and to carefully listen,
these stories will continue to -
Stop it. Stop it! Don't! Don't do it!
...uh, will continue to seek you out,
uh, over your lifetime.
To him who has often
told the tales of others,
many tales will be told.
- Sorry.
- It's all right.
The incidents that follow
were described to me
exactly as I present them here
and in a wholly unexpected way.
A number of years ago,
while suffering from a mild case
of "scribe's fever, "
a form of neurasthenia common
among the intelligentsia of that time,
I decided to spend the month of August
in the spa town of Nebelsbad
below the Alpine Sudetenwaltz,
and had taken up rooms
in the Grand Budapest,
a picturesque, elaborate
and once widely celebrated establishment.
I expect some of you will know it.
It was off-season and,
by that time, decidedly out of fashion,
and it had already begun its descent
into shabbiness and eventual demolition.
What few guests we were
had quickly come
to recognize one another by sight
as the only living souls residing
in the vast establishment,
although I do not believe any acquaintance
among our number had proceeded
beyond the polite nods we exchanged
as we passed in the Palm Court,
in the Arabian baths
and onboard the Colonnade Funicular.
We were a very reserved group, it seemed,
and, without exception... solitary.
Perhaps as a result
of this general silence,
I had established a casual and bantering
familiarity with the hotel's concierge,
a West-continental
known only as Monsieur Jean,
who struck one as being, at once,
both lazy and,
really, quite accommodating.
I expect he was not well paid.
In any case, one evening,
as I stood conferring elbow to elbow
with Monsieur Jean,
as had become my habit,
I noticed a new presence in our company.
A small, elderly man, smartly dressed,
with an exceptionally lively,
intelligent face
and an immediately perceptible
air of sadness.
He was, like the rest of us, alone,
but also, I must say,
he was the first that struck one as being
deeply and truly lonely.
A symptom of my own
medical condition as well.
- Who's this interesting old fellow?
- I inquired of Monsieur Jean.
To my surprise,
he was distinctly taken aback.
- Don't you know?
- He asked.
- Don't you recognize him?
- He did look familiar.
That's Mr. Moustafa himself.
He arrived earlier this morning.
This name will no doubt be familiar
to the more seasoned persons among you.
Mr. Zero Moustafa was at one time
the richest man in Zubrowka...
and was still indeed
the owner of the Grand Budapest.
He often comes and stays a week or more,
three times a year at least,
but never in the season.
Monsieur Jean signaled to me
and I leaned closer.
I'll tell you a secret.
He takes a single-bed room without a bath
in the rear corner of the top floor,
and it's smaller
than the service elevator.
It was well known,
Zero Moustafa had purchased
and famously inhabited
some of the most lavish castles
and palazzos on the continent,
yet here, in his own nearly empty hotel,
he occupied a servant's quarters?
At that moment, the curtain rose
on a parenthetical, domestic drama -
Shit.
... which required the immediate
and complete attention of Monsieur Jean -
...but, frankly,
did not hold mine for long.
However, this premature intermission
in the story of the curious old man,
had left me, as the expression goes,
"gespannt wie ein Flitzebogen "-
That is, on the edge of my seat,
where I remained throughout
the next morning until -
in what I have found to be its mysterious
and utterly reliable fashion -
fate, once again, intervened on my behalf.
I admire your work.
I beg your pardon?
I said, I know and admire
your wonderful work.
Thank you most kindly, sir.
Did Monsieur Jean have a word or two
to share with you
about the aged proprietor
of this establishment?
I must confess,
I did myself inquire about you.
He's perfectly capable,
of course, Monsieur Jean,
but we can't claim he's a first -
or, in earnest,
even second-rate concierge.
But there it is.
Times have changed.
The thermal baths are very beautiful.
They were in their first condition.
It couldn't be maintained, of course.
Too decadent for current tastes.
But I love it all just the same,
this enchanting old ruin.
How did you come to buy it, if I may ask?
The Grand Budapest.
I didn't.
If you're not merely being polite -
and you must tell me if that's the case -
but if it genuinely does interest you,
may I invite you to dine with me tonight,
and it will be my pleasure and, indeed,
my privilege to tell you
my story... such as it is.
Two ducks roasted with olives.
- Rabbit, salad?
- Hmm.
Pouilly-Jouvet '52,
plus a split of the Brut.
That should provide us ample time...
if I commence promptly.
By all means.
Well, it begins, as it must,
with our mutual friend's predecessor.
The beloved,
original concierge of The Grand Budapest.
It begins, of course, with...
- Bring the table to the window.
- Yes, Monsieur Gustave.
- Bring the tray to the table.
- Right away, Monsieur Gustave.
Right there.
Have those been brushed and blocked?
- Of course, Monsieur Gustave.
- Pack them in the hat boxes.
- Is that from Oberstdorf & Company?
- I believe so.
- Second trunk. Who has the tickets?
- I do.
Give them to me.
These are in order. Wait in the corner.
- I'm not leaving.
- I beg your pardon?
- Why not?
- I'm frightened.
- Of what?
I fear this may be the last time
we ever see each other.
Why on earth would that be the case?
Well, I can't put it into words,
but I feel it.
For goodness sake, there's no reason
for you to leave us if you'd rather -
- Come with me.
- To fucking Lutz?
- Please.
- Give me your hand.
You've nothing to fear.
You're always anxious before you travel.
I admit, you appear to be suffering
a more acute attack on this occasion,
but, truly and honestly - Dear God.
What have you done to your fingernails?
- I beg your pardon?
- This diabolical varnish.
- The color is completely wrong.
- Don't you like it?
It's not that I don't like it.
I am physically repulsed.
- Perhaps this will soothe you.
- What? Don't recite.
- Just listen to the words. Hush.
- Please. Not now.
"While questing once
in noble wood of gray, medieval pine,
I came upon a tomb,
rain-slick'd, rubbed-cool, ethereal;
its inscription long-vanished,
yet still within
its melancholy fissures..."
Will you light a candle for me, please?
- In the sacristy of Santa Maria?
- I'll see to it myself immediately.
Remember, I'm always with you.
- I love you.
Abfahren!
It's quite a thing winning the loyalty
of a woman like that
for 19 consecutive seasons.
- Uh, yes, sir.
- She's very fond of me, you know?
Yes, sir.
- But I've never seen her like that before.
- No, sir.
She was shaking like a shitting dog.
Truly.
Run to the cathedral of Santa Maria
in Brucknerplatz.
Buy one of the plain, half-length candles
and take back four Klubecks in change.
Light it in the sacristy,
say a brief rosary,
then go to Mendl's and get me
a courtesan au chocolat.
If there's any money left,
give it to the crippled shoeshine boy.
- Right away, sir.
- Hold it.
- Who are you?
- I'm Zero, sir. The new lobby boy.
- Zero, you say?
- Yes, sir.
I've never heard of you,
never laid eyes on you. Who hired you?
- Mr. Mosher, sir.
- Mr. Mosher!
Yes, Monsieur Gustave?
Am I to understand you've surreptitiously
hired this young man
in the position of a lobby boy?
He's been engaged for a trial period,
pending your approval, of course.
Oh...
Perhaps, yes. Thank you, Mr. Mosher.
You're most welcome, Monsieur Gustave.
You're now going to be
officially interviewed.
Uh, should I go
and light the candle first, sir?
What? No.
- Experience?
- Hotel Kinski, kitchen boy, six months.
Hotel Berlitz, mop and broom boy,
three months.
- Before that I was a skillet scrubber -
- Experience: zero.
- Thank you again, Mr. Gustave.
- Straighten that cap, Anatole.
- The pleasure's mine, Herr Schneider.
- The strap's busted.
- These are not acceptable.
- I fully agree.
- Education?
- I studied reading and spelling.
I started my primary school. I almost -
- Education: zero.
- Now it's exploded.
Good morning, Cicero.
Call the goddamn plumber.
- This afternoon, Monsieur Gustave?
- Without fail, Frau Leibling.
- What in hell is this?
- Not now.
Family?
Zero.
Six, Igor.
Why do you want to be a lobby boy?
Well, who wouldn't
at the Grand Budapest, sir?
It's an institution.
Very good.
- A thousand Klubecks.
- My goodness.
Were you ever a lobby boy, sir?
What do you think?
Well, I suppose you'd have
to start somewhere -
- Go and light the goddamn candle.
- Yes, sir.
And so, my life began.
Junior lobby boy in training,
Grand Budapest Hotel,
under the strict command
of Monsieur Gustave H.
I became his pupil, and he was to be
my counselor and guardian.
What is a lobby boy?
A lobby boy's completely invisible,
yet always in sight.
A lobby boy remembers what people hate.
A lobby boy anticipates the client's needs
before the needs are needed.
A lobby boy is, above all,
discreet to a fault.
Our guests know their deepest secrets,
some of which are rather unseemly,
will go with us to our graves.
- So keep your mouth shut, Zero.
- Yes, sir.
That's all for now.
I began to realize
that many of the hotel's
most valued and distinguished guests
came for him.
It seemed to be
an essential part of his duties -
...but I believe it was also his pleasure.
The requirements were always the same.
They had to be rich,
old, insecure,
vain, superficial,
blond,
needy.
Why blond?
Because they all were.
He was, by the way,
the most liberally perfumed man
I had ever encountered.
The scent announced his approach
from a great distance -
...and lingered for many minutes
after he was gone.
I worked six days each week
plus a half-day Sunday,
5:00 a.m. until just after midnight.
Our meals were small but frequent,
for stamina.
Two breakfasts,
two lunches and a late supper.
Monsieur Gustave also delivered
a nightly sermon.
Rudeness is merely the expression of fear.
People fear they won't get what they want.
The most dreadful and unattractive person
only needs to be loved
and they will open up like a flower.
I'm reminded of a verse:
"The painter's brush
touched the inchoate face
by ends of nimble bristles
and with their blush of first color,
rendered her lifeless cheek living."
His own dinner, he took alone in his room.
The identity of the owner of the hotel
was unknown to all of us.
Each month, his emissary,
known as Deputy Kovacs,
arrived to review the books
and convey messages
on behalf of the mysterious proprietor.
On these occasions, Monsieur Gustave
and our business manager, Herr Becker,
met with him in private consultation
above Reception.
This was also when I met Agatha.
But we won't discuss that.
Subtitle
www.movieddl.me
- What do you want?
- Look.
- Dear God.
- I'm terribly sorry, sir.
- We must go to her.
- We must?
Tout de suite. She needs me,
and I need you to help me with my bags.
- Tout va bien?
- Attendez-moi, darling.
- How fast can you pack?
- Five minutes.
Do it. And a bottle of Pouilly-Jouvet '26
in an ice bucket with two glasses
so we don't have to drink the cat piss
they serve in the dining car.
I blame myself.
She tried to tell me
she had a premonition. I didn't listen.
All of Lutz will be dressed in black,
except her own ghastly, deceitful children
whom she loathed
and couldn't bear to kiss hello.
They'll be dancing like gypsies.
There's really no point
in doing anything in life,
because it's all over
in the blink of an eye.
The next thing you know,
rigor mortis sets in.
Oh, how the good die young.
With any luck, she's left a few Klubecks
for your old friend,
but one never knows until the ink
is dry on the death certificate.
She was dynamite in the sack, by the way.
She was 84, Monsieur Gustave.
I've had older.
When you're young, it's all fillet steak,
but as the years go by,
you have to move on to the cheaper cuts,
which is fine with me,
because I like those.
More flavorful, or so they say.
Why are we stopping at a barley field?
Well, hello there, chaps.
- Documents, please.
- With pleasure.
It's not a very flattering portrait.
I was once considered a great beauty.
What does the "F" stand for? Fritz? Franz?
- Franz.
- I knew it!
He's making a funny face.
That's a migratory visa with stage three
worker status, Franz, darling.
He's with me.
Come outside, please.
Now, wait a minute. Sit down, Zero.
His papers are in order.
I cross-referenced them myself
with the Bureau of Labor and Servitude.
You can't arrest him
because he's a bloody immigrant.
He hasn't done anything wrong.
Stop it, damn you! Damn you!
Never mind, Monsieur Gustave!
Let them proceed!
Ow! That hurts!
Ah!
You filthy, goddamn,
pockmarked, fascist assholes!
Take your hands off my lobby boy!
- What's the problem?
- This is outrageous.
The young man works for me
at the Grand Budapest Hotel in Nebelsbad.
Monsieur Gustave?
My name is Henckels.
I'm the son of Dr.
and Mrs. Wolfgang Henckels-Bergersdörfer.
Do you remember me?
I know exactly who you are. It's uncanny.
You're little Albert.
I'm terribly embarrassed. Release them.
Release them!
Hmm. Your colleague is stateless.
He'll need to apply
for a revised Special Transit Permit,
which at this point
may be very difficult to acquire.
Take this.
It's temporary,
but it's the best I can offer, I'm afraid.
And how's your wonderful mother?
- She's very well, thank you.
- I adore her. Send my love.
I will.
Your companion was very kind to me
when I was a lonely little boy.
My men and I apologize for disturbing you.
I beg your pardon, sir.
You see? There are still
faint glimmers of civilization left
in this barbaric slaughterhouse
that was once known as humanity.
Indeed, that's what we provide
in our own modest, humble, insignificant -
Oh, fuck it.
Where is she, Clotilde? Take me to her.
You're looking so well, darling.
You really are.
They've done a marvelous job.
I don't know what cream they've put on you
down at the morgue, but I want some.
Honestly, you look better
than you have in years.
You look like you're alive.
Oh, you changed it after all.
It's perfect.
- Clotilde?
- Oui, Monsieur Gustave?
A glass of chilled water
with no ice, please.
Oh. All right, then.
I shan't be long, darling.
We were escorted
through a green baize door,
down a narrow service corridor
and into the butler's pantry.
A moment later,
the kitchen passage swung open
and a small servant dressed in white
jolted into the room.
I've never forgotten
the look on that man's face.
What the devil is going on?
I, myself, had never set foot
inside a house of this kind in my life.
I understood very little about the events
that were to follow,
but, eventually, I came to recognize:
when the destiny of a great fortune
is at stake,
men's greed spreads
like a poison in the bloodstream.
Uncles, nephews, cousins,
in-laws of increasingly
tenuous connection.
The old woman's most distant relations
had come foraging out of the woodwork.
At the head of this congregation -
it was a disorienting coincidence -
we discovered our own Deputy Kovacs,
himself an important attorney, of course.
He was the executor
of the dead widow's estate.
This is Madame D's
last will and testament.
It consists of a general tontine
drawn up before the event
of her husband's death 46 years ago,
in combination with 635 amendments,
notations,
corrections and letters of wishes
executed during the subsequent decades.
The ultimate legality of this accumulation
requires further analysis,
but in the opinion of this office,
it was Madame D's intention
that control
of the vast bulk of her estate
should be transferred, forthwith,
to her son, Dmitri,
with special allowances for his sisters,
Marguerite, Laetizia and Carolina,
and minor gifts for various members
of the extended family
as shown in the List of Recipients,
which I will elucidate in due course.
However...
an additional codicil,
delivered into my possession by post
only this morning,
and, by all indications, sent by Madame D
during the last hours of her life,
contains an amendment
to the original certificate,
which, as prescribed by law,
I will read to you now.
The authenticity of this document
has not yet been confirmed
by the presiding magistrate,
so I ask that all parties be patient
and refrain from comment
until such time as our investigations
can be completed.
"To my esteemed friend
who comforted me in my later years
and brought sunshine
into the life of an old woman
who thought that she would
never be happy again,
Monsieur Gustave H...
I bequeath, bestow and devise,
free of all taxation
and with full and absolute
fiduciary entitlement...
the painting known as Boy with Apple -
- Wow!
- ...by Johannes van Hoytl -
- I can't believe it.
- ...the younger -
- What?
- ...which gave us both so much pleasure."
The van Hoytl?
- Tax-free?
- Can she do that?
Who's Gustave H?
I'm afraid that's me, darling.
That fucking faggot!
He's a concierge. What are you doing here?
I've come to pay my respects
to a great woman whom I loved.
- This man is an intruder in my home.
- It's not yours yet, Dmitri.
Only when probate is granted,
and the Deed of Entitlement -
You're not getting Boy with Apple,
you goddamn little fruit.
How's that supposed to make me feel?
Call the police. We're pressing charges.
This criminal has plagued my family
for nearly 20 years.
He's a ruthless adventurer
and a con artist
who preys on mentally feeble,
sick old ladies.
- And he probably fucks them, too.
- I go to bed with all my friends.
Where's Céline?
What? She's dead. We're reading her will.
Oh, yes, yes, of course.
If I learn you ever once laid a finger
on my mother's body, living or dead,
I swear to God, I'll cut your throat.
You hear me?
I thought I was supposed to be
a fucking faggot.
- You are, but you're bisexual.
- Let's change the subject. I'm leaving.
That picture, Boy with Apple,
is priceless.
- Understand?
- Congratulations, Monsieur Gustave.
They're going to fight me
for the son of a bitch.
- Is it very beautiful?
- Beyond description.
"E'en the most gifted bard's rhyme
can only sing
but to the lack of her and all she isn't!
- His tongue doth -"
- Can I see it?
I don't see why not.
This is van Hoytl's exquisite portrayal
of a beautiful boy on the cusp of manhood.
Blond, smooth. Skin as white as that milk.
Of impeccable provenance.
One of the last in private hands,
and unquestionably the best.
It's a masterpiece.
The rest of this shit is worthless junk.
Mm-hmm.
What did you want to tell me, before?
I think I cannot say right now.
Write me tomorrow. Lutzbahn Station!
I'll never part with it.
It reminded her of me.
It will remind me of her. Always.
I'll die with this picture above my bed.
See the resemblance?
Oh - Oh, yes.
Actually, we should sell it.
Sooner rather than later,
in case they try to steal it back.
Plus, something about those lunatic
foot soldiers on the express.
This could be a tricky war
and a long dry spell in the hotel trade.
For all we know,
they could board us up tomorrow.
Let's make a solemn blood pact:
we'll contact the black market
and liquidate Boy with Apple
by the end of the week,
then leave the country and lay low
somewhere along the Maltese Riviera
until the troubles blow over
and we resume our posts.
In exchange for your help, your loyalty
and your services as my personal valet,
I pledge to you 1.5%
of the net sale's price.
- 1.5?
- Plus room and board.
- Could we make it ten?
- Ten? Are you joking?
That's more than I'd pay an actual dealer,
and you wouldn't know
chiaroscuro from chicken giblets.
No, 1.5 is correct,
but I'll tell you what:
if I die first, and I most certainly will,
you will be my sole heir.
There's not much in the kitty
except a set of ivory-backed hairbrushes
and my library of romantic poetry,
but when the time comes,
these will be yours,
along with whatever we haven't already
spent on whores and whiskey.
This is our sacred bond.
I'll draw it up right now.
I, Monsieur Gustave H,
being of relatively sound mind and body,
on this day, the 19th of October,
in the year of our Lord 1932...
He never told me
where he came from.
I never asked who his family had been.
Excuse me.
Uh-huh?
The police are here. They asked for you.
Tell them I'll be right down.
Okay.
- Ever been questioned by the authorities?
- Yes, on one occasion.
I was arrested and tortured by the rebel
militia after the Desert Uprising.
- Right. You know the drill, then. Zip it.
- Of course.
- You've never heard the word "van Hoytl."
- Got it.
Okay, let's go.
How may we serve you, gentlemen?
Ah, Inspector Henckels.
By order of the Commissioner of Police,
Zubrowka Province,
I hereby place you under arrest
for the murder
of Madame Céline Villeneuve
Desgoffe und Taxis.
I knew there was something fishy.
We never got the cause of death.
She's been murdered
and you think I did it.
Hey!
Stop!
What happened?
What happened, my dear Zero,
is I beat the living shit
out of a sniveling little runt
called Pinky Bandinski,
who had the gall to question my virility.
If there's one thing we've learned
from penny dreadfuls,
it's that, when you find yourself
in a place like this,
you must never be a candy-ass.
You've got to prove yourself from day one.
You've got to win their respect.
You should take a long look
at his ugly mug this morning.
He's actually become a dear friend.
You'll meet him, I hope.
- So, you've talked to Kovacs?
- I saw him last night in secret.
He made me take an oath on a Bible
I wouldn't tell a soul.
- You're supposed to also.
- I'll do that later.
- He suspects you're innocent.
- Of course he does.
What's the charge?
In the small hours
of the evening of 19 October,
an individual well known to the house
and staff, a Monsieur Gustave H,
did arrive at the Desgoffe und Taxis
residence in Lutz
and entered by the rear service alley,
alerting no one to his presence,
and did then proceed by way
of back stairs and servants' passage,
to deliver himself into
the private chambers of Madame D.
There is no evidence
to indicate whether this visit
had been prearranged with her or not.
The next morning Madame D
was found dead by strychnine poisoning.
Monsieur Gustave was not observed
on the premises again
until, of course, 24hours later.
The identity of his accusers is made clear
in this notarized deposition.
They include, essentially,
all members of the extended family,
but the key witness who actually,
ostensibly, saw the alleged events
appears to have fled the jurisdiction.
His whereabouts are currently unknown,
but he's being sought and pursued
by the relevant authorities.
Who is he?
- Serge?
- I'm afraid so.
That little prick.
No, I don't believe it.
They put him up to it.
- I've been dropped into a nest of vipers.
- You have an alibi?
Of course, but she's married
to the Duke of Westfalia.
I can't allow her name to get mixed up
in all this monkey business.
- Your life may be at stake.
- I know, but the bitch legged it.
She's already onboard the Queen Nastassja
halfway to Dutch Tanganyika.
Don't give up.
The details of the conspiracy,
now a matter of public record,
were, at that time,
impossible for us to apprehend.
I'm looking for Serge X,
a young man in the service of my employer,
the family Desgoffe und Taxis
of Schloss Lutz.
- Yes, sir?
- You're his sister?
- Yes, sir.
- Seen him lately?
- No, sir.
- No, sir?
No, sir.
I need to find him right away,
for his own safety and everybody else's.
If he shows up -
- Yes, sir?
- Tell him Jopling says... "Come home."
But one thing was certain...
the Desgoffe und Taxis
were a very powerful family...
and time was not on our side.
A letter from Monsieur Gustave. Zero.
- You want me to...?
- Read it.
"My dear and trusted colleagues -"
I miss you deeply
as I write from the confines
of my regrettable
and preposterous incarceration.
Until I walk amongst you again
as a free man,
the Grand Budapest remains in your hands,
as does its impeccable reputation.
Keep it spotless and glorify it.
Take extra special care
of every little-bitty bit of it
as if I were watching over you like a hawk
with a horse whip in its talons,
because I am.
Should I discover a lapse
of any variety during my absence,
I promise swift and merciless justice
will descend upon you.
A great and noble house
has been placed under your protection.
Tell Zero if you see any funny business.
"Your devoted Monsieur Gustave."
Then there's a poem, but we might want to
start on the soup since it's 46 stanzas.
"A moist, black ash dampens
the filth of a dung-dark rat's nest
and mingles with the thick scent
of wood rot
while the lark song of a guttersnipe -"
I never trusted that butler.
- He's too honest.
- Too honest, you say?
- Mm-hmm.
- Uh-huh.
Right, well, be that as it may,
find him quick and make it snappy.
May I offer any of you inmates
a plate of mush?
No? Anyone?
You with the very large scar on your face?
Try it. It's actually quite warm
and nourishing this morning.
It needs a dash of salt.
Good day.
Mush, gents? Any takers?
Suit yourselves.
Rise and shine. Chop-chop.
Good morning, Pinky.
- Mendl's again?
- Precisely.
Who's got the throat-slitter?
- Out of this world.
- Mendl's is the best.
- Well, back to work.
- Monsieur Gustave?
Yes?
Me and the boys talked it over.
We think you're a really straight fellow.
Well, I've never been accused of that
before, but I appreciate the sentiment.
You're one of us now.
What a lovely thing to say.
Thank you, dear Pinky. Thank you, Günther.
Thank you, Wolf.
Anything else?
Tell him, Ludwig.
Checkpoint 19 ain't no two-bit hoosegow.
You got broad-gauge iron bars
on every door, vent and window.
You got 72 guards on the floor
and 16 more in the towers.
You got a 325-foot drop
into a moat full of crocodiles.
But, like the best of them,
it's got a soft spot,
which in this case
happens to take the form
of a storm drain sewer system
dating from the time
of the original rock fortification
way back in the Middle Ages.
Now, nobody's saying it's a stroll
down a tree-lined promenade
with a fine lady and a white poodle,
but it's got what you'd call...
vulnerability,
and that's our bread and butter.
Take a look.
Who drew this?
What do you mean, "Who drew this?" I did.
Very good. You've got a wonderful line.
This shows great artistic promise.
Question: how do you intend to penetrate
this lowest rudiment?
It's 25 inches of reinforced
granite masonry, is it not?
Digging with the throat-slitter,
this would take
three-to-six months of continual effort,
during which time several of our members
will have been violently executed.
You hit the nail on the head, Mr. Gustave.
We got fake documents,
second-hand street clothes,
a rope ladder
made of sticks and bunk linens,
but we need digging tools,
which are proving hard to come by
in this flophouse.
At this point in the story,
the old man fell silent
and pushed away his saddle of lamb.
His eyes went blank as two stones.
I could see he was in distress.
- Are you ill, Mr. Moustafa?
- I finally asked.
- Oh, dear me, no.
- He said.
It's only that I don't know
how to proceed.
He was crying.
You see, I never speak of Agatha, because
even at the thought of her name,
I'm unable to control my emotions.
Well, I suppose there's no way around it.
You see, she saved us.
On our third formal rendezvous,
I had asked for her hand in marriage
and she had agreed.
- Will you marry me?
- Yes.
We did not have 50 Klubecks
between the two of us.
No one knew, of course,
but, then, who would have cared?
We were each
completely on our own in the world...
and we were deeply in love.
- Here.
- Thank you.
- It's a book.
- I see.
Romantic Poetry, Volume One.
Monsieur Gustave recommended it.
I have a copy of my own as well.
- I ruined the surprise, I suppose.
- I'll go ahead and open it, anyway.
Okay.
Read the inscription.
Monsieur Gustave insisted on an immediate
and thorough cross-examination -
She's charming. She's so charming.
... during which he
presented Agatha with a porcelain pendant
and five dozen individually
tissue-wrapped white tulips
in a box the size of a child's coffin.
- It's not right.
- I beg your pardon?
Why is he sulking?
She's my girlfriend.
You can't just buy her things.
I'm only interviewing
this vision of loveliness on your behalf.
Never be jealous in this life, Zero,
not even for an instant.
Is he flirting with you?
- Yes.
- I approve of this union.
Agatha, my beauty, return to your beloved.
Soon we learned -
Blessings upon you both.
...not only was Agatha immensely skilled
with a palette knife
and a butter cream flourish -
- Mendl.
- Go.
...she was also very brave.
I believe she was born that way.
Something's missing.
A crucial document, either misplaced or,
conceivably, destroyed.
I don't know what it contains,
I don't know what it represents,
I don't know what it is,
but there are traces
and shadows of it everywhere.
Now, I don't want to alarm you,
and I don't expect to see
any significant change
in the magistrate's ultimate decision
vis-à-vis your own inheritance,
but, especially given
the circumstances of the death,
as well as the disappearance
of the key witness
in the murder case, Serge X -
...I suggest that we immediately
bring this matter
to the attention
of the municipal inspector
so that there can be
absolutely no question
of impropriety at any future date.
- Agreed?
- Not agreed.
- Not agreed?
- Can I ask you a question, Vilmos?
- Yes, Dmitri?
- Who are you working for?
- I beg your pardon?
Who are you working for? I thought
you're supposed to be our lawyer.
Well, in point of fact,
I'm the executor of the estate.
In this particular situation,
I represent the deceased.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
A provision for my fees
was included in the -
Just wrap it up and don't make waves.
Agreed?
I'm an attorney, Dmitri. I'm obligated
to proceed according to the rule of law.
Not agreed.
This stinks, sisters.
Did he just throw my cat out the window?
- I don't think so.
- No. Did he?
Shh!
Okay.
There's something
I haven't told you, Agatha.
- Okay.
- We stole a painting.
It's very valuable,
maybe five million Klubecks, in fact.
I don't know if anyone's even noticed,
but if something should happen to me -
You steal art?
One picture. Anyway,
we need to make a plan for your survival.
Hide this. It's in code and you might
need a magnifying glass to read it,
but it tells you exactly where and how
to find Boy with Apple.
Don't take less than half
the retail asking price. Also -
- Zero, I'm a baker.
- You're a pastry chef.
I'm not a fence, if that's the term.
I don't trade in stolen property.
I said it wrong. She willed it to him.
Go to sleep.
Yes, Herr Mendl.
- Hide this.
- No.
Okay, but take it anyway.
The next morning,
Herr Becker received a peculiar,
last-minute notice
from the office of Deputy Kovacs
postponing their scheduled meeting...
in perpetuity.
Let's blow.
- How did you get out there?
- Shut the fuck up.
These guys are trying to escape.
What's wrong with you, you goddamn snitch?
Guard! Guard!
It's you. Thank you.
Thank you, you sweet, kind man.
Okay.
Whoa!
I suppose you'd call that a draw.
Good evening.
Stand up.
Let me introduce you. Pinky, Wolf, Ludwig,
this is the divine Zero.
Günther was slain in the catacombs.
Well, boys, who knows when
we'll all meet again, but if one day -
Hold it.
No time to gab.
Take care of yourself, Mr. Gustave.
Good luck, kid.
- Which way to the safe house?
- I couldn't find one.
No safe house? Really?
We're completely on our own out here?
I'm afraid so. I asked around, but, uh -
I understand. Too risky.
We'll just have to wing it, I suppose.
Let's put on our disguises.
- We're wearing them.
- No, we're not.
We said false whiskers
and fake noses and so on.
- You didn't bring any?
- I thought you were growing one.
And it wouldn't -
it wouldn't look realistic, would it?
No, when done properly,
they're perfectly convincing.
But I take your point. So be it.
Give me a few squirts of L'air de Panache,
please, will you?
- Can I not get a squirt, even?
- I forgot the L'air de Panache.
Honestly, you forgot the L'air de Panache?
I don't believe it. How could you?
I've been in jail, Zero.
Do you understand how humiliating this is?
I smell.
Huh, that's just marvelous, isn't it?
I suppose this is to be expected back in -
where do you come from again?
- Aq Salim al-Jabat.
- Precisely.
I suppose this is to be expected
back in Aq Salim al-Jabat,
where one's prized possessions
are a stack of filthy carpets
and a starving goat,
and one sleeps behind a tent flap
and survives on wild dates and scarabs,
but it's not how I trained you.
What possessed you to leave the homeland
where you very obviously belong
and travel unspeakable distances
to become a penniless immigrant
in a refined, highly-cultivated society
that, quite frankly, could've gotten along
very well without you?
The war.
Say again?
Well, you see, my father was murdered
and the rest of my family
were executed by firing squad.
Our village was burned to the ground
and those who managed to survive
were forced to flee.
I left because of the war.
I see. So you're, actually,
really more of a refugee, in that sense?
Truly.
Well, I suppose I'd better take back
everything I just said.
What a bloody idiot I am. Pathetic fool.
Goddamn selfish bastard.
This is disgraceful, and it's beneath
the standards of the Grand Budapest.
I apologize
on behalf of the hotel.
It's not your fault.
You were just upset I forgot the perfume.
Don't make excuses for me.
I owe you my life.
You are my dear friend and protégé,
and I'm very proud of you.
You must know that.
I'm so sorry, Zero.
We're brothers.
How's our darling Agatha?
"'Twas first light
when I saw her face upon the heath;
and hence did I return,
day by day, entranced:
tho' vinegar did brine my heart, never -"
Very good. I'm going to stop you there
because the alarm has sounded,
but remember where we left off
because I insist you finish later.
I want roadblocks
at every junction for 50 kilometers.
I want rail blocks
at every train station for 100 kilometers.
I want 50 men and ten bloodhounds
ready in five minutes.
We're going to strip search
every pretzel-haus, waffel-hut, biergarten
and especially every grand hotel
from Äugenzburg to Zilchbrück.
These men are dangerous,
professional criminals.
At least three of them are anyway.
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
Civilian personnel aren't permitted.
- This is a military investigation.
- This is Mr. Jopling, sir.
His employer's mother
was one of the victims -
Shut up.
You work for the family
Desgoffe und Taxis?
Are you aware of the murder of Deputy
Vilmos Kovacs on the 23rd of October?
I'm aware of his disappearance.
His body was found stuffed
in a sarcophagus behind a storage room
at the Kunstmuseum late last night.
He was short four fingers.
- What do you know about that?
- Nothing.
Escort Mr. Jopling off the premises.
Mendl's.
Operator, get me the Excelsior Palace
in Baden-Jürgen and reverse the charges.
We've no choice.
There's nowhere else to turn.
I'll hold. Thank you.
It's our only hope. Otherwise, I shouldn't
even mention its existence to you.
It goes without saying, never breathe
a word about this to a living soul.
- Do you swear?
- Of course. What is it, in fact?
I can't say.
Guten Abend. Monsieur Ivan, bitte. Danke.
How does one come by front-row aisle seats
for a first night at the Opera Toscana
with one day's notice?
How does one arrange a private viewing
of the tapestry collection
at the Royal Saxon Gallery?
How does one secure a corner table
at Chez Dominique on a Thursday?
Ivan, darling, it's Gustave. Hello.
Well, I was until about five minutes ago.
We've taken it upon ourselves to clear out
in a hurry, if you see what I mean.
Well, through a sewer, as it happens.
Exactly.
Listen, Ivan, I'm sorry to cut you off,
but we're in a bit of a bind.
This is an official request.
I'm formally calling
upon the special services of -
I'll call you back, Gustave.
Right. Stand by.
I beg your pardon. Do you prefer to walk?
We're right here. It's very simple.
Straight down the corniche, then left.
Jojo, see the gentleman out.
Get me Monsieur Georges
at the Château Luxe, please.
Take over.... ?
Hello, Ivan?
Got it.
Get me Monsieur Dino
at the Palazzo Principessa, please.
Higher, goddamn it. Higher!
Take over.
- Monsieur Georges.
- Higher.
I see. Straightaway.
Get me Monsieur Robin
at l'Hôtel Côte du Cap, please.
...and two and three.
Monsieur Robin.
There's a call from Monsieur Dino for you.
Take over.
- One, two, three.
- Yes, Dino.
Yes, Dino. Okay, Dino.
Get me Monsieur Martin
at the Ritz Imperial, please.
Too much salt.
Not enough pepper.
- Monsieur, you have a call.
- Take over.
- Robin? Martin.
- Too much salt.
So I've heard.
Maybe. Let me make a few calls.
Serge X: missing.
Deputy Kovacs: also missing.
Madame D: dead.
Boy with Apple: stolen, by us.
Dmitri and Jopling:
ruthless, cold-blooded savages.
Gustave H: at large. What else?
- Zero: confused.
- Zero: confused, indeed.
The plot thickens, as they say.
Why, by the way? Is it a soup metaphor?
I don't know.
Get in.
We found the butler.
He's hiding out in the remote foothills
near Gabelmeister's Peak.
Our contact convinced him
to meet you midday tomorrow
at the observatory on the summit.
Tell no one. He'll explain everything.
Your train departs
in four and a half minutes.
Here's your tickets.
- Oh, third class?
- It was overbooked,
but the conductor used to be a sommelier
at the old Versailles.
He pulled some strings.
You'll need these for the dining car.
One last thing.
L'air de Panache.
They only had the half-ounce.
We should give him something
as a symbolic gesture.
- How much money you got?
- 42 Klubecks and three postage stamps.
Give me 25. Yes.
- Bless you.
- Please.
- I've got to hand it to him.
- Jesus Christ.
I didn't see that coming.
Well, what do you want next?
Talk to the club-footed sister again.
And, this time, be persuasive.
Goddamn son of a bitch.
Holy fuck!
What's the meaning of this shit?
Boy with Apple? I thought you'd hidden it.
- Why are you only noticing now?
- I assumed it went to the tax appraiser.
- Are you fucking kidding me?
- Excusez-moi.
I believe it was removed
by Monsieur Gustave.
I'm not angry with Serge.
You can't blame someone
for their basic lack of moral fiber.
He's a frightened, little,
yellow-bellied coward.
- It's not his fault, is it?
- I don't know. It depends.
You can say that about most anything.
"It depends." Of course it depends.
Of course it depends of course it depends.
Yes, I suppose you're right.
Of course it depends.
However, that doesn't mean I'm not going
to throttle the little swamp rat.
May I officiate, by the way? The ceremony?
With pleasure.
I must say,
I find that girl utterly delightful.
Flat as a board, enormous birthmark
the shape of Mexico over half her face,
sweating for hours on end
in that sweltering kitchen
while Mendl, genius though he is,
looms over her like a hulking gorilla.
Yet without question, without fail,
always and invariably,
she's exceedingly lovely.
Why?
Because of her purity.
She admires you as well, Monsieur Gustave.
- Does she?
- Very much.
That's a good sign, you know?
It means she "gets it."
That's important.
Don't flirt with her.
A radio telegram was delivered
and signed for by the girl at 4:00 a.m.
The envelope was found near the body,
but its contents were missing.
However, the telegraph office always keeps
a carbon of the ticker tape for 24hours.
I copied it down. It reads as follows:
"Pack your things. Stop.
Be ready to leave at moment's notice.
Stop.
Hideout is vicinity
of Gabelmeister's Peak. Stop.
Destroy this message.
All my love. Full stop."
Where's the basket?
Where you headed, mister?
Skiing? Sledding? Mountain climbing?
Three Klubecks.
By express wireless,
I wrote Agatha with instructions
to move to our prearranged hideout:
a Gypsy caravan
on the outer Nebelsbad road,
while Monsieur Gustave and I
continued east into the Zubrowkian Alps,
toward our high-altitude rendezvous
with the butler Serge X.
As a precaution, we disembarked quietly
in the freight yard
just outside the station.
L'air de Panache.
It's a hell of a view.
I give them that.
I agree.
"'Tis oft remarked:
no single, falling flake does any other
- in its pure and perfect form -"
- Somebody's coming.
Are you Monsieur Gustave
of the Grand Budapest Hotel in Nebelsbad?
- Uh-huh.
- Get on the next cable car.
Are you Monsieur Gustave
of the Grand Budapest Hotel in Nebelsbad?
- Uh-huh.
- Switch with me.
Are you Monsieur Gustave
of the Grand Budapest Hotel in Nebelsbad?
- Uh-huh.
- Put these on and sing.
Psst.
- Are you Monsieur Gustave of the -
- Yes, damn it!
- Confess.
- I'm innocent!
Hmm? No, no.
Forgive me, Monsieur Gustave.
I never meant to betray you.
They threatened my life
and now they've murdered my only family.
No. Who did they kill this time?
- My dear sister.
- The girl with the club foot?
- Yes.
- Those fuckers!
- I tried to warn you at the beginning.
- I know. Let's put that behind us.
Listen, I hate to put you on the spot,
but I must ask you to clear my name.
- Obviously, you're grieving -
- There's more.
Okay.
- To the story.
- I get it. Go on.
I was the official witness
in Madame D's presence
to the creation of a second will
to be executed only in the event
of her death by murder.
- A second will?
- Right.
- In case she got bumped off?
- Uh-huh?
- But they destroyed it.
- Oh, dear.
- However -
- Uh-huh?
- ...I pulled a copy.
A second copy of the second will?
- Right.
- Uh-huh?
What does it say? Where is it?
What's it all about, damn it?
Don't keep us in suspense. This has been
a complete fucking nightmare.
Just tell us what the fuck is going on!
Serge? Serge? Serge!
Bloody hell.
They've strangled the poor slob.
Come on! Let's go!
- What do we do if we catch him?
- I don't know.
He's a homicidal psychopath. Let's stop!
I can't. I can barely steer.
You sick, pathetic creep. I hate you.
"'If this do be me end: farewell!',
cried the wounded piper boy...
whilst the muskets cracked
and the yeomen roared 'Hurrah!'
and the ramparts fell.
'Methinks me breathes me last,
me fears!', said he -"
Holy shit! You got him!
Well done, Zero!
Gustave H!
You are a fugitive from justice!
Surrender lawfully and I will personally
vouchsafe your fair treatment.
Do not attempt to flee!
- What do you think?
- I don't know.
I'd rather jump off this cliff right now
than go back to fucking prison.
We steal that sick maniac's motorcycle,
go fetch Agatha,
take back Boy with Apple
and head for the Maltese Riviera.
Very good. You're so extraordinary, Zero.
Thank you.
A moment of silence
in memoriam of a devoted servant
killed violently
during the conduct of his duties.
Good-bye, Serge.
Okay, let's go.
The war began at midnight.
Pffeifelstad fell by lunch
under heavy shelling,
and ten battalions surged across
the long western border.
High command advanced to Nebelsbad.
Compliments of Herr Mendl,
for the executive staff.
General Stieglitz requests a garden-view
sitting room with an extra rollaway.
Let's put him in the Duke Leopold Suite.
Secretary Woroniecki's office cabled.
He's checking in a day early.
Rooms 401-2-3.
Tell Tactical Logistics we're moving them
to a standard double on the third floor.
They'll need more space than that.
The beginning of the end
of the end of the beginning has begun.
A sad finale played off-key
on a broken-down saloon piano
in the outskirts
of a forgotten ghost town.
I'd rather not bear witness
to such blasphemy.
Me neither.
The Grand Budapest
has become a troops' barracks.
I shall never cross
its threshold again in my lifetime.
- Me neither.
- Never again shall I -
Actually, I think we might be
going in there right now after all.
Dmitri.
Agatha.
Good evening, Mr. Desgoffe und Taxis.
I'm Monsieur Chuck.
We've booked you and your sisters
into the King Ferdinand Suite.
Good evening.
General von Shrecker asked me -
- Who's that?
- I... beg your pardon?
I think that girl's got my picture.
Excuse me.
- Six.
- Hold it.
Six.
Compliments of Herr Mendl.
Excuse me.
Have you seen a pastry girl with a package
in the last minute and a half?
Yep. She just got on the elevator
with Mr. Desgoffe und Taxis.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Uh, I'm sorry. Who are you?
- Otto, sir, the new lobby boy.
- You haven't been trained properly.
A lobby boy never provides
information of that kind.
You're a stone wall. Understood?
Pretty picture.
Sixth floor.
Where's Boy with Apple?
None of your goddamn business!
I'm gonna blast your candy-ass
once and for all right now.
Drop your weapon!
- Cease fire! Cease fire!
- Whoa!
Stop it!
Who's shooting who?
That's Gustave H,
the escaped murderer and art thief.
I've got him cornered.
That's Dmitri Desgoffe und Taxis.
He's responsible for the killing
of Deputy Kovacs, Serge X,
and his club-footed sister,
plus his own mother!
Nobody move. Everybody's under arrest.
Who's out the window?
Agatha.
310-bis. Hang on! Here I come!
Something's on the back of the -
Agatha! Agatha!
- Are you all right?
- I think so.
- Something's on the back of the picture.
- What?
She left everything
to Monsieur Gustave, of course.
- The mansion, known as Schloss Lutz -
- I knew her, intimately.
... the factories, which produced weapons,
medicine and textiles -
...an important newspaper syndicate...
and perhaps you've already deduced,
this very institution,
the Grand Budapest Hotel.
He anointed me his successor,
and as the war continued,
I served my adopted country
from the narrow desk still found
against the wall in the next room.
He was the same as his disciples:
insecure, vain, superficial, blond, needy.
- In the end, he was even rich.
- Everyone's going to join me.
He did not succeed, however,
in growing old.
Are you ready?
Dearly beloved, we are gathered together -
Nor did my darling Agatha.
She and our infant son would be killed
two years later by the Prussian grippe.
An absurd little disease.
Today we treat it in a single week,
but in those days, many millions died.
On the 21st day of the occupation,
the morning the independent state
of Zubrowka officially ceased to exist,
we traveled with Monsieur Gustave to Lutz.
In answer to your earlier question,
by the way:
of course.
Zero asked me about my humble beginnings
in the hotel trade.
I was perhaps, for a time,
considered the best lobby boy
we'd ever had at the Grand Budapest.
I think I can say that.
This one finally surpassed me.
Although, I must say,
he had an exceptional teacher.
Truly.
"Whence came these two radiant,
celestial brothers,
united, for an instant,
as they crossed the stratosphere
of our starry window?
One from the East and one from the West."
Very good.
Don't flirt with her.
Why are we stopping
at a barley field again?
I find these black uniforms very drab.
Well, hello there, chaps.
We were just talking about you.
- Documents, please.
- With pleasure, as always.
You're the first
of the official death squads
to whom we've been formally introduced.
How do you do?
Plus ça change, am I right?
Uh, that's a migratory visa
with stage three worker status, darling.
Read this.
- Come outside.
- Now, stay there.
I give you my word,
if you lay a finger on this man,
I'll see you dishonorably discharged,
locked up in the stockade
and hanged by sundown.
There are still
faint glimmers of civilization left
in this barbaric slaughterhouse
that was once known as humanity.
You filthy, goddamn,
pockmarked, fascist assholes!
He was one of them.
What more is there to say?
What happened in the end?
In the end, they shot him.
So it all went to me.
After dinner,
we went to collect the keys to our rooms,
but Monsieur Jean had abandoned his post.
I expect he's forgotten all about us.
In recent years, of course,
such properties and holdings
as the Grand Budapest
had, with very few exceptions, become...
common property.
While the precise terms of his negotiation
with the new government
had never been announced,
the result was an open secret:
Zero Moustafa had traded
a great and important fortune
in exchange for one costly,
unprofitable, doomed hotel.
Why? Was it merely sentimental?
It was quite forward of me
and a bit out of character,
but I felt I must know...
for my health, I suppose.
Forgive me for asking.
I hope I haven't upset you.
No, of course not.
Is it simply your last connection
to that vanished world -
his world, if you will?
His world?
No, I don't think so.
You see, we shared a vocation.
It wouldn't have been necessary.
No. The hotel I keep for Agatha.
We were happy here.
For a little while.
To be frank,
I think his world had vanished
long before he ever entered it.
But I will say:
he certainly sustained the illusion
with a marvelous grace.
- Are you going up?
- No, I'll sit for a little while.
Good night.
The next week,
I sailed for a cure in South America
and began a long,
wandering journey abroad.
I did not return to Europe for many years.
It was an enchanting old ruin.
But I never managed
to see it again.