On December 26th, 2004, the deadliest tsunami
on record hit the South East Coast of Asia.
The lives of countless families all
over the world changed forever.
This is the true story of
one of those families.
Oh, God!
Did you....
- ...Did you set the alarm before we left?
- Yes, it was the last thing I did!
No, I was the last one to leave.
I was the last one to leave
and I'm sure I didn't set it.
No darling, I was the last one out...
and I did, I promise.
_ are You sure?
- Yep!
Okay!
No, no, I was the last one
'cause I went back in.
And that means the alarm is not set.
Cause I didn't set it.
Well, I guess that means that we be coming
home to a large bunch of hippies...
...sleeping in our bed.
What? Just like your old college days?
It's all right. It's fine.
It's just turbulence, Maria.
Please Turn Off Electronic Devices.
Ladies and gentlemen, we are about
to begin our descent to Phuket Airport.
The local time is 1:30 in the afternoon...
What are you doing? It's time to sit down,
we are about to land, darling.
Lucas won't talk to me.
Please fasten your seatbelts...
...and return your seat to
the upright position.
Take my seat.
- What did I do? I didn't do anything.
- It's all right. Just sit down and stop worrying.
Buckle up!
Sit down please, madam!
Lucas.
_ Lucas.
- What?!
You know you could try being a bit nicer to
your brother, he's just scared.
_ so What else is new, everything scares him?
I wonder who he takes after.
KHAOLAK, THAILAND CHRISTMAS EVE
Take your stuff. Don't forget all your bags.
Have you been to Khao Lak before?
No, it's our first time.
This is the best holiday season ever.
All resorts are full,
but this area is really quiet.
Great for families.
The Orchid Beach Resort is brand new.
We just opened a week ago.
- You'll love it here.
_ all Right.
I'm sorry, but we made a booking
on the third floor, the sea view room.
I know. We are sorry,
that was a mistake.
But we feel...
you might like this better.
_ Where Do You Come from?
_ Japan.
You don't look Japanese.
No, well, I work for a big company there,
and we move around a lot, you know.
And you, you don't work?
I'm a doctor.
Not practicing right now.
Just taking care of the kids.
I see, you got promoted.
Well, that's nice, isn't it?
- Mom!
_ Yes.
_ can I have one of these, please?
_ Lucas, if You are thirsty, will You just...
_ Drink some juice or a glass of water.
_ Exactly.
_ Boys, Come And see this.
_ Come on.
Look.
_ Yeah, look. Look at this.
- Oh!
Isn't it great?
_ Dad, can We swim in there?
_ Yeah, We can go swimming. Yeah.
Ten, nine...
...eight, seven, six...
...five, four, three...
...two, one!
Go!
Wow!
That one isn't going up!
_ Yes, It is.
_ It is going up.
No, it's not.
It's going a different way than the others.
Yeah!
- It's catching up.
- Yeah, it's catching up.
No, Dad, it's going
in the opposite direction.
We got any of that wine left?
They're fast asleep.
Good morning.
Ahh!
Get off!
- Wake up!
_ What are You doing?
- It's Christmas!
It's Christmas morning!
It's Christmas!
Coins!
The money's leading this way.
The money's going outside!
No, no, no!
Wait, wait! One at a time!
Oh!
A telescope!
It's the complete nova stars...
It's like, you can stick on your ceiling.
- It's the whole Milky Way.
_ And Then They light up?
Oh, look at this gorgeous scarf! I love it.
_ Thank You, darling.
- That's all right, my love.
I mean Santa Claus.
What have you got, wee man?
_ a ball.
_ a ball?
Goal!
I can't get to sleep.
- Must be jet lag!
_ Yeah. Sure.
Can we go outside and watch the stars?
Maybe tomorrow.
Just close your eyes and
think of something nice.
Mom, do you want to play ball with me?
In a minute, darling, play with Lucas.
- I can't believe you. You're hopeless!
_ What?
I'm gonna hide that thing
and forget where I put it.
I was just checking to see about the house
we put a bid on in Japan.
Liar.
The truth is I got a text
saying that Yunioshi has been given
a two-year extension on his contract.
Which means there will be
two of us doing the same job.
And that can only really mean one thing.
They can't fire you.
That would be too expensive. Don't worry.
Well, I do worry because
we can't afford to lose this job, can we?
Hey, Dad! Come and play with us!
I could go back to work. Maybe it's time.
_ in Japan?
_ No.
Oh, you want to go home?
It's not the worst idea, is it?
Well, we should think about it.
But I'm gonna play with the boys now, so...
Here, Dad!
Dad, they are the worst trunks ever!
- Awful!
- They're awful, Dad!
- No, you're the awful!
- Yes, they are!
- Boys! Oh!
- Fish!
- Try to splash 'em!
- Ha, ha, beat you!
Lucas!
Oh, no!
Go get it, Lucas! Go on!
- Henry, the boys!
- Lucas!
Dad!
Lucas!
Mom! Help!
- Lucas!
- Mom!
- Help me!
Lucas!
Help me! Help!
Get me out of this, Mom!
Lucas! Stay there!
Mom!
Hold on! Hold on!
- Mom! Swim towards me!
- Be careful!
Grab that mattress!
- Lucas, grab that mattress!
- Mom!
Lucas! Swim!
Mom!
- I want to go home!
- Grab my hand!
Mom!
Come on!
Grab on.
- Mom!
- Lucas!
Lucas!
Come on!
- Lucas!
- Mom!
Someone help! Someone help!
Lucas!
Lucas, go under!
Mom!
Mom...
No...
Mom!
Mom. Mom.
Mom... Mom!
Mom!
- Lucas!
- Mom!
Never do that to me again, Mom.
- I'm here.
_ Never Do that to me again.
We have to find somewhere safe.
It's okay. I'm here.
Mom...
Mom, look, that tree. That tree over there.
Yes. Yes. This is perfect. It's perfect.
Careful, Lucas.
Don't... Don't move.
Stay really still.
I thought I was a brave kid, Mom.
I'm scared.
Come here. Come here.
I'm scared, too.
Is it over?
I don't know. I don't know.
Mom?
What?
You're bleeding, Mom.
_ Oh, God.
It's okay.
- I can't see you like this.
- It's okay, it's okay.
Sorry. I just... Sorry.
You go first.
That tree there, the big one.
Do you think we can climb it?
Okay, let's go.
_ Wait. Did You hear that?
- There's nothing we can do.
_ Wait...
We are almost there.
We have to get to safety.
No, we have to help that boy.
Mom, if another wave catches
us down here, we will die.
We have to climb that tree
right now. Come on.
Where are you?
Mom, look at you! We need help!
We cannot risk it.
We can't risk it, Mom. Come on.
Listen...
What if that boy was Simon or Thomas?
What if they needed help?
You'd want someone
to help them, wouldn't you?
Simon and Thomas are dead!
Even if it's the last thing we do.
Where are you?
Look there, Mom! I see him!
Are you okay?
- Yeah, he's okay. He's okay.
What's your name?
I'm Lucas. What's your name?
_ Daniel.
_ Okay, Daniel. Okay, Come on.
You're gonna be okay.
We're gonna get you out. Okay?
Lift him up.
- It's all right.
- It's okay. It's okay.
It's all right.
Are you okay?
Okay. Are you okay?
- It's okay, it's okay!
Don't worry. Everything's okay.
Okay? You stay here. I'll be back. Okay?
Mom, coming down. Just give me a second.
No. I can do it.
- No, Mom, I'm coming down.
- I can do it, Lucas!
Just stay there. Please.
Mom? Mom...
Okay...
Thank you. Thank you.
Did you hear that?
Mom, look! Look, they're coming for us!
Hey! Over here!
Hey!
Climb down, Lucas.
_ Lucas...
Lucas! Please...
No, no, no! God, please! No...
Lucas?
_ Lucas?
- Mom, I'm here.
Thank you so much. Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you...
Thank you. Thank you so much.
My boys...
I cannot see them, my boys...
My boys.
Okay, Okay.
Don't let them take me
anywhere without you.
Don't worry, Mom.
I'm not gonna leave you alone. I promise.
Bye-bye.
Where's Daniel? Daniel?
Daniel. Lucas, where's Daniel?
- I don't know.
_ Daniel...
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Mom.
Lucas.
It's so cold in here.
It's not cold, Mom.
Don't move.
Mom? Mom, what's wrong?
I need some antibiotics.
Look in the cupboard.
Oh, God.
I can't read the labels. They're all in Thai.
There's got to be some English. Look...
Look on the sides. Look carefully, Lucas.
Thank God. Please.
See that boy?
I'm all he's got in the world.
Do you understand?
I'm a doctor, too. I've got a lot of bleeding.
You've got to stop it, please.
I need some antibiotics. Please help.
Are you okay?
I lost my husband and two children.
If anything happens to me...
What color is it?
_ What?
_ my leg.
Is it still red?
Yeah. It's still red.
_ What does that mean?
It's good. As long as it doesn't turn black.
Here.
You need to eat something. Eat it.
You're so bossy.
I wonder who I take after.
Hello.
What's your name?
My name's Maria. And this is my son, Lucas.
Hey.
Give her some tangerine.
She must be starving.
Be careful.
_ Be careful, Lucas.
Turn your head to the side, please.
You'll choke if you don't.
Please, please,
she needs help. Turn her head.
Help her, Lucas. Help her. Turn her head.
_ You okay?
_ Mom, are You okay?
Mom? Mom? Are you okay?
What are you doing?
_ Mom, are You okay?
Stop it, Mom! That's enough! Mom, stop it!
_ Mom...
Mom, stop it!
Mom? Mom?
Francesca!
I need to go to the toilet.
Please...
Please.
_ Lucas.
- Somebody help me!
Look at this place. It's so busy in here.
You've got to go and do something.
Go and help people. You're good at it.
What do you want me to do?
Something.
Anything.
Will you be all right?
Come on, Lucas. I'm...
I'm not going anywhere.
_ I promise.
_ Okay.
Bernström!
Three! Bernström!
Hello? Help me.
Bernström! Bernström. From Sweden.
_ your family?
_ Agda. Josef. Mårten.
You're looking for your family.
Have you seen them? Bernström!
Okay! Calm down. I will help you. Okay?
Agda. Mårten. Josef.
I'll try and help you. Okay.
Okay.
Agda Bernström?
Excuse me. Are you Josef Bernström?
_ or Mårten Bernström?
_ No.
Mårten Bernström?
Excuse me? Excuse me.
I'm looking for my son.
Your son?
Peter Berry. Yes.
He'll be wondering where I am.
Okay.
Peter Berry?
Mårten Bernström? No? Agda Bernström?
Peter Berry? Josef...
Anna Marie?
Anna Marie DeBrauwn.
I'm sorry. What's your name again?
Anna Marie DeBrauwn, anyone?
Renata Castorini.
Tatiana. Tatiana Cherneshova.
Pah Chu Lihn.
Josef Bernström, anyone?
Sang Sak is...
Agda Bernström? Renata Castorini?
Gunnar Diehl!
Anna Marie DeBrauwn?
Mårten Bernström?
Ja.
Mårten Bernström from Sweden?
I know your dad.
Pappa?
Yeah, your pappa. He's here.
- I'll bring him here, okay?
_ Yes.
No, no, no! You need to stay here.
Okay.
I will bring your pappa here. Okay?
No! No, you have to stay here.
You have to stay here
because it's a very long way,
and you have to rest. Okay?
_ Okay.
Bernström!
Where's my mom?
Mom?
Mom!
No. No! What are you doing?
No, this is my mom's bed! Get off! No!
- Get off! Get off!
- It's all right.
It's okay. Take it easy, boy.
No! My mom was here, and she took her file.
Look, you have to come with me.
I will help you. Okay?
Okay?
Okay. Okay.
What's your name?
Lucas Bennett.
Where were you staying?
In the, uh, the Orchid...
The Orchid Beach Resort in Khao Lak.
Was somebody else traveling with you?
Lucas?
My dad and my two little brothers.
Do you know what happened to them?
Is there somebody we could call?
Um...
My granddad.
What's his name?
Brian. But I don't remember his number.
Lucas?
Lucas!
Maria!
Hotel, we have
prepared transport for you.
We have to move to the Sangdee camp.
Move, everyone, please.
You can't just stayhere.
Hey, man!
You all right?
I just need to lie here a minute.
I'll be up in a second.
Don't even bother. They're sending trucks
to drive us all up to the mountains.
Just hang on tight, all right?
They'll be here soon.
Yeah, I know. Can you tell them I'm back?
Yeah, sure. Hold on.
Hey, boys! Your daddy's back!
Dad! Dad! Dad!
Dad! Dad!
Hey.
Dad, a whole lot of helicopters just flew by!
_ Did they?
_ Yeah.
Mom and Lucas?
Why don't you come down here
a minute, Thomas.
What about me?
You stay and see if you can see
any more helicopters. Okay?
_ Okay.
_ Good boy.
You're almost there, buddy. You got it?
I still haven't found them.
Did you see a lot of dead people?
What happened was very serious, Thomas.
Not Mom and Lucas, right?
No, I didn't see them.
I burnt my feet on the roof.
It was really hot, and everyone was leaving.
Oh.
Can we leave yet?
I need you to, um...
I need you to do me a favor, Thomas.
I've heard that everyone's
going to the mountains, you see,
to a shelter where it's really safe.
But I can't go with you.
You can't leave us alone again, Dad.
I have to keep looking for them, you see.
You have to look after Simon...
No! No, stay with us. I can't look...
I've never looked after
someone before. I'm scared.
I know. I know. I'm scared, too.
But do you know the most scary bit for me?
When the water hit?
No. After that.
When I came up, and I was all on my own.
That was the scariest part.
And then I saw the two of you
clinging to the tree, and I...
I didn't feel so scared anymore,
because I knew I wasn't
on my own, you see?
What if Mommy and Lucas
are on their own right now?
Hmm?
Imagine how scared they'll be.
We'll look for them together.
No. Thomas, you have to look after Simon.
And I'm going to keep looking for them.
Okay?
I know you understand.
Everyone move out.
You can't stand here.
There might be another wave
coming soon. Move out.
Hello? Yeah, I can hear you.
Nobody knows what's going on.
Are you all right? Have you lost someone?
We're fine. We just want to get out of here.
I'll call you back. Okay? Bye.
Uh, excuse me.
I've been trying to place
a call back home all day.
I wondered, could I use your phone?
_ It would Be really quick.
_ Look around You, man.
Everybody's needing something right now.
But our battery is almost dead.
We need the phone.
Yes, as I said,
we are trying to clear the road, but...
I understand, but I'd like to talk
to somebody in charge
who knows a little bit more.
I'll see you in the morning, okay?
You're not coming?
I'm not coming, wee man, no.
Thomas will take care of you, all right?
Listen to me. You're gonna
behave yourselves, okay?
And you stay with this group,
and I'm gonna be with you
just as soon as I can, okay?
You're gonna behave yourselves, okay?
I love you.
Okay.
Will you look out for my boys
for me, please?
Come with us.
You know it's useless.
I can't stop looking.
_ I love you.
I'll be with you tomorrow, I promise.
I love you.
Maria!
Lucas!
- Oh!
Oh, no. No.
Hey, man, are you okay?
Get in the car.
We'll drive you somewhere safer.
My wife didn't want
to come to Thailand
for Christmas holidays,
because of my leg.
I insisted. My little girl, Gina,
she's just two.
The noise woke me up.
I was alone in the room.
I went out to the terrace
and saw the sea coming inland.
It took me five seconds to reach the stairs,
but the water was already there.
It was not more than five seconds.
On the bed,
I found a note from my wife,
saying that they were at the beach.
You were at the Orchid, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, my whole family were in
the swimming pool when the water hit.
I found my middle son first,
Thomas. He was...
He was at the top of this really tall tree.
Took me ages
to convince him to come down
because he was so scared, you know?
And then I found my little one, Simon.
He was holding onto a palm tree.
He's only five.
I sent them to the mountains.
You know?
So that I could keep looking
for my wife and my elder son.
Toughest choice I ever made.
_ have You called home yet?
- I can't find a phone.
I'm saving my battery.
Just in case my family calls.
Please.
Thank you. I'll be very quick, I promise.
- Yes?
_ Brian?
Yes, Henry, thank God. How are you guys?
Did you hear from anyone yet?
No, Henry, you're the first to call.
Is everybody all right?
- Henry?
_ Maria And Lucas are not Here.
What do you mean, "not there"?
The water came and swept everyone away.
And I found... I found Thomas and Simon,
but I don't know where Maria and Lucas are.
Henry? Don't do that.
And I don't know what to do,
I don't know where to look for them.
Henry. Henry, calm down.
Henry? Henry?
Brian, I have to go.
Lots of people
need to use this phone, okay?
- I'll just call you later.
_ Henry?
Sorry. I'm sorry, sorry.
Thank you.
What do you want me to do?
You can't leave it like that. Go on!
- Come on!
_ go on.
_ Come on, man.
_ Come on.
I should call him back.
- Yes, Henry?
- Brian, it's me again.
Look, I promise you
that I won't stop looking
_ until I find them. okay?
- Okay.
I don't know what I'm gonna do
because it's nighttime now, but I'll...
I'll look in all the hospitals.
- Okay.
- And I'll look
in all the shelters and everything, okay?
I will find them, I promise you that.
- I'll call you when I do.
- Okay.
_ Okay. Okay.
Thanks.
Can I go with you?
I'm scared.
Close your eyes. Think of something nice.
May I sit with you?
How old are you?
Almost 74. And you?
Seven and a half.
Get these ants off me.
_ is he all right?
- Yeah, he's asleep. He's fine.
He's got a bit of ant bites on him.
He's all right.
You like looking at stars, don't you?
I do. At home I can find
most of the constellations.
But here in the sky, it's different.
Some of those stars
have been burnt out for a long, long time.
Did you know that?
They're dead, aren't they?
They're dead.
But once they were so bright
that their light is still
traveling through space.
We can still see them.
How can you tell which ones are dead
and which ones are not?
Oh, you can't. It's impossible.
It's a beautiful mystery, isn't it?
Mmm.
Lucas Bennett?
Can you come with me?
Sit here.
Your name is Lucas Bennett, is that right?
Yeah.
And your mother's name is Maria Bennett.
_ is that correct?
_ Uh-huh.
We'd like you to look at these things, please,
and see if you recognize any of them.
Have a good look.
Take your time.
Does anything look familiar?
I don't know.
You don't know?
I...
Do you recognize anything?
- I don't think so.
- You don't think so?
Lucas...
Could you please come with us?
Mom.
Where the hell have you been?
Where the hell have I been?
Where the hell were you?
You promised me
you weren't going anywhere.
You weren't there.
I thought you were dead, Mom.
I'm sorry.
I thought you were dead.
We're so sorry.
Someone must have changed
her records during surgery.
How is she?
She's had surgery on her chest.
But she lost a lot of blood.
She was too weak
to have her leg operated on.
She has to go back to surgery
when she recovers.
But she'll be okay, right?
Nothing. What next?
We should, uh...
We should try and get a ride
to Takuapa Hospital.
_ Where are my kids?
- They're taking them away.
They wouldn't let me go
with them. I'm sorry.
_ Where?
- I don't know.
I need to pee.
You have to wait, Simon.
Mom. Mom.
_ Lucas...
_ Wake up.
Mom, guess who I just saw outside?
My leg. What color is my leg?
It's still red.
Please. My mom.
Her wounds are looking really bad.
We are doing the best we can.
We are taking your mom
to surgery right away.
No more sick here since yesterday.
It's full. We move out.
No, no, no! Five minutes.
Give me five minutes, please.
Please.
I don't want you to slow down.
These are the names of my
little girl, Gina, and Kathy,
my wife. She's American.
Would you check the list for me?
_ of course.
_ Please.
They told us our daughter
could be in Surat Thani.
And we've already been to this hospital.
We have checked all hospitals
but this one. Please.
Five minutes, please.
Just only five minutes.
Okay.
I won't be long. I'll be right back.
Lucas.
Anything left in the can?
Don't worry. I'll get you something.
Dad?
Dad!
I need to pee!
_ can You hold it?
_ No.
Simon! What are you doing?
Boys! Get back
on the bus right now!
Hurry up! They're gonna leave us here!
What are you doing?
No luck.
Sorry.
Sorry. And thanks for waiting.
Okay. We go now.
Coming!
- We're coming!
- We have to go now!
Dad!
It's Lucas.
- Lucas!
Simon! Thomas!
Lucas! Lucas!
Lucas!
Thomas! Simon!
Lucas! Lucas!
Lucas! Lucas! Lucas!
- Lucas!
- Simon!
Searched everywhere...
Simon.
Thomas.
Are you okay?
Lucas!
Dad! Dad...
Dad. Dad?
Lucas!
- Dad!
- Lucas!
Dad!
Dad! Dad! Dad! Dad!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I left you both.
Dad, we did it.
Let's go. No need to wait.
Are you okay? Are you okay?
_ Mom is Here.
_ What?
She's really weak. She says
some weird stuff sometimes.
The nurse says they're gonna
try and operate on her
as soon as they can.
I think it's serious.
Mom? Mom.
Look who's here.
Hey.
Hey, my darling.
Mom.
I thought you were all dead.
We're all okay.
Am I dead?
No.
It's okay to take this off?
Here, here, here. I've got it.
_ You came back.
_ Yes.
_ Yeah.
Oh, thank God.
I can rest now.
Maria, what? What? What, darling?
I'm dying.
No. No.
You're going to be fine.
Take care of our babies.
Hey, that's not what I came here for.
You're gonna be fine.
They're gonna take good care of you, okay?
I promise you, we're gonna be fine.
Oh, Henry, I'm scared.
We're gonna be fine.
Henry...
Sweetheart, I promise you're gonna be okay.
We're taking her to surgery.
We need to take her now.
Okay.
I love you.
You're gonna be okay.
I love you so much. I love you.
I love you, Maria. You know that, don't you?
I'm sorry if I let you down in any way.
Lucas.
Thanks for taking care of Mom.
We took care of each other.
Dad?
Yeah.
There's something I didn't tell Mom.
And I really need her to know.
I have a family, too.
I've been saving my strength
because I want to see them
one more time.
Oh. Do you have to?
We don't want you to feel any pain.
I'm afraid to go to sleep.
Shh. You're in good hands.
Close your eyes
and think of something nice.
Think of something nice.
Lucas!
Dad!
Mom's okay, Lucas.
We're going home.
Be careful. You okay?
Mr. Bennett! Mr. Bennett!
I'm Oliver Tudpole from Zurich Insurance.
They sent me to take care of your family.
You have nothing to worry about now.
In a few hours, you'll be at
Singapore General Hospital,
where your wife will receive
the best treatment in all of Asia.
These people will take you onto the plane.
I'll see you once you get there.
Have a safe flight.
Okay.
Where are we going?
They'll take us to Singapore.
You'll be safe there, okay?
Please take your seat.
We'll be taking off shortly.
Okay.
_ can I just...
_ Yeah. Okay. one minute.
Hey.
How are you?
Here. With you.
Mom.
Guess what?
I saw Daniel again.
He was so happy.
He was in somebody's arms.
I bet it was his dad, Mom.
I love you.
Lucas, I love you so much.
Thank you. Thank you.
I'm sorry, but you have
to go back to your seat now.
Fasten your seatbelts, please.
I don't want to.
Why not? You have to do
your seatbelts up in a plane.
It's okay. It's only the plane.