- Mr. Szpilman?
- Hello.
I came specially to meet you.
I love your playing.
- Who are you?
- My name's Dorota, Jurek's sister.
- You're bleeding!
- It's nothing.
You can write him a fan letter later.
This isn't the best time. Come on.
Jurek, where have you been hiding her?
- I don't know what to take.
- You always take too much.
How many suitcases are you taking?
I'm packing my red dress.
And what, what do you think, should I,
should I take uncle Szymon's portrait?
Take it, don't take it,
take what you like.
- Can't you see I'm worried sick?
- He'll come home, he'll be alright.
We should have
another case just for shoes.
Wladek! Mama, Wladek's home!
Thank God. Wladek! You're wounded?
No, no, no,
it's a little cut, it's nothing.
I've been worried sick.
I told her not to worry.
You had your papers on you.
If you'd been hit by a bomb,
they'd have known where to take you.
Henryk, Henryk,
don't say things like...
don't say things like that.
- I can't find anything.
- God forbid. God forbid.
- Papa, Wladek's home.
- What did I tell you?
- What are you doing?
- What's it look like we're doing?
Has anybody seen
my hat with the wide brim?
I don't know they bombed us,
we're off the air.
Warsaw's not the only radio station.
Pack, pack, darling.
Get your things, pack.
- Where are we going?
- Pfff. Out of Warsaw.
- Out of Warsaw where?
- You haven't heard?
- Heard what?
- Haven't you seen the paper?
- Where's the paper?
- I used it for packing.
She used it for packing.
The government's moved to Lublin.
All able bodied men must leave the city,
go across the river and set up a new line
of defense, that's what it said.
There's hardly anybody left in this
building only the women the men have gone.
And what do you think you'll do while
you're setting up a new line of defense?
- Wonder around lugging your suitcases?
- Pack, Wladek. There's no time.
- I'm not going anywhere.
- Good! I'm not going anywhere either!
Don't be ridiculous,
we've got to keep together.
No, no, look, look.
If I'm going to die, I prefer to die
in my own home, staying put.
- God forbid.
- Sssh! Shut up! I've got something listen.
...from the BBC in London.
The British government... having received
no reply to the ultimatum presented...
to the German government...
has declared war on Nazi Germany.
- That's wonderful! Wonderful!
- It is expected that...
within the next few hours,
France will make a similar declaration.
Poland is no longer alone.
My God!
It's great, great,
wonderful, wonderful!
- Mama, that was a great dinner.
- Yes, it certainly was.
Well when there's something to celebrate,
you've got to make an effort.
Here's to Great Britain and France!
I told you. Didn't I tell you?
All will be well.
Hey!
Five thousand and three.
Is that all?
Yes, five thousand and three zlotys,
that's all we've got left.
It's three thousand and three
zlotys too much. Look...
"Re: Further restrictions
regarding liquid assets.
Jews will be allowed to keep a maximum
of two thousand zlotys in their homes."
- What do we do with the rest?
- Deposit it in a bank. A blocked account.
Banks?! Who'd be stupid enough
to deposit money in a German bank?
We could hide the money. Look here. We can
hide the money under the flower pot.
No, no, no. I'll tell you what we'll do.
We'll use try and tested methods.
You know what we did in the last war?
We made a hole in the table leg...
And we hid the money in there.
- And suppose they take the table away?
- What do you mean take the table away?
The Germans go into Jewish homes
and they just take what they want...
furniture, valuables, anything.
- Do they?
- Idiot! What would they want with a table.
Hey? A table like this?
- What on earth are you doing?
- No, listen, look.
This is the best place for it.
No-one would think of looking
under the flowerpot.
No, no. No, no.
Listen, listen, I've been thinking...
Really? That's a change.
- You know what we do? We use psychology.
- We use what?
We leave the money
and the watch on the table...
and we cover it like this. In full view.
Are you stupid?
The Germans will search high and low,
I promise you, they'll never notice.
That's the stupidest thing I've ever seen.
Of course they'll notice it. Look.
Look here... Idiot.
And you call me stupid.
No, that is very good
because that is the last place...
- This would take hours.
- We are not in a hurry. We'd get it back.
- It won't take hours.
- How will you get them out? Tell me that!
Tell me that, I would like to know.
How would you get them out?
- Why do you resist?
- Quiet! Order, please!
- You take each one out individually.
- Order please!
No-one listens to me, no one listens.
Quiet, please, quiet!
Order, order, please!
- She's a lawyer, she likes order.
- Listen, just listen. Look,
the watch we put under the flowerpots
and the money we stuff in the violin.
Um...
- Will I still be able to play?
- Well, you'll find out.
- Jurek? It's Wladek Szpilman.
- Wladek, how are you?
Fine, fine, we're fine, thank you.
And you?
Fine, we're fine under the circumstances.
But I guess what you've called about.
There's nothing we can do.
They won't re-open the station.
Just won't re-open the station.
Yes, I know, but um, Jurek...
Not even music, nothing,
no radios for the Poles.
I know, Jurek!
But I'm sure you'll find work.
A pianist like you Wladek!
Well, maybe, maybe not, but um...
listen, don't be offended, but I didn't
call to discuss my future career.
I nagged Jurek for weeks and weeks,
and at last he gave in and said...
"All right, come with me tomorrow",
And so I came and...
they bombed the station.
I tell you, meeting you like that
was absolutely wonderful.
- Really?
- Yes, it was... It was unforgettable.
I've always loved your playing,
Mr. Szpilman.
Call me Wladek, please.
- No-one plays Chopin like you.
- I hope that's a compliment.
- Of course, I mean it.
- I was... trying to be funny.
Shall we go to the Paradiso,
have a coffee?
I'd like that.
- And you, what do you do?
- I finished with the conservatoire.
- You're a musician?
- Yes. But only just.
- What instrument?
- The cello.
I love to see a women playing the cello.
Here we are.
NO JEWS
This is disgraceful. How dare they?
You know what people are like,
they want to be better Nazis than Hitler.
- I'm going in there to complain.
- No. It's better not, believe me.
- It's so humiliating. Someone like you!
- Good-bye!
We'll find somewhere else.
- We can walk in the park.
- No, we can't.
It's an official decree.
No Jews allowed in the park.
- My God. Are you joking?
- I'm not joking, it's true.
I suggest we just sit on a bench somewhere
but that's another official decree,
"no Jews allowed on public benches".
This is absurd!
I'll tell you what we can do.
We can just stand here and talk.
I think we're allowed to do that,
don't you?
So, you play the cello Dorota.
That's nice.
And who's your favorite composer?
Chopin? Really? Well...
you'll have to learn to play
his cello sonata, won't you?
And what about you, Wladek? Well...
Perhaps I could accompany you.
Me on the piano, you on the cello.
Mr. Szpilman, you're quite,
quite wonderful.
Call me Wladek, please.
"Re: Emblems for Jews
in the Warsaw district."
I hereby order that all Jews
in the Warsaw district...
will wear visible emblems
when out of doors.
This decree will come into force
on the 1st of December, 1939...
and applies to all Jews
over 12 years of age.
The emblem will be worn
on the right sleeve...
and will represent a blue star
of David on a white background.
The background must
be sufficiently large...
for the star to measure eight
centimeters from point to point.
The width of the arms of the star
must be one centimeter.
The Jews that do not respect this
decree will be severely punished.
"Governor of Warsaw district,
Dr. Fischer."
I won't wear it.
I'm not going to be branded.
Let, let me see this.
Does it say that we have to provide
these armbands ourselves?
- Where will we get them?
- We're not going to get them.
We're not going to wear them!
You!
Come here.
Why didn't you bow?
I beg your pardon.
You're forbidden to walk on the pavement.
Walk in the gutter!
- Have you seen this?
- What, what, what? I'm working. What?
What is it?
- That's where they're going to put us.
- What do you mean, put us?
"By order of the governor of the
Warsaw district, Dr. Fischer...
concerning the establishment of
the Jewish district in Warsaw.
There will be created a Jewish district
in which all Jews living in Warsaw
or moving to Warsaw will have to reside."
Look here. "Jews living outside
of the prescribed area"
will have to move to the Jewish
district by 31st of October, 1940."
They won't get all of us. It's too small.
There's 400 thousand of us in Warsaw.
No, 360 thousand. So it will be easy.
What am I supposed to do? You tell me.
You're a clever man,
you'll tell me what I will buy.
I do my best.
Mama?
Mama, what is it?
20 zlotys!
That's all we have left, 20 zlotys.
What, what can I buy with 20 zlotys?
I am sick of cooking potatoes,
potatoes, potatoes.
That's the price.
That's what I'm offering.
My advice is to accept.
You won't get more from anyone else.
- But, it's a Bechstein, Mr. Lipa!
- Two thousand. My advice is to take it.
What are you going to do when
you're hungry? Eat the piano?
- Get out!
- Hey! What's the matter with you?
- Stop it!
- We'd rather give it away. Go on, get out!
Haven't you eaten today?
What you suffering from?
You people are crazy.
I'm doing you a favor. Two thousand
and I'm paying for the removal.
I'm not even charging for the removal!
You haven't eaten today. You're crazy.
Take it.
Hello.
Hello. Hi.
I didn't want to come.
I didn't want to see all this, but...
I couldn't stop myself.
- How are you doing?
- Fine.
Good.
No, not really. They arrested my cousin.
Jurek says they'll let him out.
- This is disgraceful.
- It won't last long. Don't worry.
That's what I said myself.
It's too absurd.
I... I should go.
Well, I'll, I'll see you...
Soon.
Good-bye.
Well...
to tell you the truth,
I thought it would be worse.
- Where will we sleep?
- I sleep in the kitchen with the girls.
You, Henryk and papa, in here.
Look.
Come and look.
Go away. Go away! Go away!
Papa! Papa! Papa!
- Sell anything?
- Just one. Dostoievski, The Idiot.
- Three zlotys.
- It's better than yesterday.
Three lousy zlotys. And there are
people there making millions.
- I know.
- You don't know, believe me.
They bribe the guards,
the guards turn a blind eye.
They're bringing in cartloads of food,
tobacco, liquor, French cosmetics.
And the poor are dying all around
and they don't give a damn.
Excuse me, have you seen
my husband, Izaak Szerman?
A tall, a tall handsome man,
with a little gray beard... No?
- I'm afraid not.
- Excuse me. Good-bye.
Sleep well. But, but, but if you see him,
write to me, yes?
Izaak Szerman.
Why do we have to have a gentile
street running through our area?
Why can't they go around?
Don't worry about it. They're about
to build a bridge. Haven't you heard?
A bridge, a bridge a smedge.
The Germans claim to be intelligent.
But do you know what I think?
I think they are totally stupid.
I have a family to feed.
I spend half of my time here
waiting for them to let us through.
Maybe they think I come
here to listen to the music?
You're cold?
Dance!
- Dance!
Come on, come on! Dance!
Faster!
Good, they're here.
Yitzchak Heller's been waiting for you.
- What's this about?
- Sit down, have tea.
I'll start lunch
when the girls get here.
- So, what are you doing here?
- He brought cakes.
His... his father's back
in the jewelery business.
He's, doing well, hey, Yitzchak, hey?
Amazing, jewelery.
- We're recruiting.
- Who is recruiting?
Don't be clever with me, Henryk.
I'm coming as a friend.
They're bringing Jews
in from all over the country.
Soon there will be half million
people in the ghetto.
- We need more Jewish police.
- More Jewish police!
You mean you want me to beat up Jews with
my truncheon and catch the Gestapo spirit.
- I see!
- Someone's got to do it, Henryk.
But why me?
I thought you only recruited
boys with rich fathers.
Look at my father, look at us, I mean.
Yes, I'm looking at you,
that's why I'm here.
Your whole family can have a better life.
You want to go on struggling for survival,
selling books on the street?
Yes, please.
I'm doing you people a favor.
What about you, Wladek?
You're a great pianist.
And we've got an excellent
police jazz band.
They'd welcome you with open arms.
Join us!
- You've got no work.
- Thank you, I've got work.
Yes of course!
I'm sorry, Wladek, he wants you to stop.
Who wants me to stop?
I always say,
look on the bright side.
You're in a small ghetto with
intellectuals, professional people.
You're better off than us.
Here in the large ghetto it's a cesspool.
Jehuda, give me something to do.
You're an artist, Wladek. You keep
peoples' spirits up. You do enough.
- I want to help, I want to do something.
- You're too well known, Wladek.
And you know what? You musicians
don't make good conspirators.
You're too... too... musical.
- Who is that?
- Symche.
Majorek.
There are notices going up.
City is to be cleansed of undesirables.
- No notices going up.
- Hello, Symche.
Dolek... Mrs. Zyskind.
Jehuda, working hard?
Majorek. This is the greatest pianist
in Poland. Maybe the whole world.
Wladyslaw Szpilman, meet Majorek.
- How do you do?
- I know your name.
- I've never heard you play.
- Majorek used to be in the Army.
Brilliant man. The only thing I've got
against him is he's not a socialist.
You better go now, Wladek.
It's nearly curfew.
You know how many copies
we print of our newspaper?
Five hundred.
You know how many people on
average read one copy? Twenty.
That makes ten thousand readers.
These will start the uprising.
Majorek hides them in his underpants
and leaves them in toilets.
- Toilets?
- As many toilets as I can find.
Germans never use Jewish toilets.
They're too clean for them.
Please, Mister, please, one zloty.
Hold it!
You little bastard!
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it!
Come on, come on, come on.
Come on boy.
Stand up. Stand up. Stand up!
Please, tonight for once, I don't
want anything bad talked about.
- Enjoy our meal.
- Fine, then I'll tell you something funny.
You all know who I mean by Dr. Raszeja?
- The surgeon.
Well, for some reason,
don't ask me why,
the Germans allowed him into
the ghetto to perform an operation.
On a Jew? They let a Pole
to come in to operate on a Jew?
He got a pass, that's all I know.
Anyway, so he...
he puts the patient to sleep
and starts the operation.
He'd just made the first incision
when the SS burst in...
shoot the patient lying on the table,
then Dr. Raszeja and everybody
else who was there.
Isn't that a laugh?
The patient didn't feel a thing,
he was anesthetized.
I said nothing bad, Henryk.
What's the matter with you all?
You lost your sense of humor?
It's not funny.
Well, you know what's funny?
You're funny, with that ridiculous tie.
What are you talking about my tie for?
What's my tie have to do with anything?
- I need this tie for my work.
- Your work?
- Yes, that's right, I work.
- Yes, yes, your work.
Playing the piano for all
the parasites in the ghetto.
- Parasites?
- Parasites.
Boys. Boys!
They don't give a damn
about people's sufferings.
And you blame me for their apathy, right?
I do because I see it every day.
They don't even notice
what's going around them.
- I blame the Americans.
- For what? For my tie?
The American Jews,
and there are lots of them.
What have they done for us, hey?
What do they think they're doing?
People here are dying.
Haven't got a bite to eat.
The Jewish bankers over there
should be persuading America
to declare war on Germany.
Lights! Lights!
Stand up!
You, stand up! Come on!
Throw him out!
Shhh. Shhh. Be quiet, Mama,
for God's sake, shhh, be quiet.
My God!
Matches! Matches!
- Excuse me!
- Yes!
- I'm Mr. Szpilman's sister.
- Yes, come in. Not you!
- What's happened?
- My God, it's terrible.
- What?
- They're hunting people in the streets.
They've taken Henryk.
All right, go home, alright?
Go home, I'll take care of it.
Excuse me. Have you seen
my husband? Izaak Szerman?
- No, I'm afraid not.
- Tall, handsome, a little gray beard.
If you see him, write to me.
Don't forget. Izaak Szerman.
Faster, keep moving! Run!
What happened here?
They've got my grandson in there.
They pick them up, they take them away.
What they do to them,
I've stopped believing in God.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Yitzchak?
Yitzchak? Yitzchak, here,
it's Wladek Szpilman!
Here!
- Henryk's in there.
- I haven't seen him.
- Believe me. They picked him up.
- Tough luck!
Can you help?
Now you need me, yes, now you need me!
Can you help us?
- It costs.
- I have no money.
Then there's nothing I can do.
You should've joined us
when you had the chance.
- Yitzchak they told me you had influence.
- Who told you?
People, people I know.
They said you're an important man.
Yitzchak!
- Who is this?
- Good morning Herr Rubinstein.
Good morning.
Kaputt. Kaputt.
- Want a cigarette?
- Cigarette?
Thank you.
Help! Help! Help! Help! A snatcher!
A snatcher! Help, help me!
- Why did they pick you up?
- So you go to Yitzchak Heller?
- Did I ask you to talk to him?
- You're out, aren't you?
Did you beg, did you grovel to
that piece of shit, that cockroach?
I didn't grovel, I asked him to help you.
What did you pay him?
With what, with what could I pay him?
With what?
Every zloty I earn we spend on food.
- I can look after myself.
- They were taking you away.
It's got nothing to do with you.
It's me they wanted, not you.
Why do you have to interfere
with other people's business?
You're mad. That's,
that's your trouble, is your mad.
That's also my business.
Hey, hey! What's the matter?
What's the matter? Are you sick?
Hungry.
Mr. Szpilman!
Employment certificate? What's that
mean, no employment certificate?
You have to have an
employment certificate...
to work for one of the German firms
in the ghetto, otherwise...
- Otherwise what?
- You'll be deported.
- So the rumors were true.
- They're going to resettle us...
and send us to labor camps, in the East.
- And they're closing the small ghetto.
- My God!
Wladek? Wladek?
I thought you'd be off on tour playing
London, Paris, New York, Chicago.
- Not this week.
- You look terrible.
Have you heard the rumors?
They're going to resettle us in the East.
Rumors! You take it all too much
to heart Wladek. What's the trouble?
I, I've been trying to get the
certificate of employment for my father.
But I managed to get one for me
and the rest of my family,
but I need another one for my father.
- I've been to all the firms and shops...
- Why didn't you come to me?
I didn't know you were
in the certificate business.
I'm not, but Majorek is.
Can you help? I have no money.
Please, don't insult us.
Can you do something for him?
Be at the Schultz workshop tomorrow,
four o'clock.
You see what a wonderful piece
of luck you've had today?
That's the historical imperative
in action! That's why I always say:
- Look on the bright side!
- The bright side, yes, I know.
- How's your back?
- Better.
Better?
Better not ask!
- Thank you.
- My pleasure. Won't help you anyway.
Thank you, Mr. Schultz.
Well, at least we got work in the ghetto.
Hey?
At least we are still together.
All out! Into the yard!
We're all employed.
We've got work permits.
Wait.
Here.
Go over there. Hurry.
You.
You. You.
The rest of you,
get dressed and report back here!
Bring your belongings, only 15 kilos!
Where are you taking us?
I'm sorry, I did my best.
I thought the certificates would save us.
Stop it, Wladek.
Let's just hope that Henryk
and Halina will be better off.
Move on!
Come on, come on!
- Where will we be going?
- You're going to work.
You'll be much better off than
in the stinking ghetto. Move.
Why did I do it?
Why did I do it? Why did I do it?
I beg you,
don't you have a drop of water?
Don't you have a drop of water?
He's dying.
My child is dying of thirst.
- I beg you. I beg you.
- I'm sorry.
Don't you have a drop of water?
I beg you.
Did you hear what I'm saying?
- I'm telling you, it's a disgrace.
- I can hear you.
We're letting them take us
to our death like sheep to the slaughter.
- Not so loud.
- Why don't we attack them?
There's half a million of us here.
We can break out of the ghetto.
At least we can die honorably,
not as a stain on the face of history.
Why are you so sure they're
sending us to our death?
I'm not sure. You know why I'm not sure?
Because they didn't tell me.
But I'm telling you,
they're going to wipe us all out.
Dr. Ehrlich, what do you want me to do?
Do you want me to fight?
To fight, you need organization,
plans, guns.
He's right. What do you think I
can do? Fight them with my violin bow?
The Germans would never squander
a huge labor force like this.
They're sending us to a labor camp,
it's obvious.
Sure.
Look at that cripple there,
look at the old people, the children.
They're gonna work?
Look at you! Well, you're going to carry
iron girders on your back?
Henryk! Halina, Henryk!
Halina! Henryk!
My God!
We heard you were here.
we wanted to be with you!
We wanted to be with you!
Stupid. Stupid.
Why did I do it?
She's getting on my nerves.
- What did she do, for God's sake?
- She smothered her baby.
They prepared a hiding place
and of course they went there.
But the baby cried
just as the police came.
She smothered the cries with
her hands, the baby died.
A policeman heard the death rattle
and found where they were hiding.
What are you reading?
"If you prick us, do we not bleed?
If you tickle us, do we not laugh?
If you poison us, do we not die?
And, if you wrong us,
shall we not revenge?"
- Very appropriate.
- Yes. That's why I brought it.
Idiot. What's he think he's
gonna do with the money?
Hey boy, come here.
Come here.
- How much for a caramel?
- Twenty zlotys.
What? For one caramel? What do you think
you're gonna do with the money?
Twenty zlotys.
We've got 20 between us.
I've got ten, I think.
Five, ten, twenty.
Why did I do it?
Why did I do it? Why did I do it?
- Halina?
- What?
- It's a funny time to say this, but...
I wish I knew you better.
Thank you.
Szpilman? Szpilman!
Fuck off stupid! Go!
Papa? Papa?
Papa? Mama? Halina?
Halina? Mama?
What do you think you're doing Szpilman?
I've saved your life. Get out just go! Go!
Don't run!
Mama! Mama! Mama!
Well, off they go to the melting pot.
What are you doing? She's pregnant!
Wladek?
Why are you here, Wladek?
It's like this, I, I...
We...
All of them, all of them.
All of them.
Perhaps they're lucky.
The quicker, the better.
It's not finished yet.
We'll stay here for a couple of days,
until things die down.
I've bribed a policeman,
he'll come when it's over.
My God, I haven't been outside in,
it must be two years.
Don't get overexcited.
It's gold. Very good price.
Someone you know?
A beauty. Who is she?
She's a singer. I knew her well actually.
Her husband's an actor.
They're good people.
I'd like to talk to her.
Don't forget, Wladek.
They hang them for helping Jews.
- Stop!
- Halt!
How long have you been here?
Since last night.
I was pleased to see you.
They're going to start
the final resettlement now.
We know what it means.
We sent someone out.
Zygmunt, a good man.
His orders were to follow
the trains out of Warsaw.
He got to Sokolow.
A local railway man told
him the tracks divided,
one branch leading to Treblinka.
He said everyday freight trains
carrying people from Warsaw...
branched off to Treblinka
and returned empty.
No transports of food
are ever seen on that line.
And civilians are forbidden
to approach the Treblinka station.
They're exterminating us.
It won't take them long.
We're 60 thousand left,
out of half a million.
Mostly young people.
And this time we're gonna fight.
We're in good shape.
Organized. We're prepared.
If you need help, I...
You! Come here!
Shit!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I, I don't know what I was thinking.
Get him away from here.
I hope you play the piano better
than you carry bricks.
He won't last long
if he goes on like this.
I'll see if I can get him
something better.
Trouble.
Assemble! Fall in!
Round up! Only the Jews.
Poles go on working.
Only the Jews!
I have good news for you.
There are rumors going around
that we like to...
umsiedeln... Resettle you.
I promise you that now
and in the future...
nothing else is planned.
Ja? For this reason, we put
information posters on the wall.
To show you our goodwill...
you should vote one of you
to be allowed...
to go in town daily...
and bring three kilos
of Kartoffeln potatoes, ja?
And one loaf of bread
for each of your workers.
So, why should we do something else
like this if we would resettle you?
You can make good business
out of the things you don't eat.
Isn't that something that you Jews
are good in? Make money?
Carry on.
That one, with the string.
The others, tied by wire.
Now!
Majorek.
I have a favor to ask.
I want to get out of here.
It's easy to get out. It's how you
survive on the other side that's hard.
I know.
Last summer, I worked for a day
in the Zelazna Brama Square.
I saw someone I knew,
she's an old friend.
A singer, her husband's an actor.
I filled their names down
and their address, if they're still there.
Janina Godlewska and Andrzej Bogucki.
They're good people.
Would you try to make contact?
You go to town every day.
Would you just ask them, ask them
if they'd help me get out of here?
Got a plaster?
What are you up to?
What's in that?
We're allowed to take food
into the ghetto.
Three kilos of potato and bread.
Open it.
It's only potatoes and bread.
You're lying. I can smell it.
Open it.
Potatoes!
You Jews are all the same.
Give a Jew your little finger...
and he takes the whole hand.
Lie to me again,
I'll shoot you... personally.
I tried your friends.
- They don't live there anymore.
- Did you make contact?
- Be ready to leave.
- When?
- Soon.
- Halt!
Shit! Shit!
I'll teach you discipline, you dirty pigs!
Know why we're beating you?
No.
Know why we beat you?
- Why?
- To celebrate New Year's Eve.
No, quick march! March!
March and sing!
Sing something cheerful!
Sing it loud and clear!
♪ Hey ranks unite
and follow the white eagle ♪
♪ Stand up and fight
our mortal enemies ♪
♪ Riflemen, hey!
Let's give them fire and brimstone ♪
♪ We'll blow away the yoke of slavery ♪
♪ Punish and rout
the rapists of our nation ♪
♪ We'll smash the knout
to save we our dignity ♪
I'm sorry.
I'm dirty. I'm so filthy.
We haven't much time. Come on.
We must hurry.
Here. See if these fit.
We're going to have to keep moving you.
The Germans are hunting
down indiscriminately now.
Jews, non-Jews, anybody, everybody.
And Wladek, you'd better shave.
Use my razor on the shelf.
You'll be looked after
by Marek Gebczynski.
He's on the other side of town.
You stay there tonight,
then we'll find you somewhere else.
- I'll bring you food.
- Alright, let's go.
I'll show you where
you're going to sleep.
You have to stay here
until tomorrow afternoon.
We have a flat for you near
the ghetto well. But it's safe.
It's not going to be very comfortable.
I'll be fine.
Thank you.
I'll take it. Here. Give it to me.
Go as near to the front as possible,
to the German section.
DO NOT PASS
I'm going to draw the curtains now.
But you leave them open
during the daytime. Don't forget.
Must feel better on
this side of the wall?
Yes.
But sometimes I'm still not sure
which side of the wall I'm on.
Some bread, potatoes, onions.
I'll come again. And Janina Bogucki
will visit twice a week.
Bring more food, see how you are.
Thank you.
This is very important.
In case of emergency...
I mean emergency,
go to this address.
Puppy dog, what do you mean you forgot?
What do you think I mean, Kitten?
I forgot, that's what I mean.
You know what, you treat me like dirt.
I treat you
like dirt because you are dirt.
- Pig! Pig!
- Bitch!
- Dirty pig!
- You are a dirty ply!
Takes one to know one. Ply.
You play like an angel, Kitten.
If I play like an angel,
why don't you listen?
I was listening, Kitten.
Liar!
You fell asleep. Ply!
Thank you.
- I wanted to come earlier, but...
- No, no, no, thank you.
No-one thought
they'd hold out so long.
I never should have come out. I should've
stayed there and fought with them.
Wladek, stop that. It's over now.
Just be proud it happened.
- My God, did they put up a fight!
- Yes.
- So did the Germans.
- They're in shock!
They didn't expect it.
Nobody expected it. Jews fighting back?
- Who would have thought?
- What good did it do?
What good?
Wladek, I'm surprised at you.
They died with dignity,
that's what good it did.
And you know something else?
Now the Poles will rise. We're ready.
We'll fight too. You'll see.
Get your things together.
You have to leave.
What? What's happened?
- I'm on the run.
- What's happened?
The Gestapo found our weapons.
They've arrested Janina and Andrzej.
They're bound to find out about this
place too. You must get away at once.
Where do you want me to go?
Look at me, I'm not leaving.
- Can I take my chances here?
- That's your decision.
But when they storm the flat,
throw yourself out the window,
don't let them get you alive.
I have poison on me.
They won't get me alive either.
Open up!
Open this door
at once or we'll call the police!
Are you from this flat?
You're not registered.
It belongs to a friend of mine.
I just came to visit,
but I must have just missed him.
Have you got your identity card?
What?
- Let me see your identity card.
- Yes, of course.
- I want to see your identity card!
- What's happening?
He's a Jew! A Jew!
Stop the Jew!
Don't let him out! Stop him!
- Yes?
- Mr. Gebczynski sent me.
- Wladyslaw Szpilman.
- Dorota.
Come in.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I was given this address
and I'm looking for a Mr. Dzikiewicz.
Michal Dzikiewicz, he's my husband.
Come in.
Sit.
I need help.
He'll be back before curfew.
I've... I've been in hiding.
- I need somewhere to stay.
- He'll be here soon.
- How long have you been married?
- Just over a year.
And... how's Jurek?
Dead.
- And when, when is your baby due?
- Christmas.
This is not a good time to have children,
but then...
This is my husband. Wladyslaw Szpilman.
- Marek Gebczynski sent him.
- Yes, I remember.
Mr. Gebczynski said to contact you
only in case of emergency.
Don't worry now.
We can't move you tonight.
You'll sleep on the sofa.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry, could I,
could I have a piece of bread?
Yes, of course. We'll eat.
Sit. Please, sit.
Thank you.
You're in a very German area.
The building opposite is a hospital
taking in wounded from the Russian front.
And next door is the Schutzpolizei.
Safest place to be.
Right in the heart of the lion's den.
I'll be locking you in.
No-one knows you're here,
so keep as quiet as possible.
All well?
Thank you.
This is Antek Szalas.
He'll be looking after you.
- How do you do?
Thank you.
I've given him a second key. He'll
bring you food, see that you're alright.
He's with the underground,
he's a good man.
- You don't remember me Mr. Szpilman?
- I don't think so.
Warsaw Radio. I was a technician.
I saw you almost every day.
- I'm sorry, I don't remember, I...
- It doesn't matter.
You've nothing to worry about.
I'll visit often.
You'll be pleased to hear that
the Allies are bombing Germany...
night after night, after night.
Cologne, Hamburg, Berlin.
And the Russians are really giving
them hell. It's the beginning of the end.
Let's hope so.
Still alive then?
Here. Sausage, bread.
You still got that vodka?
- How long is this meant to last?
- Not long now.
I think, I think I've got jaundice.
Don't worry about that.
It just makes you look funny.
My grandfather was jilted by
his girlfriend when he got jaundice.
Drink up.
Why didn't you come sooner?
It's been over two weeks.
- I got...
- Problems.
Money.
I've got to raise money to buy the food.
I need things to sell,
it's not easy.
Here. Sell this.
Food's more important than time.
Yes. I meant to tell you!
The Allies have landed in France.
Russians will be here soon.
They'll beat the shit
out of the Germans...
any day now.
Wladek?
I knew it. I knew this would happen.
- I'll get a doctor.
- You can't. It's too dangerous.
- I'll get Dr. Luczak. We can trust him.
- Dorota. Don't be ridiculous,
he's a pediatrician.
- He's still a doctor.
- No.
You stay. I'll go.
We came to say goodbye.
We're going to stay
with my mother in Otwocks.
The baby's already there. It's safer.
There's talk that the uprising
will begin any day now.
That man Szalas should be shot.
He's been collecting money
on your behalf all over Warsaw.
Apparently people gave generously,
so he collected a tidy sum.
My God.
The liver the size of a football.
Acute inflammation of the gall bladder...
but he'll live.
I'll try to get him some levulose,
but it's not easy.
- Can you visit him again?
- Who knows.
- Doctor, thank you.
- Don't speak, rest.
Thank you so much for coming.
We've brought you some food.
I'll prepare something now for you,
then we must go.
Get out, get out,
get out into the streets!
Get out now! The Germans
have surrounded the building!
Somebody... Somebody!
somebody help me!
Heinrich?
What are you doing here?
Who are you?
- Understand?
- Yes.
What are you doing?
I, I was...
trying to open this can.
Do you live here?
Do you work here?
No.
What do you do?
I am...
I was a pianist.
Pianist?
Come on.
Play something.
Are you hiding here?
Jew?
Where are you hiding?
In the attic.
Show me.
Got any food?
Jew!
Excuse me. Please.
What's all that gunfire?
Russians. Across the river.
All you have to do is wait a few weeks.
- What's happening?
- We're leaving.
- Are the Russians here?
- Not yet.
I... I don't know how to thank you.
Thank God, not me.
He wants us to survive.
Well, that's what we have to believe.
Here. Take it.
- And you?
- I've got another...
a warmer one.
What'll you do when it's all over?
I'll play the piano again.
On the Polish radio.
Tell me your name.
I'll listen out for you.
Szpilman.
Good name for a pianist.
German! German!
No! No!
No! Don't shoot! I'm, I'm Polish!
Please! I'm Polish!
I'm...
Come out with your hands up!
Please! I beg of you!
Don't shoot, don't shoot, don't shoot.
I beg you, I'm a Polish, please.
Come down!
Please, I'm Polish! Please... please.
He's Polish.
Yes, he's Polish.
Why the fucking coat?
I'm cold.
Look at them. German fuckers!
Murderers! Murderers!
- Dirty bastards!
- Assassins!
- Bastards!
- Look at you now!
You took everything I had.
Me, a musician.
You took my violin, you took my soul!
Musician?
Yes.
Do you know a pianist named Szpilman?
Polish radio?
Of course I know him.
I helped him when
he was in hiding. Tell him I'm here.
Ask him to help me.
What's your name?
Hosenfeld.
What?
It was here, I'm certain of it.
Well, it's not here now.
I shouted, abuse at them.
I'm not proud of it but that's what I did.
And I'm certain
I stood where you are now.
There was barbed wire,
and this German came up to me.
- You didn't catch his name?
- No.
I'll ask at the factory.
They may know something.