Stay down.
The Bodyguard (1992)
- 25 fps -
Freeze!
Just freeze.
Your hands ever shake, Frank?
Sometimes.
It's just adrenaline.
Of course.
How did you know?
- Saw him washing the car.
- So did I.
They don't wash cars
on parking levels.
Frank, I'd like you to stay on.
I'm no good in a permanent position.
My feet go to sleep.
Rachel!
You're turning down $2000 a week?
You say you won't protect her
because she's in show business?
No celebrities.
- 2500.
- There's many good men for that much.
Have you talked to...
...Racine? Fitzgerald?
- Portman?
- Portman was interested.
But we heard you were the best.
There's no such thing.
We're talking about a frightened lady
with an 8-year-old son.
I wouldn't be here
if this wasn't real.
She begged me to get you.
Please.
Okay, I'll come.
I'll look it over.
If I take it...
...it's 3000 a week.
You must be very deadly
for 3 grand a week.
Watch and see.
Shit!
I know it's something...
Better not stand there.
Frank Farmer to see Miss Marron.
What?
Alexander Graham Bell
to see Miss Marron.
Got an appointment?
The atomic number of zinc is 30.
All right.
Yeah, can I help you?
You the man
on the intercom?
No.
Can I help you?
Name's Edison.
I have an appointment.
That was arranged by...?
Mr. Devaney.
Go ahead, Mr. Edison.
What happened?
A doll.
Henry Ford
for Mr. Devaney.
Henry Ford.
Come in.
Playback.
That's what I want.
Glad you came.
I'll introduce you to Rachel.
I bet you loved it.
- Doesn't know great art.
- Frank Farmer's here.
- Isn't this me?
- It's terrific.
Who's here?
The bodyguard.
Rory should be my bodyguard.
Raise your butt
and come meet him.
All right, I'm up.
Frank Farmer...
...Rachel Marron.
You don't look like a bodyguard.
What'd you expect?
I don't know,
maybe a tough guy.
This is my disguise.
His timing's good.
Nicki, Rachel's sister...
...and secretary.
Nice to meet you.
Tony Scibelli.
Sy Spector, publicist.
Can we get you a drink?
An orange juice.
Straight?
Yeah.
This is Bill's idea,
a sudden obsession with protecting me.
Tony's done my security.
We're just fine.
Bill's right.
It's time you took more precautions.
I'm sure the number of nuts
writing fan letters...
...jumps whenever Rachel's
on a magazine.
- Not like this.
- Relax, guys. Relax!
I said I'll do it, so I will.
See what I'm dealing with?
I'll do it, as long as
we understand each other.
- I won't let this alter my life.
- Honey, that won't be a problem.
This household is informal.
We're on a first-name basis.
You'll fit in fine.
You can choose...
...the alarm system for the house,
improved security for the gate.
What else?
I'm safe when I'm at the house.
The main thing is when I go out.
Tony will fill you in.
Don't fall over me everywhere I go.
Most important:
Fletcher cannot be affected.
We'll tell the boy
you've got another function.
I don't want him to think
he's in prison.
So the estate must not be altered.
- Miss Marron.
- Rachel.
There's been a misunderstanding.
If you'll show me the way out,
I'll save us trouble.
You can go by the pool.
Nice meeting you.
Or the door...
Tony, shut up!
Wait a minute!
We shouldn't beg this guy.
Sy, I'm handling this.
Farmer, would you wait?
I should have told you more.
I'm sorry.
- I thought I'd let you two work it out.
- We did.
She's not a bad person. Whether
she knows it or not, she needs you.
You've come this far. Wait.
I want to show you something.
Please, Farmer!
How are you today?
I'm fine.
How about you?
Do you like boats?
No, I don't like boats.
Why not?
I don't know.
Sure you do.
But you don't want to tell me.
You're a smart kid.
One time I was stuck on a boat
with some people for 4 months.
A lifeboat?
No. It was a big, white yacht.
You're the bodyguard.
What do you know about it?
I've got ears.
I'll remember that.
This is just in the last 6 months.
Ever had these
professionally assessed?
- You were in the Secret Service.
- That's right.
Ever guard the main man?
2 years with Carter,
4 with Reagan.
Reagan got shot.
Not on my shift.
Good.
This could be something.
Do you think it is
the guy who rigged the doll?
Did you tell Miss Marron?
About the doll?
We said there'd been
an electrical problem, a short circuit.
She doesn't need
this kind of worry right now.
What about the police?
No need.
No one got hurt.
The chauffeur did.
That was nothing.
It was just our people there.
I think we should show him the room.
Is this her bedroom?
She sleeps in a room next to Fletcher's.
Sy did this for a magazine.
"Superstars in their boudoirs."
Did you see it?
No.
We found the letter here.
In here?
Someone broke in
and masturbated on the bed.
- She doesn't know?
- You kidding?
It'd really freak her out.
What do you think?
Someone penetrates the house,
jerks off on the bed.
I'd say that qualifies as a problem.
We don't...
What kind of problem?
- The house is wide open.
- Excuse me?
The house is wide open.
You have no clue what security is...
...or how to achieve it.
I'll accommodate your work.
I can't do it like this.
Like what?
Won't be responsible for her safety
if she doesn't know all this.
I'll talk to her.
I'll make her understand.
- She won't give you static, I promise.
- Sure she will.
So what job's perfect?
You're a bodyguard.
It's Oscar time again.
The money's on Rachel Marron
for best actress.
And with the theme song "I Have Nothing"
still big on the charts...
...the versatile actress/singer
might end up having everything.
Why'd you say
you were Edison?
To see how difficult it was to get in.
And it wasn't.
Put it on your arm.
Helps the ache.
You can fill a whole day washing cars
and driving Miss Marron.
That's my job.
We're adding to your duties.
You're my new assistant.
Says who?
I've guarded a lot of people
and I've found one thing to be true.
No matter how incompetent the assassins,
or how much they miss...
...one person always gets hit.
Who?
The cocky black chauffeur.
Put this in the pool.
This gate will be replaced next week.
I'll have 2 cameras here.
A face camera by the call box and
a scene camera on top of this pillar.
I want these trees cut back so
the lights can shine onto the property.
The people who come into the property,
make sure we know who they are.
I want these all cut back.
She paid a lot for the estate,
she ought to be able to see it.
- What're you looking at?
- Frank.
This fence will come around here
and end by the gate.
Come on. Let's go.
Not yet, not yet.
Now brake!
Power...
...and stop.
Come here!
Come here.
That's an unusual tactic
for a guard dog, but it's effective.
You can look around
if you want.
- Sorry to disturb you.
- It's an excuse to rest.
This is my place.
I'm the only one who works out here.
My own ego wall.
No platinum records.
Is this you and Rachel?
When I was a kid,
I put together this band.
We played school dances
and stuff like that.
Rachel joined the act. As you can
imagine, she was quite an entertainer.
Even then she could stop the show.
So I kind of quit.
- Professionally, anyway.
- You never went back?
It was obvious
who the star in our family was.
Lot of work went into this.
A lot of work.
No fingerprints, though.
You think
this is tied to the doll?
Her manager does.
"I have nothing" is a natural,
given the record...
...the movie and all.
I lost track of you
after Washington.
So how's the private stuff?
It's fine.
Big money?
It's big money, right?
You wouldn't want this job.
It's big money! I knew it!
You need an assistant?
I'm due to get out and I have had it
with assholic behavior.
What a scumbag we're covering now!
A walking schlong senator
who shall remain nameless.
- Hellfire Henry Kent.
- Someone wants to pop him.
No surprise, with what
the shithead's been saying.
Yeah, do everyone a favor.
As you know,
we're non-political these days.
I'll send it to Behavioral Sciences.
I'll have an answer in a few days.
Thanks.
Ray, why am I getting
all this cooperation?
- Are you kidding?
- She's a big star.
Important people care about her.
Politics and showbiz,
it's the same thing these days.
There she is.
Can I have your autograph?
Sure you can.
Can we get a photo?
You're her favorite actress.
We've seen all your movies.
Take a good one.
Thank you so much.
She'll appreciate it.
I'm surprised
you didn't plug them.
Help me with this stuff. You sign
"Much love, Rachel" and you sign...
Let me set you straight
on a few things.
For starters, I love this lady.
What I do for her, I do out of love.
I'm not some hired gun
who's here to make her life miserable.
I do things the way she likes.
Her happiness...
...is everything to me.
No problem. I'd like
to know how you handle things.
I handle things fine.
You watch me and you'll learn.
Turn right here.
Is that him?
What's going on?
Short cut.
Want me to do a 180?
No, I want you to slow down.
Go to the house!
Shut up!
Just shut up!
He's through
messing with my life.
I'm getting sick of running up here
every time he steps on your toes.
Farmer, would you come in here?
- He's nuts!
- Guess who couldn't get in yesterday?
Robin Leach.
He speaks to 20 million people
and he can't get in!
With an appointment?
What about brunch at Charlie's?
Rachel goes every Sunday.
She can't do
what she's always done.
"Can't do what she's always done."
He's a fanatic!
Like the guys
he's protecting you from.
Excuse me if I don't faint.
Then think about your son.
What do you want?
I want some peace around here!
We're almost done.
I want to eat brunch
with my friends.
Go on Tuesdays.
Tuesday brunch.
Where'd you get him, Bill?
Louise, you have great stuff.
Take it all, darling.
Yeah, I'll try this on.
Want to come in with me?
Just to be safe?
You probably won't believe this...
...but I have a reputation
for being a bitch.
I didn't used to be.
Get known for being a certain way,
a way people think you are...
...and soon, you get like that.
Guess you can't help it.
You don't think so?
You're an expert on the famous?
- I've seen a few.
- And you disagree?
You can be
as you choose to be.
Takes discipline,
but it can be done.
Is that why you never stay
with your clients?
They too undisciplined for you?
- Or maybe you start caring about them?
- Right.
Can't you answer straight once?
You're too clever for me.
I can't keep up.
Look at me!
You don't approve of me.
Disapproval's a luxury I can't afford.
Don't like your emotions getting to you?
Never mix business with pleasure?
Right.
Will you grab that red jacket?
I'm here to keep you alive,
not help you shop.
Thanks.
- 2 minutes.
- 3, 4.
Wait.
I want to make it really full.
What?
Straight up.
Right there.
Hold it.
Hold it still.
What am I looking for?
Bomb.
Don't worry,
I already checked.
Put it back here a little deeper.
Hold it.
Now turn it. Good.
Now right there.
Wait, pull up there for a second.
Son of a bitch!
I thought it was dinner.
- Are we going somewhere else?
- The Mayan.
- What's that?
- It's a club. Let's go.
- You got to tell me about these things.
- I just did.
Nice suit, Frank.
I want you to keep this.
It's beautiful.
It has a radio transmitter.
The clasp sends a signal.
If there's ever a problem, press it.
I'll know you need me.
Okay, she knows how it works.
Let's go.
Come on, let's go.
Look at this!
Look at this, Rachel.
They don't forget.
Get inside. The show's inside.
Henry, just keep driving.
He's from Paris,
an amazing director.
This is his first video.
Rachel loves it.
This is Sy's idea.
- I honestly thought...
- You said I had an exclusive.
Maybe later. What can I say?
Laurie, how are you?
- You know Paul.
- I know who she is.
She doesn't do these places.
He wants it for the video.
He sent another one.
What do you mean "another one"?
What do you mean?
- They didn't tell you.
- What?
There were some letters before.
Same kind of threats.
We didn't want to worry you.
And somebody got into the house.
In my house?
Let's not get hysterical.
Wait!
While Fletcher was there?!
The house is like Fort Knox.
- Right?
- We should go.
No one could...
No one could what?!
Everyone calm down.
Let's just see how she is.
How are you, honey?
"Watch the door"
means no candy, no flowers.
Is he out there?
- He's here, isn't he?
- Maybe.
We don't know that.
You know he was in my house!
Let's go home. We'll have
to make an announcement.
Fine, Bill, you make it!
You tell them!
They'll tear the place apart!
Ladies and gentlemen...
...I'm sorry, but due to...
...circumstances beyond our control...
Wait!
Don't do it.
It's not worth it.
No fucking freak
will run me off stage.
Get it cued up front.
Let's go.
We're on.
We're not coming.
Rachel will not be able
to appear tonight.
Just a minute.
Give me a chance.
Bill Devaney, everybody!
Hello!
Just wanted to stop by
and maybe sing a song.
I hope you don't mind, do you?
All right, thank you so much!
Isn't Billy Thomas the greatest?
Let's give him a hand.
Go for it, Rachel.
Want to see my new video?
Are we having a communication problem?
A communication problem?
I mean...
Excuse me.
I need to keep this aisle clear.
I know what you're saying.
You've got a job to do.
But understand that Rachel does too.
And that's what she's doing.
Out there.
She's so hot now.
This is her time.
If she doesn't get out there...
...she's dead.
Forget the crazy death threats,
if she doesn't sing...
...she's dead anyway.
Handled properly, this thing could be
worth a million in free publicity.
One word!
One word about this in print...!
Come on!
Out of the way!
I'll get it.
Follow me!
Where's the fucking limo?
Go!
Henry!
It's me, Sy!
Stop it!
Fuck!
Keep driving, Henry.
Never done that before.
It's been a long night.
Don't you want to know
why I behave that way?
I know why.
I don't want to talk about this again.
Got you, didn't I?
Bet you wonder what I'm doing.
Didn't know I jog, did you?
Afraid I'll get picked off
in my snazzy suit?
No. I'm afraid
that I'll have to jog with you.
Will you walk with me?
I know this is kind of late...
...but thank you.
I'm glad you're here.
And I'm going to try to cooperate.
That would be good.
Farmer, I have this problem.
This minor little problem.
I'd like to go out
for an evening.
With a guy. Like a date.
But, I can't go out on a date...
...because you have to be with me
every minute.
What if he wants to invite me up
to his place? Will you come too?
So...
...the only thing I can figure...
...is for you to take me out.
That's what I was wondering.
You know?
I mean, what do you think?
Only if you want to.
God, this is so embarrassing.
You decide, okay?
Sandy Harris is on the phone.
Tell her I'll call her back.
I'm getting fixed up here.
He didn't look like
he wanted to die.
There's a big difference between
wanting to die and not fearing death.
And so because he had no fear,
he was invincible?
What do you think?
He sure creamed them all in the end.
Yeah, it was a good movie.
How many times have you seen it?
62 times, I think.
- I've seen it a lot.
- You can say that!
Your kind of place?
Your kind of music?
Absolutely.
You figure no one can get by you here.
If someone's willing to swap his life
for a kill, nothing can stop him.
Great!
What do I need you for?
He might get me instead.
You're ready to die for me?
It's the job.
And you do it?
Why?
I can't sing.
Maybe there is some glory in saving
a president, but just anybody?
Like you?
Yeah, like me.
It's a matter of discipline.
I don't trust discipline.
I know at that crucial moment
I'd cop out.
It happens.
But not to you, fierce Frank.
Have you ever liked anybody?
What do you mean?
Like me, a girl?
Yeah, a long time ago.
What happened?
Do you mind if I ask?
Mind if I don't answer?
I don't want to pry.
Oh, yeah!
I can see that.
What?
She didn't die, did she?
While you were protecting her
she got killed, right?
God! That's not it, is it?
That's it, isn't it?
Nobody's perfect.
I'm sorry, Frank.
I'm sorry.
No.
Nice try, though.
It was less dramatic than that.
She didn't love me anymore.
Can you imagine that?
No, not really.
So...
...is this a full-service date, Frank?
I'm just asking you to dance.
Come on.
You can dance, can't you?
This is kind of a cowboy song?
Nothing.
It's nothing.
It's so depressing.
Have you ever listened to the words?
- It is kind of depressing.
- Yes, it is.
It's one of those somebody's-always
- leaving-somebody songs.
Don't worry.
I'll protect you.
It's very quiet here.
You ever going to hang these up?
Maybe when I'm here long enough.
"West Virginia University Football."
Take a look at you.
- What'd you play?
- End.
Were you tough?
No, I was fast.
You were in the Secret Service?
What made you get out?
Money.
Yeah, I can see
your tastes are extravagant.
May I?
Yeah.
Be careful.
You're a hard one to figure out.
A bodyguard must know
very little peace.
Watch this.
I've never felt this safe before.
No one could get by you.
Right now might not be too difficult.
What are you doing?
I don't want to get confused
about what I'm doing here.
I'm not confused.
You pay me to protect you.
That's what I do.
Did I do something wrong?
Nothing.
Then what is it?
Do you want me to beg?
What's going on, Frank?
I want to keep straight what my job is.
What is that, exactly?
Making me feel like shit?
I'm sorry, it's my fault.
Don't apologize. Just tell me
what I did. I'm a big girl.
You didn't do anything.
It was me.
I got involved with my client.
Your client?!
I made a mistake.
You're not attracted
to your client anymore?
Christ, I told you why!
I can't protect you like this.
So that's it for me?
That's it?
Yeah.
I don't believe it!
Live with it, or fire me.
But I can't fuck you.
She's real mad at you, isn't she?
She doesn't know why
you're being so shitty to her.
I don't like you using that language.
I learned not to react to things
like other people do.
That's my job.
It doesn't always work.
Doesn't always work.
I don't think I understand.
I'm old compared to you
and I don't understand either.
I'm starting to get the feeling...
...that I never will.
Thought you'd like to know.
Everyone said she was a sure thing.
But you already knew that.
I am sorry. It was out of line,
none of my business.
It's off to Miami today for Best
Actress nominee Rachel Marron.
She'll give 2 AIDS charity concerts
at the Fontainebleau Hilton.
$1000 a plate, no less.
And it's a brave man who'd deny
she's worth every cent.
This is mobile 1 to station 2.
Zero 2, engineering.
Have them do a 14 reference
to presidential suite balcony.
It's okay. They're cleared.
Mobile 2 to Catering.
Security says to clear kitchen aisle...
...of all obstructions and traffic,
effective immediately.
Mobile 2 to house.
Security wants updated list
of all concert ticket holders.
Fax any names which are added
to the list to Security Office.
What a silly job this is!
Okay, we're rolling!
- Showtime, everybody!
- Is this necessary?
Yes, it is.
Let's go.
Quit bitching!
This is the part you do get paid for.
Can you give us
a couple of minutes?
- How do you like our city?
- I love it! I love Miami!
Do you arrange all this?
That's me!
Hello, Frank.
Portman.
It's been a long time.
You working?
Not technically, but the governor
may come so I thought...
...I'd give a light check.
Someone else is covering him now.
How old's she?
Maybe 18.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Listen, you're so right.
I want you to have a good time...
...and drink as much of Ben Schiller's
liquor as possible. Thank you.
I'd call that a step up
from the President.
Probably sings better too.
Handful.
Lost track of you
after the Reagan thing.
Yeah.
Wasn't your fault.
You weren't even there.
I need a drink.
It's orange juice!
Who are you?
Greg Portman.
I take it you've met my bodyguard.
We used to work together.
What do you do now?
Same thing as Farmer.
2 samurai, huh?
Are you working now?
Not right now.
Good.
Because I'm the only person
in this room that needs protection.
Come on, let's get a drink.
A real one.
Orange juice, sir?
I've been watching you all
night from across the room.
Why don't you keep watching?
No, I'm not doing this.
You are.
Please go now.
Not right now.
Mr. Portman was just leaving us.
Good night, Rachel.
Shit!
What are you looking at?
Probably never had a heavy night
in your whole disciplined life.
Coffee?
Farmer, you're
a self-righteous son of a bitch.
Don't you dare judge me!
I didn't tell you
to fuck everyone in the hotel!
Fuck this.
I don't need this shit.
Industrial detergent
matches the traces...
...in the glue.
We'll nail this sucker.
Don't take too long.
It's good money, isn't it?
It's good money.
- Where is she?
- I don't know.
- Where's Tony?
- I thought you were with her.
Thuringer, this is Farmer.
Where's your man at the door?
The door to the suite!
Where is he?
Get someone up here now!
He doesn't know.
Where are you going?
Rachel, where have you been?
I went to Bal Harbor to shop.
- Want these in the bedroom?
- Leave them so I can look at them.
You had us worried.
You're not supposed to do that.
I'll do what I want when I want.
Besides...
...I'm tired
of hanging around deadbeats.
No offense, Tony.
Once more
and I'm gone.
You remember something:
You work for me!
Where're you going?
To check the route, as usual.
Did Fletcher call?
Gomez!
- What are you doing?
- None of your fucking business.
Move it!
Stick it up your ass!
Don't hurt my husband, mister!
Please, don't hurt him.
He not up to nothing.
I'm sorry.
- Hello.
- Mommy?
Fletcher, is that you?
No.
Listen.
I'm through, Bill.
I'll get you back to L.A.
And that's it.
Fletcher's guard will cover you.
She got a call.
- I don't care.
- It was him. Same guy!
It really shook her up!
She thought it was Fletcher calling.
I know she'll be reasonable now.
Save it, Devaney!
My clients don't have to be convinced
to save their own lives!
Call me when she's ready.
Nothing that's happened between us
matters.
I understand now.
You'll have to believe me
because I won't beg.
It wasn't what he said...
...it was the way he said it.
Frank, I need you.
I'm afraid!
And I hate my fear.
Please protect me.
Protect Fletcher.
If anything happened to him...
I can't.
I can't protect you like this.
It's impossible.
The odds are on his side.
I will do whatever you say.
I'd want to take you
away from here for a while.
I can do that.
It'd mean canceling your concerts.
All right.
No more Sy.
Give Devaney and Tony a vacation.
Okay.
You cross me up this time,
I swear I'll kill you myself.
Lake's low.
It'll rise when it thaws.
They all in trouble?
Just one.
He likes you.
Is that protecting us?
Yeah, he's a trained noisemaker.
Come here, Foster.
Just what we need.
I don't like big dogs.
They don't know who they're eating.
And this one does?
Yeah, this one does.
Excuse me.
Katherine had this place
organized the way she liked.
That's Frank's mama.
Fletcher can't swim very well.
He better stay in the boat, then.
So you're a singer.
Yeah, that's right.
We're kind of out of things up here.
I'm sorry.
That's okay.
You must be very successful
if you need Frank.
It's quiet here.
Frank spent 6 months here
after that Reagan thing.
Reagan thing?
Frank was gone when Reagan was shot.
He never got over it.
That's...
...the day we buried Katherine.
He's a real rascal now.
You tell us.
I never hit him ever.
That's unusual for my people.
So what happens,
he's 10 years old...
...and he starts complaining to me.
How about that?
I'll tell them
about you stripping in court.
I want to hear this.
I don't mind.
I'm proud of that!
Anyway, he starts playing
tackle football...
...and one day he says to me
he's afraid of being hit.
Says it's my fault.
"How come you never hit me?"
How about that?
He got over it, turned into
one hell of a wide receiver.
He was always like that.
Couldn't stand being afraid.
Something scared him, he'd keep
doing it until the fear went away.
His mama was the same way.
You have a beautiful family.
- Had enough to eat?
- Wipe your mouth.
- You through?
- Save some for dessert.
I won't tell them about when you were 13
and discovered girls.
Come on, Frank.
You can run but you can't hide.
I'm black, right?
You know you're white.
Your move!
It's my move?
You're sure?
The last move,
I took your rook.
That's right.
How long has this been going on?
3 years.
First year
he had me on the run.
What do you think?
Knight to king-4.
City kid!
Son, you come sit with me.
That's it for me, guys.
I'm going to bed.
You're in trouble.
Foster, right here.
Turn around.
Good night, Rachel.
Good night, Frank.
Good night, Foster.
It's good to hear you laugh.
Stay.
You're very thorough.
What's with you and Rachel?
One minute she has magnetic hands,
the next she hates you.
I don't know what's going on now.
You follow all her moves this closely?
It's a living.
No, it's not.
You must think my life's pretty sick.
You must.
I do.
Then why don't you change it?
Is it that easy?
You're a lovely woman.
But you don't want me?
I'm surprised.
Thorough fellow like you.
Why stop at one sister
when you can fuck them both?
I make my mistakes.
You didn't say no to the boss.
Is this elk?
A deer?
Big.
Jesus loves me
First time I've heard church music
in the midle of the week.
For the Bible tells me so
Jesus loves me
Oh, yes
He does
Jesus loves me
Oh, yes
He does
For the Bible
Tells me so
- Hey, kiddo.
- Hey, honey.
Where's Fletcher?
He can't swim!
Let me have him!
What were you doing?
You're crazy!
You are out of your mind!
You could have drowned him!
I'm sorry.
I got careless.
How will we get the boat?
Put them in there.
Someone's cut the phone lines.
Could be anywhere from here to town.
Both cars are dead.
I don't know how.
Who knows you're here?
Don't know.
This place has nothing to do with her.
Maybe it has to do with you.
- And we can't walk out of here at night.
- I know.
Let's stay tonight
and walk out at first light.
I was an idiot last night.
What'd you think about today?
I think this is no maniac.
He knows what he's doing.
You're right.
He does.
Tell me about him.
Who is it, Nicki?
How do we stop him?
- He almost got the baby!
- Who is it?
I don't know.
Call it off.
He doesn't even know who hired him.
I don't know who he is.
He doesn't know me.
How did you do it?
How?
I went to a bar in East L.A.
I asked around
and there was this guy...
Name?
- Armando.
- His name!
Armando.
He arranged it.
That's all I know.
All paid for?
Is it?
And then some, okay?
Till it's done.
He keeps going until he kills her?
- What's the name of the bar?
- I'm not sure. I was stoned.
All right.
How about the letters?
The letters came first.
I don't know who's writing them.
Shit, but they're reading my mind.
Those are my thoughts.
I hate her.
It made me think I could do it.
But I would never hurt the baby.
I would never hurt Fletcher!
- You must stop it.
- We will.
You and me.
Don't you want to know why?
You told me.
She has everything.
What if we can't find him?
Stay here and don't move.
It's me!
What's happening?
Stay with her!
- Where's Nicki?
- No, stop! I'm the one...
We're all right.
- Doesn't make sense.
- What do you mean?
We got him.
What do you mean?
Where?
Here in L.A. Last night.
You should see his locker.
He's obsessed with her.
- You sure it's him?
- Forensics say a 100% positive ID.
And he's got a black Toyota 4 x 4.
Ray's with him now.
You sent her the letters.
We don't need you to admit it.
We know!
We know it!
Whoever you got wasn't here last night.
This was a professional.
This is crazy.
What do you want to do?
How long can you keep him?
All he's done is write some letters.
48 hours. You know the deal.
I know.
Stringent security surrounded
the funeral of Nicki Marron...
...who was shot at a lakeside retreat
by an unknown intruder.
Nicki was the eldest sister
of Rachel Marron.
A spokesman for the Oscar-nominated
actress said she was devastated...
...and that it cast a pall
over the upcoming award ceremony.
You okay?
Yeah, Fletcher, I'm okay.
How about yourself?
I couldn't sleep.
It was so scary,
just thinking about it.
You feel scared, Frank?
Everybody's afraid of something.
That's how we know we care about things,
when we're afraid to lose them.
What are you afraid of?
You should try to go back to sleep.
Is it the man who killed Nicki?
Are you afraid of him?
Then what?
What are you afraid of?
I'm afraid of not...
...being there.
It's late.
Want me to take you up to your room?
You mind if I sit?
It isn't over, is it?
So he'll come again?
It's possible.
At the Oscars?
Maybe.
Back in Squirrel Hill...
...I bet my friends 50 bucks each
that someday I'd win an Oscar.
It's very important for them
to see me up there if I win.
If each of those pikers comes through,
it'd add up to a lot of money.
I don't know, Rachel.
I think it's still dangerous.
I didn't get here by doing
the smart thing every time.
How about you?
Out there on the edge.
Have you done anything
that didn't make sense?
Except somewhere inside you?
I know you have.
Because no one gets good without it.
And I know you're good.
Look...
...I don't know why
this is happening...
...but I know it's not your fault.
I hope you hear me
because this is how I say sorry.
So...
...I'll go to the Oscars
and see if I win.
And I won't worry about it at all.
I have you to protect me.
That's right.
We'll go straight to the green room.
Got that, Tony?
Tony knows what he's doing.
I wish you guys would relax.
Nothing bad's going to happen.
Right?
Unless I lose the award.
What a crew!
Screw it.
I'm tired of worrying about it.
When your time is up...
...it's up.
Right, Frank?
- How are you?
- Fine. And you?
You look lovely.
- Thank you.
- They love you.
They're going wild!
So are you the queen of this night?
Let's hope I'm the queen tonight.
Good luck.
Rachel Marron, everybody.
And the award for best
achievement in sound...
...goes to Kay Colvin...
...and Mychal Smith for "Hot and Cold."
Thank you so much.
I want to thank our producers.
There is a gap, house left, rows EE, FF.
Get fillers.
I just need to tell you
your responsibilities.
Now it's Best Sound.
Then a song, then you.
At 8:07, you will be presenting
with Clive Healy.
Your lines.
Teleprompter is straight ahead
and, we pray, working.
I understand it's my honor
to escort you on stage.
That's right, and I don't like it one
bit that you look skinnier than me.
I wish.
How's the Hollywood cricket scene?
Coming out of commercial.
5, 4, 3, 2. Cue music.
And cue Robert.
And enter Robert's monologue.
Stand by, dancers.
I heard that the New York economy
is so bad...
...that the Mafia has
laid off 5 judges.
I'm going to look around,
then come back for her.
No more carrots.
Did you ever see...
...a woman on sound
that looked like that?
She must have been the boom girl.
Looked like the
bada-bing-bada-boom girl.
If she's working sound,
who's listening?
30 to lighting change.
- 20 seconds.
- Cue him the 20 seconds.
Hi, Frank.
How are you?
What are you doing here?
- On the job.
- Who?
Him.
Short-term gig...
...but profitable.
Frank, I'm sorry about Miami.
Cue music.
Cue dancers.
Back to work.
See you at the Governor's Ball.
- Not a bad singer.
- Sounds great.
I want her run out of town.
She's got to go!
Tony, you there?
I have a feeling it's tonight.
He'll go for her on camera.
That's crazy!
That's how he wants it to look.
He's very clever.
I need you to help me tonight.
You can't use that.
There's bad breakthrough.
I'm going to have to disconnect you.
I'll do it.
You get it back after the show.
What's wrong?
Ready to go?
Shall we go?
Excuse me, is this necessary?
We have our own man at the door!
Please.
No. I want him.
Fine!
Stay alert.
Let us brighten this firmament.
Coming through, please.
How much time do we have?
Resetting staircases.
Scenery coming in.
30 to lighting change.
30 seconds. Don't panic.
Clear this area.
Up, to the right and through.
Clive, up, to the left and through.
You'll meet...
...on the landing.
Watch your step.
Somebody spilled water.
Shall we?
Try to relax.
You must be excited.
Thank you.
Presenting the Best Song award are...
...Hollywood's newest couple.
England's knight in shining armor...
...and America's queen of the night.
Please welcome
Clive Healy and Rachel Marron.
I know you only came to present.
You'll want to leave when we're done.
No, I'm very interested
in one of the awards tonight.
Best Actor.
Tonight we've heard 5 songs...
...and the names of their creators.
And I know
you have no personal favorites.
The Best Song nominees are...
..."Clock On The Wall"
by Dana S. Lee and Sarah Spring...
..."Give Me Your Trust"
by David Siegel and Barbara Gordon...
..."I Have Nothing" from "Queen
of the Night" by Nancy Garber...
...and "Reflections of My Heart"
from "Hot and Cold" by Leslie Moraes.
Let's find out...
...who the winner is.
The envelope.
Shall I do the honors?
And the winner is:
"I Have Nothing"...
...from "Queen of the Night"
by Nancy Garber.
She's good, Frank.
I'm okay.
I said she's nuts.
I'm okay, all right?
You make me a raving lunatic!
You going to be okay?
Yes!
Fucking actresses!
- Where's Portman?
- Who?
Never heard of him.
If you want to be in your seat
for Best Actress, you must go now.
Why don't you go twitch
somewhere else?
Everything's fine.
No one noticed.
- Everyone's jumping out of their skins.
- Bullshit.
He's making me into a lunatic!
- You should know...
- You're driving her crazy!
I know who it is.
Shut up!
You've embarrassed me...
...in front of billions of people.
You won't quit!
Wait for Frank.
Honey, please.
Calm the fuck down!
Is he coming or not?
I know who it is.
It's Portman.
Remember?
The guy in Miami.
- Yeah, pencil neck!
- Is anyone coming?
After tonight, you're in charge.
He knows nothing about show business.
2 minutes to Best Actress.
You're an asshole.
To present the Best Actress award...
...we have the man who won last year...
...for his performance
in "South of Waco"...
Please welcome Mr. Tom Winston.
Thank you, Academy.
- Did you see him?
- No.
- Go to the other side of the stage.
- What do I do?
See those people?
They don't need to be there.
That camera guy doesn't...
I'll take care of it.
Rachel Marron for "Queen of the Night."
Hey, I said you.
You!
Rachel Marron...
..."Queen of the Night."
Go to commercial.
He's got a gun!
She's bleeding!
It's not me!
He's my bodyguard!
Stay with me!
Come on, Frank.
God!
Hurry up!
Come on, Frank!
Stay with me!
How's it going?
It's under control.
Won't be the same without you.
How you doing?
You shouldn't be here.
You're quitting show business?
Too bad.
You had talent.
Fletcher, go to the plane.
How's the new guy?
He's got white hair.
He's very good.
Did it have to be an old man?
I don't trust you.
Let's get this over with, okay?
Give me a kiss.
Goodbye, Rachel.
Bye, Frank.
If I should stay
I would only be
In your way
So I'll go
You okay?
But I know
I'll think of you
Every step of the way
Wait!
And I will always love you
I will always love you
My darling, you
Bittersweet...
...memories
That is all
I'm taking with me
So goodbye
Please don't cry
We both know
I'm not what you need
And I will always love you
I will always love you
Our speaker this evening
has been a lone courageous voice.
He alone has challenged those
who have linked organized crime...
...with legitimate business
in our state.
Welcome, Congressman.
First our benediction will be delivered
by Reverend Phillip Hardy...
...of the First Presbyterian Church
of Iowa Rapids.
Heavenly Father...
...please bless us today
as we meet in friendship and duty.
And, Lord, whatever dangerous endeavors
we may take...
...let us never be
without Your sanctuary.
We know in our hearts...
...though we may pass
through the valley of death...
...You are with us...
...guiding and protecting us.
Amen.