Man: 13 METERS. YOU SHOULD SEE IT.
OKAY, TAKE HER UP AND OVER THE BOW RAIL.
Okay, Mir 2, we're going over the bow.
Stay with us.
OKAY, QUIET. WE'RE ROLLING.
SEEING HER COMING OUT OF THE DARKNESS LIKE A GHOST SHIP
STILL GETS ME EVERY TIME--
TO SEE THE SAD RUIN OF THE GREAT SHIP SITTING HERE
WHERE SHE LANDED AT 2:30 IN THE MORNING OF APRIL 15, 1912
AFTER HER LONG FALL FROM THE WORLD ABOVE.
YOU ARE SO FULL OF SHIT, BOSS.
Man: DIVE SIX-- HERE WE ARE AGAIN ON THE DECK OF TITANIC
2½ MILES DOWN, 3,821 METERS.
THE PRESSURE OUTSIDE IS 3½ TONS PER SQUARE INCH.
THESE WINDOWS ARE NINE INCHES THICK AND IF THEY GO
IT'S SAYONARA IN TWO MICROSECONDS.
ALL RIGHT, ENOUGH OF THAT BULLSHIT.
JUST PUT HER DOWN ON THE ROOF
OF THE OFFICER'S QUARTERS LIKE YESTERDAY.
Man: SURE.
Man: Okay, Mir 2.
We have landed right on the grand staircase.
You guys set to launch?
YEAH, BROCK-- LAUNCHING DUNKIN NOW.
GO, CHARLIE.
ALL RIGHT, TETHER OUT.
Man: TETHER OUT.
Man: Okay, Brock
we're dropping down along the hull.
Brock: ROGER THAT.
OKAY, DROP DOWN AND GO
INTO THE FIRST CLASS GANGWAY DOOR.
I WANT YOU GUYS WORKING THE D DECK RECEPTION AREA
AND THE DINING SALOON.
Man: Copy that.
TETHER OUT.
Man: TETHER OUT.
NOW LEFT, LEFT.
I'M COMING LEFT.
Brock: Snoop Dog is on the move.
We're headed down the stairwell.
OKAY, LEWIS, DROP DOWN TO B DECK.
A DECK.
Lewis: GIVE ME SOME ROPE, CAPTAIN.
B DECK-- GET IN THERE, GET IN THERE.
Brock: WATCH THE DOORFRAME.
WATCH THE DOORFRAME-- WATCH IT, WATCH IT.
I SEE IT. I GOT IT.
WE'RE GOOD-- JUST CHILL, BOSS.
Brock: MAKE YOUR TURN.
COME AROUND.
Lewis: CABLE OUT, CAPTAIN.
MAKE YOUR TURN, WATCH THE WALL.
YEAH, BROCK, WE'RE AT THE PIANO, YOU COPY?
Brock: Okay, copy that.
Brock: OKAY, RIGHT THERE.
RIGHT THERE-- THAT'S IT!
THAT'S THE BEDROOM DOOR.
I SEE IT... I SEE IT.
WE'RE IN!
WE'RE IN, BABY, WE'RE THERE!
Brock: THAT'S HOCKLEY'S BED.
THAT'S WHERE THE SON OF A BITCH SLEPT.
Lewis: OOPS, SOMEBODY LEFT THE WATER RUNNING.
HEY, HOLD IT JUST A SECOND.
GO BACK TO THE RIGHT.
THAT WARDROBE DOOR-- GET CLOSER.
YOU SMELLING SOMETHING, BOSS?
I WANT TO SEE WHAT'S UNDER IT.
GIVE ME MY HANDS, MAN.
ALL RIGHT.
TAKE IT EASY, IT MIGHT COME APART.
OKAY.
GO, GO, GO, GO.
FLIP IT OVER, FLIP IT OVER, GO.
KEEP GOING, GO, GO, GO.
OKAY, DROP IT.
OH, BABY, BABY, ARE YOU SEEING THIS, BOSS?
IT'S PAYDAY, BOYS.
KA-CHING!
WE DID IT, BOBBY.
Lewis: OH, YEAH, WHO'S THE MAN?
WHO'S THE BEST, BABY?
SAY IT, SAY IT.
YOU ARE, LEWIS.
BOBBY, MY CIGAR.
Bobby: RIGHT HERE.
Brock: OKAY, CRACK HER OPEN.
SHIT.
NO DIAMOND.
YOU KNOW, BOSS, THIS SAME THING HAPPENED TO GERALDO
AND HIS CAREER NEVER RECOVERED.
TURN THE CAMERA OFF.
Bobby: BROCK, THE PARTNERS WOULD LIKE TO KNOW
HOW IT'S GOING.
HEY, DAVE, BARRY, HI.
LOOK, IT WASN'T IN THE SAFE
BUT HEY, HEY, DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
THERE'S STILL PLENTY OF PLACES IT COULD BE.
HELL YES!-- THE FLOOR DEBRIS IN THE SUITE, THE MOTHER'S ROOM
PURSER'S SAFE ON C DECK.
JIMMY HOFFA'S BRIEFCASE.
Brock: A DOZEN OTHER PLACES.
GUYS, LOOK, YOU'VE JUST GOT TO TRUST MY INSTINCTS.
I KNOW WE'RE CLOSE.
WE JUST GOT TO GO THROUGH A LITTLE PROCESS OF ELIMINATION.
HANG ON A SECOND.
LET ME SEE THAT.
Bobby: WE MIGHT HAVE SOMETHING HERE, GUYS.
WHERE'S THE PHOTOGRAPH OF THE NECKLACE?
WE'LL CALL YOU RIGHT BACK.
I'LL BE GODDAMNED.
Reporter: Treasure hunter Brock Lovett
is best known for finding Spanish gold...
IT'S OKAY. I'LL FEED YOU IN A MINUTE.
Now he has chartered Russian subs to reach
the most famous shipwreck of all: the Titanic.
He is with us live via satellite
from the research ship Keldysh in the North Atlantic.
Hello, Brock.
Brock: Hello, Tracy.
Everyone knows the familiar stories of Titanic--
the nobility, the band playing till the very end and all that.
But what I'm interested in are the untold stories
the secrets locked deep inside the hull of Titanic.
We're out here using robot technology
to go further into the wreck
than anybody's ever done before.
Your expedition is at the center of a storm of controversy
over salvage rights and even ethics.
Many are calling you a grave robber.
Nobody called the recovery of the artifacts
of King Tut's tomb "grave robbing."
Woman: WHAT IS IT?
TURN THAT UP, DEAR.
I have museum-trained experts out here making sure
that these relics are preserved and catalogued properly.
Take a look at this drawing that we found just today:
a piece of paper that's been underwater for 84 years
and my team were able to preserve it intact.
Should this have remained unseen
at the bottom of the ocean for eternity?
I'LL BE GODDAMNED.
Man: Vnimanye, Vnimanye...
Bobby: BROCK!
THERE'S A SATELLITE CALL FOR YOU.
BOBBY, WE'RE LAUNCHING.
YOU SEE THESE SUBMERSIBLES GOING IN THE WATER?
TRUST ME, BUDDY.
YOU WANT TO TAKE THIS CALL.
THIS BETTER BE GOOD.
YOU GOT TO SPEAK UP.
SHE'S KIND OF OLD.
GREAT.
THIS IS BROCK LOVETT.
HOW CAN I HELP YOU, MRS...
CALVERT, ROSE CALVERT.
MRS. CALVERT?
I WAS JUST WONDERING
IF YOU HAD FOUND THE HEART OF THE OCEAN YET, MR. LOVETT.
TOLD YOU YOU WANTED TO TAKE THE CALL.
ALL RIGHT, YOU HAVE MY ATTENTION, ROSE.
CAN YOU TELL US WHO THE WOMAN IN THE PICTURE IS?
OH, YES.
THE WOMAN IN THE PICTURE IS ME.
SHE'S A GODDAMNED LIAR--
SOME NUT CASE SEEKING MONEY OR PUBLICITY.
GOD ONLY KNOWS WHY, LIKE THAT RUSSIAN BABE, ANESTHESIA.
THEY'RE INBOUND!
ROSE DEWITT BUKATER DIED ON THE TITANIC
WHEN SHE WAS 17, RIGHT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
IF SHE HAD LIVED, SHE'D BE OVER 100 BY NOW.
101 NEXT MONTH.
OKAY, SO SHE'S A VERY OLD GODDAMNED LIAR.
LOOK, I'VE ALREADY DONE THE BACKGROUND ON THIS WOMAN
ALL THE WAY BACK TO THE '20s
WHEN SHE WAS WORKING AS AN ACTRESS.
AN ACTRESS!
THERE'S YOUR FIRST CLUE, SHERLOCK!
HER NAME WAS ROSE DAWSON BACK THEN.
THEN SHE MARRIES THIS GUY NAMED CALVERT.
THEY MOVE TO CEDAR RAPIDS
AND SHE PUNCHES OUT A COUPLE OF KIDS.
NOW, CALVERT'S DEAD
AND FROM WHAT I HEAR, CEDAR RAPIDS IS DEAD.
AND EVERYBODY WHO KNOWS ABOUT THE DIAMOND
IS SUPPOSED TO BE DEAD OR ON THIS BOAT, BUT SHE KNOWS.
DOESN'T EXACTLY TRAVEL LIGHT, DOES SHE?
MRS. CALVERT, I'M BROCK LOVETT.
WELCOME TO THE KELDYSH.
OKAY, LET'S GET HER INSIDE THERE.
HI, MS. CALVERT.
HI.
WELCOME TO THE KELDYSH.
Man: HEY.
HEY!
Rose: YES?
ARE YOUR STATEROOMS ALL RIGHT?
Rose: OH, YES, VERY NICE.
HAVE YOU MET MY GRANDDAUGHTER LIZZIE?
SHE TAKES CARE OF ME.
WE MET JUST A FEW MINUTES AGO.
REMEMBER, NANA, UP ON DECK?
THERE, THAT'S NICE.
HAVE TO HAVE MY PICTURES WHEN I TRAVEL.
CAN I GET YOU ANYTHING?
IS THERE ANYTHING YOU'D LIKE?
YES.
I WOULD LIKE TO SEE MY DRAWING.
Brock: LOUIS XVI WORE A FABULOUS STONE
THAT WAS CALLED THE BLUE DIAMOND OF THE CROWN
WHICH DISAPPEARED IN 1792
ABOUT THE SAME TIME OLD LOUIS LOST EVERYTHING
FROM THE NECK UP.
THE THEORY GOES
THAT THE CROWN DIAMOND WAS CHOPPED, TOO
RECUT INTO A HEARTLIKE SHAPE
THAT BECAME KNOWN AS "THE HEART OF THE OCEAN."
TODAY IT WOULD BE WORTH MORE THAN THE HOPE DIAMOND.
IT WAS A DREADFUL, HEAVY THING.
I ONLY WORE IT THIS ONCE.
Lizzie: YOU ACTUALLY THINK
THIS IS YOU, NANA?
IT IS ME, DEAR.
WASN'T I A DISH?
I TRACKED IT DOWN THROUGH INSURANCE RECORDS--
AN OLD CLAIM THAT WAS SETTLED UNDER TERMS OF ABSOLUTE SECRECY.
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHO THE CLAIMANT WAS, ROSE?
I SHOULD IMAGINE SOMEONE NAMED HOCKLEY.
Brock: NATHAN HOCKLEY, THAT'S RIGHT.
PITTSBURGH STEEL TYCOON.
CLAIM WAS FOR A DIAMOND NECKLACE
HIS SON CALEDON BOUGHT HIS FIANCEE-- YOU
A WEEK BEFORE HE SAILED ON TITANIC.
IT WAS FILED RIGHT AFTER THE SINKING
SO THE DIAMOND HAD TO HAVE GONE DOWN WITH THE SHIP.
YOU SEE THE DATE?
"APRIL 14, 1912."
WHICH MEANS IF YOUR GRANDMOTHER IS WHO SHE SAYS SHE IS
SHE WAS WEARING THE DIAMOND THE DAY THE TITANIC SANK.
AND THAT MAKES YOU MY NEW BEST FRIEND.
THESE ARE SOME OF THE THINGS
WE RECOVERED FROM YOUR STATEROOM.
THIS WAS MINE.
HOW EXTRAORDINARY!
AND IT LOOKS THE SAME AS IT DID
THE LAST TIME I SAW IT.
THE REFLECTION HAS CHANGED A BIT.
ARE YOU READY TO GO BACK TO TITANIC?
Lewis: OKAY, HERE WE GO.
SHE HITS THE BERG ON THE STARBOARD SIDE, RIGHT?
SHE KIND OF BUMPS ALONG
PUNCHING HOLES LIKE MORSE CODE-- DIT-DIT-DIT--
ALONG THE SIDE, BELOW THE WATERLINE.
THEN THE FORWARD COMPARTMENTS START TO FLOOD.
NOW, AS THE WATER LEVEL RISES
IT SPILLS OVER THE WATERTIGHT BULKHEADS
WHICH UNFORTUNATELY DON'T GO ANY HIGHER THAN E DECK.
SO NOW AS THE BOW GOES DOWN, THE STERN RISES UP
SLOW AT FIRST, THEN FASTER AND FASTER UNTIL FINALLY
SHE'S GOT HER WHOLE ASS IS STICKING UP IN THE AIR
AND THAT'S A BIG ASS.
WE'RE TALKING 20,000, 30,000 TONS, OKAY?
AND THE HULL'S NOT DESIGNED TO DEAL WITH THAT PRESSURE
SO WHAT HAPPENS?
SHE SPLITS, RIGHT DOWN TO THE KEEL
AND THE STERN FALLS BACK LEVEL.
THEN AS THE BOW SINKS, IT PULLS THE STERN VERTICAL
AND THEN FINALLY DETACHES.
NOW, THE STERN SECTION JUST KIND OF BOBS THERE LIKE A CORK
FOR A COUPLE OF MINUTES, FLOODS
AND FINALLY GOES UNDER ABOUT 2:20 A.M.
TWO HOURS AND 40 MINUTES AFTER THE COLLISION.
THE BOW SECTION PLANES AWAY
LANDING ABOUT A HALF A MILE AWAY
GOING 20, 30 KNOTS WHEN IT HITS THE OCEAN FLOOR.
PRETTY COOL, HUH?
THANK YOU FOR THAT FINE FORENSIC ANALYSIS, MR. BODINE.
OF COURSE, THE EXPERIENCE OF IT WAS... SOMEWHAT DIFFERENT.
WILL YOU SHARE IT WITH US?
I'M TAKING HER TO REST.
NO.
COME ON, NANA.
NO!
TAPE RECORDER.
TELL US, ROSE.
IT'S BEEN 84 YEARS.
IT'S OKAY.
JUST TRY TO REMEMBER ANYTHING--
ANYTHING AT ALL.
DO YOU WANT TO HEAR THIS OR NOT, MR. LOVETT?
IT'S BEEN 84 YEARS...
AND I CAN STILL SMELL THE FRESH PAINT.
THE CHINA HAD NEVER BEEN USED.
THE SHEETS HAD NEVER BEEN SLEPT IN.
TITANIC WAS CALLED "THE SHIP OF DREAMS"
AND IT WAS, IT REALLY WAS.
Man: ALL THIRD-CLASS PASSENGERS
WITH A FORWARD BERTH
THIS WAY, PLEASE, THIS QUEUE.
RIGHT HERE.
BIG BOAT, HUH?
DADDY, IT'S A SHIP.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I DON'T SEE WHAT ALL THE FUSS IS ABOUT.
IT DOESN'T LOOK ANY BIGGER
THAN THE MAURITANIA.
YOU CAN BE BLASE ABOUT SOME THINGS, ROSE
BUT NOT ABOUT TITANIC.
IT'S OVER 100 FEET LONGER THAN MAURITANIA
AND FAR MORE LUXURIOUS.
YOUR DAUGHTER IS FAR TOO DIFFICULT
TO IMPRESS, RUTH.
SO THIS IS THE SHIP
THEY SAY IS UNSINKABLE.
IT IS UNSINKABLE.
GOD HIMSELF COULD NOT SINK THIS SHIP.
SIR, YOU HAVE TO CHECK YOUR BAGGAGE
THROUGH THE MAIN TERMINAL.
IT'S ROUND THAT WAY, SIR.
I PUT MY FAITH IN YOU, GOOD SIR.
NOW, KINDLY SEE MY MAN.
YES, SIR, MY PLEASURE, SIR.
IF I CAN DO ANYTHING AT ALL.
OH, YES, RIGHT.
ALL THE TRUNKS FROM THAT CAR THERE
12 FROM HERE, AND THE SAFE...
TO THE PARLOR SUITE, ROOMS B-52, 54, 56.
LADIES...
BETTER HURRY.
MY COAT?
Woman: I HAVE IT.
Man: ALL THIRD-CLASS PASSENGERS
DUE HERE FOR HEALTH INSPECTION.
ALL THIRD-CLASS PASSENGERS DUE HERE FOR HEALTH INSPECTION.
HEAD UP.
WELCOME ABOARD, MA'AM.
WELCOME TO TITANIC.
Rose: IT WAS THE SHIP OF DREAMS TO EVERYONE ELSE.
TO ME IT WAS A SLAVE SHIP
TAKING ME BACK TO AMERICA IN CHAINS.
OUTWARDLY, I WAS EVERYTHING A WELL-BROUGHT-UP GIRL SHOULD BE.
INSIDE, I WAS SCREAMING.
JACK, YOU ARE PAZZO.
YOU BET EVERYTHING WE HAVE.
WHEN YOU GOT NOTHING
YOU GOT NOTHING TO LOSE.
SVEN?
ALL RIGHT... MOMENT OF TRUTH.
SOMEBODY'S LIFE'S ABOUT TO CHANGE.
FABRIZIO?
NIENTE.
OLAF?
NOTHING.
SVEN?
UH-OH...
TWO PAIR.
I'M SORRY, FABRIZIO.
CHE "SORRY?" MA VAFFANCULO!
YOU BET ALL THE MONEY.
I'M SORRY, YOU'RE NOT GOING TO SEE
YOUR MOM AGAIN FOR A LONG TIME
BECAUSE WE'RE GOING TO AMERICA.
FULL HOUSE, BOYS.
WHOA!
YEAH!
DIO MIO, GRAZIE!
COME ON.
FIGLIO DI PUTTANA!
I'M GOING HOME!
I'M GOING HOME.
I GO TO AMERICA.
Man: NO, MATE.
TITANIC GO TO AMERICA IN FIVE MINUTES.
COME ON.
COME ON, HERE.
Fabrizio: ANDIAMO.
WE'RE RIDING IN HIGH STYLE NOW.
WE'RE A COUPLE OF REGULAR SWELLS.
WE'RE PRACTICALLY GODDAMN ROYALTY, RAGAZZO MIO.
Fabrizio: YOU SEE, IT'S MY DESTINO!
LIKE I TOLD YOU, I GO TO AMERICA
TO BE MILLIONARIO.
Driver: WHOA, WHOA!
BASTARDO!
YOU'RE PAZZO!
MAYBE, BUT I'VE GOT THE TICKETS.
COME ON, I THOUGHT YOU WERE FAST.
ASPETTA!
WAIT, WAIT!
HEY, WAIT.
WE'RE PASSENGERS.
PASSENGERS.
HAVE YOU BEEN THROUGH THE INSPECTION QUEUE?
OF COURSE!
ANYWAY, WE DON'T HAVE ANY LICE.
WE'RE AMERICANS, BOTH OF US.
RIGHT, COME ABOARD.
WE'RE THE LUCKIEST SONS OF BITCHES
IN THE WORLD, YOU KNOW THAT?
GOOD-BYE!
YOU KNOW SOMEBODY?
OF COURSE NOT-- THAT'S NOT THE POINT.
GOOD-BYE! I'LL MISS YOU!
GOOD-BYE!
I'M GOING TO NEVER FORGET YOU.
ALL THE WAY, DARLING.
360, 360...
EXCUSE ME, MA'AM.
OH, RIGHT HERE.
HEY, HOW YOU DOING?
JACK.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
I'M JACK DAWSON.
HOW YOU DOING?
WHO SAYS YOU GET TOP BUNK, HUH?
THIS IS YOUR PRIVATE PROMENADE DECK, SIR.
WOULD YOU BE REQUIRING ANYTHING?
HMM...
EXCUSE ME.
Woman: THIS ONE?
Rose: NO... IT HAD A LOT OF FACES ON IT.
THIS IS THE ONE.
WOULD YOU LIKE ALL OF THEM OUT, MISS?
YES... WE NEED A LITTLE COLOR IN THIS ROOM.
PUT IT IN THERE, IN THE WARDROBE.
GOD, NOT THOSE FINGER PAINTINGS AGAIN.
THEY CERTAINLY WERE A WASTE OF MONEY.
THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN CAL'S TASTE IN ART
AND MINE IS THAT I HAVE SOME.
THEY'RE FASCINATING...
LIKE BEING INSIDE A DREAM OR SOMETHING.
THERE'S TRUTH, BUT NO LOGIC.
WHAT'S THE ARTIST'S NAME?
SOMETHING PICASSO.
"SOMETHING PICASSO."
HE WON'T AMOUNT TO A THING.
HE WON'T, TRUST ME.
PUT THE DEGAS IN THE BEDROOM.
AT LEAST THEY WERE CHEAP.
AH, PUT IT IN THE WARDROBE.
AT CHERBOURG, A WOMAN CAME ABOARD NAMED MARGARET BROWN.
WE ALL CALLED HER MOLLY.
HISTORY WOULD CALL HER "THE UNSINKABLE MOLLY BROWN."
WELL, I WASN'T ABOUT TO WAIT
ALL DAY FOR YOU, SONNY.
HERE, YOU THINK YOU CAN MANAGE?
HER HUSBAND HAD STRUCK GOLD SOMEPLACE OUT WEST
AND SHE WAS WHAT MOTHER CALLED "NEW MONEY."
BY THE NEXT AFTERNOON, WE WERE STEAMING WEST
FROM THE COAST OF IRELAND
WITH NOTHING OUT AHEAD OF US BUT OCEAN.
TAKE HER TO SEA, MR. MURDOCH.
LET'S STRETCH HER LEGS.
YES, SIR.
ALL AHEAD FULL, MR. MOODY.
VERY GOOD, SIR.
ALL AHEAD FULL.
Man: ALL AHEAD FULL.
COME ON, LADS.
GET MOVING.
WHAT'S THE READING?
ALL RIGHT, LET'S STOKE THEM RIGHT UP!
WE'RE GOING FULL AHEAD!
21 KNOTS, SIR.
HEY, LOOK, LOOK, LOOK!
LOOK, LOOK!
SEE IT?
THERE'S ANOTHER ONE.
SEE HIM?
LOOK AT THAT ONE.
LOOK AT HIM JUMP!
WHOO-HOO!
WHOO!
I CAN SEE THE STATUE OF LIBERTY ALREADY!
VERY SMALL, OF COURSE.
I'M THE KING OF THE WORLD.
Man: SHE'S THE LARGEST MOVING OBJECT EVER MADE BY THE HAND OF MAN
IN ALL HISTORY.
AND OUR MASTER SHIPBUILDER, MR. ANDREWS HERE
DESIGNED HER FROM THE KEEL PLATES UP.
WELL, I MAY HAVE KNOCKED HER TOGETHER
BUT THE IDEA WAS MR. ISMAY'S.
HE ENVISIONED A STEAMER SO GRAND IN SCALE AND SO LUXURIOUS
IN ITS APPOINTMENTS
THAT ITS SUPREMACY WOULD NEVER BE CHALLENGED.
AND HERE SHE IS
WILLED INTO SOLID REALITY.
Man: HEAR, HEAR.
YOU KNOW I DON'T LIKE THAT, ROSE.
SHE KNOWS.
WE'LL BOTH HAVE THE LAMB...
RARE, WITH VERY LITTLE MINT SAUCE.
HMM... YOU LIKE LAMB, RIGHT, SWEET PEA?
ARE YOU GOING TO CUT HER MEAT FOR HER, TOO, THERE, CAL?
HEY, UH, WHO THOUGHT OF THE NAME "TITANIC"?
WAS IT YOU, BRUCE?
WELL, YES, ACTUALLY.
I WANTED TO CONVEY SHEER SIZE
AND THE SIZE MEANS STABILITY
LUXURY, AND ABOVE ALL, STRENGTH.
DO YOU KNOW OF DR. FREUD, MR. ISMAY?
HIS IDEAS ABOUT THE MALE PREOCCUPATION WITH SIZE
MIGHT BE OF PARTICULAR INTEREST TO YOU.
WHAT'S GOTTEN INTO YOU?
EXCUSE ME.
I DO APOLOGIZE.
SHE'S A PISTOL, CAL.
HOPE YOU CAN HANDLE HER.
WELL, I MAY HAVE TO START MINDING
WHAT SHE READS FROM NOW ON, WON'T I, MRS. BROWN?
FREUD-- WHO IS HE?
IS HE A PASSENGER?
...MAKES THESE WAVES, MAKES THEM SPIN.
Fabrizio: THE SHIP IS NICE, HUH?
YEAH, IT'S AN IRISH SHIP.
IS ENGLISH, NO?
NO, IT WAS BUILT IN IRELAND.
15,000 IRISHMEN BUILT THIS SHIP.
SOLID AS A ROCK.
BIG IRISH HANDS.
THAT'S TYPICAL.
FIRST-CLASS DOGS COME DOWN HERE TO TAKE A SHIT.
UH... IT LETS US KNOW
WHERE WE RANK IN THE SCHEME OF THINGS.
LIKE WE COULD FORGET?
I'M TOMMY RYAN.
JACK DAWSON.
HELLO.
FABRIZIO.
HI. DO YOU MAKE ANY MONEY
WITH YOUR DRAWINGS?
OH, FORGET IT, BOYO.
YOU'D AS LIKE HAVE ANGELS FLY OUT OF YOUR ARSE
AS GET NEXT TO THE LIKES OF HER.
DO YOU MIND?
I HOPE YOU'RE PROUD OF THIS.
I SAW MY WHOLE LIFE AS IF I'D ALREADY LIVED IT--
AN ENDLESS PARADE OF PARTIES AND COTILLIONS
YACHTS AND POLO MATCHES
ALWAYS THE SAME NARROW PEOPLE, THE SAME MINDLESS CHATTER.
I FELT LIKE I WAS STANDING AT A GREAT PRECIPICE
WITH NO ONE TO PULL ME BACK
NO ONE WHO CARED OR EVEN NOTICED.
DON'T DO IT.
STAY BACK.
DON'T COME ANY CLOSER.
COME ON.
JUST GIVE ME YOUR HAND.
I'LL PULL YOU BACK OVER.
NO! STAY WHERE YOU ARE.
I MEAN IT.
I'LL LET GO.
NO, YOU WON'T.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, NO, I WON'T?
DON'T PRESUME TO TELL ME WHAT I WILL AND WILL NOT DO.
YOU DON'T KNOW ME.
WELL, YOU WOULD HAVE DONE IT ALREADY.
YOU'RE DISTRACTING ME.
GO AWAY.
I CAN'T.
I'M INVOLVED NOW.
YOU LET GO
AND I'M GOING TO HAVE TO JUMP IN THERE AFTER YOU.
DON'T BE ABSURD.
YOU'LL BE KILLED.
I'M A GOOD SWIMMER.
THE FALL ALONE WOULD KILL YOU.
IT WOULD HURT.
I'M NOT SAYING IT WOULDN'T.
TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH
I'M A LOT MORE CONCERNED
ABOUT THAT WATER BEING SO COLD.
HOW COLD?
FREEZING.
MAYBE A COUPLE DEGREES OVER.
YOU EVER, UH...
EVER BEEN TO WISCONSIN?
WHAT?
WELL, THEY HAVE SOME OF THE COLDEST WINTERS AROUND.
I GREW UP THERE NEAR CHIPPEWA FALLS.
I REMEMBER WHEN I WAS A KID
ME AND MY FATHER, WE WENT ICE FISHING
OUT ON LAKE WISSOTA.
ICE FISHING IS, YOU KNOW, WHERE YOU...
I KNOW WHAT ICE FISHING IS!
SORRY.
YOU JUST SEEM LIKE, YOU KNOW, KIND OF AN INDOOR GIRL.
ANYWAY, I, UH...
I FELL THROUGH SOME THIN ICE
AND I'M TELLING YOU...
WATER THAT COLD, LIKE RIGHT DOWN THERE
IT HITS YOU LIKE A THOUSAND KNIVES
STABBING YOU ALL OVER YOUR BODY.
YOU CAN'T BREATHE
YOU CAN'T THINK--
AT LEAST NOT ABOUT ANYTHING BUT THE PAIN.
WHICH IS WHY I'M NOT LOOKING FORWARD
TO JUMPING IN THERE AFTER YOU.
LIKE I SAID...
I DON'T HAVE A CHOICE.
I GUESS I'M KIND OF HOPING
YOU'LL COME BACK OVER THE RAIL AND GET ME OFF THE HOOK HERE.
YOU'RE CRAZY.
THAT'S WHAT EVERYBODY SAYS, BUT...
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT, MISS
I'M NOT THE ONE HANGING OFF THE BACK OF A SHIP HERE.
COME ON.
COME ON, GIVE ME YOUR HAND.
YOU DON'T WANT TO DO THIS.
WHEW!
I'M JACK DAWSON.
ROSE DEWITT BUKATER.
I'M GOING TO HAVE TO GET YOU
TO WRITE THAT ONE DOWN.
COME ON.
I GOT YOU!
COME ON!
HELP! PLEASE!
PLEASE GET ME!
LISTEN... LISTEN TO ME.
I'VE GOT YOU... I WON'T LET GO.
NOW PULL YOURSELF UP.
COME ON!
COME ON.
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU CAN DO IT.
I GOT YOU.
WHAT'S ALL THIS?
YOU STAND BACK!
AND DON'T MOVE AN INCH!
FETCH THE MASTER-AT-ARMS!
CARE FOR A BRANDY?
Cal: THIS IS COMPLETELY UNACCEPTABLE!
WHAT MADE YOU THINK
THAT YOU COULD PUT YOUR HANDS ON MY FIANCEE?
LOOK AT ME, YOU FILTH!
CAL...
WHAT DO YOU THINK YOU WERE DOING?
CAL, STOP.
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
AN ACCIDENT?
IT WAS.
STUPID REALLY.
I WAS LEANING OVER, AND I SLIPPED.
I WAS LEANING FAR OVER TO SEE THE, UH...
UH... UH...
THE, UH... UH...
PROPELLERS?
PROPELLERS, AND I SLIPPED.
AND I WOULD HAVE GONE OVERBOARD
BUT MR. DAWSON HERE SAVED ME
AND ALMOST WENT OVER HIMSELF.
Cal: YOU WANTED TO SEE...
SHE WANTED TO SEE THE PROPELLERS.
LIKE I SAID
WOMEN AND MACHINERY DO NOT MIX.
WAS THAT THE WAY OF IT?
YEAH... YEAH, THAT WAS PRETTY MUCH IT.
WELL, THE BOY'S A HERO THEN.
GOOD FOR YOU, SON.
WELL DONE.
SO IT'S ALL'S WELL
AND BACK TO OUR BRANDY, EH?
LOOK AT YOU.
YOU MUST BE FREEZING.
LET'S GET YOU INSIDE.
PERHAPS A LITTLE SOMETHING FOR THE BOY.
OF COURSE.
MR. LOVEJOY, I THINK A 20 SHOULD DO IT.
IS THAT THE GOING RATE
FOR SAVING THE WOMAN YOU LOVE?
ROSE IS DISPLEASED.
WHAT TO DO?
I KNOW.
PERHAPS YOU COULD JOIN US FOR DINNER TOMORROW EVENING
TO REGALE OUR GROUP
WITH... YOUR HEROIC TALE.
SURE, COUNT ME IN.
GOOD.
SETTLED THEN.
THIS SHOULD BE INTERESTING.
MMM.
CAN I, UH...
BUM A SMOKE?
YOU'LL WANT TO TIE THOSE.
IT'S INTERESTING.
THE YOUNG LADY SLIPS SO SUDDENLY
AND YOU STILL HAD TIME
TO REMOVE YOUR JACKET AND YOUR SHOES.
I KNOW YOU'VE BEEN MELANCHOLY.
I DON'T PRETEND TO KNOW WHY.
I INTENDED TO SAVE THIS
UNTIL THE ENGAGEMENT GALA
NEXT WEEK.
BUT I THOUGHT TONIGHT.
GOOD GRACIOUS.
PERHAPS AS A REMINDER
OF MY FEELINGS FOR YOU.
IS IT A...?
DIAMOND? YES.
56 CARATS TO BE EXACT.
IT WAS WORN BY LOUIS XVI
AND THEY CALLED IT "LE COEUR DE LA MER."
Both: THE HEART OF THE OCEAN.
YES.
IT'S OVERWHELMING.
WELL, IT'S FOR ROYALTY.
WE ARE ROYALTY, ROSE.
YOU KNOW, THERE'S NOTHING I COULDN'T GIVE YOU.
THERE'S NOTHING I'D DENY YOU
IF YOU WOULD NOT DENY ME.
NOW OPEN YOUR HEART TO ME, ROSE.
Jack: WELL, I'VE BEEN ON MY OWN SINCE I WAS 15
SINCE MY FOLKS DIED.
AND I HAD NO BROTHERS OR SISTERS
OR CLOSE KIN IN THAT PART OF THE COUNTRY.
SO I LIT ON OUT OF THERE
AND I HAVEN'T BEEN BACK SINCE.
YOU COULD JUST CALL ME
A TUMBLEWEED BLOWING IN THE WIND.
WELL, ROSE...
WE'VE WALKED ABOUT A MILE
AROUND THIS BOAT DECK
AND CHEWED OVER HOW GREAT THE WEATHER'S BEEN
AND HOW I GREW UP
BUT I RECKON THAT'S NOT WHY YOU CAME TO TALK TO ME, IS IT?
MR. DAWSON, I...
JACK.
JACK...
I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR WHAT YOU DID.
NOT JUST FOR... FOR PULLING ME BACK
BUT FOR YOUR DISCRETION.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
LOOK, I KNOW WHAT YOU MUST BE THINKING.
POOR LITTLE RICH GIRL.
WHAT DOES SHE KNOW ABOUT MISERY?
NO.
NO, THAT'S NOT WHAT I WAS THINKING.
WHAT I WAS THINKING WAS
WHAT COULD HAVE HAPPENED TO THIS GIRL
TO MAKE HER THINK SHE HAD NO WAY OUT?
WELL, I...
IT WAS EVERYTHING.
IT WAS MY WHOLE WORLD
AND ALL THE PEOPLE IN IT
AND THE INERTIA OF MY LIFE
PLUNGING AHEAD
AND ME, POWERLESS TO STOP IT.
GOD! LOOK AT THAT THING.
YOU WOULD HAVE GONE STRAIGHT TO THE BOTTOM.
500 INVITATIONS HAVE GONE OUT.
ALL OF PHILADELPHIA SOCIETY WILL BE THERE
AND ALL THE WHILE I FEEL I'M...
STANDING IN THE MIDDLE OF A CROWDED ROOM
SCREAMING AT THE TOP OF MY LUNGS
AND NO ONE EVEN LOOKS UP.
DO YOU LOVE HIM?
PARDON ME?
YOU'RE BEING VERY RUDE.
YOU SHOULDN'T BE ASKING ME THIS.
WELL, IT'S A SIMPLE QUESTION.
DO YOU LOVE THE GUY OR NOT?
THIS IS NOT A SUITABLE CONVERSATION.
WHY CAN'T YOU JUST ANSWER THE QUESTION?
THIS IS ABSURD.
YOU DON'T KNOW ME, AND I DON'T KNOW YOU
AND WE ARE NOT HAVING THIS CONVERSATION AT ALL.
YOU ARE RUDE AND UNCOUTH AND PRESUMPTUOUS
AND I AM LEAVING NOW.
JACK... MR. DAWSON, IT'S BEEN A PLEASURE.
I SOUGHT YOU OUT TO THANK YOU
AND NOW I HAVE THANKED YOU...
AND YOU'VE INSULTED ME.
WELL, YOU DESERVED IT.
RIGHT.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE LEAVING.
I AM.
YOU ARE SO ANNOYING.
WAIT.
I DON'T HAVE TO LEAVE.
THIS IS MY PART OF THE SHIP.
YOU LEAVE.
OH-HO-HO, WELL, WELL, WELL.
NOW WHO'S BEING RUDE?
WHAT IS THIS STUPID THING YOU'RE CARRYING AROUND?
SO WHAT ARE YOU, AN ARTIST OR SOMETHING?
WELL, THESE ARE RATHER GOOD.
THEY'RE, UH...
THEY'RE VERY GOOD ACTUALLY.
JACK, THIS IS EXQUISITE WORK.
THEY DIDN'T THINK TOO MUCH OF THEM IN OLD PAREE.
PARIS!
YOU DO GET AROUND FOR A POOR...
WELL, UH, UH, A PERSON OF LIMITED MEANS.
GO ON, A POOR GUY, YOU CAN SAY IT.
WELL, WELL, WELL.
AND THESE WERE DRAWN FROM LIFE?
WELL, THAT'S ONE OF THE GOOD THINGS ABOUT PARIS--
LOTS OF GIRLS WILLING TO TAKE THEIR CLOTHES OFF.
YOU LIKED THIS WOMAN.
YOU USED HER SEVERAL TIMES.
WELL, SHE HAD BEAUTIFUL HANDS, YOU SEE?
I THINK YOU MUST HAVE HAD A LOVE AFFAIR WITH HER.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
JUST WITH HER HANDS.
SHE WAS A ONE-LEGGED PROSTITUTE.
SEE?
OH!
AH, SHE HAD A GOOD SENSE OF HUMOR, THOUGH.
OH, AND THIS LADY...
SHE USED TO SIT AT THIS BAR EVERY NIGHT
WEARING EVERY PIECE OF JEWELRY SHE OWNED
JUST WAITING FOR HER LONG-LOST LOVE.
CALLED HER MADAME BIJOU.
SEE HOW HER CLOTHES ARE ALL MOTH-EATEN?
WELL, YOU HAVE A GIFT, JACK.
YOU DO.
YOU SEE PEOPLE.
I SEE YOU.
AND?
YOU WOULDN'T HAVE JUMPED.
BUT THE PURPOSE OF UNIVERSITY
IS TO FIND A SUITABLE HUSBAND.
ROSE HAS ALREADY DONE THAT.
LOOK, HERE COMES THAT VULGAR BROWN WOMAN.
QUICKLY, GET UP BEFORE SHE SITS WITH US.
HELLO, GIRLS.
I WAS HOPING I'D CATCH YOU AT TEA.
WE'RE AWFULLY SORRY YOU MISSED IT.
THE COUNTESS AND I WERE JUST OFF
TO TAKE THE AIR ON THE BOAT DECK.
WHAT A LOVELY IDEA.
I NEED TO CATCH UP ON MY GOSSIP.
Molly: COUNTESS.
SO YOU'VE NOT YET LIT THE LAST FOUR BOILERS?
NO, I DON'T SEE THE NEED.
WE ARE MAKING EXCELLENT TIME.
THE PRESS KNOWS THE SIZE OF TITANIC.
NOW I WANT THEM TO MARVEL AT HER SPEED.
WE MUST GIVE THEM SOMETHING NEW TO PRINT.
THIS MAIDEN VOYAGE OF TITANIC MUST MAKE HEADLINES.
MR. ISMAY...
I WOULD PREFER NOT TO PUSH THE ENGINES
UNTIL THEY'VE BEEN PROPERLY RUN IN.
OF COURSE I'M JUST A PASSENGER.
I LEAVE IT TO YOUR GOOD OFFICES
TO DECIDE WHAT'S BEST.
BUT WHAT A GLORIOUS END TO YOUR FINAL CROSSING
IF WE WERE TO GET INTO NEW YORK ON TUESDAY NIGHT
AND SURPRISE THEM ALL.
MAKE THE MORNING PAPERS.
RETIRE WITH A BANG, EH, E.J.?
GOOD MAN.
WELL, AFTER THAT
I WORKED ON A SQUID BOAT IN MONTEREY.
THEN I WENT DOWN TO LOS ANGELES
TO THE PIER IN SANTA MONICA
AND STARTED DOING PORTRAITS THERE
FOR TEN CENTS APIECE.
WHY CAN'T I BE LIKE YOU, JACK--
JUST HEAD OUT FOR THE HORIZON
WHENEVER I FEEL LIKE IT?
SAY WE'LL GO THERE SOMETIME TO THAT PIER
EVEN IF WE ONLY EVER JUST TALK ABOUT IT.
NO, WE'LL DO IT.
WE'LL DRINK CHEAP BEER.
WE'LL RIDE ON THE ROLLER COASTER TILL WE THROW UP.
THEN WE'LL RIDE HORSES ON THE BEACH
RIGHT IN THE SURF.
NOW, BUT YOU'LL HAVE TO DO IT
LIKE A REAL COWBOY.
NONE OF THAT SIDESADDLE STUFF.
YOU MEAN, ONE LEG ON EACH SIDE?
YEAH.
CAN YOU SHOW ME?
SURE... IF YOU LIKE.
TEACH ME TO RIDE LIKE A MAN.
AND CHEW TOBACCO LIKE A MAN.
AND SPIT LIKE A MAN.
THEY DIDN'T TEACH YOU THAT IN FINISHING SCHOOL?
NO.
WELL, COME ON, I'LL SHOW YOU.
LET'S DO IT.
I'LL SHOW YOU HOW-- COME ON.
JACK, NO! JACK, NO!
WAIT, JACK.
NO, JACK.
I COULDN'T POSSIBLY, JACK.
WATCH CLOSELY.
THAT'S DISGUSTING!
ALL RIGHT, YOUR TURN.
THAT WAS PITIFUL!
COME ON, YOU REALLY GOT TO HAWK IT BACK, YOU KNOW?
GET SOME LEVERAGE TO IT.
USE YOUR ARMS, ARC YOUR NECK.
SEE THE RANGE ON THAT THING?
MM-HMM.
Jack: OKAY, GO.
THAT WAS BETTER-- YOU GOT TO WORK ON IT.
REALLY?
REALLY TRY AND HAWK IT UP
AND GET SOME BODY TO IT, YOU KNOW?
YOU GOT TO...
MOTHER.
MAY I INTRODUCE JACK DAWSON?
CHARMED, I'M SURE.
THE OTHERS WERE GRACIOUS AND CURIOUS
ABOUT THE MAN WHO HAD SAVED MY LIFE
BUT MY MOTHER LOOKED AT HIM LIKE AN INSECT--
A DANGEROUS INSECT WHICH MUST BE SQUASHED QUICKLY.
WELL, JACK, SOUNDS LIKE YOU'RE A GOOD MAN TO HAVE AROUND
IN A STICKY SPOT.
WHY DO THEY ALWAYS INSIST ON ANNOUNCING DINNER
LIKE A DAMN CAVALRY CHARGE?
SHALL WE GO DRESS, MOTHER?
SEE YOU AT DINNER, JACK.
UH, SON?
SON!
DO YOU HAVE THE SLIGHTEST COMPREHENSION WHAT YOU'RE DOING?
NOT REALLY.
WELL, YOU'RE ABOUT TO GO INTO THE SNAKEPIT.
WHAT ARE YOU PLANNING TO WEAR?
I FIGURED.
COME ON.
I WAS RIGHT.
YOU AND MY SON ARE JUST ABOUT THE SAME SIZE.
PRETTY CLOSE.
YOU SHINE UP LIKE A NEW PENNY.
GOOD EVENING, SIR.
GOOD EVENING.
Man: HELLO.
Cal: DO YOU KNOW THAT THERE ARE
SEVERAL THOUSAND TONS OF HOCKLEY STEEL
IN THIS VERY SHIP?
Ruth: HMM... WHICH PART?
Cal: ALL THE RIGHT ONES, OF COURSE.
THEN WE'LL KNOW WHO TO HOLD ACCOUNTABLE IF THERE'S A PROBLEM.
WHERE'S MY DAUGHTER? OH, SHE'LL BE ALONG.
THERE IS THE COUNTESS.
HELLO, MY DEAR. GOOD EVENING, CAL.
Cal: SO GOOD TO SEE YOU.
I SAW THAT IN A NICKELODEON ONCE
AND I ALWAYS WANTED TO DO IT.
Ruth: I'LL SEE YOU AT DINNER.
DARLING?
SURELY YOU REMEMBER MR. DAWSON.
DAWSON?
WELL, IT'S AMAZING.
YOU COULD ALMOST PASS FOR A GENTLEMAN.
ALMOST.
EXTRAORDINARY.
Ruth: MY DEAR, IT'S DELIGHTFUL TO SEE YOU.
WHAT A REMARKABLE VOYAGE THIS IS.
IT'S MAD, ISN'T IT?
Ruth: I LOVE YOUR PERFUME.
THERE'S THE COUNTESS OF ROTHES.
AND, UM... THAT'S JOHN JACOB ASTOR--
THE RICHEST MAN ON THE SHIP.
HIS LITTLE WIFEY THERE, MADELEINE, IS MY AGE
AND IN A DELICATE CONDITION.
SEE HOW SHE'S TRYING TO HIDE IT?
QUITE THE SCANDAL.
HMM.
AND THAT'S BENJAMIN GUGGENHEIM
AND HIS MISTRESS MADAME AUBERT.
MRS. GUGGENHEIM IS AT HOME
WITH THE CHILDREN, OF COURSE.
AND OVER HERE WE HAVE
SIR COSMO AND LUCILLE LADY DUFF-GORDON.
SHE DESIGNS NAUGHTY LINGERIE, AMONG HER MANY TALENTS.
VERY POPULAR WITH THE ROYALS.
CONGRATULATIONS, HOCKLEY.
SHE'S SPLENDID.
WHY, THANK YOU.
CARE TO ESCORT A LADY TO DINNER?
CERTAINLY.
SWEET PEA?
Cal: SWEET PEA.
AIN'T NOTHIN' TO IT, IS THERE, JACK?
REMEMBER, THEY LOVE MONEY
SO JUST PRETEND LIKE YOU OWN A GOLD MINE
AND YOU'RE IN THE CLUB.
HEY, ASTOR!
WELL, HELLO, MOLLY.
NICE TO SEE YOU.
J.J., MADELEINE
I'D LIKE YOU TO MEET JACK DAWSON.
HOW DO YOU DO?
PLEASURE.
HELLO, JACK.
ARE YOU OF THE BOSTON DAWSONS?
NO-- THE CHIPPEWA FALLS DAWSONS, ACTUALLY.
OH, YES... YES.
HE MUST HAVE BEEN NERVOUS, BUT HE NEVER FALTERED.
THEY ASSUMED HE WAS ONE OF THEM--
HEIR TO A RAILROAD FORTUNE, PERHAPS.
NEW MONEY, OBVIOUSLY, BUT STILL A MEMBER OF THE CLUB.
MOTHER, OF COURSE, COULD ALWAYS BE COUNTED UPON.
TELL US OF THE ACCOMMODATIONS IN STEERAGE, MR. DAWSON.
I HEAR THEY'RE QUITE GOOD ON THIS SHIP.
THE BEST I'VE SEEN, MA'AM.
HARDLY ANY RATS.
MR. DAWSON IS JOINING US
FROM THE THIRD CLASS.
HE WAS OF SOME ASSISTANCE
TO MY FIANCEE LAST NIGHT.
IT TURNS OUT THAT MR. DAWSON
IS QUITE A FINE ARTIST.
HE WAS KIND ENOUGH TO SHOW ME
SOME OF HIS WORK TODAY.
ROSE AND I DIFFER SOMEWHAT
IN OUR DEFINITION OF FINE ART.
NOT TO IMPUGN YOUR WORK, SIR.
Ismay: SHE MAY BE MINE ON PAPER
BUT IN THE EYES OF GOD, SHE BELONGS TO THOMAS ANDREWS.
ARE THESE ALL FOR ME?
JUST START FROM THE OUTSIDE
AND WORK YOUR WAY IN.
HE KNOWS EVERY RIVET IN HER, DON'T YOU, THOMAS?
Andrews: INDEED.
YOUR SHIP IS A WONDER, MR. ANDREWS, TRULY.
THANK YOU, ROSE.
AND HOW DO YOU TAKE YOUR CAVIAR, SIR?
NO CAVIAR FOR ME, THANKS.
NEVER DID LIKE IT MUCH.
AND WHERE, EXACTLY, DO YOU LIVE, MR. DAWSON?
WELL, RIGHT NOW, MY ADDRESS IS THE R.M.S. TITANIC.
AFTER THAT, I'M ON GOD'S GOOD HUMOR.
AND HOW IS IT YOU HAVE MEANS TO TRAVEL?
I WORK MY WAY FROM PLACE TO PLACE--
YOU KNOW, TRAMP STEAMERS AND SUCH.
BUT I WON MY TICKET ON TITANIC HERE
AT A LUCKY HAND AT POKER.
A VERY LUCKY HAND.
ALL LIFE IS A GAME OF LUCK.
MMM.
A REAL MAN MAKES HIS OWN LUCK, ARCHIE.
RIGHT, DAWSON?
MMM.
AND YOU FIND THAT SORT OF ROOTLESS EXISTENCE
APPEALING, DO YOU?
WELL, YES, MA'AM, I DO.
I MEAN...
GOT EVERYTHING I NEED RIGHT HERE WITH ME.
GOT AIR IN MY LUNGS AND A FEW BLANK SHEETS OF PAPER.
I MEAN, I LOVE WAKING UP IN THE MORNING
NOT KNOWING WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN
OR WHO I'M GOING TO MEET, WHERE I'M GOING TO WIND UP.
JUST THE OTHER NIGHT, I WAS SLEEPING UNDER A BRIDGE
AND NOW HERE I AM ON THE GRANDEST SHIP IN THE WORLD
HAVING CHAMPAGNE WITH YOU FINE PEOPLE.
I'LL TAKE SOME MORE OF THAT.
I FIGURE LIFE'S A GIFT
AND I DON'T INTEND ON WASTING IT.
YOU NEVER KNOW WHAT HAND YOU'RE GOING TO GET DEALT NEXT.
YOU LEARN TO TAKE LIFE AS IT COMES AT YOU--
HERE YOU GO, CAL.
TO MAKE EACH DAY COUNT.
WELL SAID, JACK.
HEAR, HEAR!
TO MAKING IT COUNT.
All: TO MAKING IT COUNT.
Archie: BRAVO.
MR. BROWN HAD NO IDEA I'D HIDDEN THE MONEY IN THE STOVE.
SO HE COMES HOME DRUNK AS A PIG, CELEBRATING
AND HE LIGHTS A FIRE.
NEXT IT'LL BE BRANDIES IN THE SMOKING ROOM.
Archie: WELL...
JOIN ME IN A BRANDY, GENTLEMEN?
NOW THEY RETREAT INTO A CLOUD OF SMOKE
AND CONGRATULATE EACH OTHER ON BEING MASTERS OF THE UNIVERSE.
LADIES, THANK YOU FOR THE PLEASURE OF YOUR COMPANY.
ROSE, MAY I ESCORT YOU BACK TO THE CABIN?
NO, I'LL STAY HERE.
HERE YOU GO, MOLLY.
Archie: JOINING US, DAWSON?
YOU DON'T WANT TO STAY OUT HERE
WITH THE WOMEN, DO YOU?
NO, THANKS. I'VE GOT TO BE HEADING BACK.
AH.
PROBABLY BEST.
IT'LL BE ALL BUSINESS AND POLITICS
THAT SORT OF THING--
WOULDN'T INTEREST YOU.
BUT DAWSON...
GOOD OF YOU TO COME.
JACK, MUST YOU GO?
TIME FOR ME TO GO ROW WITH THE OTHER SLAVES.
GOOD NIGHT, ROSE.
SO YOU WANT TO GO TO A REAL PARTY?
IS OKAY I PUT MY HAND HERE.
OKAY.
TALLA FRIKKEN SVENSKA?
WHAT?
I CAN'T UNDERSTAND YOU.
HEY...!
BRAVO, BRAVO!
THANK YOU.
COME ON, GUYS, LET'S GO!
HO!
I'M GOING TO DANCE WITH HER NOW, ALL RIGHT?
COME ON.
WHAT?
COME WITH ME.
WHAT? JACK...
JACK, WAIT!
I CAN'T DO THIS.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO GET A LITTLE BIT CLOSER.
LIKE THIS.
YOU'RE STILL MY BEST GIRL, CORA.
I DON'T KNOW THE STEPS.
NEITHER DO I.
JUST GO WITH IT.
DON'T THINK.
HEY.
WAIT, JACK, JACK!
WAIT! STOP, JACK!
BA-BA-BA.
Rose: WAIT!
HEY... HEY!
Jack: YEAH!
JACK... NO!
WHAAA...
...JURISDICTION OF THE SHERMAN ACT
SO MY LAWYERS WILL ARGUE.
THAT'S WHAT ROCKEFELLER SAID
BUT THE SUPREME COURT IS NOT SWALLOWING IT.
WHAT?
YOU THINK A FIRST-CLASS GIRL CAN'T DRINK?
GET OUT OF HERE.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
I'M FINE.
TWO OUT OF THREE, TWO OUT OF THREE.
SO...
YOU THINK YOU'RE BIG, TOUGH MEN?
LET'S SEE YOU DO THIS.
HOLD THIS FOR ME, JACK.
HOLD IT UP.
OW!
JESUS, MARY AND JOSEPH!
YOU ALL RIGHT?
I HAVEN'T DONE THAT IN YEARS.
GO SEE MAGGIE, LADS.
GIVE HER THE HOLLEY! LET'S GO!
Musicians: HO!
COFFEE, SIR?
I HAD HOPED YOU WOULD COME TO ME LAST NIGHT.
I WAS TIRED.
YOUR EXERTIONS BELOW DECKS WERE NO DOUBT EXHAUSTING.
I SEE YOU HAD THAT UNDERTAKER OF A MANSERVANT FOLLOW ME.
HOW TYPICAL.
YOU WILL NEVER BEHAVE LIKE THAT AGAIN, ROSE.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
I'M NOT A FOREMAN IN ONE OF YOUR MILLS THAT YOU CAN COMMAND.
I'M YOUR FIANCEE.
MY FIANCEE?
MY FIANCEE?!!
YES, YOU ARE, AND MY WIFE!
MY WIFE IN PRACTICE IF NOT YET BY LAW
SO YOU WILL HONOR ME.
YOU WILL HONOR ME THE WAY A WIFE IS REQUIRED
TO HONOR A HUSBAND
BECAUSE I WILL NOT BE MADE OUT A FOOL, ROSE.
IS THIS IN ANY WAY UNCLEAR?
NO.
GOOD.
EXCUSE ME.
MISS ROSE!
WE HAD A LITTLE... ACCIDENT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT, MISS ROSE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
I'M SORRY, TRUDY.
LET ME HELP YOU.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, MISS.
TEA, TRUDY.
YES, MA'AM.
YOU'RE NOT TO SEE THAT BOY AGAIN
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
ROSE, I FORBID IT.
OH, STOP IT, MOTHER.
YOU'LL GIVE YOURSELF A NOSEBLEED.
THIS IS NOT A GAME.
OUR SITUATION IS PRECARIOUS.
YOU KNOW THE MONEY'S GONE.
OF COURSE I KNOW IT'S GONE.
YOU REMIND ME EVERY DAY.
YOUR FATHER LEFT US
NOTHING BUT A LEGACY OF BAD DEBTS
HIDDEN BY A GOOD NAME.
THAT NAME IS THE ONLY CARD WE HAVE TO PLAY.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND YOU.
IT IS A FINE MATCH WITH HOCKLEY.
IT WILL ENSURE OUR SURVIVAL.
HOW CAN YOU PUT THIS ON MY SHOULDERS?
WHY ARE YOU BEING SO SELFISH?
I'M BEING SELFISH?
DO YOU WANT TO SEE ME WORKING AS A SEAMSTRESS?
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT?
TO SEE OUR FINE THINGS SOLD AT AUCTION?
OUR MEMORIES SCATTERED TO THE WINDS?
IT'S SO UNFAIR.
OF COURSE IT'S UNFAIR.
WE'RE WOMEN.
OUR CHOICES ARE NEVER EASY.
HMM?
Congregation: ♪ PROTECT THEM BY THY GUARDIAN HAND ♪
♪ FROM EVERY PERIL ON THE LAND. ♪
♪ O SPIRIT, WHOM THE FATHER SENT ♪
♪ TO SPREAD ACROSS THE FIRMAMENT ♪
♪ O WIND OF HEAVEN, BY THY MIGHT ♪
♪ SAVE ALL WHO DARE THE EAGLE'S FLIGHT ♪
♪ AND KEEP THEM BY THY WATCHFUL... ♪
HELLO, MR. ANDREWS.
HELLO, JACK.
SIR...
I JUST NEED TO TALK TO SOMEBODY FOR A SECOND.
YOU'RE NOT SUPPOSED TO BE IN HERE.
♪ ...FIRE AND FOE ♪
♪ PROTECT THEM... ♪
I WAS JUST HERE LAST NIGHT. YOU DON'T REMEMBER ME?
NO, I'M AFRAID I DON'T.
NOW, YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO TURN AROUND.
HE'LL TELL YOU.
I JUST... I JUST NEED...
MR. HOCKLEY AND MRS. DEWITT BUKATER
CONTINUE TO BE APPRECIATIVE OF YOUR ASSISTANCE.
THEY ASKED ME TO, UH... GIVE YOU THIS IN GRATITUDE.
I DON'T WANT YOUR MONEY. PLEASE, I JUST...
AND ALSO TO REMIND YOU
THAT YOU HOLD A THIRD-CLASS TICKET
AND THAT YOUR PRESENCE HERE
IS NO LONGER APPROPRIATE.
PLEASE, I JUST WANT TO SPEAK TO ROSE FOR...
GENTLEMEN, WILL YOU PLEASE SEE
THAT MR. DAWSON GETS BACK TO WHERE HE BELONGS
AND THAT HE STAYS THERE?
YES, SIR.
COME ALONG, YOU.
♪ OH, HEAR US WHEN WE CRY TO THEE ♪
♪ FOR THOSE IN PERIL ON THE SEA. ♪
Ruth: AND WHY DO YOU HAVE TWO STEERING WHEELS?
WE REALLY ONLY USE THIS NEAR SHORE.
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
ANOTHER ICE WARNING.
THIS ONE'S FROM THE NOORDAM.
THANK YOU, SPARKS.
OH, NOT TO WORRY.
QUITE NORMAL FOR THIS TIME OF YEAR.
IN FACT, WE'RE SPEEDING UP.
I'VE JUST ORDERED
THE LAST BOILERS LIT.
Man: OKAY, SON, WIND IT UP TIGHT
LIKE I SHOWED YOU.
OKAY, NOW, LET IT GO.
WAS GOOD, WASN'T IT?
QUITE NICE.
THAT'S EXCELLENT, SON.
Rose: MR. ANDREWS, FORGIVE ME...
I DID THE SUM IN MY HEAD
AND WITH THE NUMBER OF LIFEBOATS
TIMES THE CAPACITY YOU MENTIONED
FORGIVE ME, BUT IT SEEMS THAT THERE ARE NOT ENOUGH
FOR EVERYONE ABOARD.
ABOUT HALF, ACTUALLY.
ROSE, YOU MISS NOTHING, DO YOU?
IN FACT, I PUT IN THESE NEW TYPE DAVITS
WHICH CAN TAKE AN EXTRA ROW OF BOATS INSIDE THIS ONE
BUT IT WAS THOUGHT BY SOME
THAT THE DECK WOULD LOOK TOO CLUTTERED
SO I WAS OVERRULED.
WASTE OF DECK SPACE AS IT IS
ON AN UNSINKABLE SHIP.
SLEEP SOUNDLY, YOUNG ROSE.
I HAVE BUILT YOU A GOOD SHIP
STRONG AND TRUE.
SHE'S ALL THE LIFEBOAT YOU NEED.
JUST KEEP HEADING AFT.
THE NEXT STOP WILL BE THE ENGINE ROOM.
COME ON.
JACK, THIS IS IMPOSSIBLE.
I CAN'T SEE YOU.
I NEED TO TALK TO YOU.
NO, JACK, NO.
JACK, I'M ENGAGED.
I'M MARRYING CAL.
I LOVE CAL.
ROSE, YOU'RE NO PICNIC.
ALL RIGHT, YOU'RE A SPOILED LITTLE BRAT, EVEN
BUT UNDER THAT YOU'RE THE MOST AMAZINGLY ASTOUNDING
WONDERFUL GIRL-- WOMAN--
THAT I'VE EVER KNOWN AND...
JACK, I...
NO, LET ME TRY AND GET THIS OUT.
YOU'RE, YOU'RE AMA...
I'M NOT AN IDIOT.
I KNOW HOW THE WORLD WORKS.
I'VE GOT TEN BUCKS IN MY POCKET.
I HAVE NOTHING TO OFFER YOU AND I KNOW THAT.
I UNDERSTAND.
BUT I'M TOO INVOLVED NOW.
YOU JUMP, I JUMP, REMEMBER?
I CAN'T TURN AWAY
WITHOUT KNOWING YOU'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S ALL THAT I WANT.
WELL, I'M FINE.
I'LL BE FINE, REALLY.
REALLY?
I DON'T THINK SO.
THEY'VE GOT YOU TRAPPED, ROSE
AND YOU'RE GOING TO DIE IF YOU DON'T BREAK FREE--
MAYBE NOT RIGHT AWAY
BECAUSE YOU'RE STRONG, BUT...
SOONER OR LATER THAT FIRE THAT I LOVE ABOUT YOU, ROSE...
THAT FIRE IS GOING TO BURN OUT.
IT'S NOT UP TO YOU TO SAVE ME, JACK.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
ONLY YOU CAN DO THAT.
I'M GOING BACK.
LEAVE ME ALONE.
Countess: TELL LUCILLE ABOUT THE DISASTER YOU HAD
WITH THE STATIONER'S.
WELL, OF COURSE, THE INVITATIONS HAD TO BE SENT BACK TWICE.
OH, MY DEAR!
AND THE DREADFUL BRIDESMAIDS' GOWNS--
LET ME TELL YOU WHAT AN ODYSSEY THAT HAS BEEN.
ROSE DECIDED SHE WANTED LAVENDER.
SHE KNOWS I DETEST THE COLOR
SO SHE DID IT ONLY TO SPITE ME.
Lucille: IF ONLY YOU'D COME TO ME SOONER.
RUTH SAW SOME OF MY DESIGNS
IN "LA MODE ILLUSTREE."
THEY WERE FOR THE TROUSSEAU
OF THE DUCHESS OF MALBOROUGH'S YOUNGEST DAUGHTER.
THEY WERE QUITE CHARMING
BUT I THINK YOU'LL AGREE, MY DEAR
THAT TOGETHER WE'VE CREATED
SOMETHING OF A PHOENIX FROM THE ASHES.
HELLO, JACK.
I CHANGED MY MIND.
THEY SAID YOU MIGHT BE...
SHH...
GIVE ME YOUR HAND.
NOW CLOSE YOUR EYES.
GO ON.
STEP UP.
NOW HOLD ON TO THE RAILING.
KEEP YOUR EYES CLOSED, DON'T PEEK.
I'M NOT.
STEP UP ONTO THE RAIL.
HOLD ON...
HOLD ON.
KEEP YOUR EYES CLOSED.
DO YOU TRUST ME?
I TRUST YOU.
ALL RIGHT...
OPEN YOUR EYES.
I'M FLYING!
JACK!
♪ COME, JOSEPHINE, MY FLYING MACHINE ♪
♪ GOING UP, SHE GOES, UP, SHE GOES... ♪
THAT WAS THE LAST TIME TITANIC EVER SAW DAYLIGHT.
SO WE'RE UP TO DUSK THE NIGHT OF THE SINKING.
SIX HOURS TO GO.
INCREDIBLE.
THERE'S SMITH AND HE'S STANDING THERE
AND HE'S GOT THE ICEBERG WARNING
IN HIS FUCKING HAND-- EXCUSE ME-- HIS HAND
AND HE'S ORDERING MORE SPEED.
26 YEARS OF EXPERIENCE WORKING AGAINST HIM.
HE FIGURES ANYTHING BIG ENOUGH TO SINK THE SHIP
THEY'RE GOING TO SEE IN TIME TO TURN
BUT THE SHIP'S TOO BIG WITH TOO SMALL A RUDDER.
DOESN'T CORNER WORTH A DAMN.
EVERYTHING HE KNOWS IS WRONG.
IT'S QUITE PROPER, I ASSURE YOU.
THIS IS THE SITTING ROOM.
WILL THIS LIGHT DO?
WHAT?
DON'T ARTISTS NEED GOOD LIGHT?
THAT IS TRUE, BUT I'M NOT USED TO WORKING
IN SUCH HORRIBLE CONDITIONS.
MONET!
DO YOU KNOW HIS WORK?
OF COURSE.
LOOK AT HIS USE OF COLOR HERE.
ISN'T HE GREAT?
I KNOW, IT'S EXTRAORDINARY.
CAL INSISTS ON CARTING THIS HIDEOUS THING EVERYWHERE.
SHOULD WE BE EXPECTING HIM ANYTIME SOON?
NOT AS LONG AS THE CIGARS AND BRANDY HOLD OUT.
THAT'S NICE.
WHAT IS IT, A SAPPHIRE?
A DIAMOND, A VERY RARE DIAMOND.
JACK, I WANT YOU TO DRAW ME
LIKE ONE OF YOUR FRENCH GIRLS...
WEARING THIS.
ALL RIGHT.
WEARING ONLY THIS.
THE LAST THING I NEED IS ANOTHER PICTURE OF ME
LOOKING LIKE A PORCELAIN DOLL.
AS A PAYING CUSTOMER...
I EXPECT TO GET WHAT I WANT.
OVER ON THE BED... THE COUCH.
GO... LIE DOWN.
TELL ME WHEN IT LOOKS RIGHT.
PUT YOUR ARM BACK THE WAY IT WAS.
RIGHT.
PUT THAT OTHER ARM UP, THAT HAND RIGHT BY YOUR FACE THERE.
NOW, HEAD DOWN...
EYES TO ME, KEEP THEM ON ME.
AND TRY TO STAY STILL.
SO SERIOUS.
I BELIEVE YOU ARE BLUSHING, MR. BIG ARTISTE.
I CAN'T IMAGINE MONSIEUR MONET BLUSHING.
HE DOES LANDSCAPES.
JUST RELAX YOUR FACE.
SORRY.
NO LAUGHING.
MY HEART WAS POUNDING THE WHOLE TIME.
IT WAS THE MOST EROTIC MOMENT OF MY LIFE.
UP UNTIL THEN, AT LEAST.
SO WHAT HAPPENED NEXT?
YOU MEAN, DID WE DO IT?
SORRY, TO DISAPPOINT YOU, MR. BODINE.
JACK WAS VERY PROFESSIONAL.
THANK YOU.
WHAT YOU DOING?
WILL YOU PUT THIS BACK IN THE SAFE FOR ME?
MM-HMM.
WOULD YOU EXCUSE ME?
NONE OF THE STEWARDS HAVE SEEN HER.
THIS IS ABSURD.
IT'S A SHIP, THERE'S ONLY SO MANY PLACES SHE COULD BE.
LOVEJOY, FIND HER.
CLEAR.
YES.
I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER SEEN SUCH A FLAT CALM.
LIKE A MILL POND.
NOT A BREATH OF WIND.
IT WILL MAKE THE BERGS HARDER TO SEE
WITH NO BREAKING WATER AT THE BASE.
HMM.
WELL, I'M OFF.
MAINTAIN SPEED AND HEADING
MR. LIGHTOLLER.
YES, SIR.
IT'S GETTING COLD.
YOU LOOK NICE.
Lovejoy: MISS ROSE?
MY DRAWINGS!
COME ON!
NO, WAIT, WAIT! WAIT, WAIT, WAIT!
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT!
GO, GO!
DOWN, DOWN!
Rose: QUICKLY, QUICKLY!
BYE!
SORRY!
IT'S ALL RIGHT!
PRETTY TOUGH FOR A VALET, THIS FELLOW.
SEEMS MORE LIKE A COP.
I THINK HE WAS.
Jack: OH, SHIT.
NO, OVER HERE!
QUICK!
NOW WHAT?!
WHAT?!
HOLD UP!
WHAT'RE YOU TWO DOING DOWN HERE?
YOU SHOULDN'T BE DOWN HERE!
IT COULD BE DANGEROUS!
Jack: CARRY ON!
DON'T MIND US, YOU'RE DOING A GREAT JOB!
KEEP UP THE GOOD WORK!
AH, LOOK WHAT WE HAVE HERE, HUH?
THANK YOU.
WHERE TO, MISS?
TO THE STARS.
YOU NERVOUS?
NO.
PUT YOUR HANDS ON ME, JACK.
Crewman: GOD, IT'S BLOODY COLD.
YOU KNOW, I CAN SMELL ICE, YOU KNOW...
WHEN IT'S NEAR.
BOLLOCKS.
BUT I CAN, ALL RIGHT!
Murdoch: DID YOU EVER FIND THOSE BINOCULARS
FOR THE LOOKOUTS?
HAVEN'T SEEN THEM SINCE SOUTHAMPTON.
WELL, I'LL BE ON MY ROUNDS.
CHEERIO.
YOU'RE TREMBLING.
DON'T WORRY, I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
THEY RAN DOWN THERE.
RIGHT.
Lovejoy: ANYTHING MISSING?
I'VE GOT A BETTER IDEA.
GOTCHA!
DID YOU SEE THOSE GUYS' FACES?
DID YOU SEE THE...?
WHEN THE SHIP DOCKS...
I'M GETTING OFF WITH YOU.
THIS IS CRAZY.
I KNOW.
IT DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
THAT'S WHY I TRUST IT.
OH, YES...
HERE, LOOK AT THIS.
OH, LOOK AT THAT
WOULD YOU?
THEY'RE A BIT WARMER THAN WE ARE.
WELL, IF THAT'S WHAT IT TAKES
FOR US TO GET WARMER I'D RATHER NOT
IF IT'S ALL THE SAME TO YOU.
BUGGER ME!
PICK UP, YOU BASTARDS.
Is there anyone there?
YES, WHAT DO YOU SEE?
ICEBERG! RIGHT AHEAD!
THANK YOU.
HARD TO STARBOARD!
Crewman: HARD TO STARBOARD!
Crewman: TURN, TURN! STEADY!
FULL ASTERN!
HARD OVER.
HELM'S HARD OVER, SIR.
GO, LADS! GO!
SHUT ALL THE DAMPERS!
SHUT THEM!
HOLD IT.
HOLD IT!
NOW, ENGAGE THE REVERSING ENGINE!
WHY AREN'T THEY TURNING?!
IS IT HARD OVER?!
Crewman: IT IS, YES, SIR, HARD OVER!
COME ON... COME ON... COME ON...
TURN.
YES...
IT'S GOING TO HIT!
JESUS CHRIST.
JESUS...
HARD TO PORT!
Crewman: HARD TO THE PORT!
GET BACK!
COME ON, LET'S GO!
GET OUT THE DOOR! THEY'RE CLOSING THE DOORS!
GET OUT!
GET OUT! GET OUT!
GET OUT THE DOOR!
GO ON!
GO ON! COME ON, LADS!
GO, LADS, GO!
GET OUT!
: OH, MY GOD...
THAT WAS A CLOSE SHAVE, WEREN'T IT?
SMELL ICE, CAN YOU?
BLEEDING CHRIST.
NOTE THE TIME AND ENTER IT IN THE LOG.
WHAT WAS THAT, MR. MURDOCH?
AN ICEBERG, SIR.
I PUT HER HARD TO STARBOARD
AND RAN THE ENGINES FULL ASTERN
BUT IT WAS TOO CLOSE.
I TRIED TO PORT ROUND IT BUT SHE HIT AND THE...
CLOSE THE WATERTIGHT DOORS.
Murdoch: THE DOORS ARE CLOSED, SIR.
ALL STOP.
Crewman: AYE, SIR!
FIND THE CARPENTER.
GET HIM TO SOUND THE SHIP.
YES, SIR!
Fabrizio: PORCA PUTTANA!
CHE CAZZO E?
COME ON, LET'S GET THE HELL OUT OF HERE!
COME ON, HURRY UP.
EXCUSE ME.
WHY HAVE THE ENGINES STOPPED?
I FELT A SHUDDER.
I SHOULDN'T WORRY, MADAM.
WE'VE LIKELY THROWN A PROPELLER BLADE.
THAT'S THE SHUDDER YOU FELT.
MAY I BRING YOU ANYTHING?
NO, THANK YOU.
Man: DID YOU SEE ANYTHING?
Man: I DON'T SEE ANYTHING NOW, DO YOU?
IF THIS IS THE DIRECTION THE RATS ARE GOING
THAT'S GOOD ENOUGH FOR ME.
Crewman: PLEASE, SIR, PLEASE.
EVERYTHING'S UNDER CONTROL.
YOU THERE.
SIR, THERE IS NO EMERGENCY.
YES, THERE IS, I HAVE BEEN ROBBED.
GET THE MASTER-AT-ARMS.
NOW, YOU MORON!
YES, SIR.
HEY, YOU'RE GOING TO MISS THE FUN.
DID YOU SEE WHAT HAPPEN?
NO, I MISSED IT.
APPARENTLY, IT HIT OVER THERE.
Crewman: BOILER ROOM SIX IS FLOODED EIGHT FEET ABOVE THE PLATE
AND THE MAIL HOLD IS WORSE.
SHE'S ALL BUCKLED IN IN THE FORWARD HOLD.
CAN YOU SHORE UP?
NOT UNLESS THE PUMPS GET AHEAD.
HAVE YOU SEEN THE DAMAGE IN THE MAIL HOLD?
NO, SHE'S ALREADY UNDERWATER.
THIS IS BAD.
WE SHOULD TELL MOTHER AND CAL.
I THINK THEY'RE VERY GOOD, SIR.
DON'T TOUCH ANYTHING.
I WANT THE ENTIRE ROOM PHOTOGRAPHED.
Rose: JUST KEEP HOLDING MY HAND.
WE'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR YOU, MISS.
Rose: WELL, HERE WE GO.
SOMETHING SERIOUS HAS HAPPENED.
YES, IT HAS...
INDEED. TWO THINGS DEAR TO ME HAVE DISAPPEARED THIS EVENING.
NOW THAT ONE IS BACK
I HAVE A PRETTY GOOD IDEA WHERE TO FIND THE OTHER.
SEARCH HIM.
TAKE YOUR COAT OFF, SIR.
NOW WHAT? COME ON.
CAL, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WE'RE IN THE MIDDLE
OF AN EMERGENCY.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
IS THIS IT? THAT'S IT.
THIS IS HORSESHIT!
DON'T YOU BELIEVE IT, ROSE.
DON'T!
HE COULDN'T HAVE.
OF COURSE HE COULD.
IT'S EASY ENOUGH FOR A PROFESSIONAL.
BUT I WAS WITH HIM THE WHOLE TIME.
THIS IS ABSURD.
PERHAPS HE DID IT
WHILE YOU WERE PUTTING
YOUR CLOTHES BACK ON, DEAR.
REAL SLICK CAL. ROSE, THEY PUT IT IN MY POCKET.
SHUT UP.
IT ISN'T EVEN YOUR POCKET, IS IT, SON?
PROPERTY OF A. L. RYERSON.
THAT WAS REPORTED STOLEN TODAY.
I JUST BORROWED IT.
I WAS GOING TO RETURN IT.
WE HAVE AN HONEST THIEF HERE, DO WE?
YOU KNOW I DIDN'T DO THIS, ROSE.
YOU KNOW IT-- DON'T YOU BELIEVE THEM, ROSE.
YOU KNOW IT.
YOU KNOW I DIDN'T DO IT.
COME ON, LET'S GO.
YOU KNOW I DIDN'T DO IT, ROSE. ROSE!
COME ON, SON.
THERE'S A GOOD LAD.
COME ON.
YOU KNOW I DIDN'T DO IT!
YOU KNOW ME!
Ismay: MOST UNFORTUNATE, CAPTAIN.
WATER... 14 FEET ABOVE THE KEEL IN TEN MINUTES--
IN THE FOREPEAK
IN ALL THREE HOLDS AND IN BOILEROOM SIX.
THAT'S RIGHT, SIR.
WHEN CAN WE GET UNDER WAY, DAMN IT?
THAT'S FIVE COMPARTMENTS.
SHE CAN STAY AFLOAT
WITH THE FIRST FOUR COMPARTMENTS BREACHED
BUT NOT FIVE.
NOT FIVE.
AS SHE GOES DOWN BY THE HEAD
THE WATER WILL SPILL
OVER THE TOPS OF THE BULKHEADS
AT E DECK FROM ONE TO THE NEXT.
BACK AND BACK.
THERE'S NO STOPPING IT.
THE PUMPS...
IF WE OPENED THE DOORS...
THE PUMPS BUY YOU TIME, BUT MINUTES ONLY.
FROM THIS MOMENT
NO MATTER WHAT WE DO
TITANIC WILL FOUNDER.
BUT THIS SHIP CAN'T SINK.
SHE'S MADE OF IRON, SIR.
I ASSURE YOU, SHE CAN...
AND SHE WILL.
IT IS A MATHEMATICAL CERTAINTY.
HOW MUCH TIME?
AN HOUR.
TWO AT MOST.
AND HOW MANY ABOARD, MR. MURDOCH?
2,200 SOULS ON BOARD, SIR.
WELL, I BELIEVE YOU MAY GET YOUR HEADLINES, MR. ISMAY.
OH, IT IS A LITTLE SLUT, ISN'T IT?
WILL YOU LOOK AT ME WHEN I'M TALKING TO YOU.
MR. HOCKLEY?
NOT NOW, WE'RE BUSY.
SIR, I'VE BEEN TOLD TO ASK YOU
TO PLEASE PUT ON YOUR LIFEBELTS
AND COME UP TO THE...
I SAID NOT NOW.
I'M SORRY TO INCONVENIENCE YOU, MR. HOCKLEY
BUT IT'S CAPTAIN'S ORDERS.
NOW, PLEASE, DRESS WARMLY.
IT'S QUITE COLD OUT TONIGHT.
NOW, MAY I SUGGEST TOPCOATS AND HATS.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
NOT TO WORRY, MISS.
I AM SURE IT'S JUST A PRECAUTION.
EVERYBODY UP!
LIFEBELTS ON!
WHAT'S HE YELLING ABOUT?
EVERYBODY UP! PUT YOUR LIFEBELTS ON!
WHAT'S THE RUCKUS?
JUST PUT YOU LIFEBELTS ON!
Crewman: C.Q.D.?
SIR?
THAT'S RIGHT-- C.Q.D.
THE DISTRESS CALL.
THAT'S OUR POSITION.
TELL WHOEVER RESPONDS
THAT WE'RE GOING DOWN BY THE HEAD.
WE NEED IMMEDIATE ASSISTANCE.
BLIMEY.
KEEP LOWERING!
MR. WILDE!
MR. WILDE, WHERE ARE THE PASSENGERS?
WE MOVED THEM BACK INSIDE.
IT'S TOO DAMN COLD AND NOISY FOR THEM.
YOU THERE!
GET DOWN HERE AND HELP WITH THESE LINES.
CARE FOR A DRINK, SIR?
Crewman: PLEASE PUT YOUR LIFEBELTS ON.
HEY, SONNY, WHAT'S DOING?
YOU GOT US ALL TRUSSED UP HERE
AND NOW WE'RE COOLING OUR HEELS.
SORRY, MA'AM.
LET ME GO AND FIND OUT.
I DON'T THINK ANYBODY KNOWS
WHAT THE HELL'S GOING ON AROUND HERE.
IT'S THE GODDAMNED ENGLISH
DOING EVERYTHING BY THE... BOOK.
THERE'S NO NEED FOR LANGUAGE, MR. HOCKLEY.
GO BACK AND TURN THE HEATERS ON IN OUR ROOMS.
I'D LIKE A CUP OF TEA WHEN I RETURN.
YES, MA'AM.
MR. ANDREWS...
I SAW THE ICEBERG
AND I SEE IT IN YOUR EYES.
PLEASE TELL ME THE TRUTH.
THE SHIP WILL SINK.
YOU'RE CERTAIN.
YES, IN AN HOUR OR SO...
ALL THIS WILL BE
AT THE BOTTOM OF THE ATLANTIC.
WHAT?
PLEASE, TELL ONLY WHO YOU MUST.
I DON'T WANT TO BE RESPONSIBLE FOR A PANIC
AND GET TO A BOAT QUICKLY, DON'T WAIT.
YOU REMEMBER WHAT I TOLD YOU
ABOUT THE BOATS?
YES...
I UNDERSTAND.
OVER HERE, SIR.
SIR, THEY NEED YOU
UP IN THE SECOND-CLASS PURSER'S OFFICE.
THERE'S A BIG MOB UP THERE.
GO ON, I'LL KEEP AN EYE ON HIM.
AYE, RIGHT.
SIR!
CARPATHIA SAYS THEY'RE MAKING 17 KNOTS.
FULL STEAM FOR THEM, SIR.
SHE'S THE ONLY ONE WHO'S RESPONDING?
THE ONLY ONE CLOSE, SIR.
SHE SAYS THEY CAN BE HERE IN FOUR HOURS.
FOUR HOURS?
THANK YOU, BRIDE.
MY GOD.
SIR!
WE ARE SWUNG OUT AND READY, SIR.
HADN'T WE BETTER GET THE WOMEN AND CHILDREN
INTO THE BOAT, SIR?
YES, WE DO.
SIR?
WOMEN AND CHILDREN FIRST.
YES...
YES, SIR.
Crewman: LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, YOUR ATTENTION PLEASE!
STEP THIS WAY, PLEASE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
COME TOWARDS ME.
THANK YOU.
GOOD.
FOR THE TIME BEING
I SHALL REQUIRE ONLY WOMEN AND CHILDREN.
Man: RIGHT HERE.
ALL RIGHT, BOYS, LIKE THE CAPTAIN SAID
NICE AND CHEERY SO THERE'S NO PANIC.
"WEDDING DANCE."
LIFEBELTS ON!
HERE, PUT YOUR LIFEBELTS ON.
PUT YOUR LIFEBELTS ON.
HERE, PUT YOUR LIFEBELT ON.
HERE, COME ON, HERE.
Crewman: IT ISN'T TIME TO GO UP TO THE BOATS YET.
PLEASE STAY CALM.
LOOK, PLEASE, MAKE SURE EVERYBODY
YOU'VE GOT YOUR LIFEBELTS ON
AND GENTLEMEN, ALLOW THE WOMEN AND CHILDREN
THROUGH TO THE FRONT.
WHAT ARE WE DOING, MOMMY?
WE'RE JUST WAITING, DEAR.
WHEN THEY'RE FINISHED PUTTING
THE FIRST-CLASS PEOPLE IN THE BOATS THEY'LL START WITH US
AND WE'LL WANT TO BE ALL READY, WON'T WE?
GO AND GET SOME HELP.
LOWER AWAY!
LEFT AND RIGHT TOGETHER!
STEADY!
BOTH SIDES TOGETHER!
HOLD THE LEFT SIDE!
RIGHT SIDE ONLY!
RIGHT SIDE DOWN!
LOWER AWAY TOGETHER!
STEADY, LADS!
YOU KNOW, I DO BELIEVE THIS SHIP MAY SINK.
I'VE BEEN ASKED TO GIVE YOU
THIS SMALL TOKEN OF OUR APPRECIATION.
COMPLIMENTS OF MR. CALEDON HOCKLEY.
COME ON, SISTER, YOU HEARD THE MAN-- INTO THE BOAT.
ANY ROOM FOR A GENTLEMAN, GENTLEMEN?
Crewman: ONLY WOMEN AT THIS TIME, SIR.
WILL THE LIFEBOATS BE SEATED
ACCORDING TO CLASS?
I HOPE THEY'RE NOT TOO CROWDED.
OH, MOTHER...
SHUT UP!
DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
THE WATER IS FREEZING AND THERE AREN'T ENOUGH BOATS.
NOT ENOUGH BY HALF.
HALF THE PEOPLE ON THIS SHIP ARE GOING TO DIE.
NOT THE BETTER HALF.
COME ON, RUTH, GET IN THE BOAT.
FIRST-CLASS SEATS ARE RIGHT UP HERE.
YOU KNOW, IT'S A PITY
I DIDN'T KEEP THAT DRAWING.
IT'LL BE WORTH A LOT MORE BY MORNING.
YOU UNIMAGINABLE BASTARD.
Molly: COME ON, ROSE, DARLING.
THERE'S PLENTY OF ROOM FOR YOU.
COME ON, ROSE.
YOU'RE NEXT, DARLING.
COME INTO THE BOAT, ROSE.
COME.
ROSE...
GET INTO THE BOAT.
ROSE.
GOOD-BYE, MOTHER.
ROSE!
ROSE, COME BACK HERE!
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
TO HIM?!
TO BE A WHORE TO A GUTTER RAT?
I'D RATHER BE HIS WHORE THAN YOUR WIFE.
NO... NO!
I SAID NO!
Ruth: ROSE!
PLEASE STOP!
Crewman: AND LOWER AWAY!
ROSE!!
MAN THE TILLER!
NO, WAIT!
LOWER AWAY!
ROSE!
LOWER TOGETHER!
HELP!
CAN ANYBODY HEAR ME?
HELLO, HELP ME!
HELP ME!
CAN ANYBODY HEAR ME?
SOMEBODY HELP ME, PLEASE!
Rose: MR. ANDREWS?
STEWARD, CHECK THE STARBOARD CORRIDOR.
YES, MR. ANDREWS.
MADAM, PLEASE, PUT ON A LIFEBELT.
GET TO THE BOAT DECK IMMEDIATELY.
LUCY, FOR GOD'S SAKE, PUT ON YOUR LIFEBELT.
SET A GOOD EXAMPLE.
YES, SIR.
ANYONE IN HERE?
MR. ANDREWS?
MR. ANDREWS, THANK GOD.
WHERE WOULD THE MASTER- AT-ARMS TAKE SOMEONE UNDER ARREST?
WHAT? YOU HAVE TO GET TO A BOAT RIGHT AWAY.
NO!
I'M DOING THIS WITH OR WITHOUT YOUR HELP, SIR
BUT WITHOUT WILL TAKE LONGER.
TAKE THE ELEVATOR TO THE VERY BOTTOM.
GO TO THE LEFT DOWN THE CREWMEN'S PASSAGE.
THEN GO RIGHT AND LEFT AGAIN AT THE STAIRS.
YOU'LL COME TO A LONG CORRIDOR.
THIS COULD BE BAD.
OH, SHIT.
OH, SHIT!
EXCUSE ME, THANK YOU.
Crewman: THE LIFTS ARE CLOSED.
Woman: I DO NOT CARE...
THE LIFTS ARE...
I'M SORRY, MISS, BUT THE LIFTS ARE CLOSED.
I'M THROUGH BEING POLITE, GODDAMN IT!
NOW TAKE ME DOWN!
E DECK.
COME ON.
OH, COME ON.
I'M GOING BACK UP!
NO!
NO, NO!
COME BACK!
I'M GOING BACK UP.
I'M GOING BACK UP!
CREW PASSAGE...
CREW PASSAGE.
JACK?
JACK?!
ROSE!
ROSE, I'M IN HERE!
I'M IN HERE.
JACK?!
JACK?! ROSE!
JACK! JACK!
I'M SORRY.
I'M SO SORRY.
THAT GUY LOVEJOY PUT IT IN MY POCKET.
I KNOW, I KNOW, I KNOW, I KNOW.
LISTEN, ROSE, YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO FIND A SPARE KEY, ALL RIGHT?
LOOK IN THAT CABINET RIGHT THERE.
IT'S A LITTLE SILVER ONE, ROSE.
THESE ARE ALL BRASS ONES!
CHECK RIGHT HERE, ROSE.
ROSE...
HOW DID YOU FIND OUT I DIDN'T DO IT?
I DIDN'T.
I JUST REALIZED I ALREADY KNEW.
KEEP LOOKING.
OH.
NO KEY.
THERE'S NO KEY!
ALL RIGHT, ROSE, LISTEN.
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO GO FIND SOME HELP.
IT'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
I'LL JUST WAIT HERE.
HELLO, IS THERE ANYONE HERE?
HELLO?
IS THERE ANYBODY DOWN HERE?
WE NEED HELP! HELLO!
DAMN IT.
CAN ANYBODY HEAR ME?
PLEASE, HELLO!
HELLO!
OH, THANK GOD.
WAIT, PLEASE, I NEED YOUR HELP.
THERE'S A MAN BACK HERE AND...
WAIT!
HELLO?
AH, MISS, YOU SHOULDN'T BE HERE, NOW.
PLEASE, I NEED YOUR HELP.
THIS WAY, QUICKLY.
THERE IS A MAN DOWN HERE
AND HE IS TRAPPED. PLEASE.
THERE'S NO NEED TO PANIC.
NO, I'M NOT PANICKING.
YOU'RE GOING THE WRONG WAY!
LET GO OF ME, LISTEN!
TO HELL WITH YOU.
OH!
OH, MY GOD...
JACK!
ROSE!
WILL THIS WORK?
I GUESS WE'LL FIND OUT.
COME ON.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
TRY A COUPLE PRACTICE SWINGS OVER THERE.
GOOD, NOW TRY TO HIT THE SAME MARK AGAIN, ROSE.
YOU CAN DO IT.
OKAY, THAT'S ENOUGH PRACTICE.
COME ON, ROSE, YOU CAN DO IT.
LISTEN, JUST HIT IT REALLY HARD AND REALLY FAST.
WAIT, OPEN YOUR HANDS UP A LITTLE MORE.
LIKE THAT?
RIGHT.
LISTEN, ROSE, I TRUST YOU.
GO!
YOU DID IT!
COME ON, LET'S GO.
OH, SHIT, THIS IS COLD.
OH, SHIT!
SHIT, SHIT.
THIS IS THE WAY OUT.
WE HAVE TO FIND ANOTHER WAY.
COME ON.
Tiller: PULL.
PULL.
PUT YOUR BACKS INTO IT, PULL!
PULL!
NOW, THERE'S SOMETHING YOU DON'T SEE EVERY DAY.
Crewman: WHAT'S THIS LUGGAGE DOING HERE?
GET RID OF IT, WE NEED THE ROOM.
KEEP CALM.
NO!
LOVEJOY.
SHE'S NOT ON THE STARBOARD SIDE EITHER.
WE'RE RUNNING OUT OF TIME
AND THIS STRUTTING MARTINET
ISN'T LETTING ANY MEN ON AT ALL.
THERE'S ONE ON THE OTHER SIDE LETTING MEN ON.
WELL, THEN, THAT'S OUR PLAY.
WE'LL NEED SOME INSURANCE FIRST.
COME ON.
THIS WAY.
ALL THE WAY DOWN HERE.
Steward: HERE!
WHAT DO YOU THINK YOU'RE DOING?
YOU'LL HAVE TO PAY FOR THAT, YOU KNOW.
THAT'S WHITE STAR LINE PROPERTY.
Both: SHUT UP!
WILL YOU HOLD THE BOAT A MOMENT?
I JUST HAVE TO RUN BACK TO MY ROOM...
SIT DOWN!
SHE'S THE LAST.
ALL RIGHT TO LOWER.
MR. LIGHTOLLER, WHY ARE THE BOATS
BEING LAUNCHED HALF FULL?
NOT NOW, MR. ANDREWS.
THERE, LOOK, 20 OR SO
IN A BOAT BUILT FOR 65
AND I SAW ONE BOAT WITH ONLY 12-- 12!
WELL, WE WEREN'T SURE OF THE WEIGHT, MR. ANDREWS.
THESE BOATS MAY BUCKLE.
RUBBISH.
THEY WERE TESTED IN BELFAST
WITH THE WEIGHT OF 70 MEN!
NOW, FILL THESE BOATS, MR. LIGHTOLLER
FOR GOD'S SAKE, MAN!
PLEASE, I NEED MORE WOMEN AND CHILDREN, PLEASE.
Crewman: GET BACK IN THERE.
THIS IS NOT AN EXIT.
GET BACK IN THERE.
YOU CAN'T KEEP US LOCKED IN HERE LIKE ANIMALS.
THE SHIP'S BLOODY SINKING!
BRING FORWARD THE WOMEN!
UNLOCK THE GATES.
WOMEN ONLY!
NO MEN!
GET BACK!
LOCK THE GATES!
GET THEM BACK FROM THOSE GATES!
DON'T TOUCH THE GATES!
FOR GOD'S SAKE, MAN, THERE ARE WOMEN AND CHILDREN DOWN HERE!
LET US UP SO WE CAN HAVE A CHANCE!
GET BACK!
JACK!
TOMMY!
CAN WE GET OUT?
IT'S HOPELESS THAT WAY!
WHATEVER WE DO
WE'VE GOT TO DO IT FAST.
JACK!
FABRIZIO!
THE BOATS ARE ALL GONE.
THIS WHOLE PLACE IS FLOODING.
THERE IS NIENTE THIS WAY.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO THIS WAY, ALL RIGHT?
COME ON.
I MAKE MY OWN LUCK.
SO DO I.
COME ON!
NO, COME ON, LET'S GO THIS WAY.
THIS WAY.
Steward: JUST GO BACK
TO THE MAIN STAIRWELL
AND EVERYTHING WILL BE SORTED OUT THERE.
Man: HELL, IT WILL.
IT WILL ALL GET SORTED OUT BACK THERE.
GO BACK TO THE MAIN STAIRWELL.
OPEN THE GATE.
GO BACK DOWN THE MAIN STAIR.
OPEN THE GATE RIGHT NOW!
GO BACK DOWN THE MAIN STAIRWELL
LIKE I TOLD YOU.
GODDAMN IT!
SON OF A BITCH!
Man: OPEN THE DAMN GATE!
OPEN IT!
FABRI, TOMMY, GIVE ME A HAND HERE!
Rose: MOVE ASIDE. MOVE ASIDE.
COME ON, PULL!
PULL! PULL!
MOVE ASIDE!
Steward: PUT THAT DOWN.
ONE!
TWO!
STOP THAT!
THREE!
AGAIN!
Jack: LET'S GO!
Jack: LET'S GO, ROSE.
YOU CAN'T GO UP THERE.
YOU CAN'T DO THIS!
Lightoller: KEEP ORDER HERE.
BACK, BACK, BACK.
HOLD ON TO HER!
PULL HER IN!
GET BACK I SAY
OR I'LL SHOOT YOU ALL LIKE DOGS.
KEEP ORDER HERE!
KEEP ORDER, I SAY.
MR. LOWE, MAN THIS BOAT.
Lowe: RIGHT, IS EVERYBODY ALL RIGHT?
NOBODY PANIC.
Crewman: STAY BACK!
WE'RE TOO LATE.
THERE ARE MORE BOATS DOWN THE FRONT.
STAY WITH THIS ONE-- MURDOCH.
HE SEEMS TO BE QUITE PRACTICAL.
Lowe: SIT DOWN!
STAY BACK, YOU LOT.
STAY BACK!
STAY BACK, THE LOT OF YOU!
IT'S STARTING TO FALL APART.
WE DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME.
MR. MURDOCH?
MR. HOCKLEY...
YOU TWO, WITH ME, NOW.
I'M A BUSINESSMAN, AS YOU KNOW
AND I HAVE A BUSINESS PROPOSITION FOR YOU.
Crewman: EASY NOW.
ALL TOGETHER.
LOWER AWAY, LOWER AWAY.
Jack: COME ON, ROSE.
THE BOATS ARE GONE!
COLONEL, ARE THERE ANY BOATS ON THAT SIDE?
NO, MISS, BUT THERE ARE A COUPLE OF BOATS ALL THE WAY FORWARD.
THIS WAY, I'LL LEAD YOU.
WHAT'S THE USE?
NOBODY'S LISTENING TO US ANYWAY.
WELL, THEY DON'T LISTEN TO US AT DINNER EITHER.
COME ON, LET'S PLAY.
KEEP US WARM.
"ORPHEUS."
MUSIC TO DROWN BY.
NOW I KNOW I'M IN FIRST CLASS.
WHERE IS EVERYONE?
THEY'RE ALL STILL AFT, SIR.
WE HAVE AN UNDERSTANDING THEN, MR. MURDOCH?
WOMEN AND CHILDREN ONLY!
GET BACK!
STEP BACK, SIR.
COME THROUGH, MADAM.
THIS WAY.
STEP BACK, SIR.
YOU'D BETTER CHECK THE OTHER SIDE.
GO!
Crewman: ANY MORE WOMEN AND CHILDREN?
I FOUND HER ON THE OTHER SIDE.
WAITING FOR A BOAT...
WITH HIM.
ANY MORE WOMEN AND CHILDREN?
THEY'RE ALL ABOARD, MR. MURDOCH.
ANYONE ELSE, THEN?
ANYONE ELSE?
HURRY ALONG.
STAND BY THE FALLS.
OH, GODDAMN IT ALL TO HELL.
SHIT.
FIRE!
SIR!
SIR, YOU CAN'T GO THROUGH HERE.
SIR, YOU CAN'T GO THROUGH.
YES, YES, SPLENDID.
RIGHT.
Murdoch: PREPARE TO LOWER!
READY ON THE LEFT.
TAKE THEM DOWN.
KEEP IT STEADY.
BOTH SIDES TOGETHER, STEADY.
GIVE HER TO ME.
Girl: DADDY...
Man: IT'LL BE FINE, DARLING.
DON'T YOU WORRY.
IT'S GOOD-BYE FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
ONLY FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
THERE'LL BE ANOTHER BOAT FOR THE DADDIES.
THIS BOAT'S FOR THE MUMMIES AND THE CHILDREN.
YOU HOLD MUMMY'S HAND AND BE A GOOD LITTLE GIRL.
I'M NOT GOING WITHOUT YOU.
NO, YOU HAVE TO GO... NOW!
NO, JACK.
GET IN THE BOAT, ROSE.
YES, GET ON THE BOAT.
YES, GET ON THE BOAT, ROSE.
MY GOD, LOOK AT YOU.
YOU LOOK A FRIGHT.
HERE.
PUT THIS ON.
COME.
GO ON, I'LL GET THE NEXT ONE.
NO, NOT WITHOUT YOU.
Jack: I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
LISTEN, I'LL BE FINE.
I'M A SURVIVOR, ALL RIGHT?
DON'T WORRY ABOUT ME.
Jack: NOW GO ON, GET ON.
I HAVE AN ARRANGEMENT WITH AN OFFICER
ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THE SHIP.
JACK AND I CAN GET OFF SAFELY.
BOTH OF US.
SEE.
GOT MY OWN BOAT TO CATCH.
Cal: NOW, HURRY.
THEY'RE ALMOST FULL.
STEP ABOARD, MISS.
Cal: COME ON, HURRY.
STEP ABOARD, PLEASE.
Man: BE DADDY'S GOOD GIRL.
STEP LIVELY.
Crewman: KEEP BACK, KEEP BACK, I SAY.
CLEAR THE ROW, PLEASE.
LOWER AWAY!
Crewman: SLOWLY...
KEEP GOING, KEEP GOING.
AND LOWER AWAY EVENLY, LADS.
EASY. LOWER AWAY.
YOU'RE A GOOD LIAR.
ALMOST AS GOOD AS YOU.
Crewman: EASY NOW... AND LOWER AWAY.
THERE'S NO, UH...
THERE'S NO ARRANGEMENT, IS THERE?
NO, THERE IS.
NOT THAT YOU'LL BENEFIT MUCH FROM IT.
I ALWAYS WIN, JACK...
ONE WAY OR ANOTHER.
Crewman: EASY... EVEN, LADS.
KEEP GOING, KEEP GOING.
ROSE!
STOP HER!
Jack: ROSE, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
Cal: STOP HER!
NO!
ROSE.
YOU'RE SO STUPID.
WHY'D YOU DO THAT?
YOU'RE SO STUPID, ROSE.
WHY DID YOU DO THAT? WHY?
YOU JUMP, I JUMP, RIGHT?
RIGHT.
OH, GOD, I COULDN'T GO.
I COULDN'T GO, JACK.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL THINK OF SOMETHING.
Rose: AT LEAST I'M WITH YOU.
COME ON!
COME ON, MOVE!
COME ON.
MOVE!
COME ON, COME ON, ROSE.
COME ON.
ROSE, COME ON!
MOVE, ROSE!
I HOPE YOU ENJOY YOUR TIME TOGETHER.
WHAT COULD POSSIBLY BE FUNNY?
I PUT THE DIAMOND IN THE COAT.
AND I PUT THE COAT ON HER!
COME ON.
WE CAN'T LEAVE HIM.
ALL RIGHT, COME ON.
GO BACK!
IT'S THE WRONG WAY!
COME BACK.
GO!
JACK!
ROSE!
THIS WAY.
COME ON.
GIVE ME YOUR HAND.
OH, GOD!
HELP!
WAIT, SIR, OPEN THE GATE, PLEASE.
PLEASE.
HELP US.
PLEASE!
BLOODY HELL.
COME ON, COME ON.
COME ON.
GO, GO!
JESUS.
PLEASE.
COME ON!
HURRY.
COME ON.
I'M SORRY, I DROPPED THE KEYS.
WAIT! PLEASE!
DON'T LEAVE, PLEASE!
GET MORE HELP!
I GOT THEM.
WHICH ONE IS IT, ROSE?
THE SHARP ONE, TRY THE SHARP ONE.
HURRY, JACK.
OH, NO.
IT'S STUCK.
HURRY.
HURRY, JACK!
HURRY!
I GOT IT, I GOT IT!
GO! GO, ROSE!
GO, GO!
JACK!
JACK, COME ON!
MOVE, MOVE!
Crewman: KEEP ON ROCKING.
OARS IN PLACE.
GET AN OAR UNDER IT.
Murdoch: WOMEN AND CHILDREN ONLY, DAMN YOU.
Crewman: HOLD IT, HOLD IT.
GET THESE DAVITS CRANKED IN.
THEN GET THE FALLS HOOKED UP.
Murdoch: STAY BACK.
Child: HELP ME.
KEEP GOING UP.
Murdoch: STOP PUSHING!
STAY BACK!
WILL YOU GIVE US A CHANCE TO LIVE, YOU LIMEY BASTARD?
I'LL SHOOT ANY MAN WHO TRIES TO GET PAST ME-- GET BACK!
BASTARD!
GET BACK!
WE HAD A DEAL, DAMN YOU.
YOUR MONEY CAN'T SAVE YOU ANY MORE THAN IT CAN SAVE ME.
GET BACK.
Crewman: WOMEN AND CHILDREN ONLY!
TOMMY, NO, TOMMY...
BASTARDO!
OH, NO, OH, NO...
OH, NO, TOMMY...
NO, WILL!
STAND BACK, DAMN YOU.
I HAVE A CHILD.
Cal: I HAVE A CHILD.
CLEAR A PATH HERE.
PLEASE, I HAVE A CHILD.
PLEASE, I'M ALL SHE HAS IN THE WORLD.
GO ON.
STEP BACK, STEP BACK, I SAY.
PLEASE.
Woman: HERE, GIVE HER TO ME.
GIVE HER HERE.
THERE, THERE.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
MR. ANDREWS.
OH, ROSE.
WON'T YOU EVEN MAKE A TRY FOR IT?
I'M SORRY THAT I DIDN'T BUILD YOU
A STRONGER SHIP, YOUNG ROSE.
IT'S GOING FAST.
WE HAVE TO MOVE.
WAIT.
GOOD LUCK TO YOU, ROSE.
AND TO YOU.
MR. GUGGENHEIM.
THESE ARE FOR YOU, MR. GUGGENHEIM.
NO, THANK YOU.
WE ARE DRESSED IN OUR BEST
AND ARE PREPARED TO GO DOWN AS GENTLEMEN.
BUT WE WOULD LIKE A BRANDY.
CAPITAN.
CAPITAN, WHERE SHOULD I GO?
PLEASE.
Crewman: CAPTAIN!
CAPTAIN, SIR.
RIGHT, THAT'S IT, THEN.
GOOD-BYE, WALLY, GOOD LUCK.
SO LONG, OLD CHAP.
AND SO THEY LIVED HAPPILY TOGETHER
FOR 300 YEARS
IN THE LAND OF TIR NA NOG
THE LAND OF ETERNAL YOUTH AND BEAUTY.
THERE'S NO TIME!
CUT THOSE FALLS.
CUT THEM, CUT THEM IF YOU HAVE TO.
Crewman: I NEED A KNIFE.
I NEED A KNIFE.
Crewman: CUT HER LOOSE.
CUT THOSE BLOODY FALLS.
GENTLEMEN, IT HAS BEEN A PRIVILEGE
PLAYING WITH YOU TONIGHT.
WE HAVE TO STAY ON THE SHIP
AS LONG AS POSSIBLE!
COME ON!
Jack: THIS WAY.
OVER THE RAIL!
COME ON... JUMP!
COME ON!
Jack: I GOT YOU-- JUMP!
I'VE GOT YOU, MISS!
JACK!
Jack: COME ON!
Cal: GET BACK!
NO! YOU'LL SWAMP US.
YEA, THOUGH I WALK THROUGH THE VALLEY OF THE SHADOW OF DEATH...
YOU WANT TO WALK A LITTLE FASTER THROUGH THAT VALLEY THERE?
ROW!
PULL TOGETHER!
Priest: HOLY MARY, MOTHER OF GOD
PRAY FOR US SINNERS NOW AND AT THE HOUR OF OUR DEATH, AMEN.
HAIL MARY, FULL OF GRACE
THE LORD IS WITH THEE. THIS WAY.
BLESSED ART THOU...
Jack: COME ON.
COME ON!
I SAW A NEW HEAVEN AND A NEW EARTH
WHEN THE FIRST HEAVEN AND THE FIRST EARTH HAD PASSED AWAY...
...AND THERE WAS NO MORE SEA.
Woman: HELP ME!
IT'LL BE OVER SOON.
IT'LL ALL BE OVER SOON.
Priest: AND HE SHALL DWELL WITH THEM
AND THEY SHALL BE HIS PEOPLE
AND GOD HIMSELF SHALL BE WITH THEM...
JACK...
THIS IS WHERE WE FIRST MET.
AND GOD SHALL WIPE AWAY ALL THE TEARS FROM THEIR EYES
AND THERE SHALL BE NO MORE DEATH.
NEITHER SHALL THERE BE SORROW OR CRYING.
NEITHER SHALL THERE BE ANY MORE PAIN
FOR THE FORMER WORLD HAS PASSED AWAY.
BLOODY PULL FASTER, AND PULL!
Man: HANG ON, MISS TRUDY!
Man: HELP ME! PLEASE, SAVE ME!
Woman: HELP!
Jack: HOLD ON REAL TIGHT!
GOD ALMIGHTY!
Crewman: GET THOSE BREAKERS IN! KEEP THEM IN!
WE HAVE TO MOVE!
GIVE ME YOUR HAND, I'LL PULL YOU OVER.
Rose: I CAN'T!
COME ON, GIVE ME YOUR HAND!
I'VE GOT YOU.
I WON'T LET GO.
COME ON, I'VE GOT YOU.
WHAT'S HAPPENING, JACK?
I DON'T KNOW, I DON'T KNOW!
Jack: HOLD ON!
Rose: JACK!
THAT WAS CLOSE.
Man: HELP ME, PLEASE, SOMEONE HELP ME, PLEASE!
Woman: PLEASE HELP! HELP! HELP! HELP!
THIS IS IT!
Rose: OH, GOD, OH, GOD!
HOLD ON!
OH, GOD, OH, GOD, OH!
THE SHIP IS GOING TO SUCK US DOWN.
TAKE A DEEP BREATH WHEN I SAY.
KICK FOR THE SURFACE AND KEEP KICKING.
DO NOT LET GO
OF MY HAND.
WE'RE GOING TO MAKE IT, ROSE.
TRUST ME.
I TRUST YOU.
READY? READY?
NOW!
JACK! JACK!
JACK!
JACK.
JACK! JACK!
NO!
JACK!
ROSE!
GET OFF HER!
JACK!
SWIM, ROSE!
I NEED YOU TO SWIM!
KEEP SWIMMING!
IT'S SO COLD!
SWIM, ROSE!
COME ON... HERE...
KEEP SWIMMING... COME ON.
HERE, GET ON IT.
GET ON TOP.
COME ON, ROSE.
STAY ON IT, STAY ON, ROSE.
JACK.
YOU'LL BE ALL RIGHT NOW.
Crewman: RETURN...
THE BOATS!
THE BOATS ARE COMING BACK FOR US, ROSE.
HOLD ON JUST A LITTLE BIT LONGER.
Crewman: RETURN THE BOATS!
THEY... HAD TO ROW AWAY FOR THE SUCTION
BUT NOW THEY'LL BE COMING BACK.
Woman: COME BACK!
FOR GOD'S SAKE!
PLEASE!
HELP US!
COME BACK!
FOR GOD'S SAKE!
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
IF WE GO BACK, THEY'LL SWAMP THE BOAT.
THEY'LL PULL US RIGHT DOWN, I'M TELLING YOU.
KNOCK IT OFF-- YOU'RE SCARING ME.
COME ON, GIRLS-- GRAB AN OAR, LET'S GO!
Man: ARE YOU OUT OF YOUR MIND?
WE'RE IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NORTH ATLANTIC!
NOW, DO YOU PEOPLE WANT TO LIVE
OR DO YOU WANT TO DIE?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND A ONE OF YOU.
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU?
IT'S YOUR MEN OUT THERE!
THERE'S PLENTY OF ROOM FOR MORE.
AND THERE'LL BE ONE LESS ON THIS BOAT
IF YOU DON'T SHUT THAT HOLE IN YOUR FACE!
Woman: COME BACK!
Man: HERE, TAKE THIS ONE.
Lowe: NOW BRING IN YOUR OARS OVER THERE
AND TIE THESE TWO BOATS TOGETHER AS WELL.
NOW MAKE SURE THAT'S TIED UP NICE AND TIGHT.
RIGHT, LISTEN TO ME, MEN, WE HAVE TO GO BACK.
I WANT TO TRANSFER ALL THE WOMEN FROM THIS BOAT
INTO THAT BOAT RIGHT NOW
AS QUICK AS YOU CAN, PLEASE.
LET'S GET SOME SPACE THERE.
MOVE FORWARD AND AFT.
IT'S GETTING QUIET.
IT'S JUST GOING TO TAKE THEM A COUPLE OF MINUTES
TO GET THE BOATS ORGANIZED.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU
BUT I INTEND TO WRITE A STRONGLY WORDED LETTER
TO THE WHITE STAR LINE ABOUT ALL THIS.
I LOVE YOU, JACK.
DON'T YOU DO THAT.
DON'T YOU SAY YOUR GOOD-BYES.
NOT YET, DO YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
I'M SO COLD.
LISTEN, ROSE...
YOU'RE GOING TO GET OUT OF HERE.
YOU'RE GOING TO GO ON
AND YOU'RE GOING TO MAKE LOTS OF BABIES
AND YOU'RE GOING TO WATCH THEM GROW.
YOU'RE GOING TO DIE AN OLD... AN OLD LADY WARM IN HER BED.
NOT HERE.
NOT THIS NIGHT.
NOT LIKE THIS.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
I CAN'T FEEL MY BODY.
WINNING THAT TICKET, ROSE
WAS THE BEST THING THAT EVER HAPPENED TO ME.
IT BROUGHT ME TO YOU...
AND I'M THANKFUL FOR THAT, ROSE.
I'M THANKFUL.
YOU MUST... YOU MUST...
YOU MUST DO ME THIS HONOR...
YOU MUST PROMISE ME THAT YOU'LL SURVIVE...
THAT YOU WON'T GIVE UP...
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS...
NO MATTER HOW HOPELESS.
PROMISE ME NOW, ROSE...
AND NEVER LET GO OF THAT PROMISE.
I PROMISE.
NEVER LET GO.
I WILL NEVER LET GO, JACK.
I'LL NEVER LET GO.
Crewman: RIGHT AHEAD, SIR.
Lowe: OARS!
DO YOU SEE ANY MOVING?
NO, SIR. NONE MOVING, SIR.
CHECK THEM.
BRING THAT OAR UP HERE.
CHECK THEM, MAKE SURE.
THESE ARE DEAD, SIR.
NOW GIVE WAY.
AHEAD EASY.
CAREFUL WITH YOUR OARS.
DON'T HIT THEM.
IS THERE ANYONE ALIVE OUT THERE?
CAN ANYONE HEAR ME?
WE WAITED TOO LONG.
WELL, KEEP CHECKING THEM, KEEP LOOKING!
IS THERE ANYONE ALIVE OUT THERE?
CAN ANYONE HEAR ME?
♪ AND IT'S UP SHE GOES. ♪
♪ UP SHE GOES. ♪
JACK?
JACK.
JACK, THERE'S A BOAT.
JACK?
JACK.
JACK!
THERE'S A BOAT, JACK.
JACK?
COME BACK.
COME BACK, COME BACK.
HELLO!
CAN ANYONE HEAR ME?
THERE'S NOTHING HERE, SIR.
COME BACK.
I'LL NEVER LET GO.
I PROMISE.
COME ABOUT!
1,500 PEOPLE WENT INTO THE SEA WHEN TITANIC SANK FROM UNDER US.
THERE WERE 20 BOATS FLOATING NEARBY
AND ONLY ONE CAME BACK.
ONE.
SIX WERE SAVED FROM THE WATER
MYSELF INCLUDED.
SIX... OUT OF 1,500.
AFTERWARD, THE 700 PEOPLE IN THE BOATS
HAD NOTHING TO DO BUT WAIT...
WAIT TO DIE, WAIT TO LIVE...
WAIT FOR AN ABSOLUTION THAT WOULD NEVER COME.
OH, SIR, I DON'T THINK YOU'LL FIND
ANY OF YOUR PEOPLE DOWN HERE.
IT'S ALL STEERAGE.
Woman: HIS HAIR IS REDDISH BROWN.
REDDISH BROWN, REDDISH BROWN AND A WHITE BEARD.
Woman: ISN'T THERE ANOTHER PASSENGER LIST?
THERE'S NO OTHER LIST.
PERHAPS HE'S ON ANOTHER SHIP.
WE'RE DOING ALL WE CAN, MA'AM.
THAT'S THE LAST TIME I EVER SAW HIM.
HE MARRIED, OF COURSE, AND INHERITED HIS MILLIONS
BUT THE CRASH OF '29 HIT HIS INTERESTS HARD
AND HE PUT A PISTOL IN HIS MOUTH THAT YEAR
OR SO I READ.
CAN I TAKE YOUR NAME PLEASE, LOVE?
DAWSON.
ROSE DAWSON.
THANK YOU.
WE NEVER FOUND ANYTHING ON JACK.
THERE'S NO RECORD OF HIM AT ALL.
NO, THERE WOULDN'T BE, WOULD THERE?
AND I'VE NEVER SPOKEN OF HIM UNTIL NOW.
NOT TO ANYONE
NOT EVEN YOUR GRANDFATHER.
A WOMAN'S HEART
IS A DEEP OCEAN OF SECRETS.
BUT NOW YOU KNOW THERE WAS A MAN NAMED JACK DAWSON
AND THAT HE SAVED ME
IN EVERY WAY THAT A PERSON CAN BE SAVED.
I DON'T EVEN HAVE A PICTURE OF HIM.
HE EXISTS NOW ONLY IN MY MEMORY.
Man: Keldysh, Keldysh, Mir 2 on our way to the surface.
Brock: YOU KNOW I WAS SAVING THIS FOR WHEN I FOUND THE DIAMOND.
I'M SORRY.
THREE YEARS I'VE THOUGHT OF NOTHING EXCEPT TITANIC
BUT I NEVER GOT IT.
I NEVER LET IT IN.
♪ EVERY NIGHT IN MY DREAMS I SEE YOU, I FEEL YOU ♪
♪ THAT IS HOW I KNOW YOU GO ON ♪
♪ FAR ACROSS THE DISTANCE AND SPACES BETWEEN US ♪
♪ YOU HAVE COME TO SHOW YOU GO ON ♪
♪ NEAR, FAR, WHEREVER YOU ARE ♪
♪ I BELIEVE THAT THE HEART DOES GO ON ♪
♪ ONCE MORE, YOU OPEN THE DOOR ♪
♪ AND YOU'RE HERE IN MY HEART ♪
♪ AND MY HEART WILL GO ON AND ON ♪
♪ LOVE CAN TOUCH JUST ONE TIME AND LAST FOR A LIFETIME ♪
♪ AND NEVER LET GO TILL WE'RE GONE ♪
♪ LOVE WAS WHEN I LOVED YOU, ONE TRUE TIME I HOLD TO ♪
♪ IN MY LIFE WE'LL ALWAYS GO ON ♪
♪ NEAR, FAR, WHEREVER YOU ARE ♪
♪ I BELIEVE THAT THE HEART DOES GO ON ♪
♪ ONCE MORE, YOU OPEN THE DOOR ♪
♪ AND YOU'RE HERE IN MY HEART ♪
♪ AND MY HEART WILL GO ON AND ON. ♪
♪ YOU'RE HERE, THERE'S NOTHING I FEAR ♪
♪ AND I KNOW THAT MY HEART WILL GO ON ♪
♪ WE'LL STAY FOREVER THIS WAY ♪
♪ YOU ARE SAFE IN MY HEART ♪
♪ AND MY HEART WILL GO ON AND ON. ♪