Citizens of Oz,
there have been 12 tide turns
since the Wicked Witch
of the West escaped
with our Grimmerie.
Shield your children.
Trust no animals.
She will be eliminated.
Until then, the Wizard's vision
for the Oz of tomorrow
marches on.
Do it! Move!
All right, load it up.
Come on! Let's go! Move!
No speaking.
The Wizard needs
the road finished.
Move! Move!
Come on, let's go! Move!
Fill up that basket!
Keep moving.
Come on.
Come on. Keep moving.
Get up!
Come on.
Whoa. Settle down.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.
Get back!
Retreat! Guards, retreat!
It's the Witch!
The Witch! She's back!
Go, go!
Release them!
Come with me.
What?
To meet the Wizard.
The Wizard will see you now.
Well, I guess.
Thank you.
Good. Good. Good. Good. Good.
Good.
She's so Good.
Glinda the Good.
Hup!
There's a quoncert in Quox,
if you want to attend,
next week.
Oh. Perhaps.
Uh, The Quadling Quorum
wants to honor you.
They're just not sure
for what yet.
Good to hear.
And someone sent pastries.
Good for us.
Hey, send these
to my hovel, please.
The gowns from last week?
Oh, maybe, uh, give
to the under-fortunate.
-Oh, of course.
-Good idea.
And, you know,
while we're at it,
we really should
look into trademarking
the word "good."
-Ooh. That's go--
-Ooh.
I mean, I'm goosified.
My follicles are screaming.
-I love my job so much.
-Aw. Good.
Madame Morrible.
Forgive me
for keeping you waiting.
I had no idea.
Has something happened?
Is it Elphaba?
You mean the Wicked Witch?
Right, of course.
-Come in, come in.
-Mrs. Morrible...
Would you like us
to take minutes for you?
...I c-- I can, I can get you,
like, a little snack.
You want a little snack?
Like a cherry frazzle
or a juice puff?
"Mrs. Morrible"?
She's not married.
You sh...
With the Yellow Brick Road
grand opening ahead
and the Wicked Witch attacks
growing bolder,
the public is on edge.
So it's more important than ever
that you lift
everyone's spirits,
as only you can.
Accordingly.
Oh, Madame, I love it.
What is it?
Your new mode of transport.
Your very own
vehicular spherical globule.
So, like, a bubble?
Sure.
Was that supposed to happen?
It's all right.
Are you sure?
Wha--
Does that do
what I think it does?
No!
I can't.
No way!
I'm obsessulated.
The Wizard had it crafted
especially for you.
His Ozness feels it vital
that you, as our Good Witch,
also be airborne.
I agree.
But don't fret over
your inability
to produce any actual magic.
This invention will
disguise your deficiency.
The bubble's mechanism
is cleverly concealed.
People will assume that
you are causing it to float
through your own witchly powers.
So, just let them assume.
Right.
But don't forget this.
The wand really sells it.
I'll see you
at the opening ceremony.
Thank you so much.
A magic wand?
Happy birthday, Galinda.
It's what I've wanted
most of all.
Come on, give it a go.
Yeah, try it out!
Magic! Magic!
Magic! Magic! Magic!
Come on.
Oh.
I forgot to say the spell.
-Oh!
-Oh, yeah.
The wand. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
I hereby commandify that
something magical shall happen!
She can't even make
a spark.
Look! There's a rainbow.
Wow.
Did you make that?
Um...
Well, you know
how I love rainbows.
Oh, wow!
That's my friend!
Go see the rainbow!
Isn't it fantastic?
Who is ready for some cake?
Go see Rosie and Posie.
What's wrong, dearest?
You got everything you wanted.
I know,
but I want to be magical.
For real.
And... I'm not.
Oh, but, darlingest,
everyone loves you.
Believe me,
that's all you'll ever need.
Where's that smile?
That's my girl.
Sweetheart, you coming?
Come on!
Glinda!
Fellow Ozians, good news.
Now, at last,
all roads lead to the Wizard.
Thank Goodness for you, Glinda,
and your handsome swain,
Prince Fiyero,
newly appointed captain
of the Gale Force--
assembled by the Wizard himself
to capture the Wicked Witch.
Tell us, Captain.
How does it feel?
It's frustrating.
But I became captain
to find her,
and I will keep on searching
until I do.
No!
Being engaged.
We're engaged?
Surprised?
Yes.
Good. We hoped you'd be.
Um, the Wizard and I.
And, Glinda,
dear, we are happy for you.
As Press Secretary,
I've striven to ensure
that all of Oz knows
the story of your braverism
in the face of the terrifying
Wicked Witch of the West.
Mmm. Darling?
People are so empty-headed,
they'll believe anything.
If you'll excuse us
just a clock-tick.
Come with me, dearest.
What is going on?
People are watching.
I can't just
stand there grinning,
pretending to go along
with all this.
Do you think
I like hearing them say
those awful things about her?
I hate it.
Then what are we doing here?
Let's go. Let's go.
-Let's just get out of here.
-I-I can't.
I can't when there are
people looking to me
to raise their spirits.
You can't leave
because you can't resist this.
That's the truth.
Well, maybe I can't.
Is that so wrong?
I mean, who could?
Well, you know who could.
We both know
who could and who has.
And I have to find her,
because if someone else
gets there first, she...
Fiyero, I'm worried
for her, too.
And I miss her.
Can't you see
she doesn't want to be found?
You've got to face it.
She's made her choice.
You're right.
And, look...
...if it makes you happy,
of course I'll marry you.
It'll make you happy,
too, right?
You know me. I'm always happy.
Fiyero.
Thanks plenty, dearest.
He's, um... he's gone
to fetch me a refreshment.
He's so thoughtful that way.
It's the Wicked Witch!
Take cover!
Mount up!
Glinda!
Take cover, everyone!
Everyone, please,
don't be alarmed.
She won't hurt you. It's okay.
She wants to kill us all!
Look!
Gale Force, go!
Hyah!
Fiyero!
Hyah! Come on! Hyah!
No, come.
Halt!
Captain, do you see anything?
No.
Come on.
We must not rest until
we capture that Wicked Witch.
Come on! Let's go!
-Move out.
-Fall in.
Fiyero.
Even you.
Madam Governor?
That proposed new regulation,
the Animal Anti-Motility law.
What law?
Animals would need
a permit to travel.
Munchkinland is the one place
in Oz it hasn't been ratified.
The League of Governors
is urging you to sign.
Nessa, you're not
going to sign that.
But if I don't...
people will say,
"She's just like her sister."
Give us a clock-tick, Avaric.
Boq, forgive me.
It's just that Elphaba
abandoned me when I needed her.
She didn't even come see me
when Father died.
Only you did that.
Oz only knows how I'd have coped
with all of this without you.
And I'm glad
I could be there for you.
But I've been thinking
for a while now...
Yes?
I think it's time I moved on.
I see.
Well, if that's how you feel,
I think it's best you leave.
Now.
Nessa, this won't be the
last time we'll see each other.
Oh, I know.
Attention,
passengers.
This is the final boarding
for the Emerald City Unlimited.
Doors will be closing shortly.
Please step inside and make way
for boarding passengers.
Visiting someone special?
Get a new Ozfit.
Visit the Wizard's Emporium
in downtown Emerald City.
Next.
Oh.
Excuse me.
Um, my train is boarding in...
Travel permit?
-What?
-All Munchkins are forbidden
to leave Munchkinland
without express written
permission of the Governor.
She insisted it go
into effect immediately.
...reminder to all passengers...
Stop pushing me.
-Elsa.
-Go!
-What's happening?
-Keep your hands off my family.
I don't want to hear it,
Munchkins.
Move! Forward now, Munchkins.
Go.
This is outrageous.
-You cannot treat us like this.
-Go!
Move along, Munchkins.
Next.
This is not the Oz I know.
-This is un-Ozian.
-Back in line.
Step back. What did I say?
Step-- Munchkins, step back.
Back in line.
Watch your footing.
Next group. Come on, children.
Let's move.
We have to leave now.
Stay together!
Come along now.
Keep moving.
Eyes on your children, please.
Don't worry, I'm with you.
I'll never leave you.
Don't go too fast.
-What is all this?
-Watch your step.
What are you doing?
Come, children. Quickly.
We must get out of Oz.
Don't do this. Please.
-Keep moving.
-Don't leave Oz.
Join with me.
Help me fight the Wizard.
And wait for
the monkeys to carry us off?
That's what happens
to animals who speak out.
And they're never seen again.
No.
Oz wouldn't be Oz
without all of you.
And I know you're frightened,
but this is home.
Belongs to all of us.
Elphaba.
Dulcibear.
Oh, little one.
I've missed your bear hugs.
We can't stay here.
It's become rotten.
There's only one thing left
for us to do:
escape through that tunnel
to The Place Beyond Oz.
They say The Place Beyond Oz
is just...
...emptiness.
How will you survive?
How will you survive here?
No one in Oz will be happy
until you're dead.
Why would you want to stay?
I don't know.
Try to understand.
We just can't fight anymore.
We have to.
Don't listen to her!
At night, when I close my eyes,
I still see that green face.
I can't believe it. Is that you?
Stay back!
When I was just a cub,
she snatched me from
the only home I ever knew.
You were in a cage.
If I'd have left you there,
you would never
have learned to speak.
They say she's the one
who gave the monkeys wings
and gave the Wizard his spies.
Is this true?
It's true.
I cast that spell.
And I have to live with that.
If I'd have known
I was being tricked,
if I'd have known why,
I would never have...
The Wizard lies.
I can prove it.
And if we stand together...
Dulcibear!
Little one,
I know you'll keep fighting,
because I know you.
Thank you, Boq.
Perhaps a friendly game
of cards once I'm done working?
Whatever you say,
Madam Governor.
I asked you to call me Nessa.
Remember?
Boq.
Never mind. I'll call you
when I've finished.
Now, who could have left
that door open?
I did.
It's so good to see you.
Why are you here?
I've tried to keep you
out of all of this, but...
I need you.
Thought you might have come
to apologize.
Apologize?
Our father died of shame,
and you didn't even bother
to show up.
You might at least
pretend to be sorry.
For what? He hated me.
That's a Wicked thing to say.
No, it's not.
It's just the truth.
Do you know why?
What does it matter now?
You're right.
Doesn't matter.
Because it's just us.
You're the Governor.
People will listen to you,
-and together, we...
-Why should I help you?
You fly around Oz
with that book,
helping animals
you've never even met,
and not once
have you ever thought
-to use your powers to help me.
-You never wanted my help.
I do now!
I want to go back to the way
we were at school.
That night when Boq told me
I was beautiful.
It was the first time
I ever wore these shoes.
There was music.
And everything was
still possible.
Nessa, I wish there was
something I could do, but...
"Ambulahn dare, pahto, pahpoot.
"Ambulahn dasca,
-lahfenahto."
-What are you doing?
"Ambulahn dare, pahto, pahpoot.
-Ambulahn dasca, caldapess."
-Oh.
-Oh, my shoes.
-"Lahfenahto, lahfenahtum."
Oh, they feel like
they're on fire!
"Pede, pede, caldapess!
Pede, pede, caldapess!"
I'm floating on air.
Thank you, Elphaba.
Nessa?
He called me Nessa.
It's working.
Nessa, there's something
I have to...
Look.
You.
-Boq.
-Stay back!
It's just me.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Boq, don't be afraid.
Elphaba just came
to lift my spirits.
You did this to make her happy?
I know now anything is possible
for both of us.
Nessa.
I lost my heart to Glinda
the moment I first saw her.
Lost your heart?
We'll see about that.
-Let him go.
-Don't come any closer!
You and your sister.
She's as Wicked as you are,
keeping me here like a prisoner.
What are you talking about?
I am talking about my life!
The little that's left of it.
You're going to lose
your heart to me, I tell you!
If I have to...
I have to...
...magic spell you.
There must be a magic spell
in here to capture your heart.
-Nessa, no. That's dangerous.
-What is she doing?
"Ah tum, ta tayk..."
-Stop, Nessa!
-"...ah tum, cortum."
You're pronouncing the words
all wrong!
-Wh-What is she saying?
-"Ah tum, ta tayk."
I'm going.
"Ah tum."
Boq, what is it?
My heart.
It feels like it's sh--
like it's shrinking.
-Do something!
-I can't!
A spell from the Grimmerie
can never be reversed.
Boq? This is all your fault!
-If you hadn't come here...
-I have to find another spell.
It's the only thing
that might work.
Go, now! Go!
"Ambulahn dasca."
"Lahfenahto."
"Caldapess."
He's sleeping now.
What about his heart?
It's all right.
He won't need one now.
The wedding.
Wait, where are you going?
All the most influential people
in Oz will be there.
It's the perfect opportunity
to show them all the truth
about the Wizard.
Oh, please.
Stop lying to yourself.
You're going there to find
Fiyero, but it's too late.
Nessa, I have done
everything I could for you,
and it hasn't been enough.
Nothing ever will be.
Elphaba, don't leave me!
Goodbye, Nessa.
I'm off to see the Wizard.
Where am I?
What happened?
It's all right, dearest.
You just...
What have you done?
It wasn't me.
I tried to stop her.
Boq, please.
What have you done to me?
You witch!
It wasn't me! It was her!
It was Elphaba!
Boq!
Ozians of the Emerald City,
today the winds shift
and destiny unfolds
before our very eyes...
Mm-hmm.
-...for on this night,
by the glorification
of our Wizard,
Glinda the Good
and Prince Fiyero Tigelaar
join hands in unification.
Do I have everything I need?
No, I need an earring, please.
Thank you.
Something oldish? Yes.
This is
more than just a wedding.
It is a coronation
of hope itself.
Something new?
Absolutely.
So let the very foundations
of Oz shimmer
with celebratorium...
Let's go!
...for today,
Oz writes a new chapter.
Rejoicify,
and Oz shall shine forevermore.
Something bartered.
And something askew.
I need something askew.
Just give me a clock-tick.
Elphaba Thropp,
I know you're out here.
Just come in
before the monkeys spot you.
Elphaba.
Galinda.
Get in. Go.
Elphie.
Thank Oz you're alive.
Careful. Your dress.
I still can't believe you
get around on that old thing.
Well, we can't all
come and go by bubble.
True.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
I just wanted
to come and see you.
That means a lot to me, Elphie.
But if anyone
discoverates you...
I know. I know.
You never saw me.
I was never here.
Do you understand?
No. I can't bear this anymore.
I'm taking you
to see the Wizard.
Absolutely not.
-Yes.
-No!
This is between
the Wizard and I.
I understand.
But you have to trust me.
I know how to talk to him,
and maybe I could help work
something out.
♪ Since I've... ♪
What?
You're done.
It's over.
I had a hunch
you'd be coming back to me.
I'm not here for you.
I'm here for Oz.
Elphaba.
You know, you could've
just exited normally.
Just use the door.
Hello?
-Yes?
-Don't hate me.
It's my wedding day,
and you cannot refuse
a wedding wish.
Well, you can, but it's rude.
I don't have time
for this. Now, listen.
You and I are gonna go
down there together,
and you are gonna admit
to her guests
that you have no real power
and that you cannot read
the Grimmerie.
Why is that funny?
Elphaba, uh, I've missed you.
Can't we start again?
Yes. Please.
-Just say yes.
-No.
Don't you think I wish I could?
I would give anything
to go back to a time when I...
...when I actually believed
that you were Wonderful.
"The Wonderful Wizard of Oz."
No one believed in you
more than I did.
But there's no going back.
And we can't move forward,
not until everyone knows
what I know.
And once they know the truth...
They're not gonna believe it.
How can you say that?
Well, I'm just being straight
with you.
I could tell 'em
that I'd been lying to 'em
till I'm-- forgive me--
blue in the face,
but wouldn't make
any difference.
They're never gonna stop
believing in me.
You know why?
Because they don't want to.
Watch this.
Ow!
Bee-keek, beak-beak.
Elphie, let's be honest.
Your way hasn't worked.
But if you join forces with us,
if people see that you're with
us, they'll begin to trust you.
You'll accomplish so much more.
Yeah, yeah. So much more.
You know, we could be
like a... like a family.
You know, I've never
really had a family.
Lucky you.
That's why I've wanted
to give the citizens of Oz...
everything.
-So you lied to them?
-No.
No.
No-- Well, um...
only v-verbally.
But those were the lies
that they wanted to hear.
You see, back where I come from,
we got a whole lot of people
who believe
all sorts of things
that aren't true.
You know what we call it?
History.
Ooh.
It's not my best pupil.
Come with me.
Elphie, aren't you tired
of running?
Think of what we could do.
Together.
Who are you?
And why do you seek me?
Wait.
No more blaming the animals.
And the ones
who've left Oz should be
free to return without fear.
Hey, with you by my side,
I'm not gonna need to blame
the animals anymore.
You're not gonna need
spies, either,
so set the monkeys free.
Oh, yeah? Hang on. Hang on.
Why? Why?
I think I got it.
Um...
Done.
I did it.
I mean, we did it.
I'll see you two
in a clock-tick.
Elphie, I'm so happy.
I'm getting married.
So, you want me to prove myself?
Oh, my gosh.
Look in your hand.
How'd that get there?
It's a key. It's a key.
Aren't you surprised?
I liked that dance.
That was fun. Come here.
Now,
I've been keeping them
locked in here, um,
for their own safety.
But, ah, no need
for that anymore.
Okay.
Hey, you want to come over here
and do the honors?
Uh, 'cause if you put that
in-in here, it'll let 'em go.
And, uh, I...
Gosh, I-I hope you feel good
about this whole thing, 'cause,
well, you've won,
but I think we all have.
Chistery.
Nothing can change
what's been done to you.
Well... what I've done.
But at least
you have your freedom now.
Chistery, can you speak?
Please try.
Well... go on.
You're free.
Fly.
Fly!
Wonderful. Uh...
Well...
Hey, if you and I
are gonna go down there
and greet those fancy folks,
I'd better, uh, spruce up.
Chistery, what's wrong?
Dr. Dillamond.
Can't you speak?
It's me, Elphaba.
Let me explain, 'cause th--
this is not what it looks like.
Elphaba, some animals
cannot be trusted.
Yes.
I know that now.
And these sacred vows
are to be entered into
not lightly but merrily.
Elphaba, try to understand.
No.
I'm not a bad man. I'm just a...
Yes, you are.
You're a very bad man.
You once asked me
what my heart's desire was,
and I know now what that is.
And that is to fight you
till the day I die!
Run.
Wha--
And do you, Glinda...
What is that horrendible sound?
Move!
Stay there.
Fiyero!
This is the work
of the Wicked Witch!
She wants to kill us all!
No--
How does it feel to have
your voice taken away?
Silence, Witch!
Water.
Lots of it. Bring water!
Yes, sir.
As much as you can carry.
A little help?
Ah.
Please.
Thank you.
That was, uh, unpleasant.
Well, I think my trachea
is otherwi--
What? What are you doing?
-Shush, you. Get in.
-What?
Get in.
Unless you want
the guests to know
the truth about their Wizard.
Get in!
Yes, yes.
Your Ozness!
Fiyero. What are you...
What is happening?
What's happened is that
these two traitors...
Not another word, Your Ozness.
Darling, have you misplaced
your mind?
What are you doing?
I'm going with her.
-What?
Let's go.
-Let's go.
Wait. What?
You mean to tell me
that the two of you...
-This whole time?
-No, it wasn't like that.
Go.
Now.
You deserve each other.
You frightened me.
For a while there,
I thought you changed.
I have changed.
This dulls the pain,
if you want a swig?
No, no, no, no!
No! No!
We've got the water, Madame.
Fools! You're too late.
Get out!
How could you let this happen?
Uh, do you have a hairpin?
Thanks.
Uh, she and I had a deal.
But, uh...
she double-crossed me.
We must smoke her out,
force her to show herself.
Uh, without the monkeys,
I don't know
how we're gonna do that.
Her sister.
Use her sister.
Spread a rumor
that her sister's in trouble.
She'll fly to her side,
and you'll have her.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I need to lie down.
I have a bit of a headache.
A rumor won't do.
Elphaba's too smart.
That's right.
These things must be
done delicately.
Perhaps...
a change in the weather.
You're beautiful.
You don't have to lie to me.
It's not lying.
It's...
What is it?
It's looking at things
another way.
Take cover!
Get inside! Get inside!
Boq! Boq!
Where are you?
Come on! Come on! Inside!
Stay calm.
Move! Go!
Boq!
You can't go on living here.
-They'll find you.
-I'll be all right.
Listen.
My family has a castle
in Kiamo Ko.
-Never lived in it.
-Where do you live?
In the other castle.
Okay.
-Of course. -I mean,
it's the perfect hideout.
There's tunnels,
secret passageways.
You'll be safer there.
Boq!
-Where are you?
-What?
Boq!
What is it?
What's wrong?
This isn't gonna make
any sense, but...
There's a house.
And it's flying through the sky.
Hey, hey, hey.
My sister.
-She's in danger.
I have to get to her. -What?
-I'm coming with you.
-No.
It's too dangerous.
Will we ever see
each other again?
Elphaba, we are going to be
together always.
You can see houses
flying through the sky,
but you can't see that?
-This way, dear.
-Goodbye, Dorothy.
Bye, Dodo.
It's just that one road
the whole time.
Take your time.
Hurry up, darling.
Goodbye, Nessa.
-What a touching
display of grief. -Oh, shiz.
I scare you?
I seem to have
that effect on people.
I would appreciate a moment
to say goodbye to my sister.
Alone.
Of course.
Oh, Nessa.
Forgive me.
Oh, Elphaba,
don't blame yourself, please.
It's dreadful, it is.
I mean...
to have a house fall on you...
But accidents will happen.
And...
You call that an accident?
You think cyclones just appear
out of the blue?
I don't know.
I never really thought
about it...
And how dare you send
that mulish farm girl
off to see the Wizard,
as if he could do
anything to help?
She's lost. She's far from home.
She took a dead woman's shoes.
I had to do something.
I'm a public figure now.
People expect me to...
Lie?
Be encouraging.
Those shoes are all
I have left of my sister.
They weren't yours to give.
Yes, well, it seems
a lot of us are taking things
that don't belong to us now,
aren't we?
No, you just wait a clock-tick.
It might be hard for you
to comprehend
that someone like him
could choose someone like me,
but it's happened,
and it's real.
And you can wave that
ridiculous wand all you want.
You can't change it.
He never belonged to you.
He doesn't love you.
He never did.
He loves me.
Oh, my...
Feel better?
I do.
Good.
Me, too.
Are you crazy?
Excuse me.
What do you think you're doing?
Come on!
Come on! Bring it!
Get back!
Get-- Oh! Oh!
Let's go!
You...
Please.
Where'd you get that?
What are you doing?
Come on. Let's go, greenie!
Use your hands!
Come on!
-Bring it on!
-You're out of your mind!
-Get off of me!
-No!
Attention!
-Halt in the name of the Wizard!
-Oh, come on!
-Off of me!
-Ow! Ow! -Let her go.
No, no, no, no.
I almost had her.
Easy.
Sorry it took us so long
to get here, Your Goodness.
You were a part of this?
-Elphaba, no...
-I can't believe
you would stoop so low
as to use my sister's death
to capture me.
I never meant to take it
this far. I...
Let the green girl go.
Else explain to all Oz
how the Wizard's guards
watched while
Glinda the Good was slain.
-Elphaba, go.
-No. Not without you.
Go!
Go.
I...
Now.
Go.
Please, protect her.
No! You're hurting him!
Stop it now!
Stop it.
In the name of Goodness, stop!
Can't you see
he wasn't going to harm me?
He just...
He loves her.
Glinda, I am so sorry.
Take him out to that field.
What? No, please.
Put him up on those poles
till he tells us
-where the Witch went.
-You're hurting him. No.
Fiyero! No! Please!
Let go of me!
Fiyero! Fiyero!
You have visitors.
A girl from the land of Kansas
and three friends
she picked up along the way.
A man made of tin,
another made of straw
and a very nervous lion.
They all want something
they don't have, of course.
I'm not seeing anybody.
But these are visitors
we can use.
Bring me the broomstick
of the
Wicked Witch of the West...
...so I have proof
that she's dead.
Kill her!
And this is more than
just a service to the Wizard.
I have a personal score
to settle with Elph--
with the Witch!
Yeah! Someone, kill her!
And I'm not the only one.
Tell them.
Tell them what she did to you.
How you were just a cub
and she cub-napped you.
Madame, we have
got to stop this.
It's gone too far.
I think Elphaba can
take care of herself.
Madame.
Something has been troubling me.
About Nessa and that cyclone.
Sad.
I suppose it was just her time.
Was it?
Was it? What did you do?
Now, you listen to me, missy.
--You may be fooling
the rest of Oz,
but you're not fooling me.
You wanted this
from the beginning.
"Galinda."
And now you're getting
what you wanted.
-So just do what you do best.
-No. No.
Smile.
Wave.
And shut up.
I need your help.
Monkeys!
Find that Dorothy,
and bring back
my sister's shoes!
Oh, for Oz's sake,
stop crying!
I can't listen to it anymore.
You want to get home and see
your Aunt what's-her-name again?
-Please stop.
-Then get those shoes
-off your feet!
-I'm so sorry.
I want to go home.
They're coming for you.
Let the little girl go.
Go away.
Elphaba, you can't
go on like this.
I can do whatever I want.
Haven't you heard?
I'm the Wicked Witch
of the West.
Chistery, at last.
What took you so long?
What is this?
Elphie, what is that?
It's Fiyero, isn't it?
Is he...
We've seen his face
for the last time.
Oh, no.
You're right.
It's time.
I surrender.
What? Wait.
Elphaba, what are you doing?
Glinda, you can't be found
here with me.
-You must go.
-Elphie, no. I...
Please, you must now.
Fine.
I'll go and I'll tell everyone
the truth about you,
-that you're not who they say
you are. -No, you can't.
They'll just turn against you.
-Well, I don't care.
-Well, I do.
I need you to promise that
you won't try to clear my name.
No. What? Why would I do that?
I'll tell them everything.
-Please. -No, I don't want you
to do that. Please.
I'll tell them you're not
who they say you are.
I just want you
to just listen for a minute.
-Please, please just...
-Just promise me!
Why would you ask me
to promise that?
Because they need someone
to be Wicked
so that you can be Good.
Just look at me.
Not with your eyes.
With theirs.
Here. Take it.
-What? Elphie...
-Go on.
Take it.
But you know I...
I can't read this. I...
Well, you'll have to learn.
We can't let "Good" be
just a word.
It has to mean something.
It has to change things.
You know, um...
You're the only friend
I ever had.
And I've had so many friends.
But only one that mattered.
Come on. Come on, quick.
No one can know you were here.
-You stay here.
-What?
Everything's gonna be fine.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Oh, Elphie.
Miss Glinda.
She's dead.
-Do you have her broomstick?
-No.
But I do have something else
that belonged to her.
It was a keepsake.
She told me herself.
It belonged to her mother.
This belonged to...
...her mother?
So Elphaba was yours all along.
That's why she had such powers.
She was a child of both worlds.
Oh, my Lord.
What have I done?
You have caused great harm.
Which is why
you will be leaving Oz.
Today.
Did you hear what I said?
And what...
what will I tell people?
Make something up.
You're good at that.
Excuse me.
Hello.
What? What do you want?
Look out your window.
Come on.
You don't want to miss this.
Excuse me, please.
Don't leave without us.
Please. I-I want to go home.
Ugh, I swear it never ends
with that girl.
The Wizard is taking
a permanent leave of absence.
Not a rumor, a fact.
The kind that is true.
Glinda, dear.
Can you not find it
in your heart t-to forgive me?
As Oz is my witness,
I can see now
how truly good you are.
Actually, I'm not.
Not yet.
But just think, Madame.
We have so many cages,
and all recently vacated.
You'll have your pick.
Although I can't imagine
you'll hold up very well.
I mean, my personal opinion is
you do not have what it takes.
I hope you prove me wrong.
I doubt you will.
What are you doing?
Let go of me! Let...
Whoo! Yep.
Well, this has been fun.
As you can imagine,
I have much to attend to
with the Wizard's
unexpected departure,
so if there are no further
questions, I'm gonna go.
Glinda.
Is it true you were her friend?
What?
Sorry. One sec.
Is it true you were her friend?
Friend?
Yes.
I-I mean, I did know her.
That is...
our paths did cross.
At school.
Wait.
I have something more to say.
Fellow Ozians...
All Ozians.
Yes, come out.
Wherever you are, come out.
Friends.
Because I don't see
any enemies here.
We have been through
a frightening time.
And there will be other times
and other things
that frighten us.
But if you'll let me...
...I'd like to try to help.
To change things.
I'd like to try to be
Glinda the Good.
It worked.
They all think you're dead.
Fiyero?
See?
Good as new.
You saved my life.
You're beautiful.
You don't have to lie to me.
It's not lying.
It's...
It's looking at things
in another way.
Time to go.
I wish that Glinda
could know we're alive.
But I know she can't.
No one can ever know.