Fuck. Fuck.
Fuck. Oh, God.
Okay. Holy shit. No.
For Christ's sake.
Hey.
Holy shit.
Oh, G...
No.
We're sorry,
you have reached a number that has been
disconnected or is no longer in service.
Please check the number
and try your call again.
Hello.
How did you get this number?
I was told that if I ever needed help,
serious help, to call you.
Let me ask you again.
How did you get this number?
He said you'd ask that,
the man who gave it to me,
and he said not to say.
That doesn't make very much sense,
does it?
How do I know that I can trust you
if you won't tell me
who gave you this number?
He said to say there's only one man
in the city who can do what you do.
He said, "That man is an expert.
That man is a professional."
And he said
you can never predict the future
and that maybe one day,
I may need that one man.
And that one man is you.
Where are you?
And what happened?
Okay. And you're sure?
All right.
Now, what I need you to do is gonna
be difficult, but you can do it, okay?
I need you to activate the
do-not-disturb light for your room
and then do absolutely nothing
till I get there. You understand?
Good. You're not to leave the room.
You're not to make any phone calls.
You're not to touch anything.
You're not to answer the door.
You're not to pour yourself a drink
to steady your nerves.
You understand? Repeat that back to me.
Okay. That's great. You're doing great.
Yes, I'll be there as quickly as possible.
How will you know it's me?
This is how you'll know it's me.
Everything's gonna be fine.
I'll be there before you know it.
Co-Come in.
- Did you talk to anyone?
- No.
- Call anyone?
- No. No one.
Text? Any kind of communication at all?
No. Nothing.
I sat there just like you said.
Okay. Good.
You can pour yourself that drink now.
Oh. Yeah. A-Any kind?
Strong is probably best.
Okay. Do you want something?
Thanks, no.
- Does anybody know you're here?
- I don't think so, no.
- You don't think so?
- No. No one knows I'm here.
What about the room?
Did anyone recognize you
when you checked in?
No. I used an alias. I always do.
I mean, anytime I get a hotel room.
Not when I'm...
I understand. That's good.
I got the room right after I met...
I made him wait by the elevator
so no one would...
I don't do this.
This isn't something I do.
All right, listen.
I want you to look at the time.
Is there anyone that would be concerned
that they haven't heard from you yet?
- Oh, God. I don't kn...
- Think.
Uh, n-no.
I generally go and do as I please.
Good. I understand.
- And you can make all of this go away?
- That's why you called me.
- He was jumping on the bed.
- Mmm.
And he fell and crashed into the glass.
This would be the end.
- Everything I've worked so hard to build.
- Okay.
And we're on the verge
of doing something truly important.
All right. We don't have time for that.
We don't have much time at all.
It wasn't my fault. I didn't do anything...
None of it matters.
It doesn't matter, okay?
No, no. You listen to me.
You need to know this.
I didn't do anything. We were...
If you weren't here right now,
where would you be?
What? What do you mean?
If this was a normal night,
and you weren't
in a $10,000 penthouse suite
with a dead prostitute face down
in a pool of blood and broken glass,
where would you be?
He was not a prostitute.
Home. I would be home working,
watching TV with my daughter...
Okay. Good.
That's where I want you to be now.
- Okay.
You're home. You're sitting on the couch.
What's your daughter's name?
I have two daughters.
Julia. That's who I would...
All right. You're watching TV with Julia.
Okay.
I will make sure that none of this
gets traced back to you in any way.
Like it never happened. Whatever it takes.
No matter what.
Thank you.
That's the job.
When I was given your number,
I thought it was a joke.
I didn't know
people like you really existed.
They don't.
There's nobody who can do what I do.
What was that?
- Say, "Hello."
- What?
- Hello.
Louder.
Hello?
No service, please. Thank you.
Mmm.
Can I help you?
I don't think so, no.
Who are you?
I'm here to take care of your problem.
Who is he?
I called him.
Ah.
Who called you?
Son of a bitch.
Hmm.
W-What's going on?
Yeah.
Got it.
He does. I know. It's weird. Okay.
What?
Hello? Who is this?
Oh. Oh. Okay.
Okay. Yes.
Mm-hmm. I completely
understand. And I have no doubt
that we can come to some
sort of agreement that satisfies us both.
Well, I hardly think you're
in a position to be negotiating anything.
Uh-huh.
Fair point. That is a fair point.
- So, tell me, what would you suggest?
- ...illegal camera up there?
Got a hidden fucking camera.
That's illegal surveillance.
That's a class D felony in
the state of New York. A class D felony.
You're more than welcome to leave, sir.
Your services are no longer required.
Come on.
What's the play here?
I don't know
what you're talking about, sir.
What?
You did check to see if...
Okay, you're on speaker.
Hello? Are the men there?
Can you hear me?
- Yes, they're here.
- Wonderful.
Now then, we clearly have a situation
here, and time's of the essence.
So, I'm not going to mince words.
My name is Pamela Dowd-Herdry.
This is my hotel. It's very new.
It's very expensive, and I have a clear,
vested interest in minimizing any sort
of controversy associated with it.
I am very aware of the stigma
that can become attached to a building,
and I'm not interested in being the owner
of a hotel where a district attorney,
whom I greatly admire
and whose work I believe in very much,
- was found with a dead prostitute.
- He wasn't...
So that being said,
I have brought in someone I know
through a trusted friend
to take care of this problem.
He is an expert.
He is the very best there is.
There is, quite simply, no one else
out there who can do what he does.
Thank you, Pam.
Now, of course, my guest
has her own interests at stake as well
and feels the need to make sure those
interests are protected,
which is why she has insisted on
maintaining her own person...
- Mmm.
- ...to ensure this problem goes away.
And as we have reached an impasse
as to whose man would be better suited
to accomplish the task,
we have decided that the only course
of action is for you both to work together
to clean up this
absolute fucking clusterfuck of a mess.
Hello?
No.
Pam, I'd like to have a word.
- Please, wait. Please.
- No. No.
Wait a minute.
You're joking, right? This a joke.
- You can't just leave.
- This is not how I work.
- How do I know I can trust him? I don't...
- Know this guy.
Well, sure, maybe.
Or maybe he's just some knucklehead.
You don't know me.
How do you know you can trust me?
I don't, but I trust the man
who gave me your number because...
Careful.
Because when he says something, it has
value, and he said I could trust you.
Well, Pam, I don't see how
that has anything to do with me, does it?
Are you appealing to my sense of honor?
Because that's not how this works.
This is not how I work.
He said if you take the job,
you give your word.
And that word's the measure of a man.
Not like this.
You're on those tapes too.
Forget about me.
If you... If you don't finish the job,
she's got you on camera.
Pa...
I know you can see me.
Fine.
The feeling's mutual.
Okay.
So, now what?
- Well, I need to know...
- Well, the first thing I need t...
I-I need to know
everything you did tonight.
Starting from when?
Starting from when things
went from a normal night to this.
- Sit down.
- Oh.
All right.
Uh, I was at an event a few blocks away.
After it was over, I wanted a drink.
I like the bar here.
I had just walked in
and was headed for the ladies' room
when this kid started talking to me.
H-He was funny, and he was charming,
and he was so out of place.
And I just said, you know,
"Do you wanna get a room?"
It was a... sort of a joke, sort of not.
- Mmm.
- He said, "Sure."
- And you never met him before?
- No.
- No one saw you together?
And then you came upstairs.
I don't understand
why you need to know all this.
Because I need to know
what I need to make disappear.
- We.
- What?
We need to know.
- So, you came upstairs.
- We were drinking and fooling around...
Excuse me.
When exactly did you get the room?
- Before I came upstairs.
- Before she came upstairs.
Before you met the kid
or after you met the kid?
After I met the kid.
Before I came upstairs.
O-Okay, thank you. I didn't know. Proceed.
So, you were drinking and fooling around.
- Was there ever a discussion of money?
- He's not a prostitute.
No. Hey! I already... God.
This is already fucking embarrassing
and humiliating enough as it is.
I don't understand
why I have to answer everything twice.
You don't have to answer everything twice.
You might have to
answer a few things twice.
Jesus Christ, will you...
Jesus Christ, do I know
what the two of you have spoken about?
No, I do not.
I am trying to get up to speed.
So you brought this 20-something...
...non-prostitute
up to your room.
You began drinking, fooling around, and...
He goes into the bathroom,
and he comes out,
he starts jumping up on the fucking bed,
and he falls backwards onto the
fucking bar cart, and fucking drops dead.
Is there anyone who might be concerned
they haven't heard from you tonight?
Gonna get cleaned up.
Gonna take your things,
and you're gonna leave.
Uh, I'm covered in blood.
You're gonna go home,
and you're gonna see your family,
act like nothing ever happened.
What?
Um, did you by chance...
So, you'll be in touch to coordinate the,
uh...
Don't worry about it.
That time will come, but not now.
And what exactly will happen to him?
To who?
Right.
Okay.
Hey, sweetie, did you eat?
I'm on my way home.
I can pick up some food.
- What are you doing?
- Mmm.
You know, I was giving you
the benefit of the doubt,
letting you clean up unsupervised.
Unsupervised? Wow, that's an honor.
I think you have
a fundamental misunderstanding
of what is happening here.
- Do I?
- Yes.
I wanna finish the job and go home.
Mmm. And that is where
there is a fundamental misunderstanding.
Mmm. Enlighten me.
Well, your job is to make sure that
that mess behind you
cannot be traced back to your client,
and to do that, you have to make sure that
that mess disappears completely.
As if it never happened. Difficult.
- For you, maybe.
- Well, that's irrelevant.
Because my job is
to make sure that you do your job
so that that mess
cannot be traced back to this hotel.
Less difficult.
So, you're just gonna sit there
and slurp your soda?
I'm going to...
supervise.
Fuck you.
Mmm.
Just don't touch anything.
You're gonna get blood on your sweater.
I won't get blood on my sweater.
Thanks.
Dump the body.
Finish the job. Supervise.
Oh, shit.
I told you not to touch anything.
Mmm.
It's gonna be a long fucking night.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait,
I don't understand.
Why can't you simply
dispose of the drugs as well?
- Cops find a dead kid in the park...
- There's zero reason why a kid...
- ...overdosed...
- ...like that would be walking around...
- ...they're asking questions.
- ...with this much product...
which means it's probably stolen.
So, whoever it does belong to
will be looking for it. In my experience,
it's not the kind of people you want
knocking on the door of your hotel!
I have no clue what
either one of you just said.
It strikes me that whoever those belong to
is going to wonder what happened to them.
I don't want whoever that is
showing up here,
and I certainly don't want to
take responsibility
for throwing their product into the river
or turning it over to the police.
So this is what you'll do.
You'll find out who those drugs belong to,
and you'll return them.
- Uh, no...
- Look, Pam, it's not...
It's not that simple.
- Could've been a tracker in there.
- Tracker.
You don't think they'd already
be here if there was a...
How the hell are we gonna
figure out who this belongs to?
Body first, then the drugs.
- Listen, if I were you, I'd...
- You're not.
Hey, I don't want this to take all night.
It won't.
Okay then, so...
Oh, now you wanna get involved? Fuck you.
Hey, you wanna help?
Why don't you call your boss
and have her clear out the parking garage?
We can take the body down in the tarp.
You're joking.
You have to clean the surveillance anyway.
No one's gonna see it.
Oh, I get it.
- What?
- Nothing.
Just lucky for you, I'm here,
otherwise you're caught.
- I get it.
- I'm trying to save time.
No, it's okay. You don't have to explain.
You can't do it. I'm gonna help you out.
- I can do it.
- Really?
- Yeah, really.
- So do it.
Maybe I don't want you to see how I do it.
Whatever you say.
Hey... ...you know what?
Don't call your boss. Don't call.
Fuck it. Like I need your fucking help.
Okay, I'll fucking do it.
Well, that's one way to do it.
Looks like a dead body on a luggage cart.
I'm not finished yet.
Huh.
Here's a lesson.
You don't have to help.
I don't need you to help...
- Hmm.
- ...but if you do, it'll go faster.
I am enjoying the show.
Thanks.
Happy to help.
- Dick.
- Putz.
Wait.
What?
The parking garage is on
a different security system.
You're an asshole.
I just wanted to see
how an old man would do it,
but your secret's safe with me.
It's the red one.
What?
Hmm.
That should buy you an extra five.
I don't need an extra fucking five.
I have a fob.
Just don't interfere.
The old cone in the gate?
Another trade secret?
Let's wipe the tapes and go.
- No.
- No?
Although I am curious to see
how you would've navigated
this next situation without me,
I'm afraid I have to do this one alone.
- Excuse me?
- I will wipe the tapes.
- I just can't let you watch.
- Yeah. This is a two-way street.
I was told specifically
to make sure you do not see this.
By who? Your boss?
She doesn't want you back there.
You got hidden cameras
in a brand-new, luxury hotel.
What kind of a scam are you running here?
- You're not going back there.
- Really? Why?
What are you hiding? Who are you exactly?
Who am I? Fuck you, who am I. Who are you?
- Some old bagman? Some old cleaner?
- Yeah.
I'm not letting you in there.
That's some big talk
coming from a hotel policeman.
Big talk coming from the A/V club.
I'm on those tapes
and I'm not leaving until I'm not.
No one gives a shit
if you're on those tapes.
How do you and I know
it's not some kind of a setup?
- Oh, please.
- How?
Setup, how?
Maybe your boss
brought that kid here on purpose.
- Go on.
- Yeah.
Maybe she brought him
'cause she knows he's got drugs.
Or she gave him the drugs,
and she's setting both of them up.
They're having a good time,
they're drinking,
they're laughing, all of that.
But she wants him to overdose,
and she's got it on tape.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Then she makes a deal with my boss
to clean the whole thing up
like it never happened.
But she keeps the tape.
For what?
- For leverage, you dumbass.
- Leverage for what, dipshit?
- You tell me, asshole.
- That makes no fucking sense.
- You've seen too many movies.
- Fucking putz.
Oh, I...
- Shit.
- Fuck.
You okay?
- All good.
- Yep.
That doesn't make sense,
he wasn't breathing.
You didn't check his pulse?
Fuck you, I didn't check his pulse.
He didn't have a fucking pulse.
And yet...
And yet you didn't check his pulse,
you didn't ask.
- It's the first thing you do.
- He didn't have a fucking pulse.
- And yet...
- And yet, you didn't ask.
- You didn't say, "Is he dead?"
- I didn't think I had to.
You think I didn't check his pulse?
No, I do not. I think you got rattled.
I think you forgot.
Bush-league is what you are.
You walk into a situation,
you see two people standing there,
one on the floor.
You don't ask, "Does he have a pulse?"
You don't ask, "Is he dead?"
You check for yourself.
- Thank you, sensei.
- Yeah.
I mean, maybe it was the drugs.
I don't know.
Oh, that's just lazy bullshit.
It doesn't work that way.
Well, he's not dead.
It would appear not.
- Just admit you didn't check.
- Oh, just shut up. I'm trying to think.
Oh, it was a magic drug
- that makes your heartbeat so slow...
- Would you shut the fuck up?
It doesn't matter.
This is a different thing now.
Wait, this is great.
Think about it. He's gotta know.
We need to go. We need to hurry.
It's not a guarantee.
I know, but we need to go now
before his brain turns into applesauce.
Brain probably already is applesauce.
Listen, I don't wanna
have to go door-to-door
like some fucking Jehovah's Witness
trying to return four fucking bricks of
God-knows-what-did-that-to-him, do you?
- Was that your plan?
- I'm trying to make a point.
It is worth a shot.
I agree.
Okay, then. I know someone.
Fuck no.
- What? My guy's good.
- Fuck your guy. Some bullet puller.
- The only way that'd go is sideways.
- Fuck you. We're using my guy.
It only works with my guy. It's exclusive.
My car, my guy. Fuck you.
Fucking...
And?
Didn't pick up. Where we going?
Chinatown.
Take a right out of the exit
and that'll take you...
- I know how to get to Chinatown.
- Mm-hmm.
- The Albanians.
- What?
The Albanians had this thing a while back.
Yeah, I know.
Massive shipment of pure, uncut heroin
en route from Europe
suddenly just disappears.
I know.
You think those bricks
came from their shipment?
- You should just take them back yourself.
- No.
I'm not interested in being murdered,
is what I'm saying.
The Albanians will kill
and have killed anybody they even suspect
of stealing that shipment.
So, whoever did it, sends this kid in
to be a honeypot
to seduce my client
to get some political flex,
to crack down on the Albanians to
clear the playing field to sell the drugs.
So, they send in
the kid with the backpack.
They want him to take the drugs,
they want him to overdose,
and...
No, it doesn't work.
Keep at it. You'll crack it eventually.
Left on Division.
I gotta clear you first.
Okay.
- Can't just waltz up there with a guy...
- Okay.
Nope, not tonight.
It's not about that.
I'm sure it's not.
Come on, really.
This is real. I need help.
What kind of help?
Well...
So, um, yeah.
Hold on, I'm coming down.
What happens to the kid after he talks?
If he talks, my job's done.
So, this other guy kills him?
- Do you vouch for him?
- He's been all right.
I'm not gonna vouch for him.
I... You know, can't go that far.
He's like... You know...
He's like one of those guys, you know?
No, I-I don't know. One of what guys?
One of those guys
who thinks he's, like, some genius.
- Got it all figured out, you know?
- Yeah, I'm familiar with that type.
I don't wanna fix this kid up
just so you can put a bullet in his...
He's had his moment, you know,
where he was the go-to guy,
the hot-shit guy,
but that wore off a long time ago,
and no one's told him yet.
Probably lives in
a single-bedroom apartment,
watching old black-and-white movies till
he falls asleep 'cause he's so lonely.
Hello, June.
Hello.
You didn't pick up.
- I know.
- Mmm.
Is there really a kid in your trunk?
- How long have you two been...
- Not what you think.
You told him it was exclusive.
Oh, are there more?
Is there an OD'ing kid in your trunk?
Because if there is, then this...
- Was he before me?
- Yes.
- Yes?
- No. Yes?
- Yes.
Then can we take care of the OD'ing kid
first, you fucking lunatics?
Hmm.
You need to be careful.
Both of you need to be.
There are people out there.
If they saw you two together, I...
You said it was exclusive.
What? You did!
Shit.
Come on, bring him in here.
- And careful of your back.
- Yep.
All right. On three. You ready?
Wait. One, two, three, right?
Not one, two, three, go?
- Of course not.
- Good.
One, two, three.
Do you know what he took?
- No.
- I'm not sure.
Well, it must have been
some bad combination
or something extremely pure.
God, it's like he doesn't even
have a heartbeat.
I know a lot of paramedics
would have called him.
Oh, really?
- We just need him to talk.
- Let me get this straight.
You're saying it's like
he took some kind of a magic drug?
- So, how many...
- Makes your heartbeat so slow that...
How many clowns
you got running through this joint?
Now is... It's really not the time.
- Why didn't you pick up when I called?
- Okay, both of you out. Now.
Out.
Did you know?
I had my suspicions.
Yeah.
Never saw anyone,
never heard anything, so I didn't ask.
If it makes you feel any better,
she is the best.
Sure.
My first guy, I came in to get
a bullet pulled out of my side,
and he wants to put me under.
I said, "Fuck no."
Come to find out,
he's taking people's kidneys
without asking them.
People are waking up and thinking,
"Hey, that's a big scar
for getting a bullet pulled."
She saved my life.
No kidding.
Yeah. Shrapnel, inch away from my spine.
Spent two weeks
in the basement recovering.
Back in October?
Maybe. How would you know that?
I was here.
Come on.
I was wondering why
she didn't let me near the cellar.
- She is the best.
- She is.
I guess I knew it wasn't exclusive.
- What are the odds?
- Right?
Both of us sleeping with
the same Chinatown doctor.
Oh, were you... you two not...
Stop him!
Go right at the...
- Take the...
- I know.
- Hello.
- Mm-hmm.
Come back here!
Stop running!
Ow.
Shit.
Whoa.
Fuck!
Get in the car.
Fucker.
Hey, asshole! What are you doing?
Come on.
Who are you guys?
No!
- Come on. We just need to...
- No!
Hey! Dum-dums!
Uh, catch.
Take two of the big ones
every couple of hours
and one of the small ones every six.
And lots of water.
Also, I'm not sleeping with him.
He's just fucking with you.
Yeah. I was just fucking with you.
No.
- Come on. You got a place.
- Maybe I do.
Of course you do.
Knock it off!
- You know what you sound like?
- What?
You sound like a guy who's got a place.
You got a place. Let's go to your place.
- We're not going to my place.
- Why not?
That's the point of having a place.
Exactly.
Okay.
- What the fuck?
- Get dressed.
Come on.
So that all those who
come to Christ may enter into his kingdom.
Need a room.
- Love Nest, Arabian Nights, or Safari?
- Excuse me?
Love Nest, Arabian Nights, or Safari?
Love Nest, Arabian Nights
are three minimum.
Safari I can do by the hour.
Into the family of God
and are sanctified.
He's not a prostitute.
Sit down.
So, uh, how do you wanna do this?
'Cause I've never
really done it like this be...
I mean, I could start, I guess,
and then...
- Then I just jump in when it feels right.
- Yeah. Unless you wanna start and then...
No, you go. You go. You got this.
I'll just, uh, follow your lead.
Mmm.
- Okay.
- Mm-hmm.
- Where...
- So...
Hmm.
Where'd you get the drugs?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Mm-hmm. Okay.
- Where'd you get the drugs?
- I don't know.
I don't know anything about any drugs.
- Where did you get the drugs?
- I don't...
Talk, asshole.
Show him the rest.
Come on.
Huh?
Now.
Those aren't mine.
Can I talk to you in the hall,
just for a minute?
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
You asked the same thing three times.
I thought this could...
He didn't know we had the drugs.
He was panicked. We had leverage.
He wasn't panicked.
He wasn't gonna say anything.
- You don't know that.
- How many times were you gonna ask?
Ten times? Twenty time... Hey!
You know, there's an art to this
you may not realize.
What, the art of saying
the same thing over and over?
- Okay. Well, let's see your technique.
- I'm not gonna show you my technique.
- Because you don't have a technique.
- No.
No? Then why?
Because you'll steal it.
- I'll steal it? You think I'll steal it?
- There you go, repeating again.
You don't have a technique.
I do, and it involves a little bit more
than saying the same
thing over and over again.
I showed you my luggage cart trick.
- You didn't show me. I saw it.
- Yeah, but you liked it. You'll use it.
- Maybe.
- Mmm. Come on. Admit it. It was cool.
- Okay, fine. It was very cool.
- Yeah, it's cool.
So, what's the next move here?
Can't we just get to it?
What do you mean?
Like, I don't wanna be here.
Hmm. You miss your place?
I feel like I'm getting syphilis just
standing here. Let's just get to it.
- Really?
- Why not?
Hmm. Let's get to it.
Great.
Where'd you get the fucking drugs?
- ...the fucking drugs, you asshole?
- Lagrange!
They call him Lagrange!
Lagrange?
- What about him?
- They're his... or they were... the drugs.
- Bullshit. How?
- How? What do you mean? How-How what?
How does someone like you
get involved with one of the biggest
- drug runners in the city?
- Yeah.
Well... So, I'm not a prostitute, okay.
That's n... That's not what's happening.
How did you get the drugs?
Fuck you! I'm fucking trying to explain.
Just let me explain. Let me explain, okay?
Can I get a glass of water?
- I mean, she did say hydrate.
- Yeah, I know. I...
Fine. Fine. Fuck it.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Ugh.
Thank you.
Mmm.
Oh, boy.
Oh, my goodness.
Mmm.
Okay.
So, I wake up...
Jesus Christ, kid. You woke up...
You gotta start the story there?
- Just let him talk.
- I... Yeah.
It's not gonna make sense unless
I tell you the whole thing.
So, you think
you need to add in the detail
that you woke up in case it wasn't clear?
- Yes, I do. It's how I started my day.
- That's how everyone starts their day!
What he's saying is take a minute
to think about what's
the most important part of the story
and leave the rest out.
- Well, uh, I...
- Hey!
Think about it.
Right. Um...
Well, so I'm...
I'm-I'm-I'm... I'm getting up
and I'm... I'm getting out of bed and,
um... Uh...
...you know, my room is a mess
and I'm-I'm... I'm not exactly hungover,
but I'm still feeling a little bit... Shit!
Fuck! Sorry, sorry, sorry.
Okay. I-I-I... Yes.
- Oh, I leave my house and...
- No.
All right. Just let him
do the whole thing. He can't do it.
- I... No, I can do it.
- No, you can't do it.
- Yeah, I can.
- Just go fast, all right?
- Okay. Yes. I, uh...
- Now, what the fuck happened?
Yes. Okay. So, I'm, like...
I wasn't trying to make any
money or anything, like, be a drug dealer.
Like, I-I've been taking classes at Pace.
I've been trying to learn business.
Some... Some business classes 'cause,
you know,
people are gonna try and fuck you with,
like, law and legal shit unless, you know,
you know how it works.
So, I'm taking these classes,
and there's this dude there and he's,
like, legit.
He is from some real shit but he's, like,
so smart also.
I mean he's, like, basically a genius
smart, and today his fucking mom died.
Like, he got this call in class
and his fucking mom was in the hospital,
and she fucking died because they didn't,
like, give her the right medicine
or some shit.
Like, they fucked up.
So I'm just like,
"Dude, whatever you need, dude."
And he, like, trusts me.
Like, we hang out and shit.
And I told you he's legit,
like, no fucking around.
So, he's like...
he's like, "I'm supposed to do
this drop for my boss and now I can't."
And I was like,
"Say no more, I will do it."
Like, I don't do this kind of shit.
So he gives me the shit and I'm like,
"Fuck, are you fucking serious?"
But his mom just fucking died,
so I say, "Okay, dude. I'll do it."
So I'm... I'm... I'm killing some time
before I get the address for the drop.
And I'll admit it,
I'm feeling pretty fucking cool,
but also it's scary and shit,
and my heart's, like,
fucking pounding out of my chest.
So I duck into this bar.
It's, like, this hotel bar,
and I'm... I'm... I'm kind of
feeling myself 'cause,
like, I'm on some real shit,
and it's, like, people are noticing.
Like, girls are fucking noticing, like,
I've got the fucking juice
all of a sudden.
And it's, like... I didn't even, like,
take a shower this morning, you know?
Like... Like I was trying to say before.
And it's, like, three fucking girls, they
just start talking to me, like, hot girls.
Like, I've got the fucking juice.
They're buying me drinks
and shit 'cause I'm broke.
And then,
I'm coming out of the bathroom,
and this older lady,
she's fucking hot too,
is straight up like,
"Do you wanna come up to my room?"
And I'm like, "Yes, yes, yes. Of course."
This is my life. Why not live it?
And it's, like,
Diego's mom just fucking died,
so I'm thinking about my life,
and I'm thinking about how
it could just all go away at any time.
And so, we're partying
and I fucking... I fucking...
I just wanted to see
what it was like, you know?
It's like there was magic in there
wrapped up in plastic,
like, it was radiating out,
and I just wanted to try it.
Just the tiniest amount
'cause it's, like...
Today was, like,
the first day that I ever felt cool.
Not that you guys would understand.
You're, like,
the coolest guys I've ever seen.
But I was so careful.
Like, I was so careful.
You would never know that I tried it,
but I did.
I did try it,
and it didn't make me feel cool.
It just... I just... I just... I just,
like...
Is that it?
I think so, yeah.
- Okay, then.
- What's the address for the drop?
- I don't know.
- Where's your phone?
Uh, I hid it.
In the hotel?
- No, before I left.
- Why?
In case something happened. I hid
my wallet too, in case I got picked up.
How were you gonna get the address of
the drop if you don't have your phone?
The pager.
- Pager?
- Where's your pager?
I don't have a pager.
What's this, like, the '90s?
Who has the pager?
- No one.
- No one has the pager?
- No.
- Where is it?
Diego left it for me at his work.
- Where?
- It's called Club Ice.
Used to be, uh, the something,
uh, Palazzo. Uh, I don't know.
He bartends there sometimes.
This guy, Diego, why would he trust you?
I guess 'cause we're friends.
Do you guys...
You don't think it's too late?
Early, late.
You took the job, you gave your word.
You're gonna finish it.
Right.
Are you guys seeing that?
How long have you both
worked together for?
- A long time.
- I stopped counting.
Really? Mmm.
Well, yeah, you can tell.
- Is that so?
- Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, you got, like,
basically the same clothes,
kinda talk the same, you know.
You're, like, basically the same guy.
Hey, everything's gonna be okay, right,
after I make the drop?
'Cause I just...
I have a really big exam next week.
I really don't wanna screw that up.
You won't have to worry about that.
I'll be two seconds.
- You're hilarious.
- What? No, no. I wo... I won't run.
- Well, in that case...
- No, seriously. I can just go in.
I'll get the pager. It'll be fine.
All right? I promise.
I'm not gonna... What?
Is that...
Croatian.
Why you both looking
at each other like that?
You did that thing down in Gowanus,
didn't you?
No. Why would you say that?
I wondered why he didn't call me.
And when I heard
- what a shit show that was...
- No, that wasn't a shit show.
So you did do Gowanus?
What is happening?
Not sure what happened to the body though.
You know that explosion
at the evidence warehouse in the Bronx?
You're kidding. That was you?
Yeah.
That was in October.
- You were recovering at June's.
- Yeah.
Shit. She tried to warn me tonight.
She said there were people out there
who, if they saw us t...
We need to get the pager.
Why can't we just go in and get the pager?
- Because we can't.
- Why not?
Is it 'cause of the drugs?
In case they're searching people?
'Cause one of you guys could
just wait in here with the drugs.
- I'm not leaving him with all the drugs.
- I'm not leaving him.
You don't trust your own partner?
Where is it?
- What?
- The pager.
It's at the...
No. I'm not telling.
No fucking around, kid.
- Where is the pager?
- Tell me what's going on.
- No. Where's the pager?
- Why can't you tell me?
- We can't.
- Why not?
- Because we can't.
- Why?
- Because we...
- 'Cause we're not partners.
What?
There is an expectation
of discretion in our line of work.
A kind of monasticism.
At least the way I learned it.
Same.
When you hire someone to do what we do,
you want someone who works alone.
No connections. No conflicting loyalties.
It's the only way you can be trusted,
is to trust no one.
But in that building back there
is a very scary,
very violent man who, it turns out,
we have both worked for in the past.
- And if he saw us together...
- If he even suspected
I knew what he knew...
And I knew what he knew.
Then he would, without hesitation,
have us killed immediately.
Or he'd kill us himself.
So you're secret partners?
- We're not secret partners.
- We're not partners. Jesus Christ.
All right. Here's what gonna happen.
We keep the drugs with us.
And we all go in.
No one leaves anyone's sight.
And you get that goddamn pager.
I'm going to pray to Christ that
Dimitri doesn't see you and me together.
Dumbest, most dangerous plan.
Are you really not partners?
The ladder's really cold.
What?
Shut up.
Um, I'm friends with Diego,
and he left something for me.
- What?
- He left a pager.
Diego, he left a pager for me.
It's a green pager.
- Got you, man.
- Okay. Thank you.
No, no, no. No, no, no.
It's a pager. It's right there.
Can you...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- What are you doing behind the bar?
- I wasn't doing anything.
I was just talking to that guy over there.
No.
Okay, okay.
Ooh, ah.
Hey, hey, hey!
Hey!
No, boys, no! Everyone, calm down!
What's going on here, Dimitri?
- Who the fuck is this asshole?
- Who the fuck are you?
Boys, boys, it's fine.
Everyone, calm down. Give me those.
Guns are only for the wedding party.
I'm sorry, baby. Please, I'm sorry...
...I'll fix it.
Everyone, it's okay.
They are friends.
Yeah.
Come here, both of you.
Come here.
Start the music, please.
Hey.
You crash my daughter's wedding
and then you pull out guns, huh?
I came to pay my respects.
Wait, Dimitri, you know this asshole?
Believe it or not,
you two offer not dissimilar services.
With all due respect, Dimitri,
I highly doubt that.
And if I ever see you again, bucko...
Oof.
Hey!
Let's go!
Oof.
All right, all right, all right.
Hey, leave him. Stay. Have a drink.
- I got a job to do.
- Oh, I see.
The professional.
The lone wolf. Mmm.
Sorry for the disturbance.
Congratulations
on your daughter's wedding.
Sweetie.
Hey, sweetie.
Come here. Hey.
Buddies...
Hey!
See?
I told you I wasn't gonna run.
There's no address yet.
We still got some time.
I wanna finish the job too.
Come on.
Would you shut your mouth when you chew?
Okay.
Hey, how do you even start
doing something like this?
Like what-what...
you know, what you guys do.
What is it you think we do?
Well, you fix things, right?
Like, if something's messed up or,
like, if someone, like,
messes up, you, like, make it okay, right?
More or less.
Hmm. Well, um, thank you.
Mmm.
Too bad you both can't work together.
Like, what you do must be really lonely.
I'm gonna pee.
So, Lagrange has a mole with Dimitri,
or Diego is playing both sides somehow.
- You still on this conspiracy thing?
- Diego's dead mom was a bullshit story.
They're setting the kid up. But why?
And how did Lagrange get that shipment?
What does it matter?
- You're not curious?
- Doesn't change the job.
So you're not curious?
Would be a valuable piece of intel.
We'd have to figure out how to play it.
We both can't know everything.
Okay. Then one of us would make the drop.
Then maybe we figure out
what the fuck's going on.
If we get the address.
If we get the address,
one of us makes the drop.
No.
He has to do it.
What? You... No, no, no.
He could run. He could talk.
There's too many variables with that kid.
He has to do it.
I'm not following.
Sometimes the job takes care of itself.
Oh.
So the kid walks in and he gets shot?
Because you don't wanna do it?
I don't do anything I don't have to.
Especially not that.
Or you've lost your nerve.
Mmm. I mean, this kid doesn't come home,
people are gonna look for him.
This way, they find him.
No, no. I get it.
You could just let him live.
Hmm.
Let's say you're wrong.
The kid makes the drop,
and he walks out alive.
Then...
You know why they have
multiple shooters on a firing squad?
I do.
So...
- I'm not asking. I don't need your help.
- I know y...
I'm... I'm offering.
Why? So you can say I lost my edge?
To who?
I'm saying that I unders...
I know what...
what that feels... doing that.
So maybe this way it would...
be a little less...
yeah.
You know it?
Did it go off?
Oh, thank God.
Oh, my God.
I thought we were dead.
Oh, my God. Thank you. Thank you.
Oh, thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you, thank you.
Now what?
Now you go in.
You guys aren't coming?
You took the job. Now you gotta finish it.
Right.
Are you guys gonna wait for me?
All right.
I'll be back.
It could take care of itself.
Fuck it.
- Is that the...
- The Albanians.
Fuck!
Go, go, go, go, go!
You are not wolves! You are buddies!
Three, two...
Hmm.
Is everybody dead?
Oh, my God. Jesus Christ. What the fuck?
What happened?
So, I'm walking up to the warehouse,
and I'm... I'm thinking to myself,
like, "Oh, this is really scary."
But I was thinking that I could do it,
'cause you guys
gave me confidence,
and I thought that I could do it.
Oh, my God.
Stop, stop. Stop. Doesn't matter.
Fuck. Now what?
Finish the job.
What?
You came here to drop off the drugs.
Do it.
How am I supposed to...
What, I just put 'em anywhere?
What story are you trying to tell?
Uh...
Um, I'm pretty sure that this guy, uh,
over here was in charge of these guys,
um, so maybe he had this one.
Uh...
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh. I know. Yeah.
And, uh, let's say this guy, maybe he...
...trying to get away, you know.
He didn't even wanna be here.
Looks more realistic.
Let's go. You don't wanna be here
when the sun comes up.
Um...
...could I get a ride home?
Take the subway.
Please.
We're all taking the subway.
You got blood on your sweater.
Fucker.
I didn't care.
Hmm.
Oh. What are we gonna tell my dad?
That nothing unusual happened tonight,
and if either of you
were to say anything differently,
we're gonna flip a coin
to see who's gonna kill you
and who's gonna kill your dad.
Hmm.
Was nice to meet you guys.
You never met us.
Right.
Um, hey, Dad. These guys
need to talk to you about something.
So, Frank is doing this movie,
Manchurian Candidate.
He's notorious for just doing one take.
And the director, he says,
"That was perfect. Let's do one more."
Frank says, "I'll tell you what,
if it's so perfect,
why don't you print it twice?"
You like it black?
Black's fine.
Yeah.
Hey. Get back. Come on.
Little. Come on.
So... what's this all about?
Wanna grab some breakfast?
I know a place.
Brighton Beach,
across from where they had the...
Exactly. I love that place.
That was a very intimidating
performance in there, by the way.
You like that thing
with the pliers?
Might even steal it.
You like blini?
Love a blini.
Yeah.
There we go. Thank you.
- A tracker.
- In the goddamn drugs.
Should've caught that immediately.
So, did Lagrange even
steal the drugs, or were...
I...
Oh, so now you don't care
who stole the shipment?
I don't think it matters
as long as the kid stays quiet.
You do realize one of us,
most likely, eventually...
Yeah. Probably. Cross that bridge...
If he can be killed.
Yeah. Well...
Lucky fucker.
Well, that was a night.
Yeah.
All right, then.
So, what did she say to you
to get you to work with me?
What'd she say? She had all the leverage.
She said that I didn't have a choice.
All right.
"You take a job, you give your word,
and that word's the measure of the man."
Who called you?
What?
In the car to June's.
- Who called you?
It was your guy.
My guy?
The guy that Pam got your number from.
Your guy.
- So, she must have called him.
- But then why call me?
Who called...
You're saying the DA got your number...
No.
Yeah.
We have the same guy?
We both have the same guy.
But why does he care?
It's just a cleanup job.
- He doesn't. Unless...
- Unless he knew about the drugs.
Kid's dead, can't make the drop,
so he calls us.
- One at a time, but nobody answers.
- So, he sent someone else.
- Chinatown.
- Sees the kid's alive.
- Hard to miss. The plan's back on track.
- Except,
- we're on our way to Dimitri's...
- Who would have killed us, except...
We didn't fool Dimitri. He was tipped off.
Bodyguard didn't get the memo.
The Albanians don't make a move because...
- The tracker's not even on.
- Until the page.
- It was all a setup.
- It looks like Lagrange
is trying to move the stolen drugs.
And the Albanians go to war with Lagrange,
- no competition.
- The city shuts down.
- People get arrested.
- I know a DA who's tough on crime.
- ...the real thief to clean up.
- ...who can clean drug money.
Great things to come.
No wonder they wanted
the cameras in the room.
He wanted to know who knew.
But the kid turns
the ambush into a shoot-out.
We were supposed to take the fall.
He didn't think we'd send the kid in.
We were getting cleaned.
- He's not gonna let us out of here alive.
- Nope.
They're really
not taking any chances, are they?
No.
You know, I never did catch your name.
I tell you what, we survive this...
Deal.
Ready?
Yeah.
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Whoo!
- Yeah! Yeah! Whoo!
- Whoo! Whoo.
- Whoa!
I got you.
Fuck.